<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>The Vekllei State on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/series/the-vekllei-state/</link>
	<description>Recent content in The Vekllei State on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/series/the-vekllei-state/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Education</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/education/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/education/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei. It UNFINISHED and will be completed in the next couple days. Education emerged as a foundational right for Vekllei people in the constitution of the 4th Commonwealth, in the spirit of postwar democratisation and the rising of all people. Education in Vekllei is a good example of the &amp;lsquo;system working backwards,&amp;rsquo; the popular phrase to describe the Floral Period moving in two different directions at once.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Espionage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/espionage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/espionage/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei. Espionage is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Finance</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei Even if they do not use money, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests. The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &amp;ldquo;functionally moneyless,&amp;rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>State Assets</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/assets/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/assets/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei Large segments of the Vekllei economy are dominated by industries of the state, as both direct ministerial privileges and state-owned enterprises. In total, they form the basis of the basic Vekllei standard of living, holding back catastrophe through reliable overproduction where gaps in the participatory economy might threaten serious shortages. There is no real distinction in Vekllei between state assets, state-owned enterprises (SOE) and government-owned corporations (GOC), and the terms are used interchangeably.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>