<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Kalina</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Kalina </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Allia Republic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/allia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/allia/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Allia is part of Kalina Allia Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Athlone Population 16,302 Languages Irish, Allia Creole, English Area 102 km2 Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Allia Republic is a constituent republic in the Caribbean Sea, and part of the Lesser Antilles island chain that make up the Kalina Commonwealth, which is part of Vekllei. Its closest neighbour, Antam, is just under 50km to its northeast.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Allia is part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></div>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/ms.svg);"></span> Allia Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/allia.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Athlone</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>16,302</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Irish, Allia Creole, English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>102 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-ms"></span> <strong>Allia Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> in the Caribbean Sea, and part of the Lesser Antilles island chain that make up the Kalina Commonwealth, which is part of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. Its closest neighbour, Antam, is just under 50km to its northeast.</p>
<p>Often called the &ldquo;Emerald Isle&rdquo; of the Caribbean, Allia&rsquo;s history and culture is heavily influenced by British settlement of indebted and enslaved Irish and African peoples, whose descendants make up almost all of the 16,000 people who live there today. Like all Vekllei <a href="/republics/">republics</a>, the language of government and business is English, but Alliot households speak Irish primarily and many speak Allia Creole, a combination of Irish and indigenous Kalinago languages influenced by neighbouring islands. As such, Allia has the largest population of Irish speakers outside of Ireland. They are mostly Roman Catholic.</p>
<p>Allia was uninhabited during the time of its settling by the British in the 17th Century. It was during this first century that the plantation economy started receiving shipments of slaves from Africa and later Ireland, a practice that continued up until the abolishment of slavery in the early 19th Century. It remained part of the UK in various forms until the independence of the British Atlantic Territories and subsequently became part of Vekllei. Today, its economy is mostly agricultural, but its strong music scene and creative industries are thriving in the capital of Athlone, and contribute to Allia&rsquo;s outsized cultural influence in Vekllei. Its unique history makes it a popular destination for Vekllei tourists, as well as some foreigners.</p>
<p>The island is about 18km long by 10km wide and resembles a pear. It has rugged, volcanic mountains with long pyroclastic slopes that stretch to the water. These mountains are thickly forested with jungle typical of its tropical Caribbean region. The island is actively volcanic and eruptions occur periodically, most recently in the mid-1990s when the Soufrière Hills erupted and destroyed mostly uninhabited areas in the island&rsquo;s southwest.</p>
<p>Most Alliots live in the capital of Athlone, but there are estates and villages that circumnavigate the entire coast. They are connected by a mainline train service, as well as small trams and funiculars. Allia is connected to the rest of Kalina by fast hydrofoils and flying boats.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Aloubaera Republic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloubaera/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloubaera/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Aloubaera is part of Kalina Aloubaera Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Scarborough Population 72,045 Languages English, Creole, Spanish Area 300 km2 Vekllei Accession 1930, as part of the Alford Agreement The Aloubaera Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei, and parts of the Kalina Commonwealth. It is just 35km northeast of its neighbour republic of Kairi.
Aloubaera has a tropical climate cooled substantially by its exposure to the sea.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Aloubaera is part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></div>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/aloubaera.svg);"></span> Aloubaera Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/aloubaera.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Scarborough</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>72,045</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Creole, Spanish</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>300 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1930, as part of the Alford Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-aloubaera"></span> <strong>Aloubaera Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and parts of the Kalina Commonwealth. It is just 35km northeast of its neighbour republic of <a style="color: rgb(215, 18, 45)" href="/kairi/"><span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> Kairi</a>.</p>
<p>Aloubaera has a tropical climate cooled substantially by its exposure to the sea. Most of the island is hilly, and reaches 550m above sea level at its highest point. Its interior is home to dense biodiverse rainforest, most of which is protected within the Aloubaera National Forest. It is vulnerable to seasonal hurricanes moving along the south hurricane belt.</p>
<p>Most Aloubaerans are black or mixed-race of African descent, though minority populations of Whites, Caribs and Indians also live there. The republic remains dependent on <a style="color: rgb(215, 18, 45)" href="/kairi/"><span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> Kairi</a> for electricity and tertiary education. A local creole and English are widely spoken.</p>
<p>The republic&rsquo;s economy consists of municipal goods, light agriculture in communal smallholdings, and some domestic tourism. It has spectacular coral reefs in its south, and there is a hotel there. Nonetheless, island life on Aloubaera is insular and close-knit, and many young Aloubaerans leave for Kairi or other parts of Vekllei for study and work.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Kairi Republic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Kairi is part of Vekllei Kalina Kairi Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Conquerabia Population 2,480,384 Languages English, Creole, Hindustani, Spanish Area 4831 km2 Vekllei Accession 1930, as part of the Alford Agreement The Kairi Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Caribbean. It is the southernmost part of the Kalina island group, and adjacent to Aloubaera. At its nearest point, Kairi is 11km off the coast of Venezuela, making it the closest border Vekllei has to a continental landmass.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Kairi is part of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> Kalina</div>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/kairi.svg);"></span> Kairi Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/kairi.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Conquerabia</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>2,480,384</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Creole, Hindustani, Spanish</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>4831 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1930, as part of the Alford Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> <strong>Kairi Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Caribbean. It is the southernmost part of the Kalina island group, and adjacent to <a style="color: rgb(46, 114, 225)" href="/aloubaera/"><span class="fi fi-aloubaera"></span> Aloubaera</a>. At its nearest point, Kairi is 11km off the coast of Venezuela, making it the closest border Vekllei has to a continental landmass. It comprises a single large island and a few smaller ones, and enjoys a tropical climate cooled by sea breezes year-round.</p>
<p>Kairi is home mostly to ethnic Indians and Africans, as well as Caribs who had settled the island prior to colonisation by European powers. About a third are descended from African slaves brought over to work sugar and cocoa plantations, and another third are Indian descended from indentured labourers brought over from South Asia by the British. The Indian population is the largest South Asian community in <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and retain their own language, religion and customs.</p>
<p>Kairi is the industrial heart of the Kalina island group and has substantial oil, gas, electricity, steel, aluminium, fertiliser, textiles and chemical industries. It is home to Vekllei&rsquo;s second fusion power plant, opened in 2024, which supplies its heavy industries and neighbouring republics with power.</p>
<p>The capital of Conquerabia is home to <a style="color: rgb(219, 37, 21)" href="/oil/"><span class="fi fi-min-oil fis"></span> CommOil</a> and the Cherry Automobile Plant, which manufactures consumer and commercial vehicles. <a style="color: rgb(237, 1, 0)" href="/cateral/"><span class="fi fi-min-cateral fis"></span> Cateral</a>, the largest firearms manufacturer in Vekllei, is also headquartered there. The islands are well-serviced by a dense network of small trains and trams typical of the Vekllei Caribbean.</p>
<p>Thanks to its relative wealth, development and ready accession with Commonwealth government, Kairi has long been an example republic of Vekllei governance and planning in the Caribbean. It is host to several international schools and missions, and contributes substantially to the overall prosperity of the Vekllei Caribbean. Kairi is the site of the original and main campus of the Commonwealth University of the West Indies, which ranks highly among national tertiary schools. It is also the administrative capital of the Kalina Commonwealth state.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Virgin Republic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/virgin/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/virgin/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Virgin is part of Kalina Virgin Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Roadie (administrative) Population 182,295 Languages English, French, Spanish Area 472.75 km2 Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Virgin Republic is a constituent republic of the Kalina Commonwealth in the Caribbean Sea, and is part of Vekllei. It is the westernmost part of the Kalina island group.
It comprises ten large islands in an archipelago extending eastwards of Puerto Rico (U.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Virgin is part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></div>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/vg.svg);"></span> Virgin Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/virgin.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Roadie (administrative)</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>182,295</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, French, Spanish</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>472.75 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-vg"></span> <strong>Virgin Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of the Kalina Commonwealth in the Caribbean Sea, and is part of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is the westernmost part of the Kalina island group.</p>
<p>It comprises ten large islands in an archipelago extending eastwards of Puerto Rico (U.S.), as well as about 123 smaller islets and cays. Although these islands are situated on the fault-block mountains of the Puerto Rico trench, they are usually considered part of the Lesser Antilles due to their size and proximity of that chain. Virgin&rsquo;s westernmost island, Vieques, forms the second-closest sea border to another country (Puerto Rico, part of the U.S.) after Kairi.</p>
<p>Before consolidation under the British Atlantic Territories, the Virgin archipelago was subject to competing colonial settlement and claims. English, Spanish, French and Danish ownership at various times contribute to the linguistic and cultural diversity within Virgin today. About three-quarters of its 182,000 people are black, descended from slaves who worked plantations in the colonial period. Substantial minority populations of Arawaks, Indians, Chinese and Europeans also exist. Protestant christianity is the majority religion.</p>
<p>Virgin&rsquo;s climate is subtropical and pleasant, with warm weather cooled by trade winds crossing south. Individual islands are varied, often characterised by dense tropical forest that cover steep mountain interiors, and low-lying coastal plateaus that has been cleared for agriculture. Many natural harbours exist, many of which host major settlements including the capital of Roadie, and the cities of Charlotte Amalie and Christiansted.</p>
<p>Water scarcity across the islands has been historically severe, but alleviated in the 21st Century by desalination plants powered by nuclear fusion projects on the islands of St Croix and Tortola. The economy is dominated by the civil service, financial services and petrochemicals. Virgin refineries process oil from other parts of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> for the Caribbean region. Virgin depends heavily on imports from other parts of the country, especially for machinery and manufactured goods.</p>
<p>Virgin University is the second-largest university in Kalina, and the fourth largest in Vekllei. It is common for students from smaller Commonwealth islands to travel to Virgin for study. The republic is also popular as a domestic holiday destination thanks to its excellent climate and world-renowned beaches.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
