<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Commonwealth Secretariats on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/secretariat/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Commonwealth Secretariats on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/secretariat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Culture Secretariat</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/culture/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/culture/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a secretariat of the Vekllei Commonwealth Parliament  Commonwealth Culture Secretariat COLSEC  The Commonwealth Culture Secretariat (COLSEC) is concerned primarily with &amp;lsquo;cultural values and beliefs&amp;rsquo; of the Commonwealth, their protection, and foreign relations. Its subordinate offices are dedicated to key areas of concern designed to assist its smaller member-states which may lack the political infrastructure to facilitate their own offices.
Commonwealth Central Archives The COLSEC Commonwealth Affairs Office (COLSA) is responsible for the documentation of the general disposition, welfare, culture and demography of the people of the Commonwealth.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Education Secretariat</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/education/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/education/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a secretariat of the Vekllei Commonwealth Parliament  Commonwealth Education Secretariat CHICOM  The Commonwealth Education Secretariat (CHICOM) is the commonwealth body responsible for all state education across the Commonwealth, including compulsory primary, vocational and tertiary schooling. Alongside the COSMOCOM Accreditation Directorate, CHICOM certifies teachers and the Commonwealth curriculum, and publishes textbooks and learning materials via the Children&amp;rsquo;s and Tertiary Press.
The stated mission of CHICOM is the celebration of knowledge and the development of technical skills.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Security Secretariat</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a secretariat of the Vekllei Commonwealth Parliament  Commonwealth Security Secretariat OPSEC  The Commonwealth Security Secretariat (OPSEC) is the mother organisation of the internal and external security organs of the Vekllei government. These include intelligence gathering, espionage, special policing, and state security apparatuses.
Like most features of the
Commonwealth Military Command  National Intelligence Directorate The National Intelligence Directorate (N.I.) the secret service of the Commonwealth and Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s primary covert intelligence apparatus abroad.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>