<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Ministry of Light &amp; Water</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Ministry of Light &amp; Water </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Bureau of Light</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/bureau-of-light/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/bureau-of-light/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This bureau is part of the Ministry of Light &amp; Water The Bureau of Light (Commonwealth Electric Commission, commonly Thunderburo) is responsible for the state monopoly on electricity generation in Vekllei. Although the VEC is structured as a bureau company, its subsidiaries are state-owned and consequently operates similarly to other agency-level departments of the Interior Parliament. The VEC consists of multiple subcommissions dedicated to unique types of electricity generation in Vekllei, primarily through hydro-electric, geothermal and nuclear methods.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This bureau is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-lightandwater)" href="/ministry-of-light-and-water/"><span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> Ministry of Light &amp; Water</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> <strong>Bureau of Light</strong> (Commonwealth Electric Commission, commonly <em>Thunderburo</em>) is responsible for the state monopoly on electricity generation in Vekllei. Although the VEC is structured as a bureau company, its subsidiaries are state-owned and consequently operates similarly to other agency-level departments of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior">Interior Parliament</a>. The VEC consists of multiple subcommissions dedicated to unique types of electricity generation in Vekllei, primarily through hydro-electric, geothermal and nuclear methods.</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><h4 id="magma-electric-commission">
  Magma-Electric Commission
  <a class="anchor" href="#magma-electric-commission">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The Vekllei <em>Magma-Electric Commission</em> (colloquially <em>The Magma</em> or MEC) oversees geothermal electricity production in Vekllei. Because of Vekllei&rsquo;s location over the rift of the European and American continental plates, widespread geothermal electricity production is widespread and makes up the majority of commercial and domestic electricity consumption in Vekllei. Forty-six MEC plants of varying sizes supply clean renewable energy to Vekllei households, and waste heat is used to heat greenhouses Vekllei depends on for food production.</p></span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><h4 id="hydro-electric-commission">
  Hydro-Electric Commission
  <a class="anchor" href="#hydro-electric-commission">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The Vekllei <em>Hydro-Electric Commission</em> (colloquially <em>The Hydro</em>, not to be confused with the <a href="/#vekllei-water-commission"><em>Hydroburo</em></a>) oversees hydro-electric electricity generation in Vekllei, particularly in the glacial regions of the Vekllei Islands and Kala. Dramatic mountain terrain in the interior of the Vekllei Islands proved suitable candidates for hydro-electric dams, which were mostly constructed in the pre-war and immediate post-war era. Vekllei&rsquo;s oldest dam in <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/ou/">Ou</a> has been operating continuously for 156 years.</p></span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><h4 id="nuclear-electric-commission">
  Nuclear-Electric Commission
  <a class="anchor" href="#nuclear-electric-commission">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The Vekllei <em>Nuclear-Electric Commission</em> (also <em>Atomic Vekllei</em> or NEC) oversees nuclear electricity generation in Vekllei. Nuclear energy has proliferated in postwar Vekllei, and satisfies the Commonwealth&rsquo;s growing industrial power demands. Most commercial nuclear plants in Vekllei use uranium-233 reactor fuels, processed mostly at the National Centrifuge &amp; Enrichment Plant in Speidisn. Vekllei reactors mostly of a molten salt type. The NEC maintains 56 plants in total across the Commonwealth, most of which are located in the Vekllei Islands or Kala.</p></span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bureau of Water</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/bureau-of-water/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/bureau-of-water/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This bureau is part of the Ministry of Light &amp; Water The Commonwealth Water Commission (commonly Hydroburo) is responsible for providing potable drinking water, wastewater and stormwater services across Vekllei. Water in Vekllei is universal and of good quality. The Hydroburo also maintains offices for sewerage, conservation, and construction.
In Oslola and Kala, most drinking water comes from fresh glacial runoff that requires minimal treating. Industrial water consumption is provided by nuclear desalination plants operated by the Hydroburo.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This bureau is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-lightandwater)" href="/ministry-of-light-and-water/"><span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> Ministry of Light &amp; Water</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Water Commission</strong> (commonly <em>Hydroburo</em>) is responsible for providing potable drinking water, wastewater and stormwater services across <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. Water in Vekllei is universal and of good quality. The Hydroburo also maintains offices for sewerage, conservation, and construction.</p>
<p>In <a style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190)" href="/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a> and Kala, most drinking water comes from fresh glacial runoff that requires minimal treating. Industrial water consumption is provided by nuclear desalination plants operated by the Hydroburo.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Emergency Light &amp; Water Authority</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/emergency-light-and-water-authority/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/emergency-light-and-water-authority/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This authority is part of the Ministry of Light &amp; Water The Emergency Light and Water Authority (EVA) is a specialised department of the Ministry of Light and Water designed to mitigate interruption to electricity and water supply. Its mandate includes the security of utility infrastructure and disaster preparation. In the event of major interruption to the utilities supervised by the Ministry, the EVA would assume direct control of the Hydro and Thunderburos and coordinate their recovery.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This authority is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-lightandwater)" href="/ministry-of-light-and-water/"><span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> Ministry of Light &amp; Water</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> <strong>Emergency Light and Water Authority</strong> (EVA) is a specialised department of the Ministry of Light and Water designed to mitigate interruption to electricity and water supply. Its mandate includes the security of utility infrastructure and disaster preparation. In the event of major interruption to the utilities supervised by the Ministry, the EVA would assume direct control of the Hydro and Thunderburos and coordinate their recovery. Threats include both natural disasters like volcanic eruptions and earthquakes, as well as damage from conventional or nuclear war.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>NSRE</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/nsre/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/nsre/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[NSRD is part of the Ministry of Light &amp; Water and SIRO The Commonwealth Nuclear Science Research Establishment (NSRE) is a research organisation of the Ministry of Light & Water.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">NSRD is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-lightandwater)" href="/ministry-of-light-and-water/"><span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> Ministry of Light &amp; Water</a> and <a style="color: rgb(0, 155, 113)" href="/SIRO/"><span class="fi fi-min-siro fis"></span> SIRO</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-nsre fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Nuclear Science Research Establishment</strong> (NSRE) is a research organisation of the <a style="color: var(--color-lightandwater)" href="/ministry-of-light-and-water/"><span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> Ministry of Light & Water</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
