<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>State</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/</link>
	<description>Recent content in State </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Community of Oceans</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/oceans-community/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/oceans-community/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles The Community of Oceans (CO, or OCEANS) is an international and regional organisation dedicated to the advancement of island and oceangoing communities worldwide. It was founded by the Vekllei and is headquartered in Oslola. It has observer status in the United Nations General Assembly and maintains offices throughout the Atlantic, Caribbean and Pacific regions.
The role of the council is to draw islander and oceangoing nations closer together, promote independence from larger powers, establish and protect democratic systems, and provide investment and humanitarian aid to underdeveloped members.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Community of Oceans</strong> (CO, or OCEANS) is an international and regional organisation dedicated to the advancement of island and oceangoing communities worldwide. It was founded by the <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> and is headquartered in <a style="color: rgb(38, 48, 132)" href="/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>. It has observer status in the United Nations General Assembly and maintains offices throughout the Atlantic, Caribbean and Pacific regions.</p>
<p>The role of the council is to draw islander and oceangoing nations closer together, promote independence from larger powers, establish and protect democratic systems, and provide investment and humanitarian aid to underdeveloped members. The Council of Oceans historically offers a pathway to full membership in the Commonwealth of Oceans.</p>
<p>The Community of Oceans also maintains a number of other international organisations dedicated to specialised roles.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Community of Oceans</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Organisation for the Advancement of Island Democracy</li>
<li>Crisis Internationale</li>
<li>Aid Internationale</li>
<li>International Oceans Bank</li>
<li>International Oceans Police Organisation</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Member-States of the Council of Oceans</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Jamaica</li>
<li>Belize</li>
<li><a style="color: rgb(210, 15, 52)" href="/haiti/"><span class="fi fi-ht"></span> Haiti</a></li>
<li><a style="color: rgb(2, 123, 57)" href="/seychelles/"><span class="fi fi-sc"></span></span> Seychelles</a></li>
<li><a style="color: rgb(238, 183, 14)" href="/mauritius/"><span class="fi fi-mu"></span> Mauritius</a></li>
<li><a style="color: rgb(210, 15, 52)" href="/maldives/"><span class="fi fi-mv"></span></span> Maldives</a></li>
<li><a style="color: rgb(255, 92, 0)" href="/ceylon/"><span class="fi fi-lk"></span></span> Ceylon</a></li>
<li><a style="color: rgb(233, 128, 5)" href="/east-india/"><span class="fi fi-ei"></span></span> East India</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Consosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/consosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/consosva/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Consosva (a portmanteau of consivismiosn sovis, lit. &ldquo;contributory service&rdquo;) refers to a collection of laws that require adult citizens in Vekllei to be employed. The legal obligation is fairly straightforward and is easily avoided, and in practice acts as a form of moral pressure from the state.
Consosva is a legal obligation to register an occupation with your municipality, which forwards its ledger to the Vekllei government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Consosva</strong> (a portmanteau of <em>consivismiosn sovis</em>, lit. &ldquo;<em>contributory service</em>&rdquo;) refers to a collection of laws that require adult citizens in Vekllei to be employed. The legal obligation is fairly straightforward and is easily avoided, and in practice acts as a form of moral pressure from the state.</p>
<p>Consosva is a legal obligation to register an occupation with your municipality, which forwards its ledger to the Vekllei government. This is to encourage productivity and discourage &ldquo;social parasitism,&rdquo; as a requirement to contribute to the wealth of society. Failure to do so is considered a crime and is usually penalised with community service.</p>
<p>Consosva has many recognised exemptions, including full-time study, participating in <a href="/corsosva/">Compulsory Service</a>, acting as the primary caregiver of children, and poor health.</p>
<p>Consosva applies to Vekllei citizens or permanent residents aged between 22 and 50.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Constituents</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/constituents/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/constituents/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles A constituent (also constituent commonwealth) is a type regional government in Vekllei that exercises control over multiple republics. It is an intermediate administrative body with special privileges and responsibilities.
Constituent commonwealths have their own suite of ministries and a National Assembly, and exercise power comparable to a state in other federal countries. In practice, they are represent common regional interests of individual republics in the Commonwealth government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>A <strong>constituent</strong> (also <em>constituent commonwealth</em>) is a type regional government in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> that exercises control over multiple <a href="/republics/">republics</a>. It is an intermediate administrative body with special privileges and responsibilities.</p>
<p>Constituent commonwealths have their own suite of <a href="/ministries/">ministries</a> and a <a style="color: var(--color-purple)" href="/assembly/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei-purple fis"></span> National Assembly</a>, and exercise power comparable to a state in other federal countries. In practice, they are represent common regional interests of individual <a href="/republics">republics</a> in the <a href="/government/">Commonwealth government</a>.</p>
<h2 id="public-policy">
  Public Policy
  <a class="anchor" href="#public-policy">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The Commonwealth devolves certain aspects of public policy to Constituents. In practice, many devolved matters practice parity with Commonwealth <a href="/ministries/">ministries</a> and <a href="/councils/">councils</a>, and so are functionally identical to Commonwealth central policy.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Devolved Matters</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Agriculture and resource development</li>
<li>Culture</li>
<li>Economic development</li>
<li>Environment</li>
<li>Fire and rescue services</li>
<li>Health services</li>
<li><a href="/municipalities/">Municipal matters</a>
<ul>
<li>Housing</li>
<li>Utility distribution networks</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sport and recreation</li>
<li>Tourism</li>
<li>Town and country planning</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Many other aspects of government and public administration are facilitated by Commmonwealth secretariats directly. Further, many devolved matters rely on guidance from Commonwealth agencies to operate (e.g., distribution of utilities requires coordination with Commonwealth electric and water bureaus).</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Constitution</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/constitution/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/constitution/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is incomplete. Be mindful that its content may change. The Constitution of Vekllei, also known as the Floral Constitution, was the foundational text for a new Commonwealth after British administration ended in 2015. It was developed by the Council of Roses and ratified in August 2015. PREAMBLE # THE PUBLIC OF THE OCEANS ATLANTIC RESOLVES
to bring peace to Commonwealth realms twice destroyed in the pursuit of war, and to establish a new way of living worthy of a commitment in peace, and to protect the equal rights of men and women, and the dignity and worth of the human person, and to provide for the material and spiritual needs necessary in the aim of a commitment to dignity, AND IN SERVICE OF THESE AIMS]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <style>
  h3, h4 {
      margin: 0;
      font-size: 16px;
      border-radius: 2.5px;
  }
  article[autonumbering] h3::before {
     display: none;
  }
</style>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is <strong>incomplete</strong>. Be mindful that its content may change.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The Constitution of Vekllei, also known as the Floral Constitution, was the foundational text for a new Commonwealth after British administration ended in 2015. It was developed by the <a href="/rose-council/">Council of Roses</a> and ratified in August 2015.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="preamble">
  PREAMBLE
  <a class="anchor" href="#preamble">#</a>
</h2>
<p>THE PUBLIC OF THE OCEANS ATLANTIC RESOLVES</p>
<ul>
<li>to bring peace to Commonwealth realms twice destroyed in the pursuit of war, and</li>
<li>to establish a new way of living worthy of a commitment in peace, and</li>
<li>to protect the equal rights of men and women, and the dignity and worth of the human person, and</li>
<li>to provide for the material and spiritual needs necessary in the aim of a commitment to dignity,</li>
</ul>
<p>AND IN SERVICE OF THESE AIMS</p>
<ul>
<li>to unite the languages, culture, and races of the Public under a democratic and prosperous society, and</li>
<li>to defend these values unwaveringly by all means available to its councils, and</li>
<li>to elevate the lives of Atlantic people through the efforts of Atlantic peoples</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-commonwealth---the-public-powers">
  THE COMMONWEALTH - THE PUBLIC POWERS
  <a class="anchor" href="#the-commonwealth---the-public-powers">#</a>
</h2>
<h3 id="article-1">
  Article 1
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-1">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The<a href="/vekllei/"> Commonwealth of Vekllei</a> is a sovereign and independent unitary State within the framework of international law.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The territory of the Commonwealth is inviolable.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-2">
  Article 2
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-2">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The principle of government is a federal Directory of elected peers called the <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/directory/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Directory</a>, representing the disparate communities that make up the unitary Commonwealth.</p>
<ol>
<li>The Directory consists of representatives of each <a href="/constituents/">Constituent</a> as free republics, and <a href="/territories/">dependent or autonomous territories</a>.</li>
<li>Other territories retain permanent status in the Directory and may table motions with agreement of a Constituent.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth Directorate is advised by a Cabinet of peers to provide opinion and expertise, called the <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth Directorate and Cabinet combined form the <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a>, which is the supreme executive of the Commonwealth.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth is a State under the rule of law, committed to fundamental freedoms and rights.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-3">
  Article 3
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-3">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The executive power is exercised by the Council as a single body where Commonwealth jurisdiction applies. The Council has power over national and municipal parliaments.</p>
<h3 id="article-4">
  Article 4
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-4">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The legislative power is jointly exercised by Constituent <a href="/assembly/">National Assemblies</a> and the Commonwealth Senate, with special powers provisioned for the Senate as a supreme legislative body.</p>
<h3 id="article-5">
  Article 5
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-5">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The judiciary power is exercised by the courts and tribunals.</p>
<h3 id="article-6">
  Article 6
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-6">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The separation of the administrative, legislative and judiciary functions is guaranteed.</p>
<h3 id="article-7">
  Article 7
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-7">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The standard of the Commonwealth is the Sovereign Crown.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth Flag consists of an arctic rosette, depicted as 6 petals, printed in gold on a crimson background.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The use of the flag, standard and official symbols of the Commonwealth is governed by the Flag Ordinance dated 4th March 2015.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-8">
  Article 8
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-8">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth has 16 official languages, with protections for their use and preservation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The official written language is Veletian.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The official language of international commerce and business is English.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-9">
  Article 9
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-9">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Commonwealth is a secular state and has no state religion. Religion is separated from public life and affairs. Protections are included for traditional and folk religions of Commonwealth communities.</p>
<ol>
<li>Recognised traditional faiths include folk Oslolan spiritualism, Kalina local faiths and the Catholic, Apostolic and Roman religions.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="the-directory">
  THE DIRECTORY
  <a class="anchor" href="#the-directory">#</a>
</h2>
<h3 id="article-10">
  Article 10
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-10">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Constituents of the Commonwealth provide two representatives to the Directory as Prime Ministers. The Ministers practice equal power and make decisions as a single office (Sord).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Sord are citizens elected by the National Assembly of their constituent republic and consist of one man and one woman.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-11">
  Article 11
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-11">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Seat of Commonwealth Government is Comet, in the Meteor Administrative Region.</p>
<h3 id="article-12">
  Article 12
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-12">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Commonwealth Directorate is chaired by the Oslolan Sord, and chairmanship will pass to the right each year provided the incoming Sord is a Constituent.</p>
<h3 id="article-13">
  Article 13
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-13">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Council Chair represents the Commonwealth in its relations with foreign powers.</p>
<ol>
<li>Individual Sords will conduct relations with foreign powers as a subordinate, pertaining to the best interests of Constituents as required.</li>
</ol>
<!--
### Article 14
After consulting the Crown Council the Prince signs and ratifies treaties and in international convention. He acquaints the National Council through the Minister of State with them before their ratification.

However, the following treaties must be ratified in pursuance of a law:

Treaties and international agreements affecting the organisation of the Constitution
Treaties and international agreements the ratification of which entails the modification of the existing legal provisions
Treaties and international agreements which entail the Principality’s adhesion to an international organisation the functioning of which implies the participation of the National Council’s members
Treaties and international organisations the implementation of which results in a budget expenditure pertinent to expenditure type or use, which is not provided by the budget act
The Principality’s external policy is accounted for in an annual report prepared by the government and notified to the National Council.

### Article 15
After consulting the Cabinet, the Directory exercises the right to pardon and amnesty as well as the right of naturalisation and restoration of nationality.

### Article 16
Sords or the Directory confer orders, titles and other distinctions per Law.

## FUNDAMENTAL FREEDOMS AND RIGHTS

### Article 17
All Commonwealth citizens are equal before the law. There is no privilege among them.

### Article 18
The circumstances in which Vekllei nationality may be acquired are laid down by law. The circumstances in which a person who has acquired Vekllei nationality by naturalisation may be deprived of it are laid down in the law.

Loss of Vekllei nationality in any other circumstance may occur only, as prescribed by law, further to the intentional acquisition of another nationality or of service unlawfully carried out in a foreign army.

### Article 19
Individual freedom and security are guaranteed. No one may be prosecuted except in cases provided for by law, before legally appointed judges and in the manner prescribed by law.

Apart from cases of flagrant offence, an arrest may be carried out only pursuant to the well-founded order of the judge, which must be notified at the arrest or at the latest within twenty-four hours. Any detention must be preceded by an examination.

### Article 20
No penalty may be introduced or applied except by law.

Criminal law must ensure respect for individual personality and dignity. No one may be subjected to cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment.

Death penalty is applicable only to crimes against peace, humanity, or of war. The Death Penalty is abolished for other crimes.

Criminal law cannot have any retroactive effect.

### Article 21
The domicile is inviolable. No entry and search in the domicile can take place except in cases and in the manner prescribed by law.

### Article 22
Every individual has the right for respect of private and family life and confidentiality of correspondence.

### Article 23
1. Freedom of religion and of public worship, and freedom to express one’s opinions in all matters, is guaranteed, subject to the right to prosecute any offences committed in the exercise of the said freedoms.

2. No one may be compelled to participate in the rites or ceremonies of any religion or to observe its days of rest.

### Article 24
Property is inviolable. No one may be deprived of property except for public benefit as established by law, and upon a fair, settled and paid compensation in the circumstances and manner specified by law.

### Article 25
Freedom of work is guaranteed. Its practice is determined by law.

Priority is granted to Monegasques for the obtainment of public and private positions in the circumstances prescribed by law or international conventions.

### Article 26
Vekllei nationals are entitled to the assistance of the State in the event of destitution, unemployment, sickness, handicap, old age and maternity in the circumstances and manner laid down by law.

### Article 27
Vekllei nationals are entitled to free primary and secondary education.

### Article 28
Every person may defend the rights and interests of his/her occupation and function through a trade-union action.

The right to strike is recognised, subject to regulation of law.

### Article 29
Vekllei nationals have the right to assemble peacefully and without arms in accordance with the laws that may regulate the exercise of this right without subjecting it to prior authorisation. This freedom does not extend to open-air meetings, which remain subject to police laws.

### Article 30
Freedom of association is guaranteed, subject to regulation of law.

### Article 31
Anyone may address petitions to the public authorities.

### Article 32
Foreigners enjoy all public and private rights in the Principality that are not formally reserved to nationals.

## PUBLIC DOMAIN, PUBLIC FINANCE
### Article 33
Public domain is unalienable and imprescriptible.

A public domain property may be closed down or change purpose only if pronounced by law. Law may allocate decommissioned property to the State or Commune's public domain, as the case may be.

Public domain’s consistency and regime are determined by law.

### Article 34
The Crown’s property is submitted to The Sovereignty's exercise.

They are unalienable and imprescriptible.

Its consistency and regime are determined by the House Laws at the Sovereign Family.

### Article 35
Real estate property and rights pertinent to private State held property are transferable only in accordance with the law.

The law gives authorisation to sell a part of the business capital of which at least fifty per cent is held by the State, thereby transferring the majority of this capital to one or more physical person or private law legal persons.

### Article 36
All vacant and ownerless property belongs to the Sovereign and Nature in treaty with the State. In demonstrating claims of ownership the state may petition Sovereign property for use.

### Article 37
The national budget comprises all public revenue and public expenditure of the Commonwealth and its Constituents.

### Article 38
The national budget expresses the Commonwealth’s economic and financial policy.

### Article 39
Budget is subject to a budget bill. It is voted and promulgated in the form of a law.

### Article 40
The Sovereign Household’s expenses and those of the Prince Palace are determined by budget law and withdrawn in priority from the budget’s general public revenue.

### Article 41
The revenue surplus over expenditure, established after budget implementation and year end closing of accounts, is credited to a constitutional reserve fund. The excess of expenditure over revenue provides cover withdrawing from the same account, after enactment of the relevant law.

### Article 42
Control of financial management is ensured by a Higher Audit Commission.

## THE GOVERNMENT
### Article 43
Government is exercised, under the gracious authority of the Prince, by a Minister of State, assisted by a Government Council.

### Article 44
The Minister of State represents the Prince. He oversees the executive services. He has the police force at his command. He chairs the Government Council with a casting vote.

### Article 45
Sovereign ordinances are debated in the Government Council. They are presented to the Prince with the Minister of State's signature; they mention the relevant proceedings. They are signed by the Prince; the Prince's signature makes them enforceable.

### Article 46
Sovereign Ordinances, which are excluded from debate in the Government Council and presentation to the Minister of State, pertain to:

The House Laws of the Sovereign Family and these of its members
The affairs of the Direction of the Judicial Department

The appointment of members of the Sovereign Household, the diplomatic and consular corps, the Minister of State, the Government Councillors and assimilated civil servants, the magistrates in the judiciary

The issue of exequatur to consuls

The dissolution of the National Council

The granting of honour titles

### Article 47
Ministerial decrees are debated during the Government Council and signed by the Minister of State; they mention the relevant proceedings. They are notified to the Prince within twenty-four hours after signature and become enforceable only in the absence of the Princes formal opposition within ten days after the Minister of State’s notification.

However, the Prince may let the Minister of State know He does not intend on exercising His right of opposition for some decrees or types of decrees. These are thereby enforceable as soon as they are signed by the Minister of State.

### Article 48
Unless law provides otherwise, distribution of subject matters between sovereign ordinances and ministerial decrees is determined by sovereign ordinance.

### Article 49
Government Councils proceedings are subject to minutes put on record in a special register and signed, after the vote, by the present members.

The minutes mention each members vote. Within five days after the meeting, they are notified to the Prince who can lodge an opposition under the conditions provided by the above ### Articleicle 47.

### Article 50
The Minister of State and Government Councillors are accountable to the Prince for the Principality’s administration.

### Article 51
Civil servants’ obligations, rights and fundamental guarantees, as well as their civil liability and criminal responsibility are laid down by law.

CHAPTER VI. THE STATE COUNCIL
### Article 52
The State Council is in charge of advising on draft legislation and ordinances, which the Prince submitted for their perusal.

It can also be consulted on any other draft instrument.

Its organisation and operations are prescribed by sovereign ordinance.

## THE NATIONAL COUNCIL
### Article 53
The National Council comprises twenty-four members, elected for five years by direct universal suffrage and by the list system under the conditions prescribed by law.

In accordance with the conditions determined by law, electors are Monegasque citizens of either gender, at least eighteen years old, with the exception of those deprived of the right to vote for any of the causes set forth by law.

### Article 54
All Monegasque electors of either gender, aged at least twenty-five, who have held the Monegasque nationality for at least five years, and who are not deprived of the right to stand for election for any of the causes set forth by law, are eligible.

Law determines which offices are incompatible with the National Councillor’s mandate.

### Article 55
Courts of justice are entrusted with the control of the elections’ legitimacy, under the conditions prescribed by law.

### Article 56
The National Council’s members are not liable to any civil or criminal responsibility on the grounds of opinion or votes they express during the exercise of their mandates.

Without the National Council’s authorisation, they may neither be prosecuted nor arrested during a session due to a criminal or police infringement, save in the case of flagrant offence.

### Article 57
The newly elected National Council meets on the eleventh day after elections in order to elect its board. The oldest National Council to chairs this session.

Without prejudice to [Article 74], the prior National Council’s powers expire on the day of the new National Council’s meeting.

### Article 58
The National Council meets ipso jure in two annual ordinary sessions.

The first session opens on the first working day of April.

The second session opens on the first working day of October.

Each session may not last longer than three months. The session’s closure is declared by the President.

### Article 59
The National Council meets in extraordinary session, convened either by the Prince or on the request of at least two thirds of the members, by the President.

### Article 60
The National Council's board comprises a president and a vice-president, who are elected each year by the assembly from among its members.

A mayor’s office is incompatible with that of the National Council's President and vice-president.

### Article 61
Without prejudice to the provisions of the Constitution and if need be the law, the organisation and operations of the National Council are determined by the rule of procedure which the National Council issued.

Before being enforced these rules of procedure must be submitted to the Supreme Court, which decides on its compliance with the Constitution and if need be, with law.

### Article 62
The national Council sets its agenda. It is notified to the Minister of State at least three days beforehand. On the request of the Government, at least one of the two sessions must be devoted to debating the bills introduced by the Prince.

However the agenda of extraordinary sessions convened by the Prince is set in the convocation.

### Article 63
The National Council’s meetings are public.

However the National Council may decide with a majority of two thirds of the attending members, to sit in private session.

The minutes of the public meetings are published in “Le Journal de Monaco”.

### Article 64
The Prince communicates with the National Council through messages read by the Minister of State.

### Article 65
The Minister of State and Government Councillors have reserved entrances and seats at the National Council’s meetings.

They must have the floor when they request so.

### Article 66
The instigation of law implies the agreement of wills of both the Prince and the National Council.

The Prince alone may initiate law.

Deliberating and voting on bills are the National Council's responsibility.

It falls to the Prince to sanction laws, which confers them a binding power through promulgation.

### Article 67
The Prince signs bills. These bills are introduced to Him via the Government Council and with the Minister of State's signature. After the Prince’s endorsement, the Minister of State introduces them to the National Council.

The National Council can formulate bill proposals. Within a period of six months st### Articleing from the date the Minister of State received the draft legislation, he notifies the following to the National Council:

Either his decision to turn the proposal into a bill, amended as the case may be, which shall follow the procedure provided for in paragraph 1. In this case, the bill is introduced within a period of one year st### Articleing from the expiration of the six months period mentioned above
Or his decision to interrupt the legislative procedure. This decision is explained with a declaration placed on the agenda of an ordinary session public meeting anticipated within the period. This declaration can be followed by a debate
After expiration of the six months period mentioned above, if the Government has not notified the outcome intended for this bill proposal, the latter according to the procedure prescribed for in paragraph 1. becomes ipso jure a bill.

The same procedure is applicable if the Government did not introduce the bill within the one year period provided for in paragraph 2 a).

The National Council has the right of amendment. As such, it can propose inclusions, substitutions or withdrawals in the bill. Amendments alone that have a direct link with the bill provisions relevant to the bill are admitted. The vote takes place on the amended bill, as the case may be unless the Government withdraws the bill before the final vote.

However, the provisions of the precedent paragraph are not applicable for ratification bills or budget bills.

At the beginning of each ordinary session, in public meeting, the National Council announces the update of all bills introduced by the Government whenever they were introduced.

### Article 68
The Prince issues, when necessary, ordinances to ensure the enforcement of laws and the implementation of international treaties or conventions.

### Article 69
Laws and sovereign ordinances are enforceable against third p### Articleies only from the day after their publication in the "Journal of Monaco”.

### Article 70
The National Council votes on the budget.

No direct or indirect taxation may be introduced but through a law.

Any treaty or international agreement entailing such taxation may only be ratified by a law.

### Article 71
Budget bills are introduced to the National Council before September 30th.

Budget bills are voted upon during the National Council October session.

### Article 72
Budget is voted upon chapter by chapter. Transfers from one chapter to another are forbidden unless authorised by law.

The Budget comprises among others, within expenditure items, sums made available to the Communal Council for the budgetary year to come, as provided for in ### Articleicle 87.

### Article 73
In case the appropriation of funds requested by the Government as provided for in ### Articleicle 71 has not taken place before December 31st, funds relevant to services voted upon may be opened by sovereign ordinance with the National Council’s agreement.

The same prevails for income and expenses resulting from international treaties.

### Article 74
The Prince may, after having taken the advice of the Crown Council pronounce the dissolution of the National Council. If this occurs, new elections take place within a period of three months.

## THE CROWN COUNCIL
### Article 75
The Crown Council consists of seven members of Monegasque nationality, appointed by the Prince for a period of three years.

The President and three other members are directly appointed by the Prince.

Three members are appointed at the suggestion of the National Council, chosen from outside its members.

The offices of Minister of State and Government Councillor are incompatible with those of President or member of the Crown Council.

### Article 76
The Crown Council meets at least twice a year further to the Prince's summons. In addition, the Prince may call a meeting anytime He deems it necessary, either on his own initiative or further to the suggestion of the Crown Council's President.

### Article 77
The Crown Council may be consulted by the Prince on issues regarding the States higher interests. It may offer suggestions to the Prince.

It must be consulted on the following subjects: international treaties, dissolution of the National Council requests or naturalisation and restoration of the Monegasque nationality, pardons and amnesties.

## THE COMMUNE
### Article 78
The territory of the Principality forms a single commune.

### Article 79
The Commune is administered by a municipality composed of the mayor and deputies designated by the Communal Council from amongst its members.

In accordance with the conditions determined by law, elections are Monegasque citizens of either gender, at least eighteen years of age, with the exception of those deprived of the right to vote for any of the causes set forth by law.

All Monegasque electors of either gender, at least twenty-one years of age, who have held the Monegasque nationality for at least five years and who are not deprived of the right to stand for election for any of the causes set forth by law are eligible.

### Article 80
The Communal Council is composed of 15 members elected for a term of four years by universal direct suffrage by the list system.

There is no incompatibility between the Communal Councillor's mandate and that of National Councillor.

### Article 81
The Communal Council meets every three months in ordinary session. Each Session may not last longer than fifteen days.

### Article 82
Extraordinary sessions may be held, on the request or with the authorisation of the Minister of State, for specific purposes.

### Article 83
The Communal Council may be dissolved by a well-founded ministerial decree after the State Council’s opinion is sought.

### Article 84
In case of dissolution or resignation of all the members of the Communal Council, a special delegation is appointed by ministerial decree to carry out its duties until a new Council is elected. This election shall take place within three months.

### Article 85
The Communal Council is chaired by the mayor or, in his/her absence, by the deputy or the councillor who replaces him/her; following the order of the ch### Article.

### Article 86
The Communal Council debates in public meeting on the Commune’s affairs. Its proceedings are enforceable fifteen days after notification to the Minister of State, unless a well-founded opposition under the form of a ministerial decree is initiated.

### Article 87
The communal budget is supplied with revenue produced from communal property the communes ordinary resources and appropriations prescribed by the initial budget law of the year.

## THE JUSTICE
### Article 88
Judicial power vests in the Prince, who, by the present Constitution, delegates its full exercise to the courts and tribunals.

Tribunals render justice in the name of the Prince.

The independence of judges is guaranteed.

The organisation, jurisdiction and operations of the tribunals, as well as judges’ status, are laid down by law.

### Article 89
Supreme Court is composed of five full members and two substitute members.

The Supreme Courts members are appointed by the Prince, as follows:

One full member and one substitute member are introduced by the National Council from outside its members
One full member and one substitute member are introduced by the State Council from outside its members

One full member is introduced by the Crown Council from outside its members

One full member is introduced by the Court of Appeal from outside its members

One full member is introduced by the Civil Court of First Instance from outside its members.

These introductions are done by each of the bodies here above mentioned at the rate of two per seat.

If the Prince does not agree with these introductions, He is free to require new ones.

The President of the Supreme Court is appointed by the Prince.

### Article 90
In constitutional matters, the Supreme Court rules in sovereign fashion over:
Compliance of the National Councils rules of procedure with constitutional and, if need be, legislative provisions under the conditions prescribed by ### Articleicle 61
Appeals on petitions for annulment, petitions to review validity and actions for damages arising from violations of these rights and freedoms prescribed in chapter III of the Constitution, and which are not referred to in subsection B of the present ### Articleicle
In administrative matters, the Supreme Court rules in sovereign fashion over:
Proceedings for annulment of ultra vires decisions taken by various administrative authorities or Sovereign Ordinances to enforce laws, and the award of related damages
Appeals by way of quashing decisions of last resort taken by administrative jurisdictions
Appeals for interpretation and petitions to review the validity of decisions of various administrative authorities or Sovereign Ordinances to enforce laws
The Supreme Court rules over conflicts of jurisdiction.
### Article 91
The Supreme Court deliberates either in plenary session composed of five members or in administrative section composed of three members.

It sits and deliberates in plenary session:

In constitutional matters
As judge of conflicts of jurisdiction
In administrative matters on references ordered by the President of the Supreme Court or decided by the administrative section
It sits and deliberates in administrative section in all other cases.

### Article 92
A sovereign order regulates the organisation and operations of the Supreme Court, especially relevant to the required qualifications of its members, incompatibilities regarding them as well as their status, the turnover of the administrative section’s members, the procedure to follow before the Court, effects of petitions and awards, procedure and effects of conflicts of jurisdiction, as well as necessary transitional measures.

## THE REVISION OF THE CONSTITUTION
### Article 93
The Constitution may not be suspended.

### Article 94
Any revision, in full or in part, requires a referendum of Constituents, and the agreement of the Commonwealth Council.

### Article 95
In case of initiative on the part of the Commonwealth Council, proceedings maybe taken only by a two thirds majority vote of the normal number of members elected at the assembIy.

CHAPTER XII. FINAL PROVISIONS
### Article 96
Prior constitutional provisions are repealed.

The present Constitution immediately enters into force.

The renewal of the National Council and Communal Council shall take place within three months.

### Article 97
Laws and regulations currently into force remain applicable to the extent that they are not incompatible with the present Constitution. If need be, they must be amended in order to comply, as soon as possible, with the latter.
-->
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Veletian, or Commonwealth Script, is a simplified form of Oslolan written language.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Corsosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/corsosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/corsosva/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Corsosva (a portmanteau of corsivis sovis, lit. &ldquo;compulsory service&rdquo;) is the period of civic conscription that applies to all Vekllei citizens. It requires four years of service, served between the ages of 18-32. Although administered by the Department of Compulsory Service of the Ministry of Defence, most citizens perform civilian or industrial work during Corsosva, and only a minority enter the armed forces as conscripts.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Corsosva</strong> (a portmanteau of <em>corsivis sovis</em>, lit. &ldquo;<em>compulsory service</em>&rdquo;) is the period of civic conscription that applies to all Vekllei citizens. It requires four years of service, served between the ages of 18-32. Although administered by the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/defence/#department-of-compulsory-service">Department of Compulsory Service</a> of the <a href="/cosmokos/">Ministry of Defence</a>, most citizens perform civilian or industrial work during Corsosva, and only a minority enter the armed forces as conscripts.</p>
<p>Individuals entering Corsosva elect their preferences for service, which are then weighted based on experience and ability. The most common forms of Corsosva are in construction, education and healthcare.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Documents</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/documents/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/documents/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[⚠️ This list is evolving, and will be expanded in future. The Vekllei Document System is an internal circular provided by the Government of Vekllei to direct policy. They do not represent policy in depth &ndash; rather, documents are issued discretely to relevant ministries and outline the direction or spirit of policy. Historically, they announce major events and actions. Documents 📄Document No. 1: Communiqué on the Establishment of the 4th Commonwealth 📄Document No.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><span class="smallicon" style="font-size: 14px;">⚠️</span> This list is evolving, and will be expanded in future.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>The Vekllei Document System</strong> is an internal circular provided by the Government of Vekllei to direct policy. They do not represent policy in depth &ndash; rather, documents are issued discretely to relevant ministries and outline the direction or spirit of policy. Historically, they announce major events and actions.</div>
</blockquote>

<details open>
  <summary>Documents</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li><a href="/files/documents/1.pdf"><span class="navicon">📄</span>Document No. 1</a>: Communiqué on the Establishment of the 4th Commonwealth</li>
<li><a href="/files/documents/7.pdf"><span class="navicon">📄</span>Document No. 7</a>: Communiqué on the Establishment of Government Schools</li>
<li><a href="/files/documents/9.pdf"><span class="navicon">📄</span>Document No. 9</a>: Communiqué on the Establishment of the VKIM</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Education</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/education/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/education/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei society. Education emerged as a foundational right for Vekllei people in the constitution of the 4th Commonwealth, in the spirit of postwar democratisation and the rising of all people. Education in Vekllei is a good example of the &lsquo;system working backwards,&rsquo; the popular phrase to describe the Floral Period moving in two different directions at once. Is it modern, supplied and robust in the Western tradition &ndash; children wear uniforms, are divided into school years and learning is arranged and taught in subjects.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/vekllei/">Vekllei</a> society.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Education</strong> emerged as a foundational right for Vekllei people in the constitution of the 4th Commonwealth, in the spirit of postwar democratisation and the rising of all people.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Education in Vekllei is a good example of the &lsquo;system working backwards,&rsquo; the popular phrase to describe the Floral Period moving in two different directions at once. Is it modern, supplied and robust in the Western tradition &ndash; children wear uniforms, are divided into school years and learning is arranged and taught in subjects. Other aspects of the Vekllei curriculum, like its provisions for extracurricular activities and social clubs, are novel by comparison.</p>
<p>There is something quite interesting going on in Vekllei education that is not immediately apparent at its surface. First, compulsory schooling runs between 3-5 days a week, depending on student commitments to elective and extracurricular activities. Government schools do not employ standardised testing, and rely on subject-specific means of assessment including reviews, presentations and portfolios. The <a href="#curriculum">Vekllei Curriculum</a> emphasises practicable and technical skills that blur the lines between school, community and home.</p>
<p>Education in Vekllei is considered a foundation of Vekllei democracy, and in the spirit of the Floral Period it is free, abundant and compulsory.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Education is a founding aspect of the 4th Commonwealth and is to be reaffirmed constantly and faithfully by all Parliaments and public servants, and to this end is to be provided for as a highest priority of the new Parliament.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&ndash; <a href="/documents/">Document No. 7</a></p>
<h2 id="structure">
  Structure
  <a class="anchor" href="#structure">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Download <span class="smallicon">📄</span> <a href="/files/documents/7.pdf">Document No. 7.pdf</a></div>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="administration-and-funding">
  Administration and Funding
  <a class="anchor" href="#administration-and-funding">#</a>
</h3>
<p>All forms of education in Vekllei are free, including for international students at a tertiary level. The system is funded by the <a href="/solcom/">Commonwealth Education Secretariat (SOLCOM)</a>, which also administers the school curriculum and some schools directly.</p>
<h3 id="schools">
  Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#schools">#</a>
</h3>
<p>There are several different types of school in Vekllei, but all are government-funded and adhere to the compulsory curriculum outlined by the Education Secretary. The <a href="#uniform">Vekllei Education Uniform</a> is compulsory for all students, including at independent schools.</p>
<h4 id="state-schools">
  State Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#state-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>State schools (also Central Schools) are administered and funded directly by the Education Secretariat, and are common in cities and in Commonwealth member-states. They are traditionally larger and better equipped, and usually provide for both primary and secondary schooling. Some state schools are also district colleges, meaning they serve students from <a href="#preparatory-school">Prep</a> to Year 12 or 13.</p>
<h4 id="community-schools">
  Community Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#community-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Community schools are usually administered by a borough or <a href="/municipalities/">municipality</a>, and are usually smaller than state schools. Although some community schools may combine primary and secondary schooling (called district schools), most serve only primary education. Community schools may also refer to village schools, or community-run schools in the local Vekllei tradition.</p>
<h4 id="studio--technical-schools">
  Studio &amp; Technical Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#studio--technical-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Studio and technical schools typically refer to secondary schools that specialise in arts or vocational curriculums, as a means to fast-track gifted learning. These schools may offer boarding, as only a few studio and technical schools exist across the Commonwealth and smaller member-states may send their students overseas to study there.</p>
<h4 id="faith-schools">
  Faith Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#faith-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Faith schools in Vekllei are affiliated with an approved religious organisation. The curriculum of faith schools have a religious character, usually Jewish or Roman Catholic. Faith schools are still required to adhere to the <a href="#curriculum">Commonwealth curriculum</a> as a minimum education standard. Faith Schools are also an exception to the universal coeducational system of the Commonwealth, since two schools in Oslola and one in the Kalina Isles are single-sex boarding schools.</p>
<h4 id="boarding-schools">
  Boarding Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#boarding-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Vekllei offers a handful of boarding schools, which are usually specialised institutions that may operate as orphanages or for international students. Some Vekllei boarding schools include aspects of democratic education.</p>
<h2 id="education">
  Education
  <a class="anchor" href="#education">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/commerce/">Ministry of Commerce</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Vekllei people are enrolled in 9 years of compulsory education, provided by the <a href="/solsec/">Commonwealth Education Secretariat</a> (SOLSEC). In addition, 3 years of pre-school and 3 years of senior secondary schooling are offered but not compulsory. All schools in Vekllei are funded by the state, which include community schools, state schools, studio schools, technical schools, faith schools and state boarding schools.</p>
<p>Compared to modern schooling overseas, Vekllei education places significant value on well-roundedness and practicable household and technical skills. Subject-based streams for specialised learning are common, but the basic compulsory Vekllei curriculum emphasises non-academic subjects and structures pre-tertiary subjects as electives.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/mist.jpg" alt="Image of Tzipora standing in front of school building"  title="Misty morning in front of the [Moshel St School](/moshel/) | *[Heavy Mist](/stories/mist/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Misty morning in front of the <a href="/moshel/">Moshel St School</a> | <em><a href="/stories/mist/">Heavy Mist</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Vekllei has a strong tradition of school clubs and social organisations, and these are considered essential aspects of Vekllei education. Clubs and associations are usually organised by student leadership, and offer opportunities in industry and tertiary study.</p>
<p>Compulsory and tertiary education is free for all Vekllei people, permanent residents and foreign workers. Homeschooling is illegal except by those holding a teaching certificate, and is supervised by a local school which issues the child&rsquo;s diploma. In this context, homeschooling is almost nonexistent in the Commonwealth. About 15% of the Commonwealth Budget is allocated towards education.</p>
<h3 id="compulsory-education">
  Compulsory Education
  <a class="anchor" href="#compulsory-education">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei offers preschooling from ages 3 onwards. Garden School, or kindergarten, is for 3 &amp; 4 year-olds in Vekllei, and assists with the transition from home to school, followed by preparatory school, or &lsquo;prep&rsquo;, which is the first year of compulsory primary education.</p>
<p>Vekllei primary education consists of 7 years, starting with <a href="#preparatory-school">Prep</a> at ages 5-6 and concluding with Year 6 at age 12. Secondary education lasts from years 7-12, and study until year 10 is compulsory.</p>
<p>The final year of school in Vekllei usually includes a class trip overseas, traditionally to Europe or Asia, to celebrate graduation.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Vekllei Compulsory Schooling</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>Preschool
<ul>
<li>Nursery School</li>
<li>Garden School</li>
<li>Preparatory School</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary School (Years 1-6)</li>
<li>Secondary School (Years 7-10)</li>
<li>College (Years 11-12)</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<h3 id="tertiary-education">
  Tertiary Education
  <a class="anchor" href="#tertiary-education">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Commonwealth invests heavily in tertiary education as both a social good and a product marketable overseas. Vekllei universities rank highly abroad, and education as a service is a major export of Vekllei, and contributes to Vekllei&rsquo;s reputation as an international capital of finance and skilled labour.</p>
<p>Universities in Vekllei offer places to students who have completed their Education Award and satisfy the prerequisites for their subject. These requirements differ between subjects, and usually include an interview with the admissions board.</p>
<p>In order to study abroad, Vekllei students must be sponsored by a foreigner, receive a partial scholarship from an overseas university, or receive funding from their tertiary place of study. About one in four Vekllei students study overseas for some period of time.</p>
<h4 id="university">
  University
  <a class="anchor" href="#university">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Vekllei International University offers</p>
<h4 id="vocational-schools">
  Vocational Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#vocational-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<h2 id="curriculum">
  Curriculum
  <a class="anchor" href="#curriculum">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The Commonwealth Curriculum is the common programme of study in all Commonwealth schools, and determines standards of study across all education institutions.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Commonwealth International Curriculum</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>Arts</li>
<li>Vekllei Languages</li>
<li>Foreign Languages</li>
<li>Health and Physical Education</li>
<li>Civic Sciences and Stewardship</li>
<li>Economics and Business</li>
<li>World Study</li>
<li>Political Sciences and History</li>
<li>Mathematics</li>
<li>Material Sciences and Electronics</li>
<li>Work Studies</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<h2 id="uniform">
  Uniform
  <a class="anchor" href="#uniform">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/uniforms/">Uniforms in Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/generation.jpg" alt="Illustration of different ways of wearing the same school uniform"  title="Examples of Vekllei school uniform and its functional diversity | [*A New Generation*](/stories/new-generation/)" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Examples of Vekllei school uniform and its functional diversity | <a href="/stories/new-generation/"><em>A New Generation</em></a></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>All schools in Vekllei share the Education Uniform, made compulsory by the <a href="/solsec/">Education Secretariat</a>. The Vekllei uniform is simple and purchased independently, usually from department stores. The only badged items are the tie and jewellery/pins. It is worn across all ages of schooling, including tertiary education and university, and by some teachers as well.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th><strong>Boys</strong></th>
<th><strong>Girls</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Top</td>
<td><ul> <li>White collared shirt, tucked shirttails</li> <li>Black school tie</li> <li>Navy cape or mackintosh raincoat</li> <li>Navy jumper or sweater</li> <li>Navy blazer or sports jacket</li> </ul></td>
<td><ul> <li>White blouse, tucked shirttails</li> <li>Black or red school tie or floral piece</li> <li>Navy cape, pettycape or mackintosh raincoat</li> <li>Navy jumper or sweater</li> <li>Navy pinafore or gymslip</li> </ul></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bottom</td>
<td><ul> <li>Navy trousers or shorts</li> <li>Dark or brown belt</li> </ul></td>
<td><ul> <li>Navy skirt or trousers</li> <li>White traditional trousers</li> <li>Dark or brown belt</li> </ul></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Shoes</td>
<td><ul> <li>Dark or brown leather shoes</li> <li>Dark socks</li> </ul></td>
<td><ul> <li>Dark or brown leather shoes</li> <li>white socks</li> </ul></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The colours of uniforms may vary in constituent member-states of the Commonwealth &ndash; for example, the Kalina Isles use dark green in place of navy. Nonetheless, the Education Uniform standards are set at the Commonwealth level and are generally adopted in whole.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/kalinauniform.jpg" alt="Illustration Caribbean youths wearing school uniform"  title="Examples of Caribbean Commonwealth school uniform featuring local dress. | [*Caribbean Uniforms*](/stories/caribbean-uniform/)" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Examples of Caribbean Commonwealth school uniform featuring local dress. | <a href="/stories/caribbean-uniform/"><em>Caribbean Uniforms</em></a></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Although the items are not issued by individual schools, they are provided by the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/education/#all-commonwealth-school-directorate">ACC</a> on request and as such constitute a uniform rather than a dress code. The uniform system was designed in 2015 by French migrant Charles-Édouard Laurent to be accessible and comfortable, and so that individual items could continue to be worn after schooling concluded. It is iconic overseas and well-regarded by most Vekllei students.</p>
<p>Many schools make use of felt armbands to distinguish students or to signal membership in clubs or student councils. These are traditionally red, but may also be green or blue depending on their use.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Espionage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/espionage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/espionage/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei. Espionage is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/intro/#what-is-vekllei">Vekllei</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Espionage</strong> is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers. Unsentimental, unideological and unflinching, espionage in Vekllei is conducted constantly and vigorously with the blessing &ndash; or at least willing blindness &ndash; of the state.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Espionage in Vekllei is considered the &lsquo;first thorn&rsquo; of &lsquo;assertive defence&rsquo; practiced by the 4th Commonwealth. It is maintained offensively, as operations, and defensively as counterintelligence. The means by which it does are a source of endless contention in Commonwealth parliaments, the Vekllei public and foreign governments,<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> but since independence in 2015 espionage has been conducted much the same &ndash; and so can be assumed to be achieving strategic goals.</p>
<p>Overseas strategic and industrial espionage primarily falls under the control of the Commonwealth National Intelligence Directorate, usually called Noshem, which maintains several subordinate bureaus organised regionally.</p>
<p>Current intelligence doctrine values &lsquo;signal operations&rsquo; &ndash; visible strategic actions that &lsquo;signal&rsquo; messages to public enemies of the Commonwealth state, and maintaining plausible deniability. The line between civilian and military intelligence operations is not always clear, and Noshem is implicated in assassinations and executions of state enemies overseas. The Vekllei intelligence community is known to recruit ideological and nationalist sympathisers to perform actions on behalf of the state, and to this end has among the largest networks of informants of any espionage ring in the world.</p>
<h2 id="operations">
  Operations
  <a class="anchor" href="#operations">#</a>
</h2>
<h3 id="noshem">
  Noshem
  <a class="anchor" href="#noshem">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <span class="smallicon">🏹</span> <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#national-intelligence-directorate">Noshem</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Noshem,<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> the traditional name for the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#national-intelligence-directorate">National Intelligence Directorate</a> is the secret service of the Commonwealth and is responsible for most of its overseas espionage. It has a legendary reputation for the size and quality of its informants network, and is highly feared because of its history of ruthlessness, including extrajudicial assassinations and executions. Plausible deniability makes it difficult to tell how much of its work is sanctioned by parliaments or acted out by individual Vekllei people, and the organisation generates considerable controversy. Noshem has had several publicised tactical successes as well as failures, and is considered a critical aspect of Commonwealth security as a &lsquo;jewelled sabre&rsquo; of the non-aligned movement.</p>
<p>Noshem operates 40 outlines across 6 bureaus, which are organised regionally and contain semiautonomous command and logistics elements.</p>
<h3 id="security-directorates">
  Security Directorates
  <a class="anchor" href="#security-directorates">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Cosevac (POSEC) and Vosevisi (SESEC) are the Security Directorates of the Public and State respectively. Vosevisi processes some Noshem material, and its subordinate <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#state-secrets-office">State Secrets Office</a> is also responsible for maintaining security controls and classifications. Although they collect intelligence internally, most espionage is conducted overseas by <a href="#noshem">Noshem</a>.</p>
<h3 id="adsem">
  Adsem
  <a class="anchor" href="#adsem">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Adsem is the military intelligence department of the Vekllei Armed Forces. It co-ordinates with the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/">Interior Parliament</a> via the Ministry of Defence&rsquo;s <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/defence/#intelligence-liaison-office">Intelligence Liasion Office</a>, and is concerned primarily with counterintelligence operations and strategic information relevant to war. Like the Security Directorates, most of Adsem&rsquo;s espionage is conducted by Noshem. In turn, Adsem supplies much of Noshem&rsquo;s matériel, and many of its elite intelligence units are recruited from military commando and special forces sections. Adsem may also assist in the logistics of Noshem espionage operations.</p>
<h3 id="recruitment">
  Recruitment
  <a class="anchor" href="#recruitment">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei human intelligence is generally considered superior to that of the CIA, and may even be comparable to the KGB in scope and quality. Human intelligence is the basis of contemporary Vekllei intelligence-gathering, and the intelligence state gathers and processes massive amounts of information on foreign nationals, companies, and governments. It relies on enormous, concentric rings of highly motivated unpaid sympathisers that help Noshem in passing messages, inserting agents and obscuring information.</p>
<p>There are several classes of sympathiser &ndash; some are ideologically motivated in the anarchist or pan-Atlanticist tradition, factions which the Vekllei government is willing to recognise or indulge publicly to stir positive and negative press and distinguish itself from the cold war dichotomy. Others are nationalists who help out of a sense of devotion to Vekllei, since several million Vekllei people fled after the Atomic War. Although many returned in the years after independence, there remains a large Vekllei diaspora throughout the world and especially in the United States and Western Europe, and many members continue to hold a sense of duty towards the country.</p>
<p>This network of sympathisers is aided by Vekllei&rsquo;s postwar internationalism and multiracialism, emphasising political and geographic traits that appeal to young, educated people. Where duty fails, cash often suffices, and tremendous amounts of state funds are siphoned discretely from other Ministerial budgets to fund a network of paid informants. The total number of informants is impossible to know, but is estimated to number tens of thousands across the U.S., U.K., France, Russia, Yugoslavia, China and South-East Asia.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>This controversy has prompted several commissions and parliamentary inquests by the Vekllei Comptroller, and continues to generate debate in Vekllei society. It is also a popular subject of conspiracy theorising.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Noshem is the name of the spirit-god of secrets in Vekllei mythology.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Federalisation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/federalisation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/federalisation/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Federalisation is the term for the process of integrating of a new country into the Vekllei Commonwealth. It is a shorthand for all aspects of integration, including the construction of new buildings, ratification of new laws and accession to the Vekllei Constitution and the restructuring of the government. It concludes with the establishment of a commons and the abolishment of common money through a process of hyperinflation.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Federalisation</strong> is the term for the process of integrating of a new country into the <a href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei Commonwealth</a>. It is a shorthand for all aspects of integration, including the construction of new buildings, ratification of new laws and accession to the Vekllei Constitution and the restructuring of the government. It concludes with the establishment of a commons and the abolishment of common money through a process of hyperinflation.</p>
<p>After the challenging federalisation of the Azores in the early 2020s, changes were made to the process to extend its length and reduce its immediate scope.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Finance</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/finance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/finance/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about Vekllei Even if they do not use money, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests. Overview # The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &ldquo;functionally moneyless,&rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Even if they do not use money</strong>, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &ldquo;functionally moneyless,&rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex. While the average Vekllei person is insulated from money and money-management, their Commonwealth is a major entrepôt<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> and has a reputation as an &ldquo;Atlantic Middleman.&rdquo; Vekllei&rsquo;s facilitation of frictionless free trade, large foreign-exchange reserves and received foreign direct investments have resulted in decades of consistent economic growth, and has cemented its reputation as a financial hub between Europe and the Americas.</p>
<p>Vekllei&rsquo;s history as a trade hub contributes significantly to its perceived neutrality and its reputation as a meeting place for politics and business, and regularly hosts diplomatic missions as a neutral site. It maintains its moneyless primary economy by effectively isolating its primary (<a href="#domestic-markets">domestic</a>) and secondary (<a href="#international-markets">international</a>) markets, which are the reason for its <a href="#currency">twin currencies</a> and its unusual hybrid market system. Because the Vekllei state manages all money as a function of its moneylessness, the international market and foreign trade is strongly characterised by dirigism and fundamentally beholden to the economic management of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>, which acts as both a financial regulator and investment bank.</p>
<h2 id="markets">
  Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#markets">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></div>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="domestic-markets">
  Domestic Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#domestic-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Vekllei Domestic Market is the turn-of-phrase for the unmoneyed Vekllei economy, including almost all private and public businesses and the majority of trade conducted by ordinary Vekllei people. It is the primary market of Vekllei. For most Vekllei people, the domestic market is the only one with which they will interact in their lives, except for the occasional holiday overseas. The Domestic Market includes all sectors of the Vekllei economy except state trade apparatuses like <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a>.</p>
<p>While the participatory nature of the Domestic Market affects its gross productivity, it is regarded as free, innovative and dynamic. It has a skilled workforce benefitted by a robust education system and a high quality of life. About 40% of Vekllei people were born overseas, and some 15% of the Vekllei workforce remain foreign workers. Foreign workers, unlike domestic ones, are remunerated unless residing under an immigration visa.</p>
<h3 id="industrial-markets">
  Industrial Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#industrial-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei Industrial Markets are distinguished by their ability to trade in both the moneyless <a href="#domestic-markets">Domestic Market</a> and the <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a>. There are two kinds of industrial firm in Vekllei:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Senrouive</strong>: private enterprises</li>
<li><strong>Venrouive</strong>: public enterprises with membership in an industrial <a href="/bureaus/">bureau</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Venrouive</em> (also known as public companies in Vekllei) are enterprises beholden to <a href="/bureaus/">industrial bureaus</a>, which are collections of companies with close relations and hold membership in a shared industrial council. Venrouive businesses are characterised by large-scale enterprises, some of which may be state-owned, that hold considerable power over a market. In some cases, a bureau may monopolise a market, as in the case of the Vekllei telecommunications industry.</p>
<p>Both senrouive and venrouive companies may participate in the international market, but only bureaus (and by extension, participating venrouive companies) may trade directly with overseas governments and enterprises.</p>
<h3 id="international-markets">
  International Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#international-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Download <span class="smallicon">📄</span> <a href="/files/documents/9.pdf">Document No. 9.pdf</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Vekllei International Market (VKIM) is an organisation that controls the capital, commodities and securities markets of Vekllei. VKIM is maintained by the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a> as a mechanism for foreign investors and merchants to interact with the isolated, unmoneyed Vekllei domestic market. The international market includes a commodities exchange, derivatives marketplace and other structured financial products that facilitate foreign activity in the Vekllei economy and raise foreign capital for the national liquid currency reserves. VKIM uses the Vekllei Composite Index as a measure of the Vekllei economy, which measures both commodity value and productivity.</p>
<p>The International Market is the means by which the capital account<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> of the Commonwealth Government implements its long-standing macroeconomic interest in foreign investment and soft power. The reinvestment of capital surplus in the <a href="#currency">Vekllei currencies</a> serves as a form of sterilisation and capital control, controlled directly by the central <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a>. Vekllei has the world&rsquo;s 2nd-largest foreign currency reserves.</p>
<h2 id="currency">
  Currency
  <a class="anchor" href="#currency">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2020-06-24-crown/">The Vekllei Crown</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Vekllei has two currencies that are more or less opposed in their use as money, known as the twin crowns system. The Vekllei Crown (❦VK) is a gold-backed, fixed-rate deflationary currency used primarily as a wealth reserve, and the Government Crown (✾AK) is a fiat, floating-exchange currency used for foreign investment and trade. This system preserves the isolation of the Vekllei primary economy, which is moneyless, while insulating state investments from shocks and from having to burn liquidity to maintain its exchange rate.</p>
<p>Together, the twin crowns allow for the Vekllei state to retain unprecedented control over its financial system while securing a mechanism for foreign investment and growth.</p>
<ul>
<li>The domestic market is autarkic and does not have free capital exchange, allowing it to maintain its fixed price and independent monetary policy</li>
<li>The international market is open and has free capital exchange, facilitated by ✾AK floating exchange price with policy independence maintained by capital controls from the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>For a variety of political and economic reasons, the Vekllei Commonwealth state aims to be self-sufficient. The twin crowns system provides a means to isolate its productive primary economy while also allowing foreign money controlled access to it. The unmoneyed primary economy remains a popular investment for its stability.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> As capital controls have broken down in the mid-2030s, Vekllei&rsquo;s current macroeconomic policy exists as a &ldquo;third way&rdquo; between closed autarky and recent trends towards an open economic international market.</p>
<h3 id="vekllei-crown-vk">
  Vekllei Crown (❦VK)
  <a class="anchor" href="#vekllei-crown-vk">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The <em>Vekllei Kroner</em> (lit. <em>Vekllei Crown</em>) is the primary and historic currency of Vekllei. It is minted by the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/mint/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Mint</a> as a souvenir in the tradition of Vekllei <em>medals</em>,<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> but is not otherwise used by Vekllei people as money or transacted in day-to-day life. It is primarily a deflationary currency store backed by gold, and to which each Vekllei citizen is entitled an equal share in emigration. It is not able to be used on the <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a> directly, but can be purchased as a <a href="#white-bonds">White Bond</a> as a speculative instrument. It is also used in some cases as a mechanism for trade with individuals abroad, mostly by smaller banks looking to broker purchases of goods or services unavailable in Vekllei.</p>
<h3 id="government-crown-ak">
  Government Crown (✾AK)
  <a class="anchor" href="#government-crown-ak">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The <em>Government/Commonwealth Kroner</em> (also the <em>Atlantic Kroner</em> or <em>Crown</em>) is a twin currency used primarily by the state to insure financial instruments like bonds as well as for converting and placing foreign investments and currency. The Government Crown operates on a floating exchange rate as a fiat currency tradeable in the <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a> and a means for overseas actions in the Vekllei economy.</p>
<p>The ✾AK is not minted as it does not resemble a conventional currency, and exists only in bonds, state certificates, and as a metric for some commodity money. It has a strong reputation as a hard currency because of the ✾AK&rsquo;s relative security and reliability, backed by powerful domestic institutions.</p>
<h2 id="banking">
  Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#banking">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The policy of bank consolidation under the British Occupation Government continued under the successive Floral Government, and banking was among the first industries in Vekllei to be completely socialised.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> All banks in Vekllei are run as state-owned enterprises, and subordinated to the &lsquo;<em>Old Lady</em>,&rsquo; the colloquial name for the central <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a>. &lsquo;Unbanking&rsquo; policy &ndash; the effective demonetisation of the Vekllei domestic markets &ndash; saw severe disruption to the Vekllei economy and led to a period of hyperinflation in the late 2010s.</p>
<p>Unlike in other countries, the socialisation of banking in Vekllei also saw the broad exclusion of retail investors and savings banking, effectively halting money exchange in the domestic market and institutionalising the Vekllei banking system. Today, most Vekllei banks are institutional and deal primarily with the secondary speculative markets like <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a>, or provide lending and contracts for new businesses in the <a href="#industrial-markets">industrial market</a>.</p>
<h3 id="bank-of-vekllei">
  Bank of Vekllei
  <a class="anchor" href="#bank-of-vekllei">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Bank of Vekllei (also <em>Labour Bank of Vekllei</em> and <em>Old Lady</em>) is Vekllei&rsquo;s central bank with a constitutionally-granted monopoly on the financial mechanisms of the Commonwealth, with nearly all Commonwealth banking firms subordinated to its organisation. It is responsible directly to the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a> and sets the monetary policy of Vekllei. It is primarily a macroeconomic institution that does not deal directly with the primary or secondary markets, but does over institutional banking services and complex financing for some markets in the Commonwealth.</p>
<h4 id="personal-banking">
  Personal Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#personal-banking">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Despite the functional moneylessness of the Commonwealth, banks do facilitate financial transactions with the common Vekllei person. Aside from its policy features (like holiday allowances and emigration stipends), most trade arrangements operate in the bank system, usually through the <em>Sisterbank</em>. Sisterbank (formally the <em>Petty Bank of Vekllei</em>) is a merchant bank that specialises in industrial brokerage, allowing small businesses to trade with others and stimulate economic activity. Vekllei persons looking to start a restaurant, workshop or store generally do so through the Sisterbank, which assigns a bank agent and enters the business in its internal market ledger. Not all small business in Vekllei is conducted through the an agent, but certain types of industries (particularly businesses involved in manufacturing) are almost all banked with Sisterbank.</p>
<p>In addition to government banks, money bureaus (also <em>Money Unions</em>) are a form of cooperative credit union premised on private business associations and securitised lending, and are common in Vekllei agriculture.</p>
<h4 id="institutional-banking">
  Institutional Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#institutional-banking">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Investment banking is provided primarily by the Commonwealth Bank of Vekllei (COMMBANK), which offers placement and settling services for <a href="/bureaus/">bureaus</a> seeking to engage with the International market. COMMBANK also arranges debt financing, underwriting and distribution services for overseas partners. COMMBANK also serves as the central bank of the Kalina Isles. In addition, the Bank of Vekllei maintains several subsidiaries dedicated to special financial products, like low-interest domestic infrastructure financing or overseas trade and investment.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>An entrepôt is a port where merchandise is stored and traded, often before being exported again.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>The Commonwealth capital account runs at a deficit as part of a post-war investment policy called &lsquo;Handshake Accounting,&rsquo; which sees tremendous surplus state capital invested overseas.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Foreign investment in the primary economy is usually made in the form of state-backed <a href="#blue-bonds">Blue Bonds</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Medallions, or medals, are a cultural feature in Vekllei used in spiritual ceremonies, as awards, and as a material novelty or trinket.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>&lsquo;Municipalised,&rsquo; in Vekllei political lexicon.&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Forum of Free Nations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/free-nations/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/free-nations/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles The Forum of Free Nations (FFE, also known as the Non-Aligned Movement) is a forum of countries that are not aligned with or against a power bloc. It was founded as a reaction towards the rapid bi-polarisation of world affairs, particularly of NATO and the Warsaw Pact, and advocates for independence from the superpowers of the world.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Forum of Free Nations</strong> (FFE, also known as the Non-Aligned Movement) is a forum of countries that are not aligned with or against a power bloc. It was founded as a reaction towards the rapid bi-polarisation of world affairs, particularly of NATO and the Warsaw Pact, and advocates for independence from the superpowers of the world.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Healthcare in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/health/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/health/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Overview # As elsewhere in Vekllei, healthcare is centralised in planning and standards and decentralised in delivery. Each republic has a National Health Service which governs regional policy.
Almost all healthcare available in Vekllei comes through public financing and providers. There are two private hospitals in the country which provide specialised care to foreigners.
The current system has good outcomes, and its public services are widely available to residents.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>As elsewhere in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, healthcare is centralised in planning and standards and decentralised in delivery. Each <a href="/constituents/">republic</a> has a National Health Service which governs regional policy.</p>
<p>Almost all healthcare available in Vekllei comes through public financing and providers. There are two private hospitals in the country which provide specialised care to foreigners.</p>
<p>The current system has good outcomes, and its public services are widely available to residents.</p>
<h2 id="services">
  Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#services">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">❀ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/health/">Health Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>There are 540 hospitals in Vekllei with a total of 80,000 beds.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p>Public health care covers the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>hospital inpatient services</li>
<li>most general practitioner (GP) and specialist services</li>
<li>a broad list of pharmaceuticals and medical devices</li>
<li>home care services</li>
<li>physiotherapy</li>
<li>most preventive measures, including selected vaccinations, selected general health examinations, and screenings for high-risk patients</li>
<li>maternity care, including prenatal checkups, birth, postpartum care, and breastfeeding advice</li>
<li>outpatient care for mental illness, if provided or delegated by physicians</li>
<li>medically necessary long-term care</li>
<li>hospice care if there is an underlying disease</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="mental-health">
  Mental Health
  <a class="anchor" href="#mental-health">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The country has six psychiatric hospitals. The largest is the Institute of Psychiatric Health</p>
<h2 id="pharmaceuticals-and-medicine">
  Pharmaceuticals and Medicine
  <a class="anchor" href="#pharmaceuticals-and-medicine">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The Commonwealth Government has</p>
<h2 id="funding-and-accounting">
  Funding and Accounting
  <a class="anchor" href="#funding-and-accounting">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Hospitals and staff are funded by the</p>
<p>Like all Vekllei <a href="/assets/">state-owned enterprises</a>, healthcare in Vekllei uses commercial accounting systems and records spending. Although money is not actually used, these budgets are audited regularly and expenditure is determined through an extensive costing exercise.</p>
<p>Healthcare delivery costs are often opaque in Vekllei&rsquo;s integrated health systems, in which a pharmaceutical can be produced, shipped and administered without material financial cost. Instead, prices are affixed by the Health Accounting Office and used as guides for cost. These budgets compel health services to discipline their costs.</p>
<h2 id="role-of-government">
  Role of Government
  <a class="anchor" href="#role-of-government">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Main article: <span class="smallicon">⚕️</span> <em><a href="/helsec/">Commownealth Health Council</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Public healthcare is integrated into Vekllei&rsquo;s cascading federal system. National Health Authorities (NHAs) are tasked with local policy and the delivery of most care, including health promotion programmes and the administration of hospitals. The federal Health Secretariat designs commonwealth policy, and conducts most health planning and research. The federal health authorities also purchase foreign imports necessary for domestic healthcare, including the Community Pharmacy Agreements (CPA) which negotiate foreign medicine prices.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/svg/diagrams/health.png/" alt="Diagram of public health organisation"  title="Diagram of the organisation of public health in Vekllei and its structure" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Diagram of the organisation of public health in Vekllei and its structure</figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>The foundation of Vekllei public health, however, lies in the municipalities. General Practitioners (GPs) and Family Doctors are the main primary care providers in the country, and are employed by <a href="/polis/">municipal</a> health councils.</p>
<details >
  <summary>Role of Government</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>Commonwealth Health Secretariat
<ul>
<li>Commonwealth Office of Public Health</li>
<li>Commonwealth Disease Control Authority</li>
<li>National Health Council
<ul>
<li>Vekllei Health Network</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Commonwealth Health Academy</li>
<li>Medicines Authority</li>
<li>Radiation Health Authority</li>
<li>Food and Medicines Standards Authority</li>
<li>Integrated Health office
<ul>
<li>Integrated Health Accounting Office</li>
<li>Integrated Care Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Health Democracy Advocate</li>
<li>Health Accounting Office
<ul>
<li>Health Finance Board</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Vekllei National Health
<ul>
<li>Health Sciences Authority</li>
<li>Health Promotion Board</li>
<li>Hospital Administration</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Vekllei Municipal Health
*</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Housing</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/housing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/housing/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Housing in Vekllei is socialised in the Georgist tradition. It is a recognition that all wealth lies in land, the resources beneath it, and the people that work it. In this sense, housing in Vekllei is just as radical and striking as its moneylessness. All real estate in Vekllei is negotiated, purchased and leased at a municipal level. This system depends heavily on stewardship as a factor of ownership.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Housing</strong> in Vekllei is socialised in the Georgist tradition. It is a recognition that all wealth lies in land, the resources beneath it, and the people that work it. In this sense, housing in Vekllei is just as radical and striking as its moneylessness.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>All real estate in Vekllei is negotiated, purchased and leased at a <a href="/municipalities/">municipal</a> level. This system depends heavily on stewardship as a factor of ownership. Most free homes are rented on an open market and are awarded via an interview process with the municipality, though there are many exceptions. In general, the more time a resident spends working a property, the more powerful their claim to ownership becomes. In this sense, multigenerational family homes are nearly impossible to challenge in the delicture courts.</p>
<p>As part of <a href="/metaphysics/">Vekllei metaphysics</a>, land has rights and owns itself. Human ownership is foremost a contract with the land, and the municipality is positioned as an intermediary. In practice, land ownership is portioned between different agents based on their relationship with the property. The municipality may retain a monopoly on real estate, but most Vekllei people own their residences. All residences are designed by architects, who are an essential agent of the municipality in Vekllei.</p>
<p>Real estate is also used as <a href="/news/essays/moneylessness/#why-do-vekllei-people-work">compensation</a>. Doctors are usually housed close to their place of work in homes built for that purpose. Tenancy in Vekllei is generally of this type, where homes are tied to employment. In the Vekllei delicture system, longtime employees gradually wrest ownership away from the municipality, and homes are commonly gifted after ten or fifteen years of service.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Military</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/military/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/military/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles The armed forces of Vekllei are part of the Ministry of Defence, and consist of the combined armed capability of the country, as well as services for public emergencies, law enforcement and civil defence.
Unlike common practice overseas, Vekllei does not have seperate military branches, and instead administers all aspects of defence as a single armed organisation originating as part of the Navy.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The armed forces of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> are part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmokos)" href="/cosmokos/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a>, and consist of the combined armed capability of the country, as well as services for public emergencies, law enforcement and civil defence.</p>
<p>Unlike common practice overseas, Vekllei does not have seperate military branches, and instead administers all aspects of defence as a single armed organisation originating as part of the Navy. As a union of island communities, the Vekllei Navy is its historic and contemporary primary means of defence, and Vekllei doctrine favours an integrated command. As such, all air and land warfare is conducted as part of the Navy under a unified defence command.</p>
<p>Because all services operate within the Navy, different roles are organised into different services. For example, the traditional surface navy of the <a href="#maritime-service">Maritime Service</a> does not operate its own seaborne aviation, since all aircraft are part of the Navy&rsquo;s <a href="#air-service">Air Service</a>. In this context, &ldquo;Navy&rdquo; is a synonym for &ldquo;Military&rdquo; in Vekllei, and equipment, signage and vehicles are marked as such.</p>
<h2 id="vekllei-military-services">
  Vekllei Military Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#vekllei-military-services">#</a>
</h2>
<p>A Vekllei military service is a component of the overall armed forces, and so they overlap and intersect. Unlike most other militaries, which are divided between different branches and coordinated by a central command, Vekllei military services are effectively interchangeable, and form <em>interarmes services</em> for specific missions. A single <em>interarmes service</em> may even involve regiments from all services simultaneously, which would operate as a single unit under a unified command.</p>
<p>Vekllei is a seagoing country of island communities, and so the Marine Services are the backbone of its strategic forces. They are the oldest military organisations of Vekllei and revered by the country.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Note</strong></p>
<p>In numbered Vekllei services (e.g. Terrestrial &amp; Air Services, etc.), numerical order is preserved and units are not permanently attached to a particular number. Unit numbers are administrative and assist in formation of interarmes services, so units may change numbers regularly. Instead, unit identity and honours are attached to ceremonial and historical names that remain with the unit.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="span-classnaviconspan-marine-services">
  <span class="navicon">⚓️</span> Marine Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#span-classnaviconspan-marine-services">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Marine Services consist of the armed forces most commonly associated with seaborne warfare and supply, and include equivalents to the Navy and Coast Guard. It is an administrative rather than conceptual distinction, as many other aspects of oceangoing warfare are folded into the air and territorial services, such as naval aviation and marine infantry.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="maritime-service">
  Maritime Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#maritime-service">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <strong>Maritime Service</strong> (the <strong>Navy</strong> or <em>Navy of the Public</em>) is the traditional naval warfare component of the Vekllei military and consists of its surface ships and submarines.</p>
<details >
  <summary>Maritime Service Fleet</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="commonwealth-fleet">
  Commonwealth Fleet
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-fleet">#</a>
</h5>
<p>The Commonwealth Fleet (<em>Sovereign/Central Fleet</em>) of the Vekllei Maritime Service is the largest naval formation in Vekllei and is tasked with defence of the country&rsquo;s central corridor, a triangular area with points in <a style="color: rgb(38, 48, 132)" href="/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, Verde and <a style="color: rgb(69, 81, 202)" href="/summers/"><span class="fi fi-summers"></span></span> Summers</a></p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>5 Aircraft Carriers
<ul>
<li>1 Supercarrier</li>
<li>2 Fleet Carriers</li>
<li>2 Helicopter Carriers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>3 Battlecruisers</li>
<li>12 Cruisers
<ul>
<li>2 Scout Cruisers</li>
<li>2 Torpedo Cruisers</li>
<li>6 Missile Cruisers</li>
<li>2 Aircraft Cruisers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>28 Destroyers
<ul>
<li>6 Minelayers/Minesweepers</li>
<li>22 Fleet Air Escort Destroyers</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h5 id="home-fleet">
  Home Fleet
  <a class="anchor" href="#home-fleet">#</a>
</h5>
<p>The Home Fleet of the Vekllei Maritime Service is a reserve frigate fleet stationed across the 70 island city-states that make up the country. Each Vekllei city-state serves as a home port to a particular frigate. While they serve a pseduo-ceremonial role, they are active warships that perform littoral maritime security duties and can be federalised into other fleets as necessary. The Home Fleet also consists of auxiliary and littoral vessels designed for service in the Vekllei Caribbean.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>82 Frigates
<ul>
<li>70 <a href="/stories/frigate/">Aurora-Class Republic Warships</a></li>
<li>5 Air Scout Frigates</li>
<li>4 Anti-Submarine Warfare Frigates</li>
<li>3 Guided Missile Frigates</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2 Submarine Rescue Ships</li>
<li>1 Crane Ship</li>
<li>6 Minehunters</li>
<li>4 Naval Yachts</li>
<li>3 Amenities Ship</li>
<li>2 Ammunition Ship</li>
<li>2 Floating Dock</li>
<li>1 Troopship (+ 4 Auxiliary)</li>
<li>4 Accomodation Ships</li>
<li>2 Dispatch Ships</li>
<li>4 Nuclear Replenishment Ships</li>
<li>2 Replenishment Oilers</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h5 id="arctic-fleet">
  Arctic Fleet
  <a class="anchor" href="#arctic-fleet">#</a>
</h5>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>1 Fleet Carrier</li>
<li>1 Battlecruiser</li>
<li>6 Cruisers
<ul>
<li>4 Nuclear Icebreaker Cruisers</li>
<li>2 Aircraft Cruisers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>12 Destroyers
<ul>
<li>8 Fleet Air Escort Destroyers</li>
<li>3 Missile Destroyers</li>
<li>1 Arsenal Destroyer</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h5 id="antarctic-fleet">
  Antarctic Fleet
  <a class="anchor" href="#antarctic-fleet">#</a>
</h5>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>1 Fleet Carrier</li>
<li>1 Battlecruiser</li>
<li>6 Cruisers
<ul>
<li>4 Nuclear Icebreaker Cruisers</li>
<li>2 Aircraft Cruisers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>12 Destroyers
<ul>
<li>8 Fleet Air Escort Destroyers</li>
<li>3 Missile Destroyers</li>
<li>1 Arsenal Destroyer</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Misc Republican Frigates</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Fast Attack Craft</li>
<li>Corvettes</li>
<li>Yachts</li>
</ul>
<p>(200)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Patrol Boat</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Missile Boat</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Torpedo Boat</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Gunboats</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Submarine Chaser</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Minelayer</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Minesweeper</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Minehunter</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Assault Ship - 4</p>
<ul>
<li>Landing Craft - 28</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Arsenal Ship - 2</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Submarines - 50</p>
<ul>
<li>Ballistic Missile Submarine</li>
<li>Attack Submarine</li>
<li>Midget Submarine</li>
<li>Submarine Aircraft Carrier</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="littoral-service">
  Littoral Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#littoral-service">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <strong>Littoral Service</strong> (the <em>Coast Guard</em> or <em>Navy of the Parliament</em>) is the maritime security component of the Vekllei military. It provides customs, policing and search and rescue services for Vekllei&rsquo;s territorial waters and exclusive economic zones, though it frequently patrols international waters in the Atlantic.</p>
<p>The Littoral Service has 12 commands across the Atlantic, Arctic, Antarctic and Caribbean Oceans, including the entirety of the Vekllei exclusive economic zone and territorial waters.</p>
<details >
  <summary>Littoral Service Equipment</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="customs-cutters">
  Customs Cutters
  <a class="anchor" href="#customs-cutters">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>6 Frigate Customs Cutters</li>
<li>20 Medium Customs Cutters</li>
<li>20 Fast Response Customs Hydrofoils</li>
<li>2 Air Cutters</li>
<li>12 Coastal Patrol Vessels</li>
<li>8 Search and Rescue Vessels</li>
<li>8 Fast Patrol Boats</li>
<li>16 Hovercraft Cutters</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="utility-vessels">
  Utility Vessels
  <a class="anchor" href="#utility-vessels">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>4 Seagoing Buoy Tenders</li>
<li>10 Coastal Buoy Tenders</li>
<li>4 Coastal Construction Tenders</li>
<li>5 River Tenders</li>
<li>1 Large Ocean Tugboat</li>
<li>2 Medium Ocean Tugboats</li>
<li>10 Harbour Tugboats</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="icebreakers">
  Icebreakers
  <a class="anchor" href="#icebreakers">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>4 Heavy Icebreakers</li>
<li>1 Ice-strengthened Oiler</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="survey--auxiliary-ships">
  Survey &amp; Auxiliary Ships
  <a class="anchor" href="#survey--auxiliary-ships">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>2 Hydrographic Survey Ships</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="coastal-artillery">
  Coastal Artillery
  <a class="anchor" href="#coastal-artillery">#</a>
</h4>
<details >
  <summary>Littoral Service Equipment</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="coastal-artillery">
  Coastal Artillery
  <a class="anchor" href="#coastal-artillery">#</a>
</h5>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="rocket-navy">
  Rocket Navy
  <a class="anchor" href="#rocket-navy">#</a>
</h4>
</div>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="span-classnaviconspan-aeronautical--space-services">
  <span class="navicon">✈️</span> Aeronautical &amp; Space Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#span-classnaviconspan-aeronautical--space-services">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="air-service">
  Air Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#air-service">#</a>
</h4>
<details >
  <summary>Air Service Structure</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="air-combat-command">
  Air Combat Command
  <a class="anchor" href="#air-combat-command">#</a>
</h5>
<p>The Air Combat Command provides aircraft and crew for combat air services, including both land and seaborne aviation. The vast majority of these are the No. 8 Casemate Fighter Jet.</p>
<h6 id="no-1-fighter-wing">
  No. 1 Fighter Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-1-fighter-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>The No. 1 Fighter Wing is the tip of the spear, and.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 1 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Virgin</span></li>
<li>No. 2 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Oslola</span></li>
<li>No. 3 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Demon</span></li>
<li>No. 4 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Kala</span></li>
<li>No. 5 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Kairi</span></li>
<li>No. 6 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Mira</span></li>
<li>No. 7 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Ascension</span></li>
<li>No. 8 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Bermuda</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-2-fighter-wing">
  No. 2 Fighter Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-2-fighter-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 9 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Praia</span></li>
<li>No. 10 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Summers</span></li>
<li>No. 11 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Cigateo</span></li>
<li>No. 12 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Oslola</span></li>
<li>No. 13 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Caimanas</span></li>
<li>No. 14 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Aruba</span></li>
<li>No. 15 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Barbados</span></li>
<li>No. 16 Fighter Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Comet</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-3-aeroweapons-wing">
  No. 3 Aeroweapons Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-3-aeroweapons-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>The Aeroweapons Wing consists of the attack helicopter and helijets squadrons of the Air Service, which are organised with Aeroscouts and Aerorifles to produce air-mobile platoons.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 17 Aeroweapons Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Ascension</span></li>
<li>No. 18 Aeroweapons Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Summers</span></li>
<li>No. 19 Aeroweapons Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Caimanas</span></li>
<li>No. 20 Aeroweapons Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Oslola</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-4-aeroscouts-wing">
  No. 4 Aeroscouts Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-4-aeroscouts-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>The Aeroscouts Wing provides reconnaissance services to the Territorial Service and the interarmes air-mobile platoons.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 21 Aeroweapons Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Ascension</span></li>
<li>No. 22 Aeroweapons Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Summers</span></li>
<li>No. 23 Aeroweapons Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Caimanas</span></li>
<li>No. 24 Aeroweapons Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Oslola</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-5-marine-combat-wing">
  No. 5 Marine Combat Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-5-marine-combat-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>The No. 3 Marine Combat Wing provides equipment and crew for the Commonwealth Fleet, and comprises the largest naval aviation force in the Air Service.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 17 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 18 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 19 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 20 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 21 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 22 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-6-marine-combat-wing">
  No. 6 Marine Combat Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-6-marine-combat-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 23 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 24 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-7-marine-combat-wing">
  No. 7 Marine Combat Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-7-marine-combat-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 25 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Arctic Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 26 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Arctic Fleet</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-8-marine-combat-wing">
  No. 8 Marine Combat Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-8-marine-combat-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 27 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Antarctic Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 28 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Antarctic Fleet</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-9-marine-helicopter-wing">
  No. 9 Marine Helicopter Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-9-marine-helicopter-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>The No. 9 MHW comprises the bulk of maritime rotary-wing and helijet aircraft, and are located across fleets and naval bases as required. Marine squadrons may be subdivided into Marine sections depending on the needs of the <a href="#maritime-service">Maritime Service</a>.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 29 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 30 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 31 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Arctic Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 32 Marine Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Antarctic Fleet</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h5 id="air-auxiliary-command">
  Air Auxiliary Command
  <a class="anchor" href="#air-auxiliary-command">#</a>
</h5>
<p>The Air Auxiliary Command includes aircraft types not directly associated with other command roles, and encompasses different kinds of aircraft in a support (auxiliary) role.</p>
<h6 id="no-1-air-auxiliary-wing">
  No. 1 Air Auxiliary Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-1-air-auxiliary-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>No. 1 AA Wing provides maritime patrol services to the Air Service as well as the Maritime and Littoral Services. No. 1 Squadron is assigned to the Commonwealth Fleet.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 1 Maritime Patrol Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 2 Search &amp; Rescue Squadron</li>
<li>No. 3 Air Firefighting Squadron</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-2-air-auxiliary-wing">
  No. 2 Air Auxiliary Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-2-air-auxiliary-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 4 Maritime Patrol Squadron</li>
<li>No. 5 Maritime Patrol Squadron</li>
<li>No. 6 Maritime Patrol Squadron</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-3-air-training-wing">
  No. 3 Air Training Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-3-air-training-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>The Air Training Wing has two squadrons in the Virgin and Oslolan republics, and trains pilots for the Air Service.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 1 Air Training Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Virgin</span></li>
<li>No. 2 Air Training Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Oslola</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h5 id="air-transport-command">
  Air Transport Command
  <a class="anchor" href="#air-transport-command">#</a>
</h5>
<p>The Air Transport Command supports other services, particularly the Territorial Service, and provides air mobility to Rifles regiments as part of its flexible and rapid-manoeuvre doctrine. When mounted in helicopters and helijets, Rifles regiments are known as Aerorifles, and combine with the crew and equipment of an Aerorifles squadron to form a complete air-mobile platoon.</p>
<h6 id="no-1-transport-wing">
  No. 1 Transport Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-1-transport-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>The No. 1 Transport Wing services the transport aircraft fleet. No. 1 &amp; 2 Squadrons are land-based and 3 &amp; 4 specialise in maritime transport, and include flying boats.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 1 Transport Squadron (Government)</li>
<li>No. 2 Transport Squadron (Strategic Airlift)</li>
<li>No. 3 Transport Squadron (Strategic Airlift)</li>
<li>No. 4 Transport Squadron (Tactical Airlift)</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-2-aerorifles-wing">
  No. 2 Aerorifles Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-2-aerorifles-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<p>The Aerorifles are the aircraft and crew component of an interarmes air-mobile platoon, and transport individual infantry regiments.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 5 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 6 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 7 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 8 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-3-aerorifles-wing">
  No. 3 Aerorifles Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-3-aerorifles-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 9 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 10 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 11 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 12 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h6 id="no-4-aerorifles-wing">
  No. 4 Aerorifles Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-4-aerorifles-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 13 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 14 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 15 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
<li>No. 16 Aerorifles Squadron</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h5 id="air-replenishment-command">
  Air Replenishment Command
  <a class="anchor" href="#air-replenishment-command">#</a>
</h5>
<h6 id="no-1-air-replenishment-wing">
  No. 1 Air Replenishment Wing
  <a class="anchor" href="#no-1-air-replenishment-wing">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>No. 1 Air Replenishment Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Oslola</span></li>
<li>No. 2 Air Replenishment Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Barbados</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
  </div>
</details>
<details >
  <summary>Air Service Aircraft</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="combat-aircraft">
  Combat Aircraft
  <a class="anchor" href="#combat-aircraft">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>210 No. 8 Casemate Atomic Fighters</li>
<li>33 No. 7 Demon Atomic Fighters</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="maritime-and-patrol-aircraft">
  Maritime and Patrol Aircraft
  <a class="anchor" href="#maritime-and-patrol-aircraft">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>16 Long Range Search &amp; Rescue Turboprop Aircraft</li>
<li>4 Search &amp; Rescue Flying Boats</li>
<li>2 Heavy-lift Search &amp; Rescue Aircraft</li>
<li>50 Seagoing Utility Helicopters</li>
<li>4 Ground Effect Combat Aircraft</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="tanker-aircraft">
  Tanker Aircraft
  <a class="anchor" href="#tanker-aircraft">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>1 Nuclear Replenishment Aircraft</li>
<li>2 Airborne Fuel Replenishment Aircraft</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="transport-aircraft">
  Transport Aircraft
  <a class="anchor" href="#transport-aircraft">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>27 Heavy Transport Aircraft</li>
<li>22 Medium Transport Aircraft</li>
<li>18 VIP Transport</li>
<li>24 Strategic Airlifter</li>
<li>12 Tactical Airlifter</li>
<li>4 Ground Effect Heavy Airlifters</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="helicopters">
  Helicopters
  <a class="anchor" href="#helicopters">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>42 Attack Helicopters</li>
<li>52 Scout Helicopters</li>
<li>40 Heavy-lift/Utility</li>
<li>20 Anti-Submarine Warfare/Search and Rescue</li>
<li>10 Transport/Utility</li>
<li>60 Transport/Utility</li>
<li>50 Medium-lift/Utility</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="trainer-aircraft">
  Trainer Aircraft
  <a class="anchor" href="#trainer-aircraft">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>20 Primary Trainer Aircraft</li>
<li>40</li>
<li>15 Training Helicopters</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="air-artillery-service">
  Air Artillery Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#air-artillery-service">#</a>
</h4>
<details >
  <summary>Air Artillery Service Equipment</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="missile-systems">
  Missile Systems
  <a class="anchor" href="#missile-systems">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>25 Truck</li>
<li>25 Truck</li>
<li>15 Trailer</li>
<li>1200 missile platform</li>
<li>12 Tracker Carriers</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="man-portable--aa-guns">
  Man-Portable &amp; AA Guns
  <a class="anchor" href="#man-portable--aa-guns">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>120 guns</li>
<li>1000 missiles</li>
<li>1500 missiles</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="radar-service">
  Radar Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#radar-service">#</a>
</h4>
<details >
  <summary>Radar Service Equipment</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="radar-systems">
  Radar Systems
  <a class="anchor" href="#radar-systems">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>5 Aerostat Radar Surveillance Balloons</li>
<li>40 Portable Search Target Acquisition Radar</li>
<li>12 Ground Active Electronically Scanned Array</li>
<li>4 Medium Array</li>
<li>20 Giraffe Array</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="radar-jamming-aircraft">
  Radar Jamming Aircraft
  <a class="anchor" href="#radar-jamming-aircraft">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>8 Radar Jamming Aircraft</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="missiles-service">
  Missiles Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#missiles-service">#</a>
</h4>
</div>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="span-classnaviconspan-land-and-army-services">
  <span class="navicon">🗡️</span> Land and Army Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#span-classnaviconspan-land-and-army-services">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="territorial-service">
  Territorial Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#territorial-service">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The Vekllei <strong>Territorial Service</strong> is the closest analogue to a conventional army in the Vekllei military and comprises the majority of its professional fighting force. All Rifles regiments are trained as marine infantry, and Vekllei does not maintain dedicated marine regiments. All Territorial regiments are a part of the <a href="#commonwealth-guard">Commonwealth Guard</a> and are federalised the same way, but are distinguished by their professional service and expeditionary posture.</p>
<details >
  <summary>Rifles Service Structure</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="rifle-regiments">
  Rifle Regiments
  <a class="anchor" href="#rifle-regiments">#</a>
</h5>
<p>Rifles regiments consist of 1,000 men, and can be assembled into larger divisional units. Regiment numbers are administrative only and so can change, and regiments are identified with inherited names with honours instead. Rifles are mechanised with armoured cars.  Policy is to have a standing army 50,000 strong, but the 26th-50th Rifles regiments are activated as they are combat-ready, and so the 50th and 49th are often deactivated between training.</p>
<p>All Rifles are trained as both marine infantry and air assault regiments, and are</p>
<h6 id="1st-25th-rifles-regiments">
  1st-25th Rifles Regiments
  <a class="anchor" href="#1st-25th-rifles-regiments">#</a>
</h6>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>1st Rifles Regiment <span class="hollowtag">Comet</span></li>
<li>2nd Rifles Regiment <span class="hollowtag">Comet</span></li>
<li>3rd Rifles Regiment <span class="hollowtag">Comet</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li><strong>26th-50th Rifles Regiments</strong></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<h5 id="armoured-rifles-regiments">
  Armoured Rifles Regiments
  <a class="anchor" href="#armoured-rifles-regiments">#</a>
</h5>
<p>The Armoured Rifles are mechanised with infantry fighting vehicles and tracked APCs and function as shock infantry.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li><strong>51st-52nd Armoured Rifles Regiments</strong></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>Marine Rifles Regiments</strong></li>
<li><strong>Air Rifles Regiments</strong></li>
</ul>
<h5 id="commonwealth-guard-regiments">
  Commonwealth Guard Regiments
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-guard-regiments">#</a>
</h5>
<p>The Commonwealth Guard is the national militia and primary reserve force of the Territorial Services. It is federalised by default, and contributes its servicemen for the Rifles and other territorial regiments. As such, all Territorial servicemen are part of a Commonwealth Guards regiment, but in regular service are assigned to active units in other services. Only reservists, trainees and officers remained attached to the Guard while it is federalised.</p>
<h6 id="1st-6th-regiments">
  1st-6th Regiments
  <a class="anchor" href="#1st-6th-regiments">#</a>
</h6>
<ul>
<li><strong>Democracy &amp; Civic Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>Civil Affairs Regiments</li>
<li>Military Police Regiments</li>
<li>Military Intelligence Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Special Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>Chemical Regiments</li>
<li>Nuclear Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
<details >
  <summary>Armoured Corps Service Structure</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="armoured-regiments">
  Armoured Regiments
  <a class="anchor" href="#armoured-regiments">#</a>
</h5>
  </div>
</details>
<details >
  <summary>Territorial Service Equipment</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="main-battle-tanks">
  Main Battle Tanks
  <a class="anchor" href="#main-battle-tanks">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>310 No. 4 Sekhmet MBT</li>
<li>21 No. 3 Ordoria MBT</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="infantry-fighting-vehicles">
  Infantry Fighting Vehicles
  <a class="anchor" href="#infantry-fighting-vehicles">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>300 Combat Reconnaissance Vehicles (ASLAV)</li>
<li>1600 Infantry Fighting Vehicles</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="armoured-personnel-carriers">
  Armoured Personnel Carriers
  <a class="anchor" href="#armoured-personnel-carriers">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>3500 Armoured Personnel Carriers (Commandos)</li>
<li>1400 Tracked APCs</li>
<li>800 Amphibious Armoured Vehicles</li>
<li>600 Armoured All-Terrain Carriers</li>
<li>460 Armoured Cars</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="watercraft">
  Watercraft
  <a class="anchor" href="#watercraft">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>30 Amphibious Cargo Vehicles</li>
<li>24 Mechanised Landing Craft</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="trucks--cars">
  Trucks &amp; Cars
  <a class="anchor" href="#trucks--cars">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>2,500 Multi-Purpose Utility Vehicle</li>
<li>3,560 Military Truck</li>
<li>30 High-Mobility Transporters</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="mine-resistant-and-ambush-vehicles">
  Mine-Resistant and Ambush Vehicles
  <a class="anchor" href="#mine-resistant-and-ambush-vehicles">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>240 Protected Combat Support Vehicle</li>
<li>180 Armoured Personnel Support Vehicle</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="engineering-vehicles">
  Engineering Vehicles
  <a class="anchor" href="#engineering-vehicles">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>30 Armoured Combat Engineering Vehicles</li>
<li>80 Combat Recovery Vehicles</li>
<li>20 Vehicle-Launched Bridges</li>
<li>72 Armoured Tractors</li>
<li>15 Amphibious Bridging Vehicles</li>
<li>6 Demining Vehicles</li>
<li>12 Mine Detection Vehicles</li>
<li>20 Bulldozers</li>
<li>8 Backhoe Loaders</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="field-artillery-service">
  Field Artillery Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#field-artillery-service">#</a>
</h4>
<details >
  <summary>Field Artillery Service Structure</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="field-artillery">
  Field Artillery
  <a class="anchor" href="#field-artillery">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>1st-5th Cannons Regiments</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
<details >
  <summary>Artillery Service Equipment</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="artillery">
  Artillery
  <a class="anchor" href="#artillery">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>52 Rocket Artillery</li>
<li>105 Self-Propelled Artillery</li>
<li>120 155mm Towed Howitzer</li>
<li>80 105mm Towed Howitzer</li>
<li>75 Ceremonial Gun-Howitzer</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-guard">
  Commonwealth Guard
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-guard">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The Commonwealth Guard (<em>National Guard</em>) is the national militia of Vekllei and comprises the majority of its service personnel. Unlike other national militias which require federalisation, the Commonwealth Guard are federalised by default, and are deactivated for specific republic duties as required.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commando-service">
  Commando Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#commando-service">#</a>
</h4>
<details >
  <summary>Expeditionary Service Structure</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li><strong>Commando Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>1st-5th Commandos Regiments</li>
<li>6th-7th Airborne Commandos Regiments</li>
<li>8th-9th Marine Commandos Regiments</li>
<li>10th Special Activities Regiment</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Regional Special Forces Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>11th Arctic Regiment</li>
<li>12th North Atlantic Regiment</li>
<li>13th Africa Regiment</li>
<li>14-16th Equatorial Regiments</li>
<li>17th Antarctic Regiment</li>
<li>18th Lunar Regiment</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Guards</strong>
<ul>
<li>19th-22nd Commmonwealth Guards Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Armoured Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>23rd-25th Armoured Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Artillery</strong>
<ul>
<li>25th-32nd Cannons Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Special Forces</strong>
<ul>
<li>Psychological Warfare Regiments</li>
<li>Space Operations Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="patrol-service">
  Patrol Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#patrol-service">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The Patrol Service is a border guard.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="signals-service">
  Signals Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#signals-service">#</a>
</h4>
<details >
  <summary>Signals Service Equipment</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>4 Signals Interceptor Aircraft</li>
<li>2 Intelligence &amp; Control Aircraft</li>
<li>6 Early Warning Aircraft</li>
</ul>
  </div>
</details>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h3 id="civil-defence-service">
  Civil Defence Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#civil-defence-service">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li>Police Services
<ul>
<li>Municipal Police</li>
<li>Commonwealth Police</li>
<li>Federal Police</li>
<li>Finance Police</li>
<li>Parliamentary Police</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Public Health Service</li>
<li>Civil Defence Service</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
</blockquote>

<style>
  details div {
  padding: 0;
  }
  .hollowtag {
    line-height: .8rem!important;
    padding: 0.1rem 0.25rem;
    border: 1px solid var(--color-gray);
    list-style: none;
    width: fit-content;
    color: var(--color-gray);
    border-radius: 0.25rem;
  }
</style>]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Police</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/police/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/police/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles As a federal commonwealth, Vekllei has different kinds of police for different kinds of laws.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>As a federal commonwealth, Vekllei has different kinds of police for different kinds of laws.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Republics</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/republics/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/republics/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles A Republic (Vekllei: Polis) is type of city-state that make up the country of Vekllei. They consist of island city-states known as Polisa which together form a constituent commonwealth. There are 66 republics in Vekllei that together form 8 commonwealths and the country of Vekllei.
Diagram of the a Polis administration and its structure There are a few criteria separating Polisa from regular city councils.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>A <strong>Republic</strong> (Vekllei: <em>Polis</em>) is type of city-state that make up the country of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. They consist of island city-states known as <em>Polisa</em> which together form a <a href="/constituents/">constituent commonwealth</a>. There are 66 republics in Vekllei that together form 8 commonwealths and the country of Vekllei.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/svg/diagrams/polis.png" alt="Diagram of Polis structure"  title="Diagram of the a Polis administration and its structure" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Diagram of the a Polis administration and its structure</figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>There are a few criteria separating Polisa from regular city councils. They are generally self-sufficient, and include surrounding areas capable of agriculture and industry. They also retain their own lower courts, and have a strengthened local government consisting of a popular assembly (the Municipal Assembly) and Ecclesia &ndash; special-purpose councils of important civic citizens and industrial representatives.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>List of Vekllei Republics</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Federal Territories</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Meteor Federal Territory</li>
<li>Vekllei Antarctic Territories</li>
<li>Vekllei Lunar Territories</li>
<li>Vekllei Mars Community</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Antarctic Commonwealth</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Ascension Republic (<em>Ascension</em>)</li>
<li>Falklands Republic (<em>Falklands</em>)</li>
<li>Helena Republic (<em>Saint Helena</em>)</li>
<li>Santes Republic (<em>Tristan da Cunha</em>)</li>
<li>Sude Republic (<em>South Georgia &amp; South Sandwich Islands</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Antilles Commonwealth</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Aruba Republic (<em>Aruba</em>)</li>
<li>Bonaire Republic (<em>Bonaire</em>)</li>
<li>Caimanas Republic (<em>Caimanas</em>)</li>
<li>Curaçao Republic (<em>Curacao</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Arctic Commonwealth</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Kala Republic (<em>Greenland</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Atlantic Commonwealth</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fayal Republic (<em>Faial Island</em>)</li>
<li>Flores Republic (<em>Flores Island</em>)</li>
<li>Graciosa Republic (<em>Graciosa Island</em>)</li>
<li>Maria Republic (<em>Santa Maria Island</em>)</li>
<li>Mira Republic (<em>Madeira</em>)</li>
<li>Pico Republic (<em>Pico Island</em>)</li>
<li>Porto Santo Republic (<em>Porto Santo</em>)</li>
<li>Terceira Republic (<em>Terceira Island</em>)</li>
<li>Velas Republic (<em>Sao Jorge Island</em>)</li>
<li>Verde Republic (<em>Sao Miguel Island</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Bahamas Commonwealth</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Caicos Republic (<em>Turks &amp; Caicos</em>)</li>
<li>Cigateo Republic (<em>Eleuthera</em>)</li>
<li>Curateo Republic (<em>Great Exuma</em>)</li>
<li>Grand Bahama Republic (<em>Grand Bahama</em>)</li>
<li>Guanima Republic (<em>Cat Island</em>)</li>
<li>Habacoa Republic (<em>Andros Islands</em>)</li>
<li>Inagua Republic (<em>Great Inagua</em>)</li>
<li>Lucayoneque Republic (<em>Abaco Islands</em>)</li>
<li>Mayaguana Republic (<em>Mayaguana</em>)</li>
<li>Nema Republic (<em>New Providence</em>)</li>
<li>Rum Republic (<em>San Salvador &amp; Rum Cay</em>)</li>
<li>Summers Republic (<em>Bermuda</em>)</li>
<li>Yabaque Republic (<em>Acklins</em>)</li>
<li>Yuma Republic (<em>Long Island</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Kalina Commonwealth</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Allia Republic (<em>Montserrat</em>)</li>
<li>Aloi Republic (<em>St Eustatius</em>)</li>
<li>Anguis Republic (<em>Anguilla</em>)</li>
<li>Antam Republic (<em>Antigua</em>)</li>
<li>Barbados Republic (<em>Barbados</em>)</li>
<li>Barbuda Republic (<em>Barbuda</em>)</li>
<li>Cama Republic (<em>Grenada</em>)</li>
<li>Karu Republic (<em>Guadeloupe</em>)</li>
<li>Kabuli Republic (<em>Dominica</em>)</li>
<li>Kairi Republic (<em>Trinidad &amp; Tobago</em>)</li>
<li>Liamuiga Republic (<em>St Kitts</em>)</li>
<li>Lucia Republic (<em>Saint Lucia</em>)</li>
<li>Madiana Republic (<em>Martinique</em>)</li>
<li>Oualie Republic (<em>Navis</em>)</li>
<li>Ouanalao Republic (<em>Saint Barthelemy</em>)</li>
<li>Saba Republic (<em>Saba</em>)</li>
<li>Soualiga Republic (<em>Saint Martin/Sint Maartin</em>)</li>
<li>Virgin Republic (<em>British/U.S. Virgin Islands</em>)</li>
<li>Youloumain Republic (<em>Saint Vincent &amp; The Grenadines</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Oslolan Commonwealth</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Aismious Republic (<em>Faroe</em>)</li>
<li>Demon Republic (<em>Jan Mayen</em>)</li>
<li>Helvasia Republic (<em>Svalbard</em>)</li>
<li>Oslolan Republic (<em>Iceland</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Verde Commonwealth</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Boa Vista Republic (<em>Boa Vista</em>)</li>
<li>Brava Republic (<em>Brava</em>)</li>
<li>Covoada Republic (<em>Sao Nicolau</em>)</li>
<li>Fogo Republic (<em>Fogo</em>)</li>
<li>Maio Republic (<em>Maio</em>)</li>
<li>Moroços Republic (<em>Santo Antao</em>)</li>
<li>Praia Republic (<em>Santiago</em>)</li>
<li>Principe Republic (<em>Sao Tome &amp; Principe</em>)</li>
<li>Sal Republic (<em>Sal</em>)</li>
<li>Viana Republic (<em>Sao Vicente</em>)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Territories</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/territories/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/territories/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Territories, dependencies and autonomous regions are administrative areas of the Commonwealth that are not considered Constituent members. This is usually because they lack a large permanent population able to form its own Assembly, or otherwise form part of a special administrative territory that has been federalised.
As non-constituents, they are unable to form Sords and have permanent observer status in the Council.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Territories, dependencies and autonomous regions are administrative areas of the Commonwealth that are not considered <a href="/constituents/">Constituent</a> members. This is usually because they lack a large permanent population able to form its own <a href="/assembly/">Assembly</a>, or otherwise form part of a special administrative territory that has been federalised.</p>
<p>As non-constituents, they are unable to form Sords and have permanent observer status in the <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a>. These territories include:</p>
<p><strong>Vekllei Federal Territories</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Vekllei Antarctic Territories</li>
<li>Vekllei Lunar Territories</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dependent States</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Aismious Islands (<em>Faroe Islands</em>)</li>
<li>Demon Islands (<em>Jan Mayen</em>)</li>
<li>Helvasia (<em>Svalbard</em>)</li>
<li>Sude Islands (<em>South Georgia &amp; Sandwich Islands</em>)</li>
<li>Falklands Islands (<em>Falklands Islands</em>)</li>
<li>Santes (<em>St Helena</em>)</li>
<li>Ascension (<em>Ascension Islands</em>)</li>
<li>Tristan (<em>Tristan de Cunha</em>)</li>
<li>Bermuda (<em>Bermuda</em>)</li>
</ul>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
