<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meta on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meta on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Vekllei Comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Hi everyone,
&amp;ldquo;He not busy being born is busy dying,&amp;rdquo; — that’s off a Bob Dylan bootleg. I’ve just finished my thesis and I’m busy being born again. Sometimes I feel like I’m busy dying. Drawing’s been the way out for a long time now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baron, the Father</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   People are not sure what to make of Baron. They are not sure what to make of his daughter, Tzipora, either. To that end, they are lucky to have found each other.
His obscurity is part of a severe disposition, made obvious by his astonishing disinterest in friends and hobbies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Bouncy Zelda — an animation diary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   It&amp;rsquo;s been a week since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted. Most of that was spent drawing the same thing over and over.
A painting? Please. That&amp;rsquo;s a day&amp;rsquo;s work — maybe two. A five second loop of Tzipora jumping in and shuffling over? A week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2,000 members! WOW!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Hello,
I’m Hobart. I’ve been working on this project for a while now. It doesn’t really have a purpose or an end goal — I just want to draw and write about nice things, and I’m learning a lot on the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is This Project?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   What is Vekllei?
Hi, I’m Hobart and I write and draw Vekllei at Studio MillMint.
This is a pretty complex project. Not just complex insofar as there’s a lot to read about it, but that it uses concepts and terminology you might not be familiar with if this is your first time around utopian fiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Tzipo-stcards</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Hello everyone. Just a little update.
As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.
How many cards will the set contain?
 I’m aiming for about six cards.
 How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Vekllei?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Vekllei is a country in my alt-world; a utopian fever dream of googie aesthetics, participatory economics and nostalgia.
Welcome to the ‘Petticoat Project’, a collection of stories about a country and a girl. The concept is broken down into three sections:
 Author: for blog posts and articles on the Petticoat Project, utopian fiction, personal news item, etc. Character: for posts about Tzipora, people in her life, or otherwise events that occur during her time on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
