<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>World</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/landscape/world/</link>
	<description>Recent content in World </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/landscape/world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Ceylon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/landscape/world/ceylon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/landscape/world/ceylon/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the world series of articles The Socialist Republic of Ceylon (also Śrī Laṅkā in Sinhala and Ilaṅkai in Tamil) is an island country in the Indian Ocean, off the coast of India. It is a part of the non-aligned movement and the Council of Oceans.
Ceylon is home to 19.5 million people, and is a rapidly developing country with an expanding diplomatic presence throughout South East Asia and East Africa.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint green">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Socialist Republic of Ceylon</strong> (also <em>Śrī Laṅkā</em> in Sinhala and <em>Ilaṅkai</em> in Tamil) is an island country in the Indian Ocean, off the coast of India. It is a part of the non-aligned movement and the <a href="/oceans-council/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Council of Oceans</a>.</p>
<p>Ceylon is home to 19.5 million people, and is a rapidly developing country with an expanding diplomatic presence throughout South East Asia and East Africa. It also has close ties to the United Kingdom, its former coloniser, and <a href="/vekllei"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka is an industrial hub and famous for its garment and textiles manufacturing, tea, precious stones and shipbuilding.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Portugal</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/landscape/world/portugal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/landscape/world/portugal/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the world series of articles The Second Portuguese Republic (commonly Portugal) was a Portuguese state that existed between 1926 and 2014. It succeeded the democratic First Republic and Portuguese Empire, and was ruled by the Estado Novo regime.
Portugal was incorporated into Iberia following the Spanish invasion of Portugal at the turn of the 21st Century. Portugal&rsquo;s defeat and subsequent annexation ended its independence and brought an end to the Portuguese Colonial War, which in turn decolonised most of its former empire.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint green">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Second Portuguese Republic</strong> (commonly <em>Portugal</em>) was a Portuguese state that existed between 1926 and 2014. It succeeded the democratic First Republic and Portuguese Empire, and was ruled by the <em>Estado Novo</em> regime.</p>
<p>Portugal was incorporated into Iberia following the Spanish invasion of Portugal at the turn of the 21st Century. Portugal&rsquo;s defeat and subsequent annexation ended its independence and brought an end to the Portuguese Colonial War, which in turn decolonised most of its former empire.</p>
<p>In the late 20th Century, lusotropicalist foreign policy heightened tensions with the Republican government in Spain. These compounded historical grievances, including the Estado Novo regime&rsquo;s support of the francoist coalition during the Spanish Civil War, and the deportation of Spanish students in 1975.</p>
<p>Two different massacres in Portuguese colonies, the maintenance of which was strongly opposed by Madrid, led to sanctions on Portugal and military aid to anti-colonial rebels in its colonies. The war, which started in 2013, was provoked by the assassination of Spanish president Javier Marx, for which Portgual denied responsibility. The decision to annex European Portugal rather than depose the Estado Novo regime prompted strong criticism from the <a href="/un/"><span class="fi fi-un"></span> United Nations</a> and NATO.</p>
<p>Several former Portuguese territories are part of <a href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> today. These include:</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li><a href="/mira/"><span class="fi fi-mira"></span> Mira</a></li>
<li>Azores</li>
<li><a href="/verde/"><span class="fi fi-verde"></span> Verde</a></li>
<li>Principe</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>United Nations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/landscape/world/un/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/landscape/world/un/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the world series of articles The United Nations (UN) is an intergovernmental, international organisation established to protect peace and promote human development. By 2063, almost all countries on earth have membership or observational status. It is headquartered primarily in New York, but also has assemblies in Vekllei, Geneva, Johannesburg, Brasilia and Thailand.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint green">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>United Nations</strong> (UN) is an intergovernmental, international organisation established to protect peace and promote human development. By 2063, almost all countries on earth have membership or observational status. It is headquartered primarily in New York, but also has assemblies in <a href="/vekllei"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, Geneva, Johannesburg, Brasilia and Thailand.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
