<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>2017 on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2017/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2017 on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Girl Scouts Learn to Shoot in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/blossoms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/blossoms/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora Desmoines is part of Troop 45 of the Vekllei Blossoms. Every adult, as part of mandatory service in the country of Vekllei, owns and operates a firearm, most commonly a handgun. Because of this hazard, the children of Vekllei learn gun safety at an early age, either through school or the Blossoms.
On the cusp of the teen years, they can also learn how to operate weapons, like eleven-year-old Tzipora is doing here.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Radiation Poisoning in Domestic Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/radiation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/radiation/</guid>
	  <description>He started collecting radioactive material from the clocks and electronic appliances in his house earlier in the week. The material, which included radium and americium, was placed in a compartment in the living room wall of his apartment. This exposed his wife, nine-year-old son and infant daughter to dangerous levels of radioactivity. By Wednesday that week the baby had fallen ill, and Mrs Toutan took her to Miuounne General that evening, returning with a prescription for ibuprofen.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Seaside in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/seaside/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/seaside/</guid>
	  <description>About this time of year, in the place between high summer and autumn, the weather is good in Vekllei. Vekllei is too cold for crickets, but insects are out and the air hums with life — birds, helijets, and the soft noise an ocean breeze makes as it races toward the harbour, pulling on leaves and skirt hems along the way.
The Lola monorail carries tourists and workers between the district centre and the World Expo Tower.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Beat Cops in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/cop/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/cop/</guid>
	  <description>It was just like any other evening in Monouiz; a no-good view of one part concrete, one part fescue, and a whole lotta quiet. He knew the broad from his days hunting smuggler types in jazz bars and street cars, a gig not worth gigging now that prohibition was over. She was a pretty little chickadee attached to a big guy of bad temper, and he guessed one night he took it too far.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Princess of the Earth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/princess/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/princess/</guid>
	  <description>Barbaloh was once the spirit of a rainforest, but now lives only in the world of the spirits as a merchant, selling potions, spells and other supernatural nonsense. Tzipora, a brave human girl and fierce humanist, has gained passage to the spirit world through the bones of a derden, or “angel”. She found herself in another dimension and in total darkness, and the spirits immediately sensed her presence, taking physical and anthropomorphic forms to talk to her.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Two Spies and a Vekllei Girl</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/spies/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/spies/</guid>
	  <description>In Nevada about this time of year, the temperature stays steady at 45 degrees (~115 in yank). The asphalt sticks to shoes. On the far right is Lenny the Jew. The moniker is his own; he’s a Jew from New York who ended up working for the Vekllei Rocketry Corps, the Vekllei espionage agency responsible for operations in the southern United States. Lenny the Jew is good with women, and violence.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Entering the Spirit World</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/spirit-world/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/spirit-world/</guid>
	  <description>Suddenly the blood drained from her lungs and she breathed in, only to double over, hacking blood into the grass between her shoes. She wiped her bloody mouth on the back of her arm and mumbled something like ‘sorry’ before coughing again. She slipped off her shoes and made her way to the clearing.
She saw the bones and knelt in front of them, laying some flowers out for it and waiting respectfully.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The National Dress of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/vk-dress/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/vk-dress/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei people are usually buried in their national dress. It marks the important stages in their way of life; of graduation, of marriage, of ceremony. The carousel of festivals and parades and holidays that these Atlantic people enjoy are all spent in uniform, their national costume, that forms the public face of their country.
Lou and Mey here, two happy young things in love, are dressed up for the National Holiday.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Watching the End of the World</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/missile/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/missile/</guid>
	  <description>The sight of the missiles nearly made her sick. Everything around her took on new context. It was such a peaceful afternoon, and the sirens hadn’t gone off, and here she was, watching the trails the missiles painted in the cloudless sky. And now she was blessed with a newfound psychic ability that told her that everything in this spot would be vapour in a half hour. The wheat, the forest, the road; everything.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Face of Human Extinction</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/face/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/face/</guid>
	  <description>All servants of heaven — called angels by most people but they belong to a much older name — are viciously jealous of human beings. In creation, the Earth was promised to them, but the creator God gave the Earth to the human race. In a fit of rage, the angels — or Derden, as they were called before the current chapter of humanity — buried bioengineered monsters called Lehmenan far below the surface of the Earth.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Little Vekllei General Store</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/general-store/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/general-store/</guid>
	  <description>In the narrow streets of the Lola district in Vekllei, artisans and artists hurry about, peddling art and fine goods and attracting the rest of the city to its stores. In Vekllei, there is no currency, so shopping is almost always a pragmatic affair.
Not in Lola. If you’re in Lola, you’re there to see the good stuff, produced and sold in little shops like this one. The apartments of this place are small and cramped, and the streets are rarely wide enough for vehicles to pass, but many students dream of moving into the vibrant and colourful district and building lives around their creative passions.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Pleading with Angels to Spare Humanity</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/pleading/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/pleading/</guid>
	  <description>She saw its bones and the sight of them — that they were real and not a dream — caught in her throat. She raised her hand to cough, and suddenly her lungs heaved and blood began to pour from the spaces between her fingers. Her eyes grew wide and she cupped her hand, and she retched again and her blood sprayed out like a hose. It soaked her, but she stayed steady.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Chemical Warfare in 2063</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/chemical-war/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/chemical-war/</guid>
	  <description>“We came to a town and found it scorched with mustard and the fragments of phosgene shells, and the wind whistled through the doorways that were left open. I remember being surprised by how many of them were in basements — probably because they thought the gas would blow away in the wind. The entire town was dead, and we were worried that the gasses were still lingering, so the unit wore their masks as we began to cremate them.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora, the Undying Miracle Child</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/undying/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/undying/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora is a Gregori baby, a child who doesn’t age and cannot contract cell-mutating diseases. She is the adopted daughter of Michael Desmoines, an espionage quartermaster for a foreign power in the United States.
She is clever, sensitive, and deeply humanist. Despite her shyness and her loneliness, she is remembered by the few whose lives she touched as an affectionate and exceptionally gifted girl.
She has a chronic sadness about her.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora Makes Friends with a Desert Spirit</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/desert-spirit/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/desert-spirit/</guid>
	  <description>Every natural place has a spirit that minds it. Tzipora had never met a desert spirit before, and she went looking for one in Cherry, Nevada. With air force jets glinting in the sky overhead, and the temperature scorching the mesas that surround the military town, she found one inside a burrow. In an instant, it had transformed into a rattlesnake and tried to scare her, but she dropped to her knees and begged it to forgive her for waking it.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Fashion in the Year 2063</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/fashion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/fashion/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei kids look to America as a bastion of good taste; a country of fast cars and diners and sock-hops and high-school romance. Like the Koreans look to Japanese taste, and the British look to the stuff coming out of design houses in France, Vekllei is infatuated with how Americans dress in the year 2063. Like most imported culture in Vekllei, the American teen-age style is misunderstood, butchered, and then transformed into something entirely different as production lines crank out plaid skirts, two-tone shoes and baseball jerseys for Vekllei kids.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Girl’s Life Saved by Veteran Hero in Day of Terror</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/terror/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/terror/</guid>
	  <description>Louenne Dehmones enlisted for two years but stayed for ten. He served abroad in the war department, where he performed admirably but never rose above the rank of Junior Sergeant because of a good-natured appetite for mischief. He transferred to the military police to be close to his wife and infant daughter.
It was his daughter that he thought of as he powdered the wounds of the girl at the airport with instaskin, and it was of his daughter that he thought as he picked up the girl’s body, smoke still pouring from the cavity in her chest, and carried her to the ambulances that were wailing all over the airport.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora, one of the children to stop ageing</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ageing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ageing/</guid>
	  <description>This is Tzipora. She is eleven years old, scruffy, and a Gregori baby. At the turn of the 21st century, Gregori Hordiyenko, a Ukrainian boy aged nine and a half, stopped aging entirely. By 2063, which is the year Tzipora turned eleven, there are about two hundred Gregori babies in the world, mostly living in secret. Certain religious sects, including Catholics, view Gregori babies as a sign of the Lord’s action and as a movement towards an approaching religious event.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Five Uniforms of Any Good Vekllei Girl</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/five-uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/five-uniforms/</guid>
	  <description>These are the five basic outfits a kid in the city of Vekllei rotates between in their life. This is Tzipora. She’s sharp and a little scruffy. She’s eleven years old.
The first is her school uniform, complete with embroidered armband featuring the national crest. The skirt has a longer pleated section. She wears penny loafers.
The second is the uniform of the Vekllei Blossoms, equivalent to the Pioneers in the USSR and Red China, or Boy Scouts in the West.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Anti-bullying poster in the year 2063</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/bullying/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/bullying/</guid>
	  <description>This poster circulated middle schools in 2063 as part of a wider initiative at curbing violence against women at an early age. The two Vekllei characters on the left read literally as &amp;ldquo;there is no excuse to hit a female,&amp;rdquo; but it emphasises the ‘hit’ part of it to make the idea particularly reprehensible. The girl pictured wears Vekllei middle school uniform, including a red armband with the national crest on it.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>She stands in the harbour in national dress</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/national-dress/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/national-dress/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora, a recent immigrant girl of eleven years, wears the feminine national dress of Vekllei. It is a delicate, traditional and deeply spiritual costume, and is tied to Vekllei’s foundations and aspirations as a state. It has political symbolism, but it also ties the girl to the land she stands on.
Underneath her Lawtsk Ohma (an equivalent phrase might be &amp;ldquo;Maiden’s Apron, in English, but it loses the emotion of the original phrase; it insinuates youthful innocence and domesticity, industry and love) is a wide lace half-petticoat that sits over her skirt.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora has her photo taken at Youth Meet 2063</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/youth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/youth/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora is smiling in the photo because she has won the competition for multilingual spelling. She is a recent citizen of Vekllei, a postcollectivist country in what we know as Iceland. She beat American boy scouts, Australian girl guides, Chinese and Soviet Pioneers and other youth organisations to win top prize.
The International Youth Meet is a games hosted biannually. Tzipora is representing the Vekllei Occupation Zone in Germany with a half-dozen other girls from the O.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>