<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Law</title>
	<link>/factbook/society/state/law/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Law </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/society/state/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Basic Laws</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/law/basic-laws/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/law/basic-laws/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the law series of articles The Basic Laws of the Vekllei are a quasi-constitutional laws that inform in detail aspects of Vekllei government and state not provided in the Constitution. They are superior to other types of legislation in the country, and can only be overturned by a supermajority vote in the Senate, a majority referendum of the Commonwealth and approval of the Cabinet.
Law Purpose Commonwealth of Oceans Describes structure and functions of Commonwealth government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/law/">law</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Basic Laws of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> are a quasi-constitutional laws that inform in detail aspects of Vekllei government and state not provided in the <a href="/constitution/">Constitution</a>. They are superior to other types of legislation in the country, and can only be overturned by a supermajority vote in the Senate, a majority referendum of the Commonwealth and approval of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Law</th>
<th>Purpose</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Commonwealth of Oceans</td>
<td>Describes structure and functions of Commonwealth government.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Assemblies of Oceans</td>
<td>Describes the entitlements, structure and legislative powers of Constituent republics.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Commons</td>
<td>Describes and protects the moneyless market system of the domestic markets.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The State Economy</td>
<td>Describes the financialised commons, and the role of the state in finance and industry.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Industry and Living</td>
<td>Describes the role of bureaus in the Commonwealth Economy.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Military</td>
<td>Describes the role and laws applying to a unified Commonwealth military command.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The State Secretary</td>
<td>Describes the structure and functions of the Commonwealth and Constituent governments.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Human Rights</td>
<td>Enshrines rights and freedoms of Commonwealth citizens.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Land and Stewardship</td>
<td>Enshrines property rights and opportunity of work for Commonwealth citizens.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Councils and Democracy</td>
<td>Enshrines the right to municipal representation, democracy and labour organising.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Century Society</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/law/century-society/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/law/century-society/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the law series of articles The &ldquo;Century Society&rdquo; Laws were a collection of laws designed to foster educated immigration in postwar Vekllei. In total, they promised citizenship to any person with a tertiary qualification fleeing a persecuting regime, or citizenship to any person with valuable expertise to contribute1 towards the country. Provided the immigrant could &ldquo;build their own home,&rdquo;2 they would be incentivised with permanent citizenship for their immediate family and opportunities to participate in the postwar government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/law/">law</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The &ldquo;Century Society&rdquo; Laws were a collection of laws designed to foster educated immigration in postwar <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. In total, they promised citizenship to any person with a tertiary qualification fleeing a persecuting regime, or citizenship to any person with valuable expertise to contribute<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> towards the country. Provided the immigrant could &ldquo;build their own home,&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> they would be incentivised with permanent citizenship for their immediate family and opportunities to participate in the postwar government.</p>
<p>Many &ldquo;Century Citizens,&rdquo; as immigrants under this law became known, were politically motivated to participate in the anarchist aspects of Vekllei society or otherwise seeking a better life in an emerging country. Consequently, the Century Society programme has also been called the &ldquo;Aliyah for anarchists.&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
<p>The Century Society Laws were made more restrictive in 2038, and then again in 2045. They are still part of Vekllei legislation today, but are much more closely controlled to ease migrant pressures on dense Commonwealth cities.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The desirable skills included experience in construction, medicine, trade or clerical work.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>&ldquo;Build your own home&rdquo; was a shorthand for contributing to the war-ravaged and emerging Vekllei Commonwealth. In some cases, it meant joining a Municipal Action Group and literally assisting construction of your own neighbourhood with the help of your neighbours.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>This phrase is a reference to the Jewish Aliyah to Israel in the 20th Century after the conclusion of the Second World War.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Civil Rights</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/law/rights/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/law/rights/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the law series of articles The Universal Civil Rights of the New Atlantic, commonly the Universal Rights or Civil Rights Document is a document attached to the Vekllei Constitution. It enshrines the individual rights of all people in Vekllei. Universal Civil Rights
The Universal Civil Rights of the New Atlantic guarantees fundamental rights to the individual person in Vekllei. It supports constitutional values of democracy, equality and freedom.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/law/">law</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text">The Universal Civil Rights of the New Atlantic, commonly the <em>Universal Rights</em> or <em>Civil Rights Document</em> is a document attached to the <a href="/constitution/">Vekllei Constitution</a>. It enshrines the individual rights of all people in Vekllei.</span>
</blockquote>

<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Universal Civil Rights</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The Universal Civil Rights of the New Atlantic guarantees fundamental rights to the individual person in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It supports constitutional values of democracy, equality and freedom.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Vekllei Commonwealth (the Commonwealth) must maintain, defend, promote and fulfil these rights.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Vekllei person (the Citizen) has obligations to maintain, defend, promote and fulfil these rights as determined by law.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>These rights are inviolable where not subject to the limitations contained or referred to in section 30, or elsewhere in the <a href="/constitution/">Vekllei Constitution</a>.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Application of rights</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The political concept of civil rights applies to all law, and binds the legislature, the executive, the judiciary and all federal, commonwealth, republican and municipal agents of the country, thereafter recognised as &lsquo;Vekllei&rsquo; or the &lsquo;Commonwealth&rsquo;.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The political concept of civil rights also binds and entitles a natural or a juristic person to the extent that a right is applicable considering the nature of the right and its obligations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When applying a provision of the universal civil rights to a natural or juristic person in terms of subsection (2.2), a court ­</p>
<ol>
<li>must apply or develop the common law to the extent that legislation does not give effect to a universal civil right; and</li>
<li>may develop the common law to limit the right, provided that the limitation is in accordance with section (30.1).</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to equal treatment</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone is equal before the Commonwealth, including its laws, and has the right to equal protection and benefit of the law.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Equality includes the full and equal enjoyment of all rights and freedoms. Legislative and other measures designed to protect or advance individuals and categories of individuals may be taken.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth may not unfairly discriminate directly or indirectly against anyone on one or more grounds, including race, gender, sex, pregnancy, marital status, ethnic or social origin, colour, sexual orientation, age, disability, religion, conscience, belief, culture, language and birth.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No person may unfairly discriminate directly or indirectly against anyone on one or more grounds in terms of subsection (3.3), and this right is to be protected by legislation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Discrimination on one or more of the grounds listed in subsection (3.3) is unfair unless it is established that the discrimination is fair.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to Human dignity</strong>
<br>
Everyone has inherent dignity and the right to have their dignity respected and protected.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to Life</strong>
<br>
Everyone has the right to life.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom and security of the person</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to freedom and security of the person, which includes the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>not to be deprived of freedom arbitrarily or without just cause, or be detained without trial;</li>
<li>to be free from all forms of violence from either public or private sources; and</li>
<li>not to be tortured or treated in a cruel, inhuman or degrading way.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to bodily and psychological integrity, which includes the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>to security in and control over their body;</li>
<li>to make decisions concerning reproduction; and</li>
<li>not to be subjected to medical or scientific experiments without their informed consent.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to Privacy</strong>
<br>
Everyone has the right to privacy, which includes the right not to have ­</p>
<ol>
<li>their person or home searched;</li>
<li>their property searched;</li>
<li>their possessions seized; or</li>
<li>the privacy of their communications infringed.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom from slavery, servitude and forced labour</strong>
<br>
No one may be subjected to slavery, servitude or forced labour.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of religion, belief and opinion</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to freedom of conscience, religion, thought, belief and opinion.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Religious observances may be conducted in Commonwealth institutions where they follow rules established by the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-culture); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-culture) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/culture/"><span class="fi fi-min-culture fis"></span> Ministry of Culture</a>, are conducted on an equitable basis and their attendance is free and voluntary.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This section does not prevent legislation recognising ­</p>
<ol>
<li>marriages conducted under any tradition or law consistent with this document and the Constitution; and</li>
<li>systems of personal, religious or family law.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of expression</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to freedom of expression, which includes ­</p>
<ol>
<li>freedom of the press and other media;</li>
<li>freedom to receive or impart information or ideas;</li>
<li>freedom of artistic creativity; and</li>
<li>academic freedom and freedom of scientific research.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>The rights in subsection (10.1) do not extend to ­</p>
<ol>
<li>propaganda for war;</li>
<li>incitement of imminent violence; or</li>
<li>advocacy of hatred that is based on race, ethnicity, gender or religion, and that constitutes incitement to cause harm.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of assembly, demonstration, picket and petition</strong>
<br>
Everyone has the right, peacefully and unarmed, to assemble, to demonstrate, to picket and to present petitions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of association</strong>
<br>
Everyone has the right to freedom of association.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to political organisation and participation</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Every citizen is free to make political choices, which includes the right</p>
<ol>
<li>to participate in political organisations, and</li>
<li>to campaign for a political belief or cause.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every citizen has the right to free, fair and regular elections for any legislative body established by the Constitution or organised by the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-commonwealth); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-commonwealth) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commonwealth/commonwealth-electoral-commission/"><span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> Commonwealth Electoral Commission</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every adult citizen has the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>to vote in elections for any legislative body established in terms of the Constitution, and to do so in secret; and</li>
<li>to stand for public office and, if elected, to hold office.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Citizenship</strong>
<br>
No citizen may be deprived of citizenship.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of movement and residence</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to freedom of movement.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every citizen has the right to papers for travel and a passport.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to leave the Commonwealth.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every citizen has the right to enter, to remain in and to reside anywhere in, the Commonwealth.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of trade, occupation and profession</strong>
<br>
Every citizen has the right to choose their trade, occupation or profession freely. The practice of a trade, occupation or profession may be regulated by law.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of language and culture</strong>
<br>
Everyone has the right to use the language and to participate in the cultural life of their choice, but no one exercising these rights may do so in a manner inconsistent with any right guaranteed in this document.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of cultural, religious and linguistic communities</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Persons belonging to a cultural, religious or linguistic community have the right to enjoy their culture, practise their religion and use their language, and to form, join and maintain associations and other organisations of civil society.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The rights in subsection (18.1) may not be exercised in a manner inconsistent with any provision of civil rights guaranteed in this document.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Freedom of information</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right of access to, as guaranteed by legislation providing reasonable measures to alleviate administrative burden on the Commonwealth</p>
<ol>
<li>any information held by the Commonwealth; and</li>
<li>any information that is held by another person and that is required for the exercise or protection of any rights.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to fair labour relations</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to fair labour practices.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every worker has the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>to form and join a trade union or syndicate;</li>
<li>to participate in the activities and programmes of a trade union or syndicate; and</li>
<li>to strike.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every employer has the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>to form and join an employers&rsquo; organisation; and</li>
<li>to participate in the activities and programmes of an employers&rsquo; organisation.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every trade union, bureau and employers&rsquo; organisation has the right ­to determine its own affairs, organise, and form or join a federation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every trade union, bureau, employers&rsquo; organisation and employer has the right to engage in collective bargaining. National legislation may be enacted to regulate collective bargaining. To the extent that the legislation may limit a right in this Chapter, the limitation must comply with section (30.1).</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to Environment</strong>
<br>
Everyone has the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>to an environment that is not harmful to their health or well-being; and</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to have the environment protected and preserved for the benefit of present and future generations by reasonable Commonwealth means, to prevent pollution and ecological degradation, and encourage conservation and sustainable development of resources.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to property</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>No one may be deprived of property arbitrarily.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Property may be expropriated only in terms of law of general application ­</p>
<ol>
<li>for a public purpose or in the public interest; and</li>
<li>subject to compensation, the nature of which have either been agreed to by those affected or decided or approved by a court.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>A claim to ownership of land may be determined by any ordinary court reflecting an equitable balance between the steward, public and sovereignty of nature, regarding all relevant circumstances, including</p>
<ol>
<li>the current use of the property;</li>
<li>the history of the acquisition and use of the property;</li>
<li>the utility and economic value of the property;</li>
<li>the extent of direct investment and subsidy in the acquisition by relevant Commonwealth or private organisations; and</li>
<li>the purpose of the expropriation.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth must take reasonable legislative and other measures, within its available resources, to foster conditions which enable citizens to gain access to land on an equitable basis.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No provision of this section may impede the Commonwealth from taking measures to achieve land, water and related reform, in order to redress and improve the quality of life afforded to constituent peoples, provided that any departure from the provisions of this section is in accordance with the provisions of section (30.1).</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to housing</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to have access to adequate housing.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth must take reasonable legislative and other measures, within its available resources, to achieve the progressive realisation of this right.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No one may be evicted from their home, or have their home demolished, without an order of court made after considering all the relevant circumstances. No legislation may permit arbitrary evictions.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to healthcare, food, water and security</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to have access to ­</p>
<ol>
<li>health care services, including reproductive health care;</li>
<li>sufficient food and water; and</li>
<li>social care, including, if they are unable to support themselves and their dependants, appropriate social assistance.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>No one may be refused emergency medical treatment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth must take reasonable legislative and other measures, within its available resources, to achieve the progressive realisation of each of these rights.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to education</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right ­to a primary, secondary and tertiary education, including adult education.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to receive education in English and the official languages of the Commonwealth where that education is reasonably practicable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to establish and maintain, at their own effort but not precluding Commonwealth assistance, independent educational institutions that ­</p>
<ol>
<li>do not discriminate on the basis of race;</li>
<li>are registered with the Commonwealth;</li>
<li>adhere to the National Curriculum as determined by the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-education); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-education) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/parliaments/education/"><span class="fi fi-min-education fis"></span> Education Parliament</a>; and</li>
<li>maintain standards that are not inferior to standards at comparable public educational institutions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rights of children</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Every child, a person under the age of 18 years, has the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>to a name and a nationality from birth;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to family care or parental care, or to appropriate alternative care when removed from the family environment;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to nutrition, shelter, health care services and social services;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to be protected from maltreatment, neglect, abuse or degradation;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to be protected from exploitative labour practices;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>not to be required or permitted to perform work or provide services that ­are inappropriate for their age, or risk their well-being, health, or development.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>not to be detained except as a measure of last resort, in which case only for the shortest appropriate period of time, and seperate from detained persons over the age of 18 years in a manner considerate of their age.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to have a legal practitioner assigned to the child by the Commonwealth, and at Commonwealth expense, in civil proceedings affecting the child, if substantial injustice would otherwise result; and</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>not to participate in war, and to be protected in times of war.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>A child&rsquo;s best interests are of paramount importance in every matter concerning the child.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to fair administrative action</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone has the right to administrative action that is lawful, reasonable, efficient and procedurally fair.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Everyone whose rights have been adversely affected by administrative action has the right to be given written reasons.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Right to resolutions through courts</strong>
<br>
Everyone has the right to have any dispute that can be resolved by the application of law decided in a fair public hearing before a court or, where appropriate, another independent and impartial tribunal or forum.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rights of detained and accused persons</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Everyone who is arrested for allegedly committing an offence has the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>to remain silent;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to be informed promptly ­of the right to remain silent and the consequences of not doing so;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>not to be compelled to make any confession or admission that could be used in evidence against that person;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to be brought before a court as soon as reasonably possible, but not later than ­48 hours after the arrest, or the end of the first court day thereafter, whichever is sooner;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>at the first court appearance after being arrested, to be charged or to be informed of the reason for the detention to continue; and</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to be released from detention if the interests of justice permit, subject to reasonable conditions.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Everyone who is detained, including every sentenced prisoner, has the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>to be informed promptly of the reason for being detained;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to choose, and to consult with, a legal practitioner, and to be informed of this right promptly;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to have a legal practitioner assigned to the detained person by the Commonwealth if substantial injustice would otherwise result, and to be informed of this right promptly;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to challenge the lawfulness of the detention in person before a court and, if the detention is unlawful, to be released;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to conditions of detention that are consistent with human dignity, including at least exercise and the provision of adequate accommodation, nutrition, reading material and medical treatment; and</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>to communicate with, and be visited by, that person&rsquo;s ­spouse or partner, next of kin, chosen religious counsellor and chosen medical practitioner.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every accused person has a right to a fair trial, which includes the right ­</p>
<ol>
<li>to be informed of the charge with sufficient detail to answer it;</li>
<li>to have adequate time and facilities to prepare a defence;</li>
<li>to a public trial before an ordinary court;</li>
<li>to have their trial begin and conclude without unreasonable delay;</li>
<li>to be present when being tried;</li>
<li>to choose, and be represented by, a legal practitioner, and to be informed of this right promptly;</li>
<li>to have a legal practitioner assigned to the accused person by the Commonwealth and at Commonwealth expense, if substantial injustice would otherwise result, and to be informed of this right promptly;</li>
<li>to be presumed innocent, to remain silent, and not to testify during the proceedings;</li>
<li>to adduce and challenge evidence;</li>
<li>not to be compelled to give self-incriminating evidence;</li>
<li>to be tried in a language that the accused person understands or, if that is not practicable, to have the proceedings interpreted in that language;</li>
<li>not to be convicted for an act or omission that was not an offence under either national or international law at the time it was committed or omitted;</li>
<li>of appeal to, or review by, a higher court.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Whenever this section requires information to be given to a person, that information must be given in a language that the person understands.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Evidence obtained in a manner that violates any right in this document or the Constitution must be excluded if the admission of that evidence would render the trial unfair or otherwise be detrimental to the administration of justice.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Limitation of rights</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Universal civil rights may be limited only in terms of law of general application to the extent that the limitation is reasonable and justifiable in an open and democratic society based on human dignity, equality and freedom, taking into account all relevant factors, including ­</p>
<ol>
<li>the nature of the right;</li>
<li>the importance of the purpose of the limitation;</li>
<li>the nature and extent of the limitation;</li>
<li>the relation between the limitation and its purpose; and</li>
<li>less restrictive means to achieve the purpose.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Except as provided in subsection (30.1) or in any other provision of the Constitution, no law may limit any universal civil right.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>States of emergency</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>A state of emergency may be declared only in terms of an Act of Commonwealth Federal Parliament, and only when ­</p>
<ol>
<li>the life of the nation is threatened by war, invasion, general insurrection, disorder, natural disaster or other public emergency; or</li>
<li>the principles of this document are at grave risk; and</li>
<li>the declaration is necessary to restore peace and order.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>A declaration of a state of emergency, and any legislation enacted or other action taken in consequence of that declaration, may be effective only ­</p>
<ol>
<li>prospectively; and</li>
<li>for no more than 21 days from the date of the declaration, unless the National Assembly resolves to extend the declaration. The Assembly may extend a declaration of a state of emergency for no more than three months at a time. The first extension must be adopted with a supporting vote of a majority of the members of the Assembly. Any subsequent extensions must be adopted with a supporting vote of at least two thirds of the members of the Assembly.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Any competent court may decide on the validity of ­</p>
<ol>
<li>a declaration of a state of emergency;</li>
<li>any extension of a declaration of a state of emergency; or</li>
<li>any legislation enacted, or other action taken, in consequence of a declaration of a state of emergency.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Any legislation enacted in consequence of a declaration of a state of emergency may derogate from universal civil rights only to the extent that ­</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>the derogation is strictly required by the emergency; and</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the legislation ­</p>
<ol>
<li>is consistent with the Commonwealth&rsquo;s obligations under international law applicable to states of emergency;</li>
<li>conforms to subsection (31.5); and</li>
<li>is published in the national Government Gazette as soon as reasonably possible after being enacted.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Any derogation of rights as a consequence of a state of emergency must remain consistent and lawful with subsection (30.1).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No legislation authorised in the declaration or as a consequence of a state of emergency may permit or authorise ­</p>
<ol>
<li>indemnifying the Commonwealth, or any person, in respect of any unlawful act;</li>
<li>any derogation from this section; or</li>
<li>any derogation from a section mentioned in column 1 of the Table of Non-Derogable Rights, to the extent indicated opposite that section in column 3 of the Table.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Section Number</th>
<th>Section Title</th>
<th>Extent to which the right is protected</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>Right to equal treatment</td>
<td>With respect to unfair discrimination solely on the grounds of race, colour, ethnic or social origin, sex, sexual orientation, religion or language</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Right to Human dignity</td>
<td>Entirely</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>Right to Life</td>
<td>With respect to persons not convicted of a crime against humanity or treason.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>Freedom and Security of the person</td>
<td>With respect to subsections (6.1.3) and (6.2.3).</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td>Freedom from slavery, servitude and forced labour</td>
<td>With respect to slavery and servitude.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>26</td>
<td>Rights of children</td>
<td>With respect to: subsections (26.1.4), (26.1.5) and (26.1.7); and subsection (26.1.9) in respect of children of 15 years and younger.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>29</td>
<td>Rights of detained and accused persons</td>
<td>With respect to: 1. subsections (29.1.1), (29.1.2), (29.1.3) and (29.2.4); excluding (29.3.4); subsection (29.4); and (29.5) with respect to the exclusion of evidence if the admission of that evidence would render the trial unfair.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Enforcement of rights</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Anyone listed in this section has the right to approach a competent court, alleging that a right outlined in this document has been infringed or threatened, and the court may grant appropriate relief, including a declaration of rights. The persons who may approach a court are</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>anyone acting in their own interest;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>anyone acting on behalf of another person who cannot act in their own name;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>anyone acting as a member of, or in the interest of, a group or class of persons;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>anyone acting in the public interest; and</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>an association acting in the interest of its members.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Interpretation of civil rights</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>When interpreting universal civil rights, a court, tribunal or forum</p>
<ol>
<li>must promote the values that underlie an open and democratic society based on human dignity, equality and freedom;</li>
<li>must consider international law; and</li>
<li>may consider foreign law.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>When interpreting any legislation, and when developing the common law or customary law, every court, tribunal or forum must promote the spirit, purport and objects of universal civil rights.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This document does not deny the existence of any other rights or freedoms that are recognised or conferred by common law, customary law or legislation, to the extent that they are consistent with the rights guaranteed here.</p>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<style>
.page ol {
  counter-reset: item;
  line-height: 2rem;
  font-size: 14px;
}
  ol li {
    display: block;
    position: relative;
}
.page li:before {
    content: counters(item, ".")" ";
    counter-increment: item;
    position: absolute;
    margin-right: 100%;
    right: 10px; /* space between number and text */
    font-weight: bold;
  }
</style>]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Constitution</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/law/constitution/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/law/constitution/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is incomplete. Be mindful that its content may change. The Constitution of Vekllei, also known as the Floral Constitution, was the foundational text for a new Commonwealth after British administration ended in 2015. It was developed by the Council of Roses and ratified in August 2015. PREAMBLE # THE PUBLIC OF THE OCEANS ATLANTIC RESOLVES
to bring peace to Commonwealth sovereign constituents twice destroyed in the pursuit of war, and to establish a new way of living worthy of a commitment in peace, and to protect the equal rights of men and women, and the dignity and worth of the human person, and to achieve equality and the advancement of human rights and freedoms, and to provide for the material and spiritual needs necessary in the aim of a commitment to dignity, AND IN SERVICE OF THESE AIMS]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <style>
  h3, h4 {
      margin: 0;
      font-size: 16px;
      border-radius: 2.5px;
  }
  article[autonumbering] h3::before {
     display: none;
  }
</style>
<blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is <strong>incomplete</strong>. Be mindful that its content may change.</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text">The Constitution of Vekllei, also known as the Floral Constitution, was the foundational text for a new Commonwealth after British administration ended in 2015. It was developed by the <a href="/rose-council/">Council of Roses</a> and ratified in August 2015.</span>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="preamble">
  PREAMBLE
  <a class="anchor" href="#preamble">#</a>
</h2>
<p>THE PUBLIC OF THE OCEANS ATLANTIC RESOLVES</p>
<ul>
<li>to bring peace to Commonwealth sovereign constituents twice destroyed in the pursuit of war, and</li>
<li>to establish a new way of living worthy of a commitment in peace, and</li>
<li>to protect the equal rights of men and women, and the dignity and worth of the human person, and</li>
<li>to achieve equality and the advancement of human rights and freedoms, and</li>
<li>to provide for the material and spiritual needs necessary in the aim of a commitment to dignity,</li>
</ul>
<p>AND IN SERVICE OF THESE AIMS</p>
<ul>
<li>to unite the languages, culture, and races of the Public under a democratic and prosperous society, and</li>
<li>to protect the supremacy of the constitution and the rule of law, and</li>
<li>to guarantee universal adult suffrage, and</li>
<li>to defend these values unwaveringly by all means available to its councils and government.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-commonwealth---the-public-powers">
  THE COMMONWEALTH - THE PUBLIC POWERS
  <a class="anchor" href="#the-commonwealth---the-public-powers">#</a>
</h2>
<h3 id="article-1">
  Article 1
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-1">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>The <a href="/vekllei/">Commonwealth of Vekllei</a> is one sovereign, democratic state within the framework of international law, founded on the following values:
<ol>
<li>Human dignity, the achievement of equality and the advancement of human rights and freedoms.</li>
<li>Non-racialism and non-sexism.</li>
<li>Supremacy of the constitution and the rule of law.</li>
<li>Universal adult suffrage, a national common voters roll, regular elections and a multiparty system of democratic government, to ensure accountability, responsiveness and openness.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>The territory of the Commonwealth is inviolable.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-2">
  Article 2
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-2">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The principle of government is a federal Directory of elected peers called the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/directory/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Directory</a>, representing the disparate communities that make up the unitary Commonwealth.</p>
<ol>
<li>The Directory consists of representatives of each <a href="/constituents/">Constituent</a> as free republics, and <a href="/territories/">dependent or autonomous territories</a>.</li>
<li>Other territories retain permanent status in the Directory and may table motions with agreement of a Constituent.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth Directorate is advised by a Cabinet of peers to provide opinion and expertise, called the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth Directorate and Cabinet combined form the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a>, which is the supreme executive of the Commonwealth.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth is a State under the rule of law, committed to fundamental freedoms and rights.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-3">
  Article 3
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-3">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The executive power is exercised by the Council as a single body where Commonwealth jurisdiction applies. The Council has power over national and municipal parliaments.</p>
<h3 id="article-4">
  Article 4
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-4">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The legislative power is jointly exercised by Constituent <a href="/assembly/">National Assemblies</a> and the Commonwealth Senate, with special powers provisioned for the Senate as a supreme legislative body.</p>
<h3 id="article-5">
  Article 5
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-5">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The judiciary power is exercised by the courts and tribunals.</p>
<h3 id="article-6">
  Article 6
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-6">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The separation of the administrative, legislative and judiciary functions is guaranteed.</p>
<h3 id="article-7">
  Article 7
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-7">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The standard of the Commonwealth is the Sovereign Crown.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth Flag consists of an arctic rosette, depicted as 6 petals, printed in gold on a crimson background.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The use of the flag, standard and official symbols of the Commonwealth is governed by the Flag Ordinance dated 4th March 2015.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-8">
  Article 8
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-8">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The Commonwealth has 16 official languages, with protections for their use and preservation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The official written language is Veletian.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The official language of international commerce and business is English.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-9">
  Article 9
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-9">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Commonwealth is a secular state and has no state religion. Religion is separated from public life and affairs. Protections are included for traditional and folk religions of Commonwealth communities.</p>
<ol>
<li>Recognised traditional faiths include folk Oslolan spiritualism, Kalina local faiths and the Catholic, Apostolic and Roman religions.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="the-directory">
  THE DIRECTORY
  <a class="anchor" href="#the-directory">#</a>
</h2>
<h3 id="article-10">
  Article 10
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-10">#</a>
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Constituents of the Commonwealth provide two representatives to the Directory as Prime Ministers. The Ministers practice equal power and make decisions as a single office (Sord).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Sord are citizens elected by the National Assembly of their constituent republic and consist of one man and one woman.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="article-11">
  Article 11
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-11">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Seat of Commonwealth Government is Comet, in the Meteor Administrative Region.</p>
<h3 id="article-12">
  Article 12
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-12">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Commonwealth Directorate is chaired by the Oslolan Sord, and chairmanship will pass to the right each year provided the incoming Sord is a Constituent.</p>
<h3 id="article-13">
  Article 13
  <a class="anchor" href="#article-13">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Council Chair represents the Commonwealth in its relations with foreign powers.</p>
<ol>
<li>Individual Sords will conduct relations with foreign powers as a subordinate, pertaining to the best interests of Constituents as required.</li>
</ol>
<!--
### Article 14
After consulting the Crown Council the Prince signs and ratifies treaties and in international convention. He acquaints the National Council through the Minister of State with them before their ratification.

However, the following treaties must be ratified in pursuance of a law:

Treaties and international agreements affecting the organisation of the Constitution
Treaties and international agreements the ratification of which entails the modification of the existing legal provisions
Treaties and international agreements which entail the Principality’s adhesion to an international organisation the functioning of which implies the participation of the National Council’s members
Treaties and international organisations the implementation of which results in a budget expenditure pertinent to expenditure type or use, which is not provided by the budget act
The Principality’s external policy is accounted for in an annual report prepared by the government and notified to the National Council.

### Article 15
After consulting the Cabinet, the Directory exercises the right to pardon and amnesty as well as the right of naturalisation and restoration of nationality.

### Article 16
Sords or the Directory confer orders, titles and other distinctions per Law.

## FUNDAMENTAL FREEDOMS AND RIGHTS

### Article 17
All Commonwealth citizens are equal before the law. There is no privilege among them.

### Article 18
The circumstances in which Vekllei nationality may be acquired are laid down by law. The circumstances in which a person who has acquired Vekllei nationality by naturalisation may be deprived of it are laid down in the law.

Loss of Vekllei nationality in any other circumstance may occur only, as prescribed by law, further to the intentional acquisition of another nationality or of service unlawfully carried out in a foreign army.

### Article 19
Individual freedom and security are guaranteed. No one may be prosecuted except in cases provided for by law, before legally appointed judges and in the manner prescribed by law.

Apart from cases of flagrant offence, an arrest may be carried out only pursuant to the well-founded order of the judge, which must be notified at the arrest or at the latest within twenty-four hours. Any detention must be preceded by an examination.

### Article 20
No penalty may be introduced or applied except by law.

Criminal law must ensure respect for individual personality and dignity. No one may be subjected to cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment.

Death penalty is applicable only to crimes against peace, humanity, or of war. The Death Penalty is abolished for other crimes.

Criminal law cannot have any retroactive effect.

### Article 21
The domicile is inviolable. No entry and search in the domicile can take place except in cases and in the manner prescribed by law.

### Article 22
Every individual has the right for respect of private and family life and confidentiality of correspondence.

### Article 23
1. Freedom of religion and of public worship, and freedom to express one’s opinions in all matters, is guaranteed, subject to the right to prosecute any offences committed in the exercise of the said freedoms.

2. No one may be compelled to participate in the rites or ceremonies of any religion or to observe its days of rest.

### Article 24
Property is inviolable. No one may be deprived of property except for public benefit as established by law, and upon a fair, settled and paid compensation in the circumstances and manner specified by law.

### Article 25
Freedom of work is guaranteed. Its practice is determined by law.

Priority is granted to Monegasques for the obtainment of public and private positions in the circumstances prescribed by law or international conventions.

### Article 26
Vekllei nationals are entitled to the assistance of the State in the event of destitution, unemployment, sickness, handicap, old age and maternity in the circumstances and manner laid down by law.

### Article 27
Vekllei nationals are entitled to free primary and secondary education.

### Article 28
Every person may defend the rights and interests of his/her occupation and function through a trade-union action.

The right to strike is recognised, subject to regulation of law.

### Article 29
Vekllei nationals have the right to assemble peacefully and without arms in accordance with the laws that may regulate the exercise of this right without subjecting it to prior authorisation. This freedom does not extend to open-air meetings, which remain subject to police laws.

### Article 30
Freedom of association is guaranteed, subject to regulation of law.

### Article 31
Anyone may address petitions to the public authorities.

### Article 32
Foreigners enjoy all public and private rights in the Principality that are not formally reserved to nationals.

## PUBLIC DOMAIN, PUBLIC FINANCE
### Article 33
Public domain is unalienable and imprescriptible.

A public domain property may be closed down or change purpose only if pronounced by law. Law may allocate decommissioned property to the State or Commune's public domain, as the case may be.

Public domain’s consistency and regime are determined by law.

### Article 34
The Crown’s property is submitted to The Sovereignty's exercise.

They are unalienable and imprescriptible.

Its consistency and regime are determined by the House Laws at the Sovereign Family.

### Article 35
Real estate property and rights pertinent to private State held property are transferable only in accordance with the law.

The law gives authorisation to sell a part of the business capital of which at least fifty per cent is held by the State, thereby transferring the majority of this capital to one or more physical person or private law legal persons.

### Article 36
All vacant and ownerless property belongs to the Sovereign and Nature in treaty with the State. In demonstrating claims of ownership the state may petition Sovereign property for use.

### Article 37
The national budget comprises all public revenue and public expenditure of the Commonwealth and its Constituents.

### Article 38
The national budget expresses the Commonwealth’s economic and financial policy.

### Article 39
Budget is subject to a budget bill. It is voted and promulgated in the form of a law.

### Article 40
The Sovereign Household’s expenses and those of the Prince Palace are determined by budget law and withdrawn in priority from the budget’s general public revenue.

### Article 41
The revenue surplus over expenditure, established after budget implementation and year end closing of accounts, is credited to a constitutional reserve fund. The excess of expenditure over revenue provides cover withdrawing from the same account, after enactment of the relevant law.

### Article 42
Control of financial management is ensured by a Higher Audit Commission.

## THE GOVERNMENT
### Article 43
Government is exercised, under the gracious authority of the Prince, by a Minister of State, assisted by a Government Council.

### Article 44
The Minister of State represents the Prince. He oversees the executive services. He has the police force at his command. He chairs the Government Council with a casting vote.

### Article 45
Sovereign ordinances are debated in the Government Council. They are presented to the Prince with the Minister of State's signature; they mention the relevant proceedings. They are signed by the Prince; the Prince's signature makes them enforceable.

### Article 46
Sovereign Ordinances, which are excluded from debate in the Government Council and presentation to the Minister of State, pertain to:

The House Laws of the Sovereign Family and these of its members
The affairs of the Direction of the Judicial Department

The appointment of members of the Sovereign Household, the diplomatic and consular corps, the Minister of State, the Government Councillors and assimilated civil servants, the magistrates in the judiciary

The issue of exequatur to consuls

The dissolution of the National Council

The granting of honour titles

### Article 47
Ministerial decrees are debated during the Government Council and signed by the Minister of State; they mention the relevant proceedings. They are notified to the Prince within twenty-four hours after signature and become enforceable only in the absence of the Princes formal opposition within ten days after the Minister of State’s notification.

However, the Prince may let the Minister of State know He does not intend on exercising His right of opposition for some decrees or types of decrees. These are thereby enforceable as soon as they are signed by the Minister of State.

### Article 48
Unless law provides otherwise, distribution of subject matters between sovereign ordinances and ministerial decrees is determined by sovereign ordinance.

### Article 49
Government Councils proceedings are subject to minutes put on record in a special register and signed, after the vote, by the present members.

The minutes mention each members vote. Within five days after the meeting, they are notified to the Prince who can lodge an opposition under the conditions provided by the above ### Articleicle 47.

### Article 50
The Minister of State and Government Councillors are accountable to the Prince for the Principality’s administration.

### Article 51
Civil servants’ obligations, rights and fundamental guarantees, as well as their civil liability and criminal responsibility are laid down by law.

CHAPTER VI. THE STATE COUNCIL
### Article 52
The State Council is in charge of advising on draft legislation and ordinances, which the Prince submitted for their perusal.

It can also be consulted on any other draft instrument.

Its organisation and operations are prescribed by sovereign ordinance.

## THE NATIONAL COUNCIL
### Article 53
The National Council comprises twenty-four members, elected for five years by direct universal suffrage and by the list system under the conditions prescribed by law.

In accordance with the conditions determined by law, electors are Monegasque citizens of either gender, at least eighteen years old, with the exception of those deprived of the right to vote for any of the causes set forth by law.

### Article 54
All Monegasque electors of either gender, aged at least twenty-five, who have held the Monegasque nationality for at least five years, and who are not deprived of the right to stand for election for any of the causes set forth by law, are eligible.

Law determines which offices are incompatible with the National Councillor’s mandate.

### Article 55
Courts of justice are entrusted with the control of the elections’ legitimacy, under the conditions prescribed by law.

### Article 56
The National Council’s members are not liable to any civil or criminal responsibility on the grounds of opinion or votes they express during the exercise of their mandates.

Without the National Council’s authorisation, they may neither be prosecuted nor arrested during a session due to a criminal or police infringement, save in the case of flagrant offence.

### Article 57
The newly elected National Council meets on the eleventh day after elections in order to elect its board. The oldest National Council to chairs this session.

Without prejudice to [Article 74], the prior National Council’s powers expire on the day of the new National Council’s meeting.

### Article 58
The National Council meets ipso jure in two annual ordinary sessions.

The first session opens on the first working day of April.

The second session opens on the first working day of October.

Each session may not last longer than three months. The session’s closure is declared by the President.

### Article 59
The National Council meets in extraordinary session, convened either by the Prince or on the request of at least two thirds of the members, by the President.

### Article 60
The National Council's board comprises a president and a vice-president, who are elected each year by the assembly from among its members.

A mayor’s office is incompatible with that of the National Council's President and vice-president.

### Article 61
Without prejudice to the provisions of the Constitution and if need be the law, the organisation and operations of the National Council are determined by the rule of procedure which the National Council issued.

Before being enforced these rules of procedure must be submitted to the Supreme Court, which decides on its compliance with the Constitution and if need be, with law.

### Article 62
The national Council sets its agenda. It is notified to the Minister of State at least three days beforehand. On the request of the Government, at least one of the two sessions must be devoted to debating the bills introduced by the Prince.

However the agenda of extraordinary sessions convened by the Prince is set in the convocation.

### Article 63
The National Council’s meetings are public.

However the National Council may decide with a majority of two thirds of the attending members, to sit in private session.

The minutes of the public meetings are published in “Le Journal de Monaco”.

### Article 64
The Prince communicates with the National Council through messages read by the Minister of State.

### Article 65
The Minister of State and Government Councillors have reserved entrances and seats at the National Council’s meetings.

They must have the floor when they request so.

### Article 66
The instigation of law implies the agreement of wills of both the Prince and the National Council.

The Prince alone may initiate law.

Deliberating and voting on bills are the National Council's responsibility.

It falls to the Prince to sanction laws, which confers them a binding power through promulgation.

### Article 67
The Prince signs bills. These bills are introduced to Him via the Government Council and with the Minister of State's signature. After the Prince’s endorsement, the Minister of State introduces them to the National Council.

The National Council can formulate bill proposals. Within a period of six months st### Articleing from the date the Minister of State received the draft legislation, he notifies the following to the National Council:

Either his decision to turn the proposal into a bill, amended as the case may be, which shall follow the procedure provided for in paragraph 1. In this case, the bill is introduced within a period of one year st### Articleing from the expiration of the six months period mentioned above
Or his decision to interrupt the legislative procedure. This decision is explained with a declaration placed on the agenda of an ordinary session public meeting anticipated within the period. This declaration can be followed by a debate
After expiration of the six months period mentioned above, if the Government has not notified the outcome intended for this bill proposal, the latter according to the procedure prescribed for in paragraph 1. becomes ipso jure a bill.

The same procedure is applicable if the Government did not introduce the bill within the one year period provided for in paragraph 2 a).

The National Council has the right of amendment. As such, it can propose inclusions, substitutions or withdrawals in the bill. Amendments alone that have a direct link with the bill provisions relevant to the bill are admitted. The vote takes place on the amended bill, as the case may be unless the Government withdraws the bill before the final vote.

However, the provisions of the precedent paragraph are not applicable for ratification bills or budget bills.

At the beginning of each ordinary session, in public meeting, the National Council announces the update of all bills introduced by the Government whenever they were introduced.

### Article 68
The Prince issues, when necessary, ordinances to ensure the enforcement of laws and the implementation of international treaties or conventions.

### Article 69
Laws and sovereign ordinances are enforceable against third p### Articleies only from the day after their publication in the "Journal of Monaco”.

### Article 70
The National Council votes on the budget.

No direct or indirect taxation may be introduced but through a law.

Any treaty or international agreement entailing such taxation may only be ratified by a law.

### Article 71
Budget bills are introduced to the National Council before September 30th.

Budget bills are voted upon during the National Council October session.

### Article 72
Budget is voted upon chapter by chapter. Transfers from one chapter to another are forbidden unless authorised by law.

The Budget comprises among others, within expenditure items, sums made available to the Communal Council for the budgetary year to come, as provided for in ### Articleicle 87.

### Article 73
In case the appropriation of funds requested by the Government as provided for in ### Articleicle 71 has not taken place before December 31st, funds relevant to services voted upon may be opened by sovereign ordinance with the National Council’s agreement.

The same prevails for income and expenses resulting from international treaties.

### Article 74
The Prince may, after having taken the advice of the Crown Council pronounce the dissolution of the National Council. If this occurs, new elections take place within a period of three months.

## THE CROWN COUNCIL
### Article 75
The Crown Council consists of seven members of Monegasque nationality, appointed by the Prince for a period of three years.

The President and three other members are directly appointed by the Prince.

Three members are appointed at the suggestion of the National Council, chosen from outside its members.

The offices of Minister of State and Government Councillor are incompatible with those of President or member of the Crown Council.

### Article 76
The Crown Council meets at least twice a year further to the Prince's summons. In addition, the Prince may call a meeting anytime He deems it necessary, either on his own initiative or further to the suggestion of the Crown Council's President.

### Article 77
The Crown Council may be consulted by the Prince on issues regarding the States higher interests. It may offer suggestions to the Prince.

It must be consulted on the following subjects: international treaties, dissolution of the National Council requests or naturalisation and restoration of the Monegasque nationality, pardons and amnesties.

## THE COMMUNE
### Article 78
The territory of the Principality forms a single commune.

### Article 79
The Commune is administered by a municipality composed of the mayor and deputies designated by the Communal Council from amongst its members.

In accordance with the conditions determined by law, elections are Monegasque citizens of either gender, at least eighteen years of age, with the exception of those deprived of the right to vote for any of the causes set forth by law.

All Monegasque electors of either gender, at least twenty-one years of age, who have held the Monegasque nationality for at least five years and who are not deprived of the right to stand for election for any of the causes set forth by law are eligible.

### Article 80
The Communal Council is composed of 15 members elected for a term of four years by universal direct suffrage by the list system.

There is no incompatibility between the Communal Councillor's mandate and that of National Councillor.

### Article 81
The Communal Council meets every three months in ordinary session. Each Session may not last longer than fifteen days.

### Article 82
Extraordinary sessions may be held, on the request or with the authorisation of the Minister of State, for specific purposes.

### Article 83
The Communal Council may be dissolved by a well-founded ministerial decree after the State Council’s opinion is sought.

### Article 84
In case of dissolution or resignation of all the members of the Communal Council, a special delegation is appointed by ministerial decree to carry out its duties until a new Council is elected. This election shall take place within three months.

### Article 85
The Communal Council is chaired by the mayor or, in his/her absence, by the deputy or the councillor who replaces him/her; following the order of the ch### Article.

### Article 86
The Communal Council debates in public meeting on the Commune’s affairs. Its proceedings are enforceable fifteen days after notification to the Minister of State, unless a well-founded opposition under the form of a ministerial decree is initiated.

### Article 87
The communal budget is supplied with revenue produced from communal property the communes ordinary resources and appropriations prescribed by the initial budget law of the year.

## THE JUSTICE
### Article 88
Judicial power vests in the Prince, who, by the present Constitution, delegates its full exercise to the courts and tribunals.

Tribunals render justice in the name of the Prince.

The independence of judges is guaranteed.

The organisation, jurisdiction and operations of the tribunals, as well as judges’ status, are laid down by law.

### Article 89
Supreme Court is composed of five full members and two substitute members.

The Supreme Courts members are appointed by the Prince, as follows:

One full member and one substitute member are introduced by the National Council from outside its members
One full member and one substitute member are introduced by the State Council from outside its members

One full member is introduced by the Crown Council from outside its members

One full member is introduced by the Court of Appeal from outside its members

One full member is introduced by the Civil Court of First Instance from outside its members.

These introductions are done by each of the bodies here above mentioned at the rate of two per seat.

If the Prince does not agree with these introductions, He is free to require new ones.

The President of the Supreme Court is appointed by the Prince.

### Article 90
In constitutional matters, the Supreme Court rules in sovereign fashion over:
Compliance of the National Councils rules of procedure with constitutional and, if need be, legislative provisions under the conditions prescribed by ### Articleicle 61
Appeals on petitions for annulment, petitions to review validity and actions for damages arising from violations of these rights and freedoms prescribed in chapter III of the Constitution, and which are not referred to in subsection B of the present ### Articleicle
In administrative matters, the Supreme Court rules in sovereign fashion over:
Proceedings for annulment of ultra vires decisions taken by various administrative authorities or Sovereign Ordinances to enforce laws, and the award of related damages
Appeals by way of quashing decisions of last resort taken by administrative jurisdictions
Appeals for interpretation and petitions to review the validity of decisions of various administrative authorities or Sovereign Ordinances to enforce laws
The Supreme Court rules over conflicts of jurisdiction.
### Article 91
The Supreme Court deliberates either in plenary session composed of five members or in administrative section composed of three members.

It sits and deliberates in plenary session:

In constitutional matters
As judge of conflicts of jurisdiction
In administrative matters on references ordered by the President of the Supreme Court or decided by the administrative section
It sits and deliberates in administrative section in all other cases.

### Article 92
A sovereign order regulates the organisation and operations of the Supreme Court, especially relevant to the required qualifications of its members, incompatibilities regarding them as well as their status, the turnover of the administrative section’s members, the procedure to follow before the Court, effects of petitions and awards, procedure and effects of conflicts of jurisdiction, as well as necessary transitional measures.

## THE REVISION OF THE CONSTITUTION
### Article 93
The Constitution may not be suspended.

### Article 94
Any revision, in full or in part, requires a referendum of Constituents, and the agreement of the Commonwealth Council.

### Article 95
In case of initiative on the part of the Commonwealth Council, proceedings maybe taken only by a two thirds majority vote of the normal number of members elected at the assembIy.

CHAPTER XII. FINAL PROVISIONS
### Article 96
Prior constitutional provisions are repealed.

The present Constitution immediately enters into force.

The renewal of the National Council and Communal Council shall take place within three months.

### Article 97
Laws and regulations currently into force remain applicable to the extent that they are not incompatible with the present Constitution. If need be, they must be amended in order to comply, as soon as possible, with the latter.
-->
<style>
.page ol {
  counter-reset: item;
  line-height: 2rem;
  font-size: 14px;
}
  ol li {
    display: block;
    position: relative;
}
.page li:before {
    content: counters(item, ".")" ";
    counter-increment: item;
    position: absolute;
    margin-right: 100%;
    right: 10px; /* space between number and text */
    font-weight: bold;
  }
</style><div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Veletian, or Commonwealth Script, is a simplified form of Oslolan written language.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Death Penalty in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/law/deathpenalty/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/law/deathpenalty/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the law series of articles Capital Punishment is legal in Vekllei as a sentence applied to crimes against peace, humanity and crimes of war.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/law/">law</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Capital Punishment</strong> is legal in Vekllei as a sentence applied to crimes against peace, humanity and crimes of war.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
