<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Law</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/law/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Law </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Basic Laws</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/law/basic-laws/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/law/basic-laws/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the law series of articles The Basic Laws of the Vekllei are a quasi-constitutional laws that inform in detail aspects of Vekllei government and state not provided in the Constitution. They are superior to other types of legislation in the country, and can only be overturned by a supermajority vote in the Senate, a majority referendum of the Commonwealth and approval of the Cabinet.
Law Purpose Commonwealth of Oceans Describes structure and functions of Commonwealth government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/law/">law</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Basic Laws of the <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> are a quasi-constitutional laws that inform in detail aspects of Vekllei government and state not provided in the <a href="/constitution/">Constitution</a>. They are superior to other types of legislation in the country, and can only be overturned by a supermajority vote in the Senate, a majority referendum of the Commonwealth and approval of the <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Law</th>
<th>Purpose</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Commonwealth of Oceans</td>
<td>Describes structure and functions of Commonwealth government.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Assemblies of Oceans</td>
<td>Describes the entitlements, structure and legislative powers of Constituent republics.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Commons</td>
<td>Describes and protects the moneyless market system of the domestic markets.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The State Economy</td>
<td>Describes the financialised commons, and the role of the state in finance and industry.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Industry and Living</td>
<td>Describes the role of bureaus in the Commonwealth Economy.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Military</td>
<td>Describes the role and laws applying to a unified Commonwealth military command.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The State Secretary</td>
<td>Describes the structure and functions of the Commonwealth and Constituent governments.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Human Rights</td>
<td>Enshrines rights and freedoms of Commonwealth citizens.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Land and Stewardship</td>
<td>Enshrines property rights and opportunity of work for Commonwealth citizens.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Councils and Democracy</td>
<td>Enshrines the right to municipal representation, democracy and labour organising.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Century Society</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/law/century-society/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/law/century-society/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the law series of articles The &ldquo;Century Society&rdquo; Laws were a collection of laws designed to foster educated immigration in postwar Vekllei. In total, they promised citizenship to any person with a tertiary qualification fleeing a persecuting regime, or citizenship to any person with valuable expertise to contribute1 towards the country. Provided the immigrant could &ldquo;build their own home,&rdquo;2 they would be incentivised with permanent citizenship for their immediate family and opportunities to participate in the postwar government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/law/">law</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The &ldquo;Century Society&rdquo; Laws were a collection of laws designed to foster educated immigration in postwar <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. In total, they promised citizenship to any person with a tertiary qualification fleeing a persecuting regime, or citizenship to any person with valuable expertise to contribute<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> towards the country. Provided the immigrant could &ldquo;build their own home,&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> they would be incentivised with permanent citizenship for their immediate family and opportunities to participate in the postwar government.</p>
<p>Many &ldquo;Century Citizens,&rdquo; as immigrants under this law became known, were politically motivated to participate in the anarchist aspects of Vekllei society or otherwise seeking a better life in an emerging country. Consequently, the Century Society programme has also been called the &ldquo;Aliyah for anarchists.&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
<p>The Century Society Laws were made more restrictive in 2038, and then again in 2045. They are still part of Vekllei legislation today, but are much more closely controlled to ease migrant pressures on dense Commonwealth cities.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The desirable skills included experience in construction, medicine, trade or clerical work.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>&ldquo;Build your own home&rdquo; was a shorthand for contributing to the war-ravaged and emerging Vekllei Commonwealth. In some cases, it meant joining a Municipal Action Group and literally assisting construction of your own neighbourhood with the help of your neighbours.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>This phrase is a reference to the Jewish Aliyah to Israel in the 20th Century after the conclusion of the Second World War.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Death Penalty in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/law/deathpenalty/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/law/deathpenalty/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the law series of articles Capital Punishment is legal in Vekllei as a sentence applied to crimes against peace, humanity and crimes of war.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/law/">law</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Capital Punishment</strong> is legal in Vekllei as a sentence applied to crimes against peace, humanity and crimes of war.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
