<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Countries</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries.html</link>
	<description>Recent content in Countries </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Ceylon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/ceylon.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/ceylon.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Socialist Republic of Ceylon (also Śrī Laṅkā in Sinhala and Ilaṅkai in Tamil) is an island country in the Indian Ocean, off the coast of India. It is a part of the non-aligned movement and the Community of Oceans.
Ceylon is home to 19.5 million people, and is a rapidly developing country with an expanding diplomatic presence throughout South East Asia and East Africa.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Socialist Republic of Ceylon</strong> (also <em>Śrī Laṅkā</em> in Sinhala and <em>Ilaṅkai</em> in Tamil) is an island country in the Indian Ocean, off the coast of India. It is a part of the non-aligned movement and the <a style="color: rgb(52, 95, 223)" href="/oceans-community/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Community of Oceans</a>.</p>
<p>Ceylon is home to 19.5 million people, and is a rapidly developing country with an expanding diplomatic presence throughout South East Asia and East Africa. It also has close ties to the United Kingdom, its former coloniser, and <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka is an industrial hub and famous for its garment and textiles manufacturing, tea, precious stones and shipbuilding.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Denmark</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/denmark.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/denmark.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Kingdom of Denmark is a country in Western Europe, consisting of the Jutland peninsula extending north of central West Germany and an archipelago of over 400 islands west of it. The majority of its land and people are in Jutland, though its capital, Copenhagen, is located on the westward island of Zealand.
Despite its small population and size, Denmark has contributed extensively to European and world history, and through its extensive network of trade, has contributed to world culture as well.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong><span class="fi fi-dk"></span> Kingdom of Denmark</strong> is a country in Western Europe, consisting of the Jutland peninsula extending north of central West Germany and an archipelago of over 400 islands west of it. The majority of its land and people are in Jutland, though its capital, Copenhagen, is located on the westward island of Zealand.</p>
<p>Despite its small population and size, Denmark has contributed extensively to European and world history, and through its extensive network of trade, has contributed to world culture as well. The historic Kingdom of Denmark has included territories that are now part of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, including the <a style="color: rgb(67, 101, 187)" href="/aismious/"><span class="fi fi-fo"></span> Aismious</a> (Faroese) islands and parts of western <a style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190)" href="/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>.</p>
<p>Denmark is an advanced country with a high standard of living and a robust welfare state. Its economy is dominanted by small service and manufacturing businesses, and government revenues are sourced primarily from taxes.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>East India</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/east-india.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/east-india.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The East Indian Socialist Republic (also East India) is an island country in the easternmost edge of the Bay of Bengal. Comprising more than 300 islands, East India constitutes the boundary between the Bay of Bengal to the west and the Andaman Sea to the East. Port Blair on South Andaman Island is its largest city and capital. Its many tropical islands are home to 540,000 people.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong><span class="fi fi-ei"></span> East Indian Socialist Republic</strong> (also <em>East India</em>) is an island country in the easternmost edge of the Bay of Bengal. Comprising more than 300 islands, East India constitutes the boundary between the Bay of Bengal to the west and the Andaman Sea to the East. Port Blair on South Andaman Island is its largest city and capital. Its many tropical islands are home to 540,000 people.</p>
<p>Although East India consists of hundreds islands and islets, only about three dozen have human settlements. The archipelago has a hot, wet tropical climate moderated by sea breezes. The majority of its islands are covered by thick tropical forest, which receive heavy rains in the monsoon season between May and September. The islands are home to a few native mammals, including pigs and deer, but are most known for the dense and largely undocumented indigenous flora. Its seas are plentiful with fish, turtles, sea snakes, and crocodiles.</p>
<p>East India consists of two island groups: the Andamans, in its North, which number more than 300 islands and are home to the majority of its population, and the Nicobars, in its South, which number 19 islands. They are separated by the Ten Degree Channel.</p>
<p>The Andamans are rough and hilly, with little flat land except in a few valleys. The Nicobars contain most of the republic&rsquo;s fresh water, and are more diverse in terrain.</p>
<p>As a historical trade link between the Indian subcontinent and South East Asia, East India was visited by many historic travellers between East and West, including 9th Century Arab traders and Marco Polo. It was claimed in the 18th Century by <a style="color: rgb(200, 16, 47)" href="/denmark/"><span class="fi fi-dk"></span></span> Denmark</a>, which later sold its claim to the <a style="color: rgb(200, 16, 47)" href="/uk/"><span class="fi fi-gb"></span></span> United Kingdom</a> after the UK had established successful colonies at Port Blair and and Rangat.</p>
<p>After the independence of the <a style="color: rgb(255, 153, 51)" href="/india/"><span class="fi fi-in"></span> India</a> and the exit of the UK from South Asia, the Andaman and Nicobar islands were incorporated as a union territory of India. Unrest over the government response to the July 1955 Tsunamis compounded growing nationalist sentiment, and a referendum was forced in 1966, which resulted in independence under a coalition lead by the Nicobarese Socialist Party.</p>
<p>Although a developing country, East India has much improved healthcare and education across its most populated islands. Long-held hostilities with the Indian mainland have fostered an independent Andamanese and Nicobarese identity, and they trade extensively with other island states in the Indian Ocean, including the <a style="color: rgb(210, 15, 52)" href="/maldives/"><span class="fi fi-mv"></span></span> Maldives</a>. It also maintains close political, military and economic ties with <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and is a member of the <a style="color: rgb(52, 95, 223)" href="/oceans-community/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Community of Oceans</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Haiti</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/haiti.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/haiti.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Black Republic of Haiti is a country in the Caribbean, occupying the eastern third of the island of Hispaniola. It was founded by black slaves who rebelled and won freedom from France in 1804, and most of its population today is descended from those rebels. Since independence, Haiti has been beset by political and economic problems and natural disasters that have severely impeded its development.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong><span class="fi fi-ht"></span> Black Republic of Haiti</strong> is a country in the Caribbean, occupying the eastern third of the island of Hispaniola. It was founded by black slaves who rebelled and won freedom from France in 1804, and most of its population today is descended from those rebels. Since independence, Haiti has been beset by political and economic problems and natural disasters that have severely impeded its development.</p>
<p>In 2045, a series of coups and widespread political unrest collapsed the Third Haitian Republic and Haiti fell into anarchy. In order to restore society and prevent widespread famine, the <a style="color: rgb(52, 95, 223)" href="/oceans-community/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Community of Oceans</a> staged an intervention to deliver aid and depose the criminal Destine regime. After the war, with aid and security from CO members, the Fourth Haitian Republic elected a black-liberationist communalist republic influenced by <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and operates a mixed socialist economy styled after the <a style="color: rgb(2, 123, 57)" href="/seychelles/"><span class="fi fi-sc"></span></span> Seychelles</a>.</p>
<p>As a member of the <a style="color: rgb(52, 95, 223)" href="/oceans-community/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Community of Oceans</a>, Haiti has seen rapid development in the last twenty years and its education and health systems have improved significantly. In addition to the CO members, Haiti maintains close ties with socialist republics in Africa, particularly the Guinea Socialist Republic and the <a style="color: rgb(40, 151, 40)" href="/latin-africa/"><span class="fi fi-laur"></span> Latin Africa</a>.</p>
<p>Outside of its close political allies, Haiti is functionally a closed economy and trades mostly subsistence crops. It remains a net importer of most manufactured goods.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>India</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/india.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/india.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Republic of India is a country in South East Asia.
This article is under construction, please check back soon.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Republic of India</strong> is a country in South East Asia.</p>
<p>This article is under construction, please check back soon.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Latin Africa</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/latin-africa.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/latin-africa.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Latin Africa United Republics (also Latin Africa) is a federal country located on the west coast of Africa, astride the Equator in its south and stretching up into central Africa. It consists of most of the former French colonies north of the former Belgian Congo (now Zaire), and comprises 28 states representing different cultural and language groups.
Latin Africa is a major power in subsaharan Africa and enjoys vast natural resources and relative stability within its borders.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong><span class="fi fi-laur"></span> Latin Africa United Republics</strong> (also <em>Latin Africa</em>) is a federal country located on the west coast of Africa, astride the Equator in its south and stretching up into central Africa. It consists of most of the former French colonies north of the former Belgian Congo (now Zaire), and comprises 28 states representing different cultural and language groups.</p>
<p>Latin Africa is a major power in subsaharan Africa and enjoys vast natural resources and relative stability within its borders. It maintains close relations with France, its former coloniser, but also often represents pan-African interests internationally as part of the non-aligned movement. It is a major supplier of arms and training to groups resisting white rule in Rhodesia and South Africa.</p>
<p>Its 28 states are represented in a communal assembly called the <em>High Council</em> where informal decision-making precedes legislation in their parliament. The country is highly decentralised politically, and states enjoy considerable autonomy, with the federal government primarily providing security and common infrastructure.</p>
<p>Primary industries include cash crops like coffee and sugar, but also raw commodities like oil and bauxite. The stability and prosperity of its society has encouraged many multi-national corporations to establish themselves in the capital, Yaounde, further entrenching Latin Africa as a gateway to the rest of the world for its neighbours.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Maldives</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/maldives.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/maldives.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Republic of the Maldives is a country in the north Indian Ocean, south of the Indian subcontinent. It is a scattered island chain consisting of clusters of small islands and atolls extending nearly 800km from north to south.
The Maldives are coral atolls, and as such are flat and low-lying, rarely rising more than a couple metres above sea level. Maldivians speak an indigenous language (Dhivehi) constitute a unique ethnic group from centuries of migration, including Tamils and Sinhala from India and Ceylon as well as from Arab countries and East Asia.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong><span class="fi fi-mv"></span> Republic of the Maldives</strong> is a country in the north Indian Ocean, south of the Indian subcontinent. It is a scattered island chain consisting of clusters of small islands and atolls extending nearly 800km from north to south.</p>
<p>The Maldives are coral atolls, and as such are flat and low-lying, rarely rising more than a couple metres above sea level. Maldivians speak an indigenous language (Dhivehi) constitute a unique ethnic group from centuries of migration, including Tamils and Sinhala from India and <a style="color: rgb(255, 92, 0)" href="/ceylon/"><span class="fi fi-lk"></span></span> Ceylon</a> as well as from Arab countries and East Asia.</p>
<p>The Maldives are a multi-party socialist democracy, and the state religion is Islam. Major industries include textiles and crafts, but most exports are fishing and tropical agriculture. Next to seafood, tourism and the service industry are major drivers of economic growth, and the Maldives have signed trade agreements with China, Saudi Arabia and its regional island neighbours. It is also a recent member of the  <a style="color: rgb(52, 95, 223)" href="/oceans-community/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Community of Oceans</a>. Relations with India remain tense over fishing rights.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mauritius</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/mauritius.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/mauritius.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Republic of Mauritius is a country in the south Indian Ocean, west of Madagascar. It consists of scattered volcanic islands fringed by coral reefs, which are rich with arable soil used mostly to grow sugar cane, its largest export. Mauritius&rsquo;s capital, Port Louis, is modern and well connected by good roads and its busy port.
Mauritius has a comfortable subtropical climate, with a cool and a hot season.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong><span class="fi fi-mu"></span> Republic of Mauritius</strong> is a country in the south Indian Ocean, west of Madagascar. It consists of scattered volcanic islands fringed by coral reefs, which are rich with arable soil used mostly to grow sugar cane, its largest export. Mauritius&rsquo;s capital, Port Louis, is modern and well connected by good roads and its busy port.</p>
<p>Mauritius has a comfortable subtropical climate, with a cool and a hot season. Its people are mostly descended from indentured labourers from India and Pakistan who were compelled their during French rule. English is the official language, but Creole is most commonly spoken.</p>
<p>Mauritius is a developed society with an advanced economy, known for its frequent festivals among its diverse population. It has close economic ties with nearby <a style="color: rgb(2, 123, 57)" href="/seychelles/"><span class="fi fi-sc"></span></span> Seychelles</a> and close political ties with <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and is a member of the <a style="color: rgb(52, 95, 223)" href="/oceans-community/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Community of Oceans</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Portugal</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/portugal.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/portugal.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Second Portuguese Republic (commonly Portugal) was a Portuguese state that existed between 1926 and 2014. It succeeded the democratic First Republic and Portuguese Empire, and was ruled by the Estado Novo regime.
Portugal was incorporated into Iberia following the Spanish invasion of Portugal at the turn of the 21st Century. Portugal&rsquo;s defeat and subsequent annexation ended its independence and brought an end to the Portuguese Colonial War, which in turn decolonised most of its former empire.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Second Portuguese Republic</strong> (commonly <em>Portugal</em>) was a Portuguese state that existed between 1926 and 2014. It succeeded the democratic First Republic and Portuguese Empire, and was ruled by the <em>Estado Novo</em> regime.</p>
<p>Portugal was incorporated into Iberia following the Spanish invasion of Portugal at the turn of the 21st Century. Portugal&rsquo;s defeat and subsequent annexation ended its independence and brought an end to the Portuguese Colonial War, which in turn decolonised most of its former empire.</p>
<p>In the late 20th Century, lusotropicalist foreign policy heightened tensions with the Republican government in Spain. These compounded historical grievances, including the Estado Novo regime&rsquo;s support of the francoist coalition during the Spanish Civil War, and the deportation of Spanish students in 1975.</p>
<p>Two different massacres in Portuguese colonies, the maintenance of which was strongly opposed by Madrid, led to sanctions on Portugal and military aid to anti-colonial rebels in its colonies. The war, which started in 2013, was provoked by the assassination of Spanish president Javier Marx, for which Portgual denied responsibility. The decision to annex European Portugal rather than depose the Estado Novo regime prompted strong criticism from the <a style="color: rgb(76, 146, 219)" href="/un/"><span class="fi fi-un"></span> United Nations</a> and NATO.</p>
<p>Several former Portuguese territories are part of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> today. These include:</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li><a href="/mira/"><span class="fi fi-mira"></span> Mira</a></li>
<li>Azores</li>
<li><a href="/verde/"><span class="fi fi-verde"></span> Verde</a></li>
<li>Principe</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Seychelles</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/seychelles.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/seychelles.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The Republic of Seychelles is a country in the west Indian Ocean, east of Madagascar and Kenya, comprising about 115 islands. The country consists of two main island groups, characterised by lush tropical vegetation and pristine white beaches. Its people are mostly descendants of French colonists and black slaves, and centuries of intermarriage means most are of mixed descent. There are also significant minority populations of Chinese, Indians and Malays.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong><span class="fi fi-sc"></span> Republic of Seychelles</strong> is a country in the west Indian Ocean, east of Madagascar and Kenya, comprising about 115 islands. The country consists of two main island groups, characterised by lush tropical vegetation and pristine white beaches. Its people are mostly descendants of French colonists and black slaves, and centuries of intermarriage means most are of mixed descent. There are also significant minority populations of Chinese, Indians and Malays.</p>
<p>Although Seychelles is a one-party socialist state, lead by the Seychelles People&rsquo;s United Party, it maintains a non-aligned foreign policy and receives tourists from all over the world. It has close political and economic links with <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, as well other Indian Ocean states including the <a style="color: rgb(210, 15, 52)" href="/maldives/"><span class="fi fi-mv"></span></span> Maldives</a> and <a style="color: rgb(233, 128, 5)" href="/east-india/"><span class="fi fi-ei"></span></span> East India</a>. It is a member of the  <a style="color: rgb(52, 95, 223)" href="/oceans-community/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Community of Oceans</a>.</p>
<p>Seychellois people enjoy a high standard of living, with publicly-funded healthcare and education, and easy employment in a rapidly growing economy. The Seychelles economy is dominated by tourism, service industries and light manufacturing, particularly of soft drinks and alcohol.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>United Kingdom</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/uk.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/uk.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The United Kingdom (UN) is an island country in the North Sea, off the coast of Europe.
This article is under construction, please check back soon.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>United Kingdom</strong> (UN) is an island country in the North Sea, off the coast of Europe.</p>
<p>This article is under construction, please check back soon.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>United Nations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/un.html</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/countries/un.html</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the world series of articles The United Nations (UN) is an intergovernmental, international organisation established to protect peace and promote human development. By 2063, almost all countries on earth have membership or observational status. It is headquartered primarily in New York, but also has assemblies in Vekllei, Geneva, Johannesburg, Brasilia and Thailand.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/world/">world</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>United Nations</strong> (UN) is an intergovernmental, international organisation established to protect peace and promote human development. By 2063, almost all countries on earth have membership or observational status. It is headquartered primarily in New York, but also has assemblies in <a href="/vekllei"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, Geneva, Johannesburg, Brasilia and Thailand.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
