<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Interior Parliament on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Interior Parliament on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Commerce</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commerce/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commerce/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a ministry of the Vekllei Interior Parliament Overview # COSMOSOL The Vekllei Ministry of Commerce (COSMOSOL) regulates and initiates trade in the country. Despite the functional moneylessness of the Commonwealth, COSMOSOL remains among the busiest ministries of the Interior Government, since all economic policy, international trade and entitled renumeration (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for withdrawing from the Labour Bank) occurs through its subordinate commissions. Common responsibilities of COSMOSOL include:</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Defence</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/defence/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/defence/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a ministry of the Vekllei Interior Parliament Overview # COSMOKOS The Ministry of Defence (COSMOKOS) represents the Sovereign Armed Forces of the Vekllei Commonwealth in the Interior Government, which are consolidated under the Commonwealth Military Command. COSMOKOS does not exercise command authority over the armed forces of Vekllei, and serves instead as the ministerial liaison between the Commonwealth Military Command and the Interior Government. Common responsibilities of COSMOKOS include:</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Light &amp; Water</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/light-and-water/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/light-and-water/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a ministry of the Vekllei Interior Parliament Overview # COSMOLA The Ministry of Light &amp;amp; Water (COSMOLA) is responsible for the government monopoly on water and energy in Vekllei. Through its statutory corporations (SCs) and public utilities, the ministry is responsible for the vast majority of energy production in the Vekllei Islands and contributes significantly to energy research through its network of laboratories. Increasingly, COSMOLA investment has indicated an interest in energy and water conservation.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of the Commonwealth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commonwealth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commonwealth/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a ministry of the Vekllei Interior Parliament Overview # COSMOCOM The Ministry of the Commonwealth (COSMOCOM) is the organ through which the Interior Parliament communicates and cooperates with the Commonwealth Parliament and its secretariats. Its primary responsibility is cooperation between member states and standardisation, and publishes reports and manuals towards this goal. It is also the primary ministry through which the subordinates of the Commonwealth influence the Interior Parliament.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>