<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Lin Zhi</title>
	<link>/characters/zhi/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Lin Zhi </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/characters/zhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Bald</title>
	  <link>/stories/bald/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/bald/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Zhi&rsquo;s new look. One week in February Lin Zhi (the princeling communist Chinese girl) showed up to class with a shaved head, and no one said anything because they thought she&rsquo;d finally snapped/
Lin Zhi rocks but she&rsquo;s a bit nuts, and she hates living in Vekllei. It&rsquo;s not like where she came from and she hates being pressured by her parents and school to adapt.
Tzipora is her only real friend because Tzipora is invariably attracted to outcasts and freaks.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/fullres/bald.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Zhi&rsquo;s new look.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>One week in February Lin Zhi (the princeling communist Chinese girl) showed up to class with a shaved head, and no one said anything because they thought she&rsquo;d finally snapped/</p>
<p>Lin Zhi rocks but she&rsquo;s a bit nuts, and she hates living in Vekllei. It&rsquo;s not like where she came from and she hates being pressured by her parents and school to adapt.</p>
<p>Tzipora is her only real friend because Tzipora is invariably attracted to outcasts and freaks.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Drinks</title>
	  <link>/stories/work-drinks/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/work-drinks/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Going out for drinks after work. A bit of a time-skip from the usual chronology. Here, they&rsquo;re all 22 years old.
Lin Zhi is a junior photovolume engineer, and recovers holographic crystal memory used in Vekllei photo-electric computers.
Tzipora is a librarian at Seispri Municipal Library and is waiting for someone to compliment her new cardigan.
Cobian is a ward nurse at Seispri Hospital in the nuclear medicine wing.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/fullres/drinks.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Going out for drinks after work.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>A bit of a time-skip from the usual chronology. Here, they&rsquo;re all 22 years old.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi is a junior photovolume engineer, and recovers holographic crystal memory used in Vekllei photo-electric computers.</p>
<p>Tzipora is a librarian at Seispri Municipal Library and is waiting for someone to compliment her new cardigan.</p>
<p>Cobian is a ward nurse at Seispri Hospital in the nuclear medicine wing.</p>
<p>They&rsquo;re going to the pub. Coretti is in a war in the Congo. Moise is in Indonesia working for a company whose name nobody can remember.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Picture of Integration</title>
	  <link>/stories/integration/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/integration/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Sitting on the concrete sea wall in Lola. Tzipora was a picture of integration, because she wanted badly for people to respect her. She also felt she owed something to the country which had lifted her up and given her a quality of life. She had no prospects before coming to Oslola, so she practiced gratitude in everything she did &ndash; sometimes out loud.
Lin Zhi was not a picture of integration; Lin Zhi was a black box.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/fullres/zhi.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Sitting on the concrete sea wall in <a href="/lola/">Lola</a>.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora was a picture of integration, because she wanted badly for people to respect her. She also felt she owed something to the country which had lifted her up and given her a quality of life. She had no prospects before coming to <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, so she practiced gratitude in everything she did &ndash; sometimes out loud.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi was not a picture of integration; Lin Zhi was a black box. She barely spoke English &ndash; the common language of Vekllei&rsquo;s immigrant society and international schools. A lot of the English she did speak came in short, sharp barks. Her severe disposition was well known at <a href="/moshel/">Moshel St School</a>. They were paired together in gardening class, and Tzipora learned soon enough that Lin Zhi was not so much rude as she was quiet and isolated, and did not trust or like her peers.</p>
<p>Tzipora was terrible at making friends, but not because she was out of tune with people&rsquo;s feelings. She knew Zhi was a private person instinctively, and so she did not ask her questions or force conversation except to plant crops and water ferns. Zhi in turn became used to her and they developed silent routines in class.</p>
<p>When Tzipora broke her arm a few months later, Zhi asked how she broke it, without looking up from the soil.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I was playing tennis and fell on it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>And Lin Zhi laughed once.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Dunes</title>
	  <link>/stories/dune/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/dune/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora flying down a sand dune at 45km/h. Oslola has a number of highland dunes made of fine black sand, formed by its active volcanoes and shaped by glacial runoff.
A popular game when visiting is to race someone to the bottom. Because these dunes are very steep and very tall (up to 40 meters) it&rsquo;s easy to end up flying down face-first.
The dunes also have a very important role in Oslolan mythology, as the birthplace of subterranean mole creatures called Somoron.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/fullres/dune.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Tzipora flying down a sand dune at 45km/h.</span>
</blockquote>

<p><a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a> has a number of highland dunes made of fine black sand, formed by its active volcanoes and shaped by glacial runoff.</p>
<p>A popular game when visiting is to race someone to the bottom. Because these dunes are very steep and very tall (up to 40 meters) it&rsquo;s easy to end up flying down face-first.</p>
<p>The dunes also have a very important role in Oslolan mythology, as the birthplace of subterranean mole creatures called Somoron.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Friends</title>
	  <link>/stories/friends-draft/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/friends-draft/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Paint-sketch of the girls together I never ended up finishing. Clockwise:
Cobian is an Algic girl, which means she&rsquo;s indigenous to Iceland in my world, which is called Oslola. She comes from a mixed indigenous Arctic background. Her mother is kind of crazy and Cobian is a bit insecure, but she&rsquo;s very close with Tzipora. They drift between friends and girlfriends, it&rsquo;s complicated.
Coretti is Afro-Russian. Even though she was born in Congo (sometimes called Zaire in my world) she grew up in the USSR and immigrated to Oslola later on.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/fullres/draft.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Paint-sketch of the girls together I never ended up finishing.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Clockwise:</p>
<p>Cobian is an Algic girl, which means she&rsquo;s indigenous to Iceland in my world, which is called <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>. She comes from a mixed indigenous Arctic background. Her mother is kind of crazy and Cobian is a bit insecure, but she&rsquo;s very close with Tzipora. They drift between friends and girlfriends, it&rsquo;s complicated.</p>
<p>Coretti is Afro-Russian. Even though she was born in Congo (sometimes called Zaire in my world) she grew up in the USSR and immigrated to Oslola later on. She&rsquo;s very patient and graceful, and is dating Tzipora&rsquo;s best friend Moise.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi is Chinese and always goes by her full name. She doesn&rsquo;t speak much of their language and she&rsquo;s kind of a hothead so she&rsquo;s a bit of a mystery to them. But Tzipora attracts eccentric characters and Lin Zhi doesn&rsquo;t have any other friends so she hangs out with them.</p>
<p>Finally, Tzipora (being held) is the main character of the story. Her mother was Spanish Roma and her father was Yiddish. She&rsquo;s very friendly but intense and she&rsquo;s sort of the focus point which the friendship group is centred around. She&rsquo;s got more going on with her (she doesn&rsquo;t live with her parents and how she came to Vekllei is ambiguous) but she&rsquo;s just trying her best.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sketch of Coretti Adoula</title>
	  <link>/stories/coretti/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/coretti/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Coretti Adoula, with her boyfriend Moise behind her. Pictured here is Coretti Adoula, Moise&rsquo;s sweet-natured girlfriend. Originally from the USSR, she moves to Vekllei and enters Tzipora&rsquo;s orbit of friends via Moise after they start dating.
She&rsquo;s eating Vekllei chips, which are seasoned above smoking meats and are usually eaten without sauce. Most supermarkets and many cafes offer them as snacks, as a tasty byproduct of meat preparation.
Here is her original sketch:]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/sketches/corettibg.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Coretti Adoula, with her boyfriend Moise behind her.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Pictured here is Coretti Adoula, Moise&rsquo;s sweet-natured girlfriend. Originally from the USSR, she moves to Vekllei and enters Tzipora&rsquo;s orbit of friends via Moise after they start dating.</p>
<p>She&rsquo;s eating Vekllei chips, which are seasoned above smoking meats and are usually eaten without sauce. Most supermarkets and many cafes offer them as snacks, as a tasty byproduct of meat preparation.</p>
<p>Here is her original sketch:</p>
<p><figure>
  <a href="/images/sketches/coretti.jpg"
     target="_blank"
     rel="noopener noreferrer">

    
    
    
    
    

      
      
      
      

      
      
      

      <img class="rcf-image lazyload show-if-js"
        data-srcset="/images/sketches/coretti_hu207d93032f4e9eaed7fc90d254a00387_353850_680x0_resize_q90_h2_box.webp 1x"
        src="/images/sketches/coretti.jpg"alt="sketch of coretti" 
        loading="lazy"
      />

      </a>


  
   
</figure></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tannin Rivers</title>
	  <link>/stories/tannin/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/tannin/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Broad mossy meadows slope away from Vekllei&rsquo;s &ldquo;ashen lands&rdquo; &ndash; vast, glacial moonscapes in the highland interior. The soils here are rich with nitrogen, and are dominated by an alpine heathland of button grass and tea shrubs. The oils from these plants seep downstream into the glacial runoff, and by the time the water meets the mosslands the creeks are stained tea-coloured, a mix of reds and yellows that catches gold in the light.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/tannin.jpg"/> <p>Broad mossy meadows slope away from Vekllei&rsquo;s &ldquo;ashen lands&rdquo; &ndash; vast, glacial moonscapes in the highland interior. The soils here are rich with nitrogen, and are dominated by an alpine heathland of <em>button grass</em> and <em>tea shrubs</em>. The oils from these plants seep downstream into the glacial runoff, and by the time the water meets the mosslands the creeks are stained tea-coloured, a mix of reds and yellows that catches gold in the light. These are Vekllei&rsquo;s tannin rivers; rusty freshwater streams that run red from the base of the Thanveler glacier to the outskirts of Antarta and Dasm.</p>
<p>The mosses here are thick and dewey, and Tzipora&rsquo;s house sandals did nothing to keep her out of them. With her feet soaked and her school bag on the station platform, she dared Cobian and Zhi to leap the tannin river. Local myth was that it was good luck, but she&rsquo;d have jumped it anyway.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m good at jumping,&rdquo; Tzipors said to her friends, wiping her cold nose on the back of her arm.</p>
<p>&ldquo;You&rsquo;re going to go in that bloody river and you&rsquo;ll be soaked for the train home,&rdquo; Cobian said.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Not if I make it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>She squelched a few steps backwards, squinting at the amber creek ahead.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Watch this.&rdquo;</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Café Diplomacy</title>
	  <link>/stories/vista/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/vista/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Instafilm #445. Marked &ldquo;2064&rdquo;. Month of the Mosses. You remembered that because it was about the same time war broke out in the Congo again. Everyone at the table had opinions about that war, but not much to do with it. Everyone asked Coretti what she thought about the war. She hated that, she hated being singled out for it. Coretti had been two years old when she left the Congo.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/vista.jpg"/> <p><strong>Instafilm #445</strong>. Marked &ldquo;2064&rdquo;. Month of the Mosses. You remembered that because it was about the same time war broke out in the Congo again. Everyone at the table had opinions about that war, but not much to do with it. Everyone asked Coretti what she thought about the war. She hated that, she hated being singled out for it. Coretti had been two years old when she left the Congo. But Vekllei people are far away from the world and curious and so they asked stupid questions sometimes.</p>
<p>Tzipora didn&rsquo;t like the news so she stopped reading it. Sometimes she got people asking her about America &ndash; what do you think about what they say&rsquo;s going on in Dallas? Is it real or is some of it made up to sell papers? Here&rsquo;s an idea &ndash; how about you shut your mouth and stop asking me so many fucking questions.</p>
<p>Left to right: Moise, Coretti, Lin Zhi, Cobian, Tzipora. 2064.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
	  <link>/stories/chapel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/chapel/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,
For the people hear us singing, &ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&rdquo;
As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &ndash;
For they are women&rsquo;s children and we mother them again.
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &ndash;]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/gov.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p>As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,<br>
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray<br>
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,<br>
For the people hear us singing, &ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &ndash;<br>
For they are women&rsquo;s children and we mother them again.<br>
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &ndash;<br>
Hearts starve as well as bodies: Give us Bread, but give us Roses.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Vekllei people have a right to organise in their work. This principle is expressed in the structure of the economy, in which cooperative enterprises form company ballots that go on to inform commercial and industrial practice. Collections of individual trade unions may form bureaus, massive monopolies of organised workplaces cooperating and competing under the bizarre structure of the Vekllei moneyless economy. These are expressions of a mobilised democratic workforce which sustain the country in their self-interest, and are a defining characteristic of the Floral Period.</p>
<p>Organisation also exists outside the workplace. Their negotiations occur with the municipal and state authorities, and are a common means by which groups of people express their grievances and strengthen each other. The most well-known of these are Vekllei’s Chapel system — the unionisation of local women.</p>
<p>Chapels are localised by community. Tzipora was at first very sceptical of the Chapels, which had offered her membership upon her arrival in Vekllei. You have to understand, Tzipora was in a crisis of inferiority at this time, and considered the ingratitude of the ungovernable female organisers to be naïve and entitled. She was convinced otherwise by Ayn, who was a moderate and carefully-spoken person.</p>
<p>“You want to integrate in Vekllei, don’t you?” She asked Tzipora. “This is what integration looks like; the Chapels are an expression of our democracy. A means of support and celebration; to have people know and care for you. There is no political commitment.”</p>
<p>Tzipora found Chapel meetings to be friendly and informal, characterised by shared meals and conversations of joys and grievances. Local Chapel № 23 was a social club of individuals made strong by their trust in each other. Tzipora sat silently at the end of the Chapel hall, an old concrete building with a flat roof built after the war. It had the appearance of a midcentury church. She ate her bread and sausage with her fingers and listened to the women talk amongst themselves. Children ran around, playing chasings. It was not like any place she’d been before.</p>
<p><em>Well-wishes to all this International Women’s Day</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Socialism, Backwards</title>
	  <link>/stories/socialism/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/socialism/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora had become interested in the blossoms of Vekllei society around the same time she became aware of them. That’s actually what they were called, in the pidgin of Vekllei ideology — the tenets of petticoat-style socialism were called blossoms.
Vekllei maintains it is not ideological; it is in fact very ideological — you are looking at a state that is afraid of its skeleton. In the dawning weeks after Vekllei’s catastrophic war, the British occupiers (British Recovery Expedition to Vekllei, or BREVEK) released into the streets some 16,000 activists who were rotting away in political prisons.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/socialism.jpg"/> <p>Tzipora had become interested in the blossoms of Vekllei society around the same time she became aware of them. That’s actually what they were called, in the pidgin of Vekllei ideology — the tenets of petticoat-style socialism were called blossoms.</p>
<p>Vekllei maintains it is not ideological; it is in fact very ideological — you are looking at a state that is afraid of its skeleton. In the dawning weeks after Vekllei’s catastrophic war, the British occupiers (<strong>British Recovery Expedition to Vekllei</strong>, or <strong>BREVEK</strong>) released into the streets some 16,000 activists who were rotting away in political prisons. The majority of these were communists or sympathisers, and found themselves vindicated in the ashes of prewar society. “Look at what we told you,” they wrote in the first issue of the Worker, “our country is in ashes.” It is no coincidence that the Vekllei Communist Party was founded on March 3rd, two days after the occupation of the country. They treated the British as liberators.</p>
<p>The release of political prisoners coincided with the legalisation of labour unions, which exploded in membership — some 4 million Vekllei, or 60% of the country, were union members by 2011. Most were not aware of what a union did or what purpose they served, but membership could prevent starvation and they were independent from the BREVEK occupying apparatuses.</p>
<p>This rise in unionism surprised and alarmed BREVEK commanders, who could see trouble brewing — the unions were a keg, and the communists were an open flame. Since union leadership was usually sympathetic towards the Marxists, and were effective at mobilising their members, it was not difficult to imagine the communists seizing their advantage once occupation ended and 200,000 British troops left Vekllei.</p>
<p>What resulted was the <strong>Vekllei Interim Prosperity Government</strong>, an early preparation for Vekllei independence orchestrated to temper communist support. The Interim Prosperity Government deliberately excluded existing political activists in its advisory board, but did not exclude radicals altogether — instead, communism was defanged through the invitation of “loveable radicals” in the arts, scientific, industrial and legal communities. These people were often sympathisers, but they were not equipped or networked to mobilise the labour unions, and so were seen as a favourable strategic concession by BREVEK. Another interesting fact is that over half of the Interim Government were women — simply because they were not well represented among Vekllei Communist Party leadership.</p>
<p>This is how, in an absurd way, Vekllei’s first independent government was made up mostly of communists but was not a communist government. And it was precisely this disruption of the Marxist revolutionary process that resulted in Vekllei’s unusual syndicalism, which on weekdays moves fluidly between state centralism and anarchy. It was precisely the sort of government vulnerable to displacement, if not for the threat of violence from 200,000 British occupiers. In fact, the Vekllei Communist Party was nearly driven underground by direct intervention by BREVEK command in 2014, after a general strike. The final blow to the Party came in 2015, with the outlawing of political parties in parliament and a transition to floral-style nonpartisan democracy.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi was a Chinese communist, and as of her sixteenth birthday, was now Vekllei, too. Her family, mostly princeling descendants of long-marchers, had been caught up in the purges and were now considered counterrevolutionary. There are many such communists in Vekllei. Moise’s girlfriend, Coretti, came from the socialist Congo and the USSR. Even Baron’s parents had been Labour Zionists. Vekllei was a very exciting place to be, full of memories and bitterness and optimism for an even-handed future, one in which unfavourable worker-peasant-soldiers, postcolonial refugees and dispirited Jews alike might dream of a truly multiracial socialist state.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Generation</title>
	  <link>/stories/new-generation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/new-generation/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Children of the children of the bomb — a generation of war-babies born in peacetime. That was how they thought of themselves. Their grandparents and great-grandparents had lived through the war and the occupation, and so they had inherited the burden of Vekllei&rsquo;s future as a country of long-sufferers, visionaries, and dispossessed.
Some Marxist continental intellectual had said something a half-century ago about the right way to teach children, and the idea had probably caught the ear of some commissar of the Vekllei interim government, who perhaps passed it along to some bureaucrat rebuilding the government schools.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/generation.jpg"/> <p><strong>Children of the children of the bomb —</strong> a generation of war-babies born in peacetime. That was how they thought of themselves. Their grandparents and great-grandparents had lived through the war and the occupation, and so they had inherited the burden of Vekllei&rsquo;s future as a country of long-sufferers, visionaries, and dispossessed.</p>
<p>Some Marxist continental intellectual had said something a half-century ago about the right way to teach children, and the idea had probably caught the ear of some commissar of the Vekllei interim government, who perhaps passed it along to some bureaucrat rebuilding the government schools. As a result, Vekllei children only go to school three or four days a week. There, they spend only a few hours a day in classrooms. There is, after all, no real workforce for which they are being primed. <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/#play">Vekllei&rsquo;s labour economy is a play-fantasy</a>, and so they mostly learn how to play.</p>
<p>It is not designed to &lsquo;free&rsquo; children — Vekllei schools have hierarchies, punishments and are mandatory &mdash; instead, the primary goal of education is self-discovery and self-respect. It is precisely these qualities that benefit most the modern Vekllei economy, which is heavily automated and competes internationally through the product of its participatory creative thinking.</p>
<p>There is no grading system in Vekllei — all classes are passed or failed. The value of compulsory education through government schools, then, is the socialisation of boys and girls with others boys and girls, and the availability of equipment and facilities to participate in extracurricular activities. This is the real body of Vekllei school life — its clubs, societies, and individual associations. Many professional photographers in this country discovered an affection for photography before they turned 15 years old, through exposure to it in school. These resources, and the need to socialise children with others, are the reasons the Vekllei government continues to universalise government schooling, even alongside home-schooling or independent/religious education.</p>
<p>Depicted here are the good-natured youth of the new generation in school uniform — <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/">a topic we&rsquo;ve visited before</a>. All students in Vekllei wear the same uniform, including at university. The uniforms themselves are not designed specifically to regulate appearance — and to this end, schools do not have dress codes regarding hair or cultural/religious accessories including jewellery.</p>
<p>Discard any assumptions about the meaning behind the colour or style of their clothes — all variations depicted here can be worn by whomever, no matter their age, school or association. In fact, school uniforms are not provided directly by schools — they are found at department stores, on the rack alongside suits and dresses. Because of this fact, specific styles of shirt, trousers, socks and shoes vary between students — and are acceptable as long as they meet the basic requirements of the uniform. This intersection of control and anarchy can be found widely throughout broader Vekllei society, and is an interesting example of how the basic principles of the &ldquo;Vekllei way of life&rdquo; are reflected in the microscopic mundanities of life and foundations of national culture simultaneously.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei&#39;s New-Age Women</title>
	  <link>/stories/women/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/women/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.
— Lu Xun, 1927
Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &lsquo;backward elements.&rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.
— Ding Ling on the long-marcher woman soldiers, 1942
When Tzipora first arrived in Vekllei in 2063, she was traumatised by the foreignness of everything.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/women.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p><em>A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>— <strong>Lu Xun</strong>, 1927</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &lsquo;backward elements.&rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>— <strong>Ding Ling</strong> on the long-marcher woman soldiers, 1942</p>
<p><strong>When Tzipora first arrived in Vekllei in 2063</strong>, she was traumatised by the foreignness of everything. It was not just that they drove on the wrong side of the road, or that the chocolate was made by someone else, but that her whole understanding of the world — the world she’d been raised in all her life — was unravelled within weeks. It did not matter if you learned the language, or dressed like them, or worked with them — the way a Vekllei person thinks seemed totally alien, as though they were tuned into a frequency that she couldn’t hear. That was very difficult for her.</p>
<p>Her clearest memory, out of all the emotional turmoil in her first few weeks, was the clothes. Tzipora was not fashionable or materialistic, but she’d never had nice things to wear. In Vekllei the things on the rack were simple, and often second-hand, but they were very well made and the department stores had a big variety. She picked out five shirts, nearly identical, and decided that these would be what she would wear from now on — it was her own way of establishing an identity; SHE IS THE GIRL WHO WEARS THIS TYPE OF SHIRT. Little things like that mattered a lot, because Tzipora was treated differently here. She was both ‘young’ and a ‘girl’, which had implications for how overseas people talked to her and how she was regarded. Here, almost no one seemed to notice. She had dignity by default, which was exciting and scary at the same time, so she needed something other than her appearance to claim as ‘hers’. And at that time, it was the shirt with the pleats.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Vekllei is a place that is very much radical</strong> but, either intentionally or as a byproduct of its opaque culture, suppresses the <em>appearance</em> of radicalism in its public affairs (or as they say there, ‘sun-facing space’). This is for a few reasons. First, Vekllei uses its obscurity as a weapon against its continental neighbours, who might pull it into geopolitical tensions it wants no part of. The second is that Vekllei’s failed revolutionary movements of the early 20th Century are buried with the Junta that suppressed them. The third, and most critically, is that Vekllei people themselves are unaware of just how saturated their lives are with the cultural and political ideology of the floral period, which makes “foreign” political thinking difficult and results in a lot of empty rhetoric — for example, “petticoat socialism” describes the Bureau System, which does not have much to do with either petticoats or continental socialism.</p>
<p>This paradigm makes more sense when you consider that there are really two Veklleis — the one that existed before the Atomic War, and the one that exists now, called the “Floral Period” or sometimes “Petticoat Society”. The one that existed before has little resemblance to the one that exists now, and that is the way people have continued to think in the decades of independence — anything prior to 2015 is, simply, history.</p>
<p>Make no mistake — Vekllei is tremendously radical in its culture and politics, which it tempers with conservative names and third-way politicking. Today’s post looks at how the Vekllei woman changed in the years between 2005 and 2020.</p>
<p>Not unlike revolutions of years past, postwar Vekllei had (for the moment, at least) lost many of its structural oppressors of women, since the structure itself had collapsed quickly. The interim government had taken an orthodox, though contrarian, communist position, which ushered a new handbook of rhetoric towards de-objectification of women and their pragmatic and social value in the workforce. The interim government had several key women figures among it, who are credited with its success in this critical, and rapidly changing period.</p>
<p>In the Vekllei socialist (<em>socialisme oa Vekllei</em>) line of thinking, there are two points of attack. There was the suppression of old models of feminine beauty, which argued against women’s independence and dignity in favour of their security with men, who made up Vekllei’s economic and social caste throughout the entirety of the Junta’s rule. But there was also a very real fear that women’s liberation by Western metrics would simply evolve indentured living into a more obtuse, and in some ways more sinister, commodity-woman (<em>cosmavisiousnesh</em>, lit. ‘plastic woman’<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>), who was free to educate herself but found her appearance subjected to permanent scrutiny — a product for a consumer, dependent on shifting fashions and complex social constellations still fundamentally controlled by men. This fear was not unfounded, as many educated women of the interim government (who made up nearly half of its members) had spent significant time in Western Europe and the United States, and were keenly aware of who was “gazing” (<em>lismious</em>) and who was being “gazed at” (<em>visimett</em>).</p>
<p>The solution developed by the interim government was both political and spiritual, designed to demolish the external remnants of Vekllei’s pre-war and highly stratified society, and the looming threats of foreign investment, new wealth, and an import of the modern commodity-woman. Most importantly, it understood that present notions of empowerment or disempowerment were problematic unto themselves — whether it was sexual liberation, modesty, or indeed the economic role of women in abstract — their ability to empower was still fundamentally chained to old society, which was still dominated by the sexist cultural default.</p>
<p>In 2016, Cisma de Diviousmesn, First Secretary of the War Recovery Committee, described the problem as such in The <em>Atlantic</em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We are nearing a precipice that all Vekllei women may fall into, should we follow unblinkingly the Visis Plan [postwar redevelopment plan], and allow foreign investment to replace English colonial governor-generals; we should be wise enough, so to speak, to not trade a king for a master and call it recovery.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In <em>Upen</em>’s discourse on womanhood, the essential virtues of a woman have always included good words, good work and good fortune — emphasising the role of women as both an alias for success/wealth and also as responsible for that fortune themselves, either in the workplace or through their innate spirituality. This has remained true throughout much of Vekllei’s history, but was obfuscated by the economic masculinity of Vekllei’s protectionist mercantile period. After the war, Upen saw a revival that would culminate in the spiritual fever of the late 2010s and early 2020s. The interim government co-opted this surge pragmatically, encouraging a shift in local perceptions of womanhood through spiritual, rather than political or ideological, methods.</p>
<p>“This is a New Age,” the posters said. “So become a New-Age Woman.”<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>Becoming a New Age Woman involved two things — tearing down the external oppressions of the old and interim periods (harassment, domestic violence, and male interference in the affairs of women), and the interrogation of internalised sexisms (empowerment by male opinion [this included styles women found attractive, as inherited from men], abolishment of economic preoccupations, and the reconstruction of womanhood in abstract). This individual struggle was supported by the many social programmes developed by the interim government, with names like “economic feminisation” (abolishment of the male economic burden) and “abolishment of self-beautification for your man” (<em>scisimionze</em>, or “self-adornment/self-beautification”).</p>
<p>The point was not to empower women by simply displacing men from male economic and social constructions — a move that was seen as disempowering because of who was setting those priorities —  but to rebuild Vekllei’s domestic understanding of “the woman” by the terms of women, legitimised by the authority of the interim government and the powerful cultural force Upen continues to have on society. Within such a culture, it was reasoned, women would be free to choose what womanhood meant to them, since it was not simply reactive to a sexist cultural default. The sum of this effort was called ‘sun-facing,’ or <em>semoisnesne</em>, which referred to the progressive attitude of both the individual and the country.</p>
<p>Although Vekllei’s New Age Woman had dramatic effects and benefitted the status of women in Vekllei society tremendously, it was nonetheless fundamentally political and had obscure and surprising cultural artefacts buried within. The idea that a woman would be “free to choose” her own womanhood was a little misleading, since the interim government was rapidly developing its plan for “petticoat society,” in which Sundress Municipalism, the Bureau System and Floral Aestheticism would become such powerful cultural forces that no man nor woman would be able to escape them entirely.</p>
<p>As the wealth of the country grew and then exploded in the transition to Vekllei’s floral society, it was clear how the structure of petticoat society continued to influence women in Vekllei. Women can wear whatever they like — but simplicity and subtle self-decoration are common and encouraged by the uniforms system and floral aesthetics. Women can live however they like — but education is compulsory in childhood and highly valued, and young women are encouraged to fulfil ‘the female inclination for leadership’ inherited from Upen’s mother-metaphysics. And women can date whomever they like — though ideological compatibility, and not appearance, is encouraged in the <em>semoisnesne</em> attitude.</p>
<p>Some of these things are easily argued as good — few would assume there are many feminists in the world who argue against the education of women — but they do betray the notion of truly “free” choice, insofar as Vekllei society is dominated by the economic and spiritual values of its structure. Vekllei considers capitalist economics, exponential growth, and gross historicism to be “masculine” — of course that sort of language trickles down into the social aspects of society. More directly, it prioritises form, colour, and purity in aesthetics — of course that aesthetic ideology affects how people dress, and contributes to its uniformed culture.</p>
<p>It is difficult to place where the state begins and ends in Vekllei, which is how it can be argued for as an unfree and anarchic society simultaneously. So too is it difficult to determine how much of Vekllei culture originates in the centres of power in Vekllei — either political or religious — and subsequently there are problems in clarifying how women are affected by power, especially since women participate and in some cases dominate those hierarchies. Are they externalised, or internalised? Who is gazing at who?</p>
<p>Regardless of Vekllei’s cultural obscurity, which affects much more than politics and many people other than women, it is clear a dramatic and liberating shift occurred in Vekllei’s interim period of independence, and that shift has contributed tremendously to the status of contemporary Vekllei women, who enjoy economic and social freedoms that were unimaginable just decades prior. Even though Vekllei has not embraced political iconography to celebrate their indigenous feminism, we can see just how radical and wide-ranging the changes made were.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The phrase &ldquo;plastic woman&rdquo; was coined by author John Graves, whose work found popularity in postwar Vekllei after its translation.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><em>Cosmatsisosmiosne de Ne</em>, lit. &ldquo;Woman of the New Age&rdquo;&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Justice</title>
	  <link>/stories/justice/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/stories/justice/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Lin Zhi was nuts. She was lovely, but she was nuts. Tzipora followed along, pleading occasionally, a squeaking voice of concern. The cricket bat dragged and bounced along the poor road sealing.
“You could go to prison,” Tzipora said, protesting weakly. “Why not send Moise and his boys? They’ll put the fear of God in him.”
“This is stupid,” Zhi said in clumsy Vekllei, staring ahead. “You do not know what it’s like.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/images/justice.jpg"/> <p><strong>Lin Zhi was nuts</strong>. She was lovely, but she was nuts. Tzipora followed along, pleading occasionally, a squeaking voice of concern. The cricket bat dragged and bounced along the poor road sealing.</p>
<p>“You could go to prison,” Tzipora said, protesting weakly. “Why not send Moise and his boys? They’ll put the fear of God in him.”</p>
<p>“This is stupid,” Zhi said in clumsy Vekllei, staring ahead. “You do not know what it’s like.”</p>
<p>“I do know,” Tzipora whined. Between their second-hand Vekllei and conflicting accents, they struggled to understand each other. “They call me a gypsy bitch. But I don’t hit them. And not with a bat.”</p>
<p>Zhi and Zelda were much alike. They were both fresh immigrants of school age, and stepped ashore with shadows of a world far beyond Vekllei’s utopian domesticity. Tzipora had spent time indigent in America, nearly lynched in Utah. Zhi had lost her father and uncle to the purges in Red China. Zhi told Tzipora she was the great-great-granddaughter of a hero of the communist party, who’d fought with Mao Tse-tung himself over a century ago. Tzipora did not enquire further, since she knew as much about China as she did the moon.</p>
<p>“No one is asking you to come,” Zhi said, marching ahead as Tzipora trailed.</p>
<p>“Don’t be silly, I’m coming with you. Of course I’m coming with you. I just don’t want you to ruin your life over some words.”</p>
<p>“Words add up,” Zhi said quietly.</p>
<p>The rest of Zhi’s seven sisters had taken European names to better assimilate into the hectic transcontinental <em>aliyah</em> of postwar Vekllei. Not Zhi, though. She was wilful and clear-minded, maybe recklessly. Tzipora liked her and feared her, perhaps because she saw herself in Zhi’s frequent outbursts of anger and principled view of the world.</p>
<p>The Floral Period was stuffed with new citizens, many of them in disfavour of the politics of their home country. Many of them came from Asia — <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/">Ayn’s</a> father was a Hong Konger, and <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/">Jiro</a> was from Tokyo. Vekllei’s people were indigenously “Asiatic in appearance,” as Europe called them. Most were descended from a mixture of Arctic peoples and Irish or Scandinavian settlers. To this end, Vekllei’s complicated ethnic makeup contributes to the country’s obscurity from the U.S. and Europe, as they tend to be orientalised outside of Western concern. This discrimination does not stop Vekllei people from maintaining ignorant ideas towards its incoming East Asian and South-East Asian migrants, however, and people like Zhi often had to deal with racist abuse in public and in private.</p>
<p>“Why don’t we be smart about this?” Tzipora asked, upset. “What he did to you is against school policy. He’ll be thrown out — it’ll ruin him. That’s what hurts, really. Trust me, I know. I know what it’s like for you, too. But he wants to go to the National University. If we get him thrown out, that would ruin him.”</p>
<p>Zhi scoffed, and shook her head. “That you could think the school would do anything shows how little you know,” she said.</p>
<p>“Baron is powerful. He can lean on them. He does it all the time, he’d help if I asked. I know he would.”</p>
<p>Tzipora stepped in front of her, and put her arms out. Her eyes were shining with tears.</p>
<p>“I was going to get expelled for putting a girl’s head through a window, and it was like this,” Tzipora said, sniffling. “She picked on me every day. Every day, she knew I was lonely and sad so she’d scare me. And one day I snapped and put her head through the window. I was going to be expelled, and my life would have ended there. But Baron knew I was right, and he stepped in. Sometimes that’s all it takes, to beat them. It just takes an outsider.”</p>
<p>Zhi had stopped marching, and leaned on the bat. She was out of breath. She shook her head and tossed the bat at Tzipora’s feet.</p>
<p>“Okay,” she said. “Because I like you, Zelda, that’s all. Don’t tell him anything. Don’t tell anyone anything. This is my problem. But I don’t want to upset you. We’re quite similar, I think.”</p>
<p>“Too similar,” Tzipora said, wiping her eyes. “But it’s not our fault. Not really.”</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
