<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>society on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in society on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 03:41:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 03:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
      <description>There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.
 Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or venopor) Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or cosmopor)  A young venopor officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike cosmopor, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Map of Vekllei — 100 Boroughs; 100 Hearts</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 23:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</guid>
      <description>Map Key
 Red: Magjet trains, 750km/h
Yellow: Bullet trains, 300-400km/h
Orange: Regional trains, &amp;lt;150km/h
Brown: Local trains, including limited express, &amp;lt;100km/h
Blue: National highway
Dashed: Ferry line
Green: tarmacadamed airport
 The largest division of any portion of Vekllei land is the borough; a region of varying size and population with common culture, food dependency and economic interest. Anything larger than that is simply Vekllei — they are “one city”, after all, and consider themselves a city-state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Crown — coins of a moneyless country</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 05:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
      <description>Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country. At no point do coins or paper currency change hands in the day-to-day affairs of the country.
In this sense, Vekllei is usually described as “moneyless” — yet it does in fact have a currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Village Map of Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 04:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</guid>
      <description>The village of Montre-Lola is home to about 400 people in its entirety, a stone’s throw from the Aisyo borough. Each morning, however, the population swells as 300 children from tiny villages in both Aisyo and Montre take a fast tram to the Montre-Lola Area School No. 2, a district school raising all ages of local youth.
Like many Vekllei villages, Montre-Lola’s history is complex and has origin stories in both viking-inuit settlement as well as less sentimental government programmes that flourished after the atomic war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chemical Feast</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 02:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</guid>
      <description>East of Montre, West of Tjornes, waits a rare sight among Vekllei’s hard igneous slopes — a crown of gentle sedimentary cliffs packed with ruddy sandstone, which melt glacially into the sea chasing blue-sky bergs.
Tzipora was, at the time, making her way on foot from Montre-Lola to Ada, which was a coastal town in the North-East known for its luxurious health spas. Tzipora was not much interested in health, but she was interested in walking, and she made a pilgrimage along the coast every few years to make sense of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>