<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Landscape on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://beta.millmint.net/drafts/landscape/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Landscape on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://beta.millmint.net/drafts/landscape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sundress Municipalism</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/drafts/landscape/economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/drafts/landscape/economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint yellow&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Under Construction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This page is still under construction, and may be incomplete.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-vekllei-economy&#34;&gt;The Vekllei Economy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sundress-municipalism&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sundress Municipalism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-participatory-economics-in-utopia&#34;&gt;1. Participatory Economics in Utopia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;11-introduction&#34;&gt;1.1. Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The daily functioning of the Vekllei economy is as miraculous as it is unique. Key organs and mechanisms of the Vekllei economy reality are positioned against or outright opposed against each other. And a startling series of contradictions &amp;ndash; one after the other, each more unusual than the last. Vekllei is a planned economy; it is also a free market. Property ownership is obfuscated by portioned sovereignty of land and product. Decommodification has devalued products in a country based on manufacturing. There are many contradictions, inefficiencies and simply unusual mechanisms in the Vekllei domestic market, and this article hopes to elucidate at least some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Bureau System&lt;/em&gt;, sometimes called &lt;em&gt;Product Socialism&lt;/em&gt;, is the name by which Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s economy is most often described. A primitive form was found in the anarchy in the wake of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s atomic bombing, but by 2020 it was written into the document that would become Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s postwar constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.studio/images/canal.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;canals&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the Atomic War, Vekllei was a closed, protectionist market under rule of a monarchy puppeted by a military junta. A backwards and quaint country for much of its 20th century, there is no period in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s history which we might describe as &amp;ldquo;industrial capitalism&amp;rdquo;. It is in this context, in the ashes of the Atomic War and under British occupation, that we can sympathise with the barter economy that would eventually modernise into the Bureau System, a thoroughly unique economic ideology in the world today.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes the Bureau System unique? Simply that, in common contexts, no money exists in Vekllei whatsoever. This is moneylessness in spirit, too &amp;ndash; there are no currency substitutes, be they labour vouchers or ration systems. This initial fact of life and symptom of destitution is now codified and vigorously defended by the Vekllei state, making the country the only example of a moneyless state of its size in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abolition of currency is allowed by two facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&#34;1-a-general-post-scarcity-and-surplus-of-goods&#34;&gt;1. A general post-scarcity and surplus of goods.&lt;/h4&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&#34;2-the-inefficiencies-of-a-profitless-market-compensated-by-the-total-abolition-of-waged-labourlabour-costs&#34;&gt;2. The inefficiencies of a profitless market compensated by the total abolition of waged labour/labour costs.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function fo Vekllei
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;12-principles&#34;&gt;1.2. Principles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economy informs the high standard of living, but also influences architecture, culture and even the Vekllei person himself. In the context of the Vekllei participist economy, even the notions of manhood and womanhood are reorganised around the basic principles of the economy, which are themselves symptoms of Vekllei’s history, landscape and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core principles of Vekllei’s parecon, usually identified by name as petticoat society, are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-management and self-interest through &lt;strong&gt;Sundress Municipalism&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification of property as an independent social organ, like nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abolishment of currency and currency-substitutes.
Participatory employment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Economic feminisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;13-culture&#34;&gt;1.3. Culture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most unusual is Vekllei’s cultural phantom of property and its absence in business and the home. That is not to indicate a tendency of either private or shared commodity, but rather an absence of commodity altogether — a fiscal kingdom divorced entirely from neighbouring notions of property, usurped instead by a common understanding of cityscape and objects alike as products of nature, capable neither of possessing or communalising it, codified mostly by a cultural intuition that forms one part of the Vekllei idea of ‘ownership’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, these people do not recognise property in their domestic lives, nor do they carry with them any currency or currency-substitute (labour vouchers, crediting systems, etc.) — but to describe the economic function of society as simply utopian in the fashion of 19th century fiction-writers would be misleading. Vekllei is a miracle produced in the intersection of culture and power that have determined national priority since the First Atomic War. Vekllei is not a blueprint or mathematical template, and appears to be so far irreproducible abroad. This could be because of any or all of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei is perhaps the most highly concentrated country of its size on Earth — 80 percent of the 20 millions that call it home are located in the wide urban region referred to as the Capital and the city-state of Vekllei. Indeed, domestically the entire inhabited coastline is considered to be part of one large, singular city community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei was devastated entirely by the First Atomic War, which extinguished the protectionist Denoisesn regime and left the urban centres bare of infrastructure, allowing architects and urban planners to implement a so-called ‘garden city’ design in the principle of traditional Vekllei spiritualism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei does not suffer from internal factionalism of the other great powers, and is ethnically and culturally homogenous.
The modern Vekllei economy bypassed liberalisation of trade entirely through its monarchical-authoritarian-utopian progression, and has no nostalgia for either currency or real market economics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most crucially, the last fifty years of advanced robotics has essentially relegated vast swaths of the labour of the majority of her workforce as unnecessary, or comfortable. Automation is not universal, and so all people must work in fairness, but society has reorganised around professional hierarchies where every person casts their lot in at the lowest rung  — essentially, in theory, alleviating work as anything other than hobby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Vekllei has an unusual system that is desperate to consume work-hours. It is labour-intensive where wanted, alleviated by industrial machinery where preferred, and completely automated where necessary.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-petticoat-socialism&#34;&gt;2. Petticoat Socialism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-the-bureau-system&#34;&gt;3. The Bureau System&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei History</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/drafts/landscape/culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/drafts/landscape/culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-culture&#34;&gt;8. Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Although Vekllei culture&lt;/strong&gt; can be traced unevenly across its two thousand years of settlement, modern Vekllei is influenced primarily by a convergence of traditions informed by indigenous, religious and immigrant populations bound in the multiculturalism of the Floral Period Constitution. Contemporary Vekllei culture is heavily influenced by its bombing and occupation by the United Kingdom, and new policies of state secularism and multiracialism have dominated Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s cultural legacy into the 21st Century.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;arts&#34;&gt;Arts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;media&#34;&gt;Media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cuisine&#34;&gt;Cuisine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sport-and-recreation&#34;&gt;Sport and recreation&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei History</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/drafts/landscape/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/drafts/landscape/history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;// FOR USE IN VEKLLI ARTICLE AT A LATER DATE //&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-history&#34;&gt;3. History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Vekllei&lt;/b&gt; is an ancient country even by metrics of human settlement. There is evidence of human settlement in the Home Islands from 6,000 years ago, which predates European settlement on the island by nearly 4,000 years.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ancient-vekllei&#34;&gt;Ancient Vekllei&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human habitation is known to have started in Vekllei nearly 6,000 years ago, likely by arctic peoples from nearby Kalalist, who settled along the Southern Coast of the Home Islands. Early &lt;em&gt;sagas&lt;/em&gt; incorporate much older stories and myths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-period&#34;&gt;Early Period&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;settlement-and-commonwealth&#34;&gt;Settlement and Commonwealth&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;quarters&#34;&gt;Quarters&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;middle-period&#34;&gt;Middle Period&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tribemanship&#34;&gt;Tribemanship&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;danish-rule&#34;&gt;Danish Rule&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;era-of-rest&#34;&gt;Era of Rest&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;kingdom-of-iceland&#34;&gt;Kingdom of Iceland&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;civil-war&#34;&gt;Civil War&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;kingdom-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Kingdom of Vekllei&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;late-period&#34;&gt;Late Period&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-mujsda-junta&#34;&gt;The Mujsda Junta&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;africa-wars--atomic-bombing&#34;&gt;Africa Wars &amp;amp; Atomic Bombing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;british-occupation&#34;&gt;British Occupation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;floral-period&#34;&gt;Floral Period&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the British Oil Crisis and subsequent decolonisation of Tanganyika, Vekllei was made independent amidst the failing of the British economy. The failed state of Vekllei, which had seen its government and economy totally collapse in the Atomic War, had been a tremendous expense for the United Kingdom and was done away with in a rapid independence article passed in British Parliament in 2015. This article laid out a framework for independence and deoccupation of Vekllei within three years, with provisions for British Commonwealth membership and trade reparations. In practice, independence would not be complete until nearly 2020, at which time Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s sovereignty was restored in a ceremony the people of the United Kingdom were well used to by then; the lowering of the Union Jack and in its place the raising of a new, young flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;contemporary-history--postwar-independence&#34;&gt;Contemporary History &amp;amp; Postwar Independence&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>