<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>post on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in post on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Army</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-30-army/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-30-army/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  There’s a thousand years of history in Vekllei’s armed forces, though you’ll find very little of it recalled casually today. Almost everything about Vekllei’s prewar society was scorched by the bombs, and the scraps of military infrastructure that survived were appropriated in the subsequent British occupation.
Since independence, a slate has been wiped clean, and a modern fighting force has replaced the colonial legions and battleships of yesteryear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tzipora Christmas Story</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Pachinki is a world of Tzipora’s own creation, a dorky retreat from the difficulties she has in Vekllei. Tzipora always loved stories of wild places and adventure, and Pachinki blossomed organically from within her daydreams. Eventually she started writing and drawing it. When she was sad, bored or anxious, she would descend back into Pachinki’s world of ancient magic, edible gems and pirates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Heart</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  She’d dropped out of school and had the slow accent of a person too foreign to employ. She now lived in a country that did not use money. Food was everywhere and you ate until you were satisfied. Around each corner was a new cinema or basement lounge, and water trickled through the streets like all mythic garden cities. It was a paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bea and the Mosses</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-08-bea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-08-bea/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   You run wild and far and by your banks we may find rest at last our common life is all there is your soul equals our reflections constantly you drift past us
  With us, beneath us upstream, downstream
 — The River, Rites at Dawn, Wobbler
T his is Bea, an energetic Botanist with the Landscape Bureau of Vekllei. People know her as an eccentric young woman easily persuaded by cottage-fashions, but she takes her work very seriously and spends most of her waking hours documenting the dense temperate rainforests of Vekllei’s coastal lowlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crown Land of No King</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  It would be misleading to characterise Vekllei as environmentalist in the usual idea of the word. Vekllei is no such thing. This is obvious in subtle ways, like Newda’s Dumousiantopet, or “beautiful and seperate,” which advocates the separation of human and natural design. It is also policy; Vekllei is dependent on its landscape as part of Autosuffisouitopet, or “self-sustenance,” and to this end sinks forests for hydroelectric dams and topples mountains for novel urban projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to Grips</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-01-grips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-01-grips/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  She would spend a long time by the rivulet that ran behind her apartment. She would do the housework and hang the wash out, then watch the water trickle past in the sun.
She tried to open a jar the other day and started to cry when she couldn’t get it open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of The Ground and Into The Light</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-28-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-28-city/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   NO REALTORS EXCEPT THE STATE ■ THE COUNTY THE AGENT OF THE STATE ■ THE ARCHITECT THE AGENT OF THE COUNTY
 It is clear that in Vekllei democracy is a way of living more than it is a form of government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Speak Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, https://millmint.net. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st Century Witch</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  When the light shifted just right, the ceramic tiles and concrete footpaths twinkled like water off the back of a swan. 16th Century witches could build a hut in the woods and forage for herbs; 21st Century witches were susceptible to modernist persuasions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vekllei Comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Hi everyone,
&amp;ldquo;He not busy being born is busy dying,&amp;rdquo; — that’s off a Bob Dylan bootleg. I’ve just finished my thesis and I’m busy being born again. Sometimes I feel like I’m busy dying. Drawing’s been the way out for a long time now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All That’s Solid Melts into Zelda</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   My nerves are like overused sandpaper—all dull; only the eye-catching, bizarre and grotesque can excite me now.
 Tanizaki Junichirō, 1918
The wind had died and it seemed that she would follow it. Crazy shadows distorted beneath car headlights. It occurred to her in some way that, as she approached dying, she was living out the ultimate dramatic fantasy of the American misplaced girl, in the same way the townsmen were fulfilling their grotesque constellation of death by murdering women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petrol Heaven — The Rohsm STR-750</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  The Rohsm STR series is a small racer built for clubs by Rohsm S.p.M., a hundred-year-old company headquartered in the Mediterranean racing culture of Tohs. Its most recent variant, the 750, is available in limited quantities to enthusiast owners and club pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mittens and Metaphysic — Product Atheism and Vekllei object-form</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Pictured above: various fashions worn by Vekllei women, showcasing heavy cold-weather dresses, simple styling, strong geometric shapes and colours, loose fits, and modest hemlines.
  Pictured below: postmodern neomarxism, which I’ve tricked you into reading with anime.
 Previous posts on the Vekllei economy, if you’re new:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlantic Boredom</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  For a brief period of time, Zelda and Cobian took it upon themselves to make something of their youth. Cobian fancied herself a gymnast, and though this ambition arrived too late and left too soon, she was quite good at it for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baron, the Father</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  People are not sure what to make of Baron. They are not sure what to make of his daughter, Tzipora, either. To that end, they are lucky to have found each other.
His obscurity is part of a severe disposition, made obvious by his astonishing disinterest in friends and hobbies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Bouncy Zelda — an animation diary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  It&amp;rsquo;s been a week since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted. Most of that was spent drawing the same thing over and over.
A painting? Please. That&amp;rsquo;s a day&amp;rsquo;s work — maybe two. A five second loop of Tzipora jumping in and shuffling over? A week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory and Death in the Flower Tundra</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  It was their first hike after Maya’s funeral. She had found adult life completely disappointing, and never moved out of home. In her last summer, she developed a desperate fascination with her receding childhood, and eventually took her own life outside of the classroom she’d studied in as a third-grade student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobian and Zelda &#34;head-over-heels&#34;</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  make love not lore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matchstick Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Another paint-sketch — a painting done fast. I’m trying to learn to a) paint and b) paint on an industrial scale.
She’d missed the fast tram, caught a tiny splinter in her thumb, lost a button and now the match wouldn’t strike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  They showed up at the autopool, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   On the morning of the second day, I watched a fly crawl across the cheek of the middle-aged woman, probably an office worker, lying next to me. It moved up her cheekbone to her temple, stopping now and then to rub its front legs as though performing a ritual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2,000 members! WOW!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Hello,
I’m Hobart. I’ve been working on this project for a while now. It doesn’t really have a purpose or an end goal — I just want to draw and write about nice things, and I’m learning a lot on the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Quiet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  There were plumes in the sky, sent from bunkers buried deep in the well of the Earth, killing with switches. Vekllei went to war, and so Tzipora went to war with it.
The throbbing machinery of another world began turning, and anyone who saw the bomb would hear it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Newda in Rural Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Newda is Vekllei’s national architectural ideology, applied flexibly in a range of modernist styles developed domestically in her architecture schools. Broadly, Newda buildings emphasise distinction from the surrounding landscape (called Dumousiantopet, or ‘beautiful and seperate’), natural decay, and honesty in material and construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thousand-Year-Old Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  The concept of living forever jumps out at people uncomfortable with their own existence. There is a contemplative instinct among educated people that — if they could simply will themselves into a state of self-actualisation — death would only be an obstacle to greatness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 31st Century — Vekllei throughout our Solar System</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  The Epoch of Rest #  We’ve spent a lot of time in the 21st century — but Tzipora is biologically immortal. Where does she go from here? Well, let’s enjoy a small glimpse at that future together, by winding the clock forward one thousand years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Unique among girls #  There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not realise she is unusual, or does not care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer House in the Azores</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  The Azores had been a possession of Vekllei since 2002, when they were leased from Portugal indefinitely. The lease was defunct by the time of Vekllei’s independence from U.K. occupation in 2015, and the new state took formal ownership over the small Atlantic islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Camp</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Just a paint-sketch.
The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora’s ‘Every Day Carry’</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Like a lot of girls of poverty, Tzipora was very possessive of her things. No food was ever left on her plate. There was a deep anxiety that whatever wasn’t claimed would be lost.
She was also naturally obsessive and material-oriented, keenly aware of the importance of objects measured by metrics in her own silly head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Race for Inefficiency — Vekllei’s advocation of austerity, apathy, and playfulness as economic principles</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  This post is about the economy of Vekllei. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a long one. If you have any questions, just ask.
Overview of the Bureau System #  There are many thousands of companies busy with work in Vekllei. The vast majority of these companies are single-person shops (S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.
 Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or venopor) Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or cosmopor)  A young venopor officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike cosmopor, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is This Project?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  What is Vekllei?
Hi, I’m Hobart and I write and draw Vekllei at Studio MillMint.
This is a pretty complex project. Not just complex insofar as there’s a lot to read about it, but that it uses concepts and terminology you might not be familiar with if this is your first time around utopian fiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Map of Vekllei — 100 Boroughs; 100 Hearts</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Map Key
 Red: Magjet trains, 750km/h
Yellow: Bullet trains, 300-400km/h
Orange: Regional trains, &amp;lt;150km/h
Brown: Local trains, including limited express, &amp;lt;100km/h
Blue: National highway
Dashed: Ferry line
Green: tarmacadamed airport
 The largest division of any portion of Vekllei land is the borough; a region of varying size and population with common culture, food dependency and economic interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Crown — coins of a moneyless country</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Village Map of Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  The village of Montre-Lola is home to about 400 people in its entirety, a stone’s throw from the Aisyo borough. Each morning, however, the population swells as 300 children from tiny villages in both Aisyo and Montre take a fast tram to the Montre-Lola Area School No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Most Beautiful Woman</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”
It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oa-Class Battlecruiser</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Vekllei’s defensive military posture has, in doctrine and arms development, limited its ability to meaningfully project power outside of the Atlantic. As an island nation with a large and multifaceted naval armada, the Oa-Class Battlecruiser is the heart of her armed forces, as the flagship of her fleets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canal Living</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fission Cloud at Vekllei&#39;s 50th Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  In an unprecedented event, during Vekllei’s 50th Sea Festival since Independence in 2065, an 8 kiloton fission bomb was sunk to a depth of 150 meters and detonated at midday. It was an incredible sight on a day so clear you could see the gentle curve of the earth where it met the horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rain in the Arctic Circle</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Tzipora had been ejected from the operations room once the guys arrived. She knew what was going down, anyway. No specifics. But you didn’t bring in uniformed soldiers for regular business. National Intelligence liked to work with their own people.
Five days prior, Baron hailed an EB/NI company car and it pulled up beside him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform. And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031 Apartment Diagram</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  Baron had inherited the apartment from his uncle, who passed in the year following his parents. It was in a mixed residential-industrial neighbourhood, adjacent to a canvas factory. Out back was a rivulet, which roared in the long rainstorms of early April.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Tzipo-stcards</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hello everyone. Just a little update.
As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.
How many cards will the set contain?
 I’m aiming for about six cards.
 How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiery Peaks</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  After three days in Ada, Tzipora set off towards Mt Miya. She made good time, and after three hours had happened upon the shoulders of the bright Volouisnesnkull Glacier. It was about here that she heard a morbid industrial siren, echoing up the valleys from far away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chemical Feast</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  East of Montre, West of Tjornes, waits a rare sight among Vekllei’s hard igneous slopes — a crown of gentle sedimentary cliffs packed with ruddy sandstone, which melt glacially into the sea chasing blue-sky bergs.
Tzipora was, at the time, making her way on foot from Montre-Lola to Ada, which was a coastal town in the North-East known for its luxurious health spas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trials of Cobian</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.  According to her friends, Tzipora’s contemporary afflictions were tragic. Her medical problems; her violent childhood; her sensitivity and melancholy — you could feel sorry for her, because a lot of her problems were not her fault. She invoked sympathy.
Tzipora never considered herself particularly tragic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tomorrow: 2020 Complete Guide to Vekllei
Today:
 Up in the ro, the Vekllei flower-tundra home to spirits and people alike, green slopes and igneous monument make an ample crucible for myth and magic.
 Out here, there was a very keen sense of place and purpose. “Landscape” was neither revered nor ignored, since it did not exist here altogether. Every hill, rock and tree was taken at face value in its full honesty, with commodity dead and modernism suppressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentle Enthusiasm</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-23-enthusiasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-23-enthusiasm/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tzipora stood astride the bicycle luggage rack, and looked at her best friend Moise. She smiled at him, and looked to the town before them, and squinted at the clouds rising over the Atlantic horizon.
It was a warm late summer and there was salt in the air. Pebbles made better swimmers than Tzipora, but from up here she could admire the coast and fill her heart with the breeze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ou Hydroburo Office</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Almost any other venrouive national bureau is more glamorous than Vekllei’s Hydroburo, but that fact does not detract from the organ’s critical function.
Although the sophisticated age of robotics demands the incredible yield of nuclear fission, a significant minority of Vekllei’s electricity is produced by hydroelectric dams, which are jointly operated by the Thunderburo and Hydroburo. Hydroelectricity appeals to the common Vekllei person strategically and culturally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AB/NI’s Spectres of Violence</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), a semiautonomous organ of the covert operations council of the War Department, is recognised as the busiest of the continental bureaus. There is a lot to be busy with — the Dallas Secession, the Brazilian invasion of Bolivia, the Dallas nuclear lend-lease, and the reliability of Venezuelan oil production are all of some concern to Vekllei, and so AB/NI proactively has fingers in those pies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghosts of Taiwan in the Yana Lakehouse</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-05-lakehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-05-lakehouse/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  By 2047, Vekllei had a lot of broken men. Tens of thousands had alighted troop ships at the end of the War of Taiwan, only to find that pieces of their lives had unravelled overseas. Hardy, bronze-skinned boys were left with their ghosts, and those ghosts introduced them to drinking, and brawling, and suicide.
 As part of the Birmingham Convention and the second round of the Commonwealth War Trials, a young and recently defeated Vekllei nation was chained to a conflict that was beginning to fester in East Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montre, City of Learning</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-03-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-03-learning/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The Montre Prefecture of the Vekllei city-state is among the most learned urban landscapes in the world. In the days of the monarchy, it had been an unremarkable city, home to the empire’s submarine fleet. It was obliterated by bombs in the war, and the &amp;ldquo;new Montre&amp;rdquo; that has blossomed in its place is nourished by its ashes.
Among the most prolific creatures in Vekllei’s academic elite, including prestigious folk like physicist Thomas Weihennet and Chief Engineer of General Reactor Maya Ou, almost all of them were educated in Montre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego Death and Upen&#39;s Spiritual Rebirth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-01-ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-01-ego/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   The Beach was a small part of herself.
Another stroke on the Hell Screen
She washed ashore
Two dollars were in the sand
A hound had come here to rest
Damp cotton touched green water
She thought of what she was doing here
Of what the night invoked
Hot sand met a rising wind
It happened again
She realised
There was not a single dog left to fight</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Ro Highlands</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-11-highlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-11-highlands/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  As I pick up some larger projects, my posts here will slow down a little bit. That&amp;rsquo;s okay &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m still easy to track down and get in touch with, and you guys will still see the best stuff.
I post a lot of sketches to the Vekllei Discord, which is something between a fan club and a social club for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Cobian, a concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  If you go back through my posts here, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice Tzipora is basically a cartoon whose only consistent characteristic is her iconography &amp;ndash; her hair fountain, bangs, round head and big smile. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really intentional. I&amp;rsquo;m just an amateur artist who is still learning to draw.
That doesn&amp;rsquo;t work so well in a comic with sequential panels, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on standardising my characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora, the Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Editor’s note — it’s getting close to 4 a.m. and I’m not sure I can even remember why I wrote this post. Everything is a fog. Expect revisions and possibly major changes in the morning.
Pictured above is Tzipora Desmoisnes, the Princess of the Earth and one of the most interesting persons of the last century. She has made good use of her 126 years on Earth (and counting), and a few samples have been chosen for your viewing pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salad Time</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-11-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-11-salad/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Despite appearances, most of the population of Vekllei are Scandinavian, not Asian.
Zhu is the first time in a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn an ethnically Chinese person. She was graciously lent to me to draw by u/boodyclap in an art trade. You can see his end of the deal here, complete with Tzipora balancing a baseball bat.
In Zhu&amp;rsquo;s homeland she suffers a meat-heavy diet, and Vekllei is the first time she&amp;rsquo;s seen a salad this big.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Timeline</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-05-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-05-timeline/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  This is it. The dates are laid out. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a document that tracks the story thus far. Longtime followers might be surprised by where certain events land.
This post will be pinned and serve as a stopgap until I can complete something more professional on my site.
  CLICK HERE for a timeline of the events so far, and how they line up in this story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face to Face with Immortality</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tzipora had never been taller than anyone in Vekllei at a meagre 5’2, but she was taller than Shizuku Kobayashi. Like Tzipora, Shizuku had not physically aged a day since she was a child.
It was summer, and six days after Tzipora had arrived in Japan as a Gregori ambassador from Vekllei. Although she would not be the oldest victim of Gregori-Heitzfeld syndrome until Quentin Cook’s (USA) infamous murder-suicide ten years later, she was one of the so-called &amp;ldquo;First Thirteen&amp;rdquo; publicised patients, and so was somewhat known to the international community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girls of the Last Carriage</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  She’d accidentally starched her gi quarter-pleat in the wash. She held it self-consciously against her side as she watched the clouds navigate the sharp mountains that formed Montre’s deepest valleys. Even out here, where human presence was gentle and subservient to the land, Vekllei National Railways had tracks that serviced the smallest villages. Today it was high summer, and the slopes were green and free of ice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girl and the Sublime</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-19-sublime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-19-sublime/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  When Tzipora moved to study English and Vekllei literature at the university of Montre in 2075, she had to walk from the little home where she lived to Montre-Lola’s old concrete platform, which facilitated a single electric railcar each way, each day. If she was feeling lively, she could make it to the platform in a half hour. On the days where she dreaded sighting her plimsolls in the shoebox, it might take forty-five minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Foreigner’s Guide to Female Traditional Dress in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tzipora, illustrated here, is happy because her traditional dress makes her feel stylish and her cape is soft and warm.
Vekllei is an ancient culture with many inherited and vestigial artefacts. Nowhere is this more apparent than in her national dress, particularly that for women, where old and new collide as they do all across Vekllei. Pre-war, post-war and future are present here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hobart and Tzipora are off to Japan</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora here is wearing a simplified form of Vekllei’s national dress, which plays fast and loose with lace and showcases some of Vekllei’s more decadent iconography. Long gi (decorative quarter-pleats you’ve seen around) accompany sun petticoats, or Vekllei lace aprons. Flowers take the place of astrology or the Zodiac in Vekllei, and so they often accompany spiritual runes (in upotenne, or religious script) about the girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valleys of the Wind</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-04-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-04-wind/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The summer had rolled into the valley, and so the air smelled of hot grass from the fields. It was quiet at the station, where a single train clacked each way in the afternoon. The only sound was the wind, which caught the heads of dry grass and roared up the slopes of the mountain ranges around her.
It seemed an exaggeration to even call it a station, since the bare concrete slab had been laid fifty years ago and left to crumble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So long 2019, here&#39;s to 2020!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the new Vekllei discord — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts. Speaking of which, this one is a substitute — the one I’m working on ended up being a bit too sad for an exciting new year, so I’ll put the sad stuff off until Jan 2nd in favour of something happier tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-26-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-26-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  I’m still eating pudding, but once I’m home tomorrow and settled at my drawing desk I’ll be sure to report Tzipora’s holiday adventures in full.
For the Christmasfolk out there, enjoy your presents. To everyone else, have a good holiday and be sure to celebrate the Australian way — with prawns, salmon and snags on the barbie.
(Gorgeous 25°C [77°F] yesterday)
Best,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Kodak Moment by a Vekllei Geyser</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In her journal for practicing writing the Vekllei language (appropriately called Vekllei), Tzipora wrote:
 The heavy clouds above were children of early spring, but among the steam vents it seemed like the whole sky was polluted by geysers. Large pools, opalescent with healthy minerals, were heated by the core of the Earth. In a volcanic desert of black sand, the geysers were an oasis, rising from the sulphuric fog like a little eden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life and Death in Vekllei Apartment Ideology, or “Newda”</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  To substitute for my shocking (and deeply shameful) absence over the last two weeks, please accept a longer-form post concerning domestic Apartment Ideology in Vekllei, which they call Newda and is known internationally as The Vekllei Newda School. Pictured is the apartment of our very own Zelda. While the building itself deserves a feature, for now we’ll discuss Newda as a theory and her life in this building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A “Horizon Wing” Atomic Passenger Jet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Click here for a view inside the wing.
Although the CN-1 Horizon Wing passenger jet was not a “flying wing,” that didn’t stop Comen Aeroyards, the manufacturer, from celebrating it as such. Much like similar large-wing aircraft from McDonnell and de Havilland, the CN-1’s large vertical stabilisers and obvious centre fuselage precluded it from qualifying as an authentic “flying wing,” which were already common in many air forces at this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak Sneak</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-11-sneak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-11-sneak/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   He kept bad hours. Sometimes he worked so hard he came home in the early morning and fell asleep to the television with the subtitles on. Like a guerrilla sighting a commanding officer, she would approach discreetly, wearing her blanket like a cape and bouncing on her toes. With a gentle movement she&amp;rsquo;d drape it over him and listen for a break in his snoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside VOA’s “Flying Wing” Atomic Passenger Jet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-09-wing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-09-wing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In this limited cross-section of a CN-1 “Horizon” Wing, the scale of the aircraft is immediately impressed upon the reader. It is nearly four times as wide as the older wide-body passenger jets of yesteryear, and twice as wide as most American and European supersonic jets. It is no coincidence that the “flying wing” concept was only made possible by the development of supersonic jetport infrastructure, with their wide and long runways, at the turn of the century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallabies of the Arctic — Vekllei&#39;s Pademelon and what the hell it&#39;s doing there</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-06-wallabies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-06-wallabies/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   8 days without posts feels like a century. Tomorrow, SkyMonth returns, and we’ll see what it’s like flying VAS. The day after tomorrow we’ll see an update for a few things — particularly a massive (and awesome) overhaul of the Vekllei site + wiki. Yeah, if you’re wondering where I’ve been, I’ve ditched Wordpress and have been learning HTML, which is like scraping the exposed brain against unpolished concrete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Trouble</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora never lost her youthful curiosity. She would swish about the apartment, chasing an idea or plan that had occurred to her. Baron would look over and say “What are you doing, Zelda? Making trouble?” He said that a lot. He would come home in the afternoon and she would be writing lists, or organising her paperbacks, or moving furniture and he’d say, “What are you up to, Zelda?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicating despair in the pasture of plenty</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora is doing well now. She has looked into her heart and made peace with who she is. She has discovered she is a girl who likes free jazz, and milky coffee, and cotton shirts, and trains — to the surprise of no-one who knows her. She knows what things she values in a friend, and what deserves to become family. She knows what clothes she likes and how to do her hair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean-liners of the Sky — Vacuum Dirigibles in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-24-dirigible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-24-dirigible/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Sorry it took so long, mateys. I&amp;rsquo;ve been laying the first pages of the comic down and it&amp;rsquo;s like crack for me. Not much sleep and totally fell behind on SkyMonth. But, as any longtime members know, our Months are r/vekllei usually last a little longer than they should past their expiry date. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to come!
 The Angel and Memory of the People of Vekllei is the largest and most recent of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s airships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Stewards in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-19-stewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-19-stewards/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Although Vekllei’s flag-carrying airline might appear just one of many in the small island country, don’t be fooled — all civilian aviation operates under a venrouive bureau excitingly titled the Vekllei Air Service (Skyburo), which operates several distinct ‘airlines’ but wholly controls all of them. In Vekllei economic lexicon, a bureau is the largest trade union of an industry, made up of many hundreds of others, and is partially beholden to the direction of government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Shoes</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-18-blue-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-18-blue-shoes/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Welcome to the r/Vekllei variety hour, where the tone between posts judders so inconsistently you&amp;rsquo;ll get whiplash of the mind. I was just drawing and thinking today. This is an author post, in case you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed &amp;ndash; just a shitty blog.
You see, even today I&amp;rsquo;m wildly jealous of the success of those slice-of-life artists on reddit and Twitter. I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand the genre entirely, as a phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten corpses in the snow, and a change of government in the American South</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve just pulled a body from an air force jet here that looks like General MacMillan, and we really need to know right now if it&amp;rsquo;s him.”
The partially buried remains of a U.S. Air Force passenger aircraft are the only blemish on the horizon of central Greenland’s frigid snowscape. It is the site of one of the greatest political scandals in American history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Beaches to Mountaintops</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-15-mountaintops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-15-mountaintops/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  I had the wonderful opportunity to work with one of our resident worldbuilders on reddit, u/EpicJM, and spend a while with their world and characters. The world of Eipljord has a lot of distinct, unique cultures and characters. As a sucker for uniforms I went with the garb of the Pruscyldan Academy of Magic, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find JM&amp;rsquo;s character, Honora being splattered with ice cream by Tzipora on the left and in Vekllei education uniform on the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</guid>
      <description>Station Dogs #  I’m starting a series looking at the lives and machines of domestic Vekllei life.
Vekllei National Railways, or ‘VK Rail’ was the bastard of six major pre-war rail companies that were extinguished along with the society that housed them. Today there are three rail companies in Vekllei, but all of them operate under direct supervision of a Vekllei Industry Bureau ( making it Venrouiva, in other words) and are only broken up for reasons of logistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd Draft</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  I first saw this film at a low point in my life, and watching Shizuku discover her ability was one of the most touching things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan-art guy, but I still find myself thinking about them years later and I wanted to paint them happy after the end of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Vekllei?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Vekllei is a country in my alt-world; a utopian fever dream of googie aesthetics, participatory economics and nostalgia.
Welcome to the ‘Petticoat Project’, a collection of stories about a country and a girl. The concept is broken down into three sections:
 Author: for blog posts and articles on the Petticoat Project, utopian fiction, personal news item, etc. Character: for posts about Tzipora, people in her life, or otherwise events that occur during her time on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei’s Elite Military Units — the Garden Corps and their bloody war against weeds</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post
 On Tuesday, two casualties were reported among Vekllei’s Folifedestarmie 24th and 25th Garden Companies in the ongoing war to make the capital’s parks the finest in the world. Michael Helen-Louisviuan cut his leg on an exposed nail during the deinstallation of old fence posts, and Ana Po cut her thumb on a rose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Summers in the Arctic (and Newda architecture)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post here.
The Café Resmoiones approaches its hundredth birthday as the girls outside await their fifteenth. The building was once a kindergarten, so they’d been told, but through decades of Vekllei’s irreverent planning it had become a café. It was not a very good café, the food was shit, but the building was nice and it was at the bottom of Lola’s steep residential hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post here.
 Six bodies hung from the Rodney Creek Railroad Bridge, without names. The leftmost corpse, which was a boy, had a sign slung around his neck with tomorrow’s 8am train on it. Besides the swaying boy was his father, and next to him was his mother, and so it went down the railroad bridge, counting off his little sisters and grandmama and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching a steam locomotive to school</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Most of the kids pictured here are the cubs of lumberfolk who make a living out of felling hard pines in the mountains in the North of Vekllei. About half have dark hair and rounder faces, as descendants of both inuits and Scandinavians, and others are of mixed ancestry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora Desmoines, the Eternal Teen-ager and Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora. She goes by two names &amp;ndash; Tzipora, her birth name, and Zelda, a name she mistakenly thought sounded less Jewish. She lives in Lola in the Vekllei city-state.
As an immigrant, she struggles with school but holds her own on in track and field, an inversion of her otherwise quiet and bookish nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The participatory economy of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Nestled between the regional tram offices and the pre-war Ferouistet Department Store, the Lola district is not known for much but her department store and good schools. It sits on the slope of the wide Vekllei capital basin, where the Atlantic can be seen from the street. It was Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s first home in Vekllei, and it was where she lived with her father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dad&#39;s Birthday</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Littlest Goddess in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The Palace Gods live in decadence in an isolated and incestuous land above the mortal planes called the Palace. They do not eat and will live forever, provided they stay within the gardens of the Palace and consummate their industrial godhood occasionally with domen, an opium that they believe purifies blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young and Educated</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  lmao wish I had nice clothes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mineral Lake starts absorbing Grief in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Rena’s little boy was found in the closest town with his guts turned out and his throat cut. They didn’t tell it to Rena like that, but that’s what happened to him. His village and people, the Lehmanen, are descendants of Palace Gods forced out of the heavens some millennia ago over their refusal to smoke Domen, a sort of opium of the Gods and essential practice in the Palace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Celebration of all Women across the World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Vekllei on the first of each May, the women’s councils and industrial unions wipe clean their banners and flags and join great parades that regale the main streets of the city with song and colour. They carry flags and banners in celebration of womanhood and remembrance of the dead — for those Potter’s Fields and unmarked graves that intern nameless women across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Palace Gods attempt to retrieve their runaway child</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She could feel the wind rising. The horizon beyond was warped, caught in the distortion of a forested planetoid before them. The morning sun cast a honeyed warmth on her wings of black sugar, which sang like wind chimes as she soared high above the gem deserts below. Hyssop, her new and only friend, followed her ungracefully under the spell of his flystone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sugarhouse Mountain Fortress</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  A hundred years ago, the fortress existed as a spectre of the neighbouring villages; a beast of suffering and woe with fingers deep into the mountains around Montre. In the waning days of the military junta, the beast’s creators, the Sugarhouse Fort served as a strategic command centre for Vekllei’s nuclear arsenal and a blacksite to disappear the most prolific and dangerous agitators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Generation</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  We best know Vekllei as a dense society of utopia and great infrastructure today, but there was blood in that crucible. It is difficult to imagine that only fifty years ago these streets were unpaved and impassible with the rubble of old society. Shadows on concrete marked the souls lost in the arrogance of the monarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gem girl shows off her enormous strength in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The subcontinent of Zen on the Pachinki pangea is so weathered by enormous gem deserts that there is scarcely enough space to grow wheat for bread. In places where the soil is too thin for heavy wheats, sparrowgrass is grown. This grass has large heads that can be eaten raw and taste citrusy and acidic as they only grow in toxic soils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Childhood and Modernity</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Because the other girls would not stop calling her a lesbian, and because they had realised she was scared of loud noises and made use of that fact, Tzipora struck this bitch and her friend out beyond the football pitches after school. Tzipora was a good fighter — on her side is viciousness and a conviction to fight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas everyone (plus a little Christmas story)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She had always been a very serious girl, from the first time he’d met her. It was more than a reflection of character; it was how she talked, how she carried herself. Her clothes were plain, her nervous tics were not that funny, and she was afflicted with all sorts of fears and anxieties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Suburban Constabulary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The constabulary is old-fashioned and it can’t last forever. It predates Petticoat-era Vekllei, the previous regime lost to atomic ash, and even the monarchy itself — it was the first community militia of the country and a great deal of romanticism that had been lost in the death of the monarchy has been invested in them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
