<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ta8bwp/all_chapels_for_all_women/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,
For the people hear us singing, &amp;ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men—
For they are women&amp;rsquo;s children and we mother them again.
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes—
Hearts starve as well as bodies: Give us Bread, but give us Roses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people have a right to organise in their work. This principle is expressed in the structure of the economy, in which cooperative enterprises form company ballots that go on to inform commercial and industrial practice. Collections of individual trade unions may form bureaus, massive monopolies of organised workplaces cooperating and competing under the bizarre structure of the Vekllei moneyless economy. These are expressions of a mobilised democratic workforce which sustain the country in their self-interest, and are a defining characteristic of the Floral Period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation also exists outside the workplace. Their negotiations occur with the municipal and state authorities, and are a common means by which groups of people express their grievances and strengthen each other. The most well-known of these are Vekllei’s Chapel system — the unionisation of local women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapels are localised by community. Tzipora was at first very sceptical of the Chapels, which had offered her membership upon her arrival in Vekllei. You have to understand, Tzipora was in a crisis of inferiority at this time, and considered the ingratitude of the ungovernable female organisers to be naïve and entitled. She was convinced otherwise by Ayn, who was a moderate and carefully-spoken person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You want to integrate in Vekllei, don’t you?” She asked Tzipora. “This is what integration looks like; the Chapels are an expression of our democracy. A means of support and celebration; to have people know and care for you. There is no political commitment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora found Chapel meetings to be friendly and informal, characterised by shared meals and conversations of joys and grievances. Local Chapel № 23 was a social club of individuals made strong by their trust in each other. Tzipora sat silently at the end of the Chapel hall, an old concrete building with a flat roof built after the war. It had the appearance of a midcentury church. She ate her bread and sausage with her fingers and listened to the women talk amongst themselves. Children ran around, playing chasings. It was not like any place she’d been before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well-wishes to all this International Women’s Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Fantasy</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-14-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-14-papers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&#34;And who is this lady?&#34;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s Tora, a Palace God who comes to Pachinki,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, stumbling over her words. &amp;ldquo;The other Goddesses don&amp;rsquo;t like her much, um, and she&amp;rsquo;s quite powerful. She goes to Pachinki to unite mortals against the Palace.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I see,&amp;rdquo; Baron said, not following but nodding politely. &amp;ldquo;She looks a lot like you, doesn&amp;rsquo;t she?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, brushing away the question with another piece of paper pulled from her schoolbag. &amp;ldquo;This is her mortal bodyguard, Hyssop.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What kind of name is Hyssop?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s made up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I see. Why not use normal names?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Because I keep telling you, it&amp;rsquo;s not a normal world, it&amp;rsquo;s a completely different one,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora whined in that way she did when you weren&amp;rsquo;t keeping up. &amp;ldquo;Hyssop means &amp;lsquo;Guardian of the Poor&amp;rsquo; in his language, so it&amp;rsquo;s sort of a metaphor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve put a lot of thought into this.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora talked fast and anxiously. Pachinki was a private fantasy &amp;ndash; a dreamscape of magic and planets and monsters. She was showing Baron her drawings because she shared everything with him. But now, in his hands, her drawings looked all wrong. The people looked weird and her story seemed childish. It was embarrassing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;The Palace only exists because they believe in themselves&amp;hellip; The moment they lose faith, they lose their powers and collapse their space in the Marble Realm,&amp;rdquo; she said, then stopped and rubbed her nose. &amp;ldquo;Sorry, I&amp;rsquo;m just going on and on. I get boring quickly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, you don&amp;rsquo;t,&amp;rdquo; Baron said. &amp;ldquo;Is Tora planning to rob them of their faith?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you mean it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mean what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not being tedious?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, of course not. I want to know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked relieved and rubbed her nose again. &amp;ldquo;Yes, she does, but it&amp;rsquo;s not that simple. You see&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They sat there in the afternoon sun for over an hour, talking, shuffling papers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Rivers of the Atlantic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-01-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-01-rivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ This character was illustrated as a gift to my friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Qweezi1&#34;&gt;Qweezi&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy Birthday!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Vekllei, you met all sorts of people&lt;/strong&gt;. All nations passed through the Home Islands, some to visit, others to live. Tzipora met a great many of them in her time at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sydney came from Kosava, an anarchist island commune in the Lesser Antilles we know as St Kitts and Nevis. Kosava is an independent member-state of the Kalina Islands, which describes a series of autonomous islands in the Caribbean. Together, they form the Kalina Sovereign, an independent full member of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Atlantic Commonwealth,&amp;rdquo; which is something between a federation and a superstate. It was anarchism in the confusing Vekllei sense of the word &amp;ndash; self-organising, democratic, and totally dependent on bureau overproduction to furnish the gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commonwealth members, including Vekllei, are united in a belief in Floral Economics and share a lot of social features between them, including education, security, healthcare and bureau labour. A Kalinago girl is not that different from her sister in Vekllei, so it turns out. Together they represent a vanguard of island states in the Atlantic, a self-determining Commonwealth of different people resisting the hegemonies of Europe and the Americas with new ways of living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hitori was like Tzipora; she was not from Vekllei. Her parents were Japanese and she&amp;rsquo;d come here as a baby. It seemed like every second person was an immigrant, which indicated a shift in what &amp;ldquo;Vekllei&amp;rdquo; meant in the 21st Century. Under the various regimes of the Junta, it had been a colonial turn-of-phrase to describe the Algic-European metropole in the Home Islands. These days, it was more open-ended and democratic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has been multicultural since its origins as a meeting place of Scandinavian and Algic peoples. Today is no different, except its promise reaches farther and many more are arriving than before. Things are going well in Vekllei, and the quality of life can be exquisite &amp;ndash; provided you have certain expectations of what an &amp;ldquo;exquisite life&amp;rdquo; looks like. That was what kept people coming; an emerging Vekllei and the happiness of their children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes to the Patreon</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-12-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-12-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This post&lt;/strong&gt; announced changes made for patrons of Vekllei. Read and discuss the changes made in this post on Patreon &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/posts/changes-to-61071775&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;




  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/s2ah5p/changes_to_the_petticoat_patreon/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart here, creator of this whole thing. For a couple years now I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained a small &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt; for those interested in supporting my work. Like most Patreons, this has operated monthly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on, &lt;strong&gt;patrons will only be charged on the release of a comic chapter&lt;/strong&gt;. This could be once a month, but will more likely be a bit longer. This means a little less money for me, but also less anxiety about producing enough public work to earn the money pledged to me. It seems more fair, and the comic will be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what will change? For patrons, &lt;strong&gt;nothing will change except that you will be charged less frequently&lt;/strong&gt;. You will continue to recieve precisely the same benefits I&amp;rsquo;ve promised, including future merch and roles on the Vekllei Discord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will continue to produce standalone posts,&lt;/strong&gt; much as I always have &amp;ndash; but instead of battling a creeping anxiety of losing patrons if I don&amp;rsquo;t meet a post quota, I&amp;rsquo;ll be working more creatively and flexibly according to the needs of the comic. My work will be better for it, I reckon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supporters will now be charged on the release of each chapter of the comic, instead of monthly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merch and Discord rewards will be the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You won&amp;rsquo;t pay as frequently and will get more for your money as chapters come out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to support me in other ways, maybe buy a postcard when the MillMint Shop launches!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, just leave a comment below and I&amp;rsquo;ll help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks always,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart/MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;Discuss on the Vekllei Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policing Anarchy</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-11-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-11-police/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/s1ipe4/policing_anarchy/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;police-in-the-epoch-of-rest&#34;&gt;Police in the Epoch of Rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is a place divided between public and private spaces. The public markets are very public — centralised, controlled, documented and secure. The private markets are very private — anarchic, wide-ranging, interpersonal and unseen. Police in Vekllei work in both of these spaces, maintaining the peace and navigating their unique criminal topography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has three police forces, one for each of its features as a country. These are the Police of the Public, Parliament, and Crown, reflecting the people, state and sovereign of Vekllei respectively. The diagram attached depicts seasonal variants of male and female uniforms, as well as some of their equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosmopor--the-police-of-the-public&#34;&gt;Cosmopor — the Police of the Public&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmopor&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;comoisniyan denporitsa&lt;/em&gt;, lit. Public Police) are divided between municipalities in neighbourhoods known as commissions. A commission is lead by an Inspector or Qualified Constable. Each neighbourhood commission, which might comprise an area of thousands of people, is further subdivided in constabularies, which are lead by — somewhat predictably — a constable. The constable knows each person in their constabulary, and visits each residence regularly to confirm the welfare of their community and hear their grievances. Neighbourhoods in Vekllei are quite autonomous and culturally distinct, and so are its Public Police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their uniforms are modest and pleasant, and like other uniforms in the country have multiple components that are worn at the discretion of the officer in day-to-day duties. Uniforms depicted in this graphic are mostly fully-featured as to demonstrate full dress uniform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public Police carry rubber or extendable batons as well as a pistol, usually a revolver. Some choose not to carry a sidearm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;venopor--the-police-of-the-parliament&#34;&gt;Venopor — the Police of the Parliament&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venopor&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;fedecenoayan porits&lt;/em&gt;, lit. Parliament Police) are the national police who deal with violent crime and matters of importance to the state. They have a reputation for being heavy-handed when confronted, and are widely respected. In summer, women wear a short half-cape (called a capeteht or “small cape”), and both men and women wear long wool capes in winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth remembering that the Venopor are servants of the state and rule of law first, and serve many police duties that are legally distinct from the Police of the Public. These include rapid response to and reinforcement of the Public Police, special persons protection, infrastructure security, and counterterrorism. The Police of the Parliament include many different branches, including Vekllei’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-14-coastguard/&#34;&gt;Coast Guard&lt;/a&gt; and its &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/&#34;&gt;Gold Sappers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They carry sabres, which are still in use in Vekllei today — perhaps the only Western country in which they are useful equipment. All Venopor staff are trained in use of a sabre, which is fairly blunt and rarely causes deep cuts. They are used to sweep crowds, to point and command, and against people carrying blades. More common methods of subjugation are a whack with the hilt of the blade — a chance to move along before meeting the business end. Although women have the option of carrying a rubber baton in daily patrols, they don’t have the intimidation effect of the sabre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their uniforms are inherited from the Royal Guards of the prewar Junta years, with some floral-period modernisations. In some cases the Venopor may carry machine guns, particularly around government buildings and essential infrastructure — usually a domestic variant of the Israeli Uzi family. In these duties, they may also wear military-style helmets. They are a the floral-period descendants of a police tradition that has lasted a thousand years, and take their work seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;auspor--the-police-of-the-crown&#34;&gt;Auspor — the Police of the Crown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auspor&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;ausiosmayan porits&lt;/em&gt;, lit. Police of the Land) are the police of Vekllei’s “Crown”. This means they serve a body called the Landscape Sovereign, which is not a human person but a metaphysical abstraction of all of Vekllei’s physical territory. They swear their oath to the Sovereign — not to Vekllei’s people or its government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the Venopor, the Police of the Crown are a paramilitary force equipped primarily to confront crimes against the environment, the country’s biosecurity, and its immigration and customs. The military police of the Crown Armed Forces are also part of Auspor, since Vekllei’s military also serves the Sovereign. This means that Auspor polices criminal acts of and against the army, including tribunal courts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, Auspor includes several unique branches of policing relevant to environmental emergencies, including diving recovery squads, ranger units for patrolling forest and tundra alike, and remote search outfits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of their variety of work, the uniforms depicted here are a sample of rangers employed in policing national parks and Crown Lands, which have natural borders with Vekllei. The appearance of Auspor officers varies wildly, since it includes both customs officers and skilled animal trackers alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-03-100-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-03-100-days/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/rv57tb/100_days_of_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is 2022, Year of Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next 100 days I’m going to do something for Vekllei every day. These &amp;lsquo;somethings&amp;rsquo; could be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts you see, exploring Vekllei&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Articles on &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net&#34;&gt;the website&lt;/a&gt;, including upcoming pages on Government and new character pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inking of comic pages &amp;ndash; leading up to a release soon. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming but it&amp;rsquo;ll be worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New illustrations for use in merchandise(!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on new website features or the upcoming MillMint shop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2021 was a pretty bad year. I won’t go on about it much because it’s not very interesting and it’s not the point of my writing this. Let&amp;rsquo;s only hope suffering makes good art!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last year, I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished what I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to finish, and it&amp;rsquo;s caused some anxiety for me for months now. This is my New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution to you all, including my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;beloved patrons&lt;/a&gt;, who I thank sincerely for sticking with me through a really inconsistent creative period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions are kind of corny, and they don&amp;rsquo;t work out for everyone. So don&amp;rsquo;t think of this as a resolution as such &amp;ndash; 2022 is a nice even number, and it&amp;rsquo;s a good time, arbitrary as any other, for a change in the winds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to have something to show every other day or so. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a long list of ideas I&amp;rsquo;m going to work through. Hopefully this will provoke a change in behaviour from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not join me? Pick up a pencil and I&amp;rsquo;ll draw with you. You can come say hi at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;Vekllei Discord server&lt;/a&gt; and catch me drawing sometime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again. I&amp;rsquo;m only at the start of the journey here. But this community is where it begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warm regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart/MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-01-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-01-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;Welcome to 2022,&lt;/strong&gt; year of Vekllei. Here&amp;rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&amp;rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>