<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>2022 on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2022/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2022 on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Sepia Interests</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sepia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sepia/</guid>
	  <description>The so-called Scandinationalists have a thousand years of myth in their pamphlets, but are in reality a product of the Atomic War. Racial nationalism has existed in Vekllei for centuries, but was only legitimised as a modern political force by the pre-war junta and materialised as violence by its collapse in the days after the Atomic War. Exploited grievances, hundreds in number but all basically the same, overflowed in the chaos of the war and saw savage criminal instincts acted on by militias called Stanis.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Back to Basics — A MillMint Blog</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/blog/utopia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/blog/utopia/</guid>
	  <description>The way I&amp;rsquo;m doing things now isn&amp;rsquo;t working &amp;ndash; I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy social media, or marketing my work. I haven&amp;rsquo;t done much to grow my audience these last few years. And I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by unfinished projects; difficult and wonderful things that refuse to move.
2022 is the end of the COVID era for me. I&amp;rsquo;m moving house again, moving around again (🇬🇧🇫🇷🇭🇷🇲🇪). These are all good things. I&amp;rsquo;m healthier when I&amp;rsquo;m learning, and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot these last couple months.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Silica Rivers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/silica/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/silica/</guid>
	  <description>Warm silica rivers flow through the grounds of the Moshel St School. They carry on from there, cascading down the terraces of Lola through rivulets and creeks until they meet the sea. You weren&amp;rsquo;t supposed to bathe in them because they were full of &amp;ldquo;hellpoints&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; hotspots that would burn you badly. Thick plumes of steam rise from where a hellpoint meets the air.
The algae and silica in the water is good for your skin, and has antibacterial properties.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sleep</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sleep/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sleep/</guid>
	  <description> Spiritual sequel to this post. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Teachers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/teachers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/teachers/</guid>
	  <description>From left: Ms Ninčić, Tzipora, Mr Kowalczyk. On the left is Ms Zora Ninčić, and on the right Mr Kowalczyk. Students joke that they must be brother and sister because they look similar, but they&amp;rsquo;re unrelated. Ms Ninčić teaches social sciences, and Mr Kowalczyk teaches chemistry.
Tzipora is a somewhat poor student, but she is well-loved by these teachers, and they go above and beyond in helping Tzipora muster the grades she&amp;rsquo;ll need to go on to university.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tee Shirt</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/teeshirt/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/teeshirt/</guid>
	  <description> Long tee shirt, the only shirt she wears out untucked. Good for painting houses in. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Riot</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/watch/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/watch/</guid>
	  <description> All the street was out on the stair, listening to the distant roar of people and baton rounds and sirens, trying to figure if they were moving closer. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Caribbean Uniforms</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/caribbean-uniform/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/caribbean-uniform/</guid>
	  <description>Demonstration of personalised aspects of the modular Caribbean Commonwealth uniform system. The residents of the Kalina Isles are mostly indigenous Caribs and Afro-Caribbean Garínagu, who in the 21st Century are part of a large multinational and multiethnic commonwealth of autonomous nation states. The Vekllei 4th Commonwealth, as it is now known, stretches all the way from Demon in the North Atlantic to the Antarctic Territories in the south. Although it consists of dozens of independent and self-governing nation-states, they are closely bound by shared political interests in the Atlantic and have significant commitments to the international Commonwealth parliament that legislates and shares features of these countries.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Five Years</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/five-years/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/five-years/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora is communicating the birthday rune in Upotenne, a warding sigil of good luck. Today, the subreddit is five years old. A better anniversary for this project would have been July 1st 2022 &amp;ndash; the date of my first reddit post &amp;ndash; but I missed that anniversary completely. This post is a late 5 year celebration of Vekllei. Next year I&amp;rsquo;ll celebrate with you properly on International Tzipora Day (July 1st 2023, write it down).</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Rifles Section</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/rifles/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/rifles/</guid>
	  <description>The Public Police (COSMOPOR) are not reliably equipped with firearms, and when they are, constables favour old-fashioned police revolvers. Situations that get dangerous or complicated often require the intervention of the Rifles Section of the Parliament Police, an elite policing unit trained and equipped to confront gun crime and violent behaviour.
Like some other other Parliament Police (VENOPOR) sections, the Rifles are dressed in navy silks and their mounts are painted navy with white sillitoe-patterned highlights.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Off Again</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/uk/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/uk/</guid>
	  <description>The last time I made one of these, it was January 2020. When I got back, the news was just starting to talk about a new disease outbreak in China.
It is striking to me that the shitty drawing attached to that post was the last time I went overseas. On an abstract level I can understand it&amp;rsquo;s been two years &amp;ndash; but wow, that drawing puts things in perspective. And since that post, I&amp;rsquo;ve been stuck in my house in Hobart, occasionally visiting other parts of my beautiful island state of Tasmania.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Scouts</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/puffin/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/puffin/</guid>
	  <description>The Scouts de Vous Seispri Votaisre (lit. Scouts Interior Spirit Corps) is a corps of the Commonwealth Army, modelled after the worldwide scouting association. This unusual intersection &amp;ndash; of a noncombatant youth organisation and the armed forces &amp;ndash; is typical in Vekllei, where many aspects of the military serve social roles. For example, the Vekllei Fire Service and the Royal Mail are both corps of the Commonwealth Army. To this end, the Scouts Corps (better known as Puffin Scouts overseas) has different traditions depending on which brigade it belongs to.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Lola, Borough of Genesis</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/lola/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/lola/</guid>
	  <description>Genesis of Utopia # Vekllei did not originate in Lola &amp;ndash; according to the Saga of Origins, Vekllei emerged from the corpse of a petty creator god named Oslola. But there was some truth in casting Lola as the genesis of the Vekllei nation-state, since this is where Scandinavian settlers first landed over three thousand years ago, and was where the 1st and 2nd Commonwealths consolidated their power and united the Vekllei Islands.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Story Trailer</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/trailer/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/trailer/</guid>
	  <description> No, I&amp;rsquo;m not making an low-budget 1980s television anime (yet). Yes, I&amp;rsquo;d like to. Click here to watch with sound. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Stories from the Horizon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/horizon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/horizon/</guid>
	  <description>A New Format for Stories from Vekllei # Vekllei has one hundred boroughs that are usually characterised as the foundation of the Vekllei city-state. Some, like Bakur, have only a few thousand people in them. Others, like the Great Coast, have over a million.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on this project for a while now, about five years counting backwards, and in that time what Vekllei means to me has matured.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Crown and the Gi</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/crown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/crown/</guid>
	  <description>The Crown # The crown depicted here is not the actual crown of the Vekllei Sovereign,1 but in fact the national hat of Vekllei and is part of traditional dress. This &amp;lsquo;crown,&amp;rsquo; so-called, is a felt or velvet hat with two peaks and a tall, narrow brim stitched with traditional patterns in gold thread. Historically, the crown was a work hat made of leather and wool, but today it is designed primarily for fashion and comfort, and is most commonly seen at ceremonies, schools and some professions like the Public Police.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Caught Sketching</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sketching/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sketching/</guid>
	  <description> He had a tin in his hands. She liked seeing the soldiers on patrol. He caught her staring. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Waiting for a Movie</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/movie/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/movie/</guid>
	  <description>✿ This image was part of an art trade with my friend JM. Thank you JM. This picture features his red-head character, Isabeau. See his drawing of Tzipora and Isabeau down below. Most Vekllei people do not own a television, so they go to movie theatres. Even though personal appliances are abundant in the U.S. and Europe, they are in constant shortage for almost all classes of Vekllei people, and so the social tradition of the cinema is alive and well.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>School Cape</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/cape/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/cape/</guid>
	  <description>A Uniform for All Seasons # Vekllei students are internationally renowned for their elegant and, in places, decadent uniforms. This reputation is built on an open-ended, modular uniform system that can be distilled into a simple assemblage of white, navy, gold and red. The spoken guidelines and unspoken curation of the Vekllei uniform system contributes to the variety and personality of Vekllei studentry, and is iconic of the country overseas.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Little Hyderabad</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hyderabad/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hyderabad/</guid>
	  <description>Little Hyderabad # Little Hyderabad is a community in the Great Coast, and is one of the few remaining ethnic enclaves in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s postwar period. It&amp;rsquo;s not that immigrants are rare &amp;ndash; on the contrary, about half the people you see in the street were born overseas. But the chaos of British occupation was far behind them now, and the government is more considerate in how it scatters immigrants across the boroughs.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Café Diplomacy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/vista/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/vista/</guid>
	  <description>Instafilm #445. Marked &amp;ldquo;2064&amp;rdquo;. Month of the Mosses. You remembered that because it was about the same time war broke out in the Congo again. Everyone at the table had opinions about that war, but not much to do with it. Everyone asked Coretti what she thought about the war. She hated that, she hated being singled out for it. Coretti had been two years old when she left the Congo.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Vekllei Spaceship</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/lightbulb/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/lightbulb/</guid>
	  <description>A New Frontier # The stars are close to Vekllei. The common availability of space travel is the most wonderful achievement of Vekllei aerospace. It lights the furthest corners of the imagination in the postwar Vekllei spirit of play and dreams. The democratisation of space travel is in fact the democratisation of space itself, and so essential to the realisation of the Vekllei dream — as on Earth, so in the stars.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Municipal</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/municipal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/municipal/</guid>
	  <description>The base unit of Vekllei society are municipalities, called municipolis in their language. They occupy a uniquely intimate presence in Vekllei life as an unusual body of public affairs. Unlike other state bodies in Vekllei, which function similar to their overseas counterparts, local municipalities supersede their conventional definition as mere &amp;rsquo;local governments&amp;rsquo; and are considerably more essential to the wellbeing of Vekllei communities.
In Vekllei, the word municipolis refers to</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Panaderas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/panaderas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/panaderas/</guid>
	  <description>She was in Lo, at the end of its winding river, standing in the place where the interior rains met the warm currents of the ocean. A mechanical clicking annoyed her but she could not tell if it was coming from the telephone exchange box or the electric street light above her head. It had just rained and it was a cold rain, so the air was sharp, and hurt and excited her lungs.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Towers in the Park</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/towers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/towers/</guid>
	  <description>Merce was one of seven sisters but she didn’t know it. Like many Vekllei people in young adulthood, her parents were born overseas, and so her Spanish heritage was somewhat obscured.
Growing up in postwar Vekllei, you develop an unusual esprit de corps which supersedes almost everything about you — a civic mission to establish a place in the world regardless of your prior circumstance or heritage. This well-intentioned internationalism cut both ways; you were not much judged about where you came from, but you also did not talk much about where you came from.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Transmission Towers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/transmission/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/transmission/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora finished most school days at two in the afternoon. Her routine looked something like this. Catch the tram home. Walk if the weather is &amp;lsquo;interesting&amp;rsquo; (dramatic). Unlock the apartment and exchange her shoes for sandals. Bring in the bedding airing in the backyard and say hello to the stripy stray cat. Put away her books and rinse her lunchbox. Set the meat out to defrost and boil and refrigerate the water.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Contrails</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/contrails/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/contrails/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei has the some of the clearest skies in the world, and they are criss-crossed by distant vapour trails of jets coming and going. They bring the world closer together. It was funny to think that Peking and Tokyo were just a few hours away &amp;ndash; it felt very cosmopolitan; very democratic. It emphasised the smallness of the world.
Tzipora would look at the livery of the planes to figure out where they were going.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>In-Between Stations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/liminal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/liminal/</guid>
	  <description>Out on the branch lines there are in-between stations. Sometimes they emerge out of history as relics of dead and dying towns overlooked by the timetable. Others are a quirk of the rail company machine &amp;ndash; workshops and line junctions where people switch trains. As you get further and further out of the city, and the trains get older and older, these in-between stations become more common. Between Yana and Kotaismoyeh there is an irregular line serviced by steam trains that are over a hundred years old.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Lunch in the Park</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/wine/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/wine/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei has several cold-weather wine producing regions in its south, concentrated around the boroughs of Horn and Mopapa. Local staples are hearty reds like cabernet sauvignon and pinot noir, since whites are served with dessert or as apéritifs. Wine in Vekllei is a product of mass consumption, and is often drunk with meals even by teenagers.
Tzipora liked the drowsy, warming feeling of it. She liked it so much that she kept clear of it except on occasions.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Kicking the Habit, Pt. 1 of 12</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/habit/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/habit/</guid>
	  <description> Tzipora doesn&amp;rsquo;t smoke anymore. She prefers Camel. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>School Lunch</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/lunch/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/lunch/</guid>
	  <description>✿ Read more: A Vekllei Breakfast In Vekllei schools, they take an hour and a half for lunch most days. Food is a complicated subject here, as a ubiquitous demonstration of the Vekllei cultural tradition and its relative scarcity compared to consumer societies.
Food unable to be grown for the house is usually obtained from grocers. Those grocers put in orders for produce from agricultural companies or their representatives — usually ‘petty’ (informal) bureaus.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/chapel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/chapel/</guid>
	  <description>As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,
For the people hear us singing, &amp;ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&amp;rdquo;
As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &amp;ndash;
For they are women&amp;rsquo;s children and we mother them again.
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &amp;ndash;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Private Fantasy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/drawing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/drawing/</guid>
	  <description>&#34;And who is this lady?&#34; &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s Tora, a Palace God who comes to Pachinki,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, stumbling over her words. &amp;ldquo;The other Goddesses don&amp;rsquo;t like her much, um, and she&amp;rsquo;s quite powerful. She goes to Pachinki to unite mortals against the Palace.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I see,&amp;rdquo; Baron said, not following but nodding politely. &amp;ldquo;She looks a lot like you, doesn&amp;rsquo;t she?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Oh, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, brushing away the question with another piece of paper pulled from her schoolbag.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Rivers of the Atlantic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/rivers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/rivers/</guid>
	  <description>✿ This character was illustrated as a gift to my friend Qweezi. Happy Birthday! In Vekllei, you met all sorts of people. All nations passed through the Home Islands, some to visit, others to live. Tzipora met a great many of them in her time at school.
Sydney came from Kosava, an anarchist island commune in the Lesser Antilles we know as St Kitts and Nevis. Kosava is an independent member-state of the Kalina Islands, which describes a series of autonomous islands in the Caribbean.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Changes to the Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/reading/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/reading/</guid>
	  <description>✿ This post announced changes made for patrons of Vekllei. Read and discuss the changes made in this post on Patreon here. Hello everyone,
Hobart here, creator of this whole thing. For a couple years now I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained a small Patreon for those interested in supporting my work. Like most Patreons, this has operated monthly.
From now on, patrons will only be charged on the release of a comic chapter.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Policing Anarchy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/police/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/police/</guid>
	  <description>Police in the Epoch of Rest # Vekllei is a place divided between public and private spaces. The public markets are very public — centralised, controlled, documented and secure. The private markets are very private — anarchic, wide-ranging, interpersonal and unseen. Police in Vekllei work in both of these spaces, maintaining the peace and navigating their unique criminal topography.
Vekllei has three police forces, one for each of its features as a country.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>100 Days of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/showa/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/showa/</guid>
	  <description>Hello everyone,
This is 2022, Year of Vekllei.
For the next 100 days I’m going to do something for Vekllei every day. These &amp;lsquo;somethings&amp;rsquo; could be
Posts you see, exploring Vekllei Articles on the website, including upcoming pages on Government and new character pages. Inking of comic pages &amp;ndash; leading up to a release soon. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming but it&amp;rsquo;ll be worth it. New illustrations for use in merchandise(!</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</guid>
	  <description>✿ Welcome to 2022, year of Vekllei. Here&amp;rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love. Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&amp;rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>