<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>2022 on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2022/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2022 on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>A Vekllei Spaceship</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-30-spaceship/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-30-spaceship/</guid>
	  <description>A New Frontier The stars are close to Vekllei.
The common availability of space travel is the most wonderful achievement of Vekllei aerospace. It lights the furthest corners of the imagination in the postwar Vekllei spirit of play and dreams. The democratisation of space travel is in fact the democratisation of space itself, and so essential to the realisation of the Vekllei dream — as on Earth, so in the stars.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Municipal</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-08-municipal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-08-municipal/</guid>
	  <description>The base unit of Vekllei society are municipalities, called municipolis in their language. They occupy a uniquely intimate presence in Vekllei life as an unusual body of public affairs. Unlike other state bodies in Vekllei, which function similar to their overseas counterparts, local municipalities supersede their conventional definition as mere &amp;lsquo;local governments&amp;rsquo; and are considerably more essential to the wellbeing of Vekllei communities.
In Vekllei, the word municipolis refers to</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Panaderas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-02-panaderas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-02-panaderas/</guid>
	  <description>She was in Lo, at the end of its winding river, standing in the place where the interior rains met the warm currents of the ocean. A mechanical clicking annoyed her but she could not tell if it was coming from the telephone exchange box or the electric street light above her head. It had just rained and it was a cold rain, so the air was sharp, and hurt and excited her lungs.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Towers in the Park</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-04-24-towers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-04-24-towers/</guid>
	  <description>Merce was one of seven sisters but she didn’t know it. Like many Vekllei people in young adulthood, her parents were born overseas, and so her Spanish heritage was somewhat obscured.
Growing up in postwar Vekllei, you develop an unusual esprit de corps which supersedes almost everything about you — a civic mission to establish a place in the world regardless of your prior circumstance or heritage. This well-intentioned internationalism cut both ways; you were not much judged about where you came from, but you also did not talk much about where you came from.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Transmission Towers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-23-transmission/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-23-transmission/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora finished most school days at two in the afternoon. Her routine looked something like this:
Catch the tram home. Walk if the weather is &amp;lsquo;interesting&amp;rsquo; (dramatic). Unlock the apartment and exchange her shoes for sandals. Bring in the bedding airing in the backyard and say hello to the stripy stray cat. Put away her books and rinse her lunchbox. Set the meat out to defrost and boil and refrigerate the water.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Contrails</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-17-jets/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-17-jets/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei has the some of the clearest skies in the world, and they are criss-crossed by distant vapour trails of jets coming and going. They bring the world closer together. It was funny to think that Peking and Tokyo were just a few hours away &amp;ndash; it felt very cosmopolitan; very democratic. It emphasised the smallness of the world.
Tzipora would look at the livery of the planes to figure out where they were going.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>In-Between Stations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-16-liminal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-16-liminal/</guid>
	  <description>Out on the branch lines there are in-between stations. Sometimes they emerge out of history as relics of dead and dying towns overlooked by the timetable. Others are a quirk of the rail company machine &amp;ndash; workshops and line junctions where people switch trains. As you get further and further out of the city, and the trains get older and older, these in-between stations become more common. Between Yana and Kotaismoyeh there is an irregular line serviced by steam trains that are over a hundred years old.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Lunch in the Park</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-15-wine/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-15-wine/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei has several cold-weather wine producing regions in its south, concentrated around the boroughs of Horn and Mopapa. Local staples are hearty reds like cabernet sauvignon and pinot noir, since whites are served with dessert or as apéritifs. Wine in Vekllei is a product of mass consumption, and is often drunk with meals even by teenagers.
Tzipora liked the drowsy, warming feeling of it. She liked it so much that she kept clear of it except on occasions.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Kicking the Habit, Pt. 1 of 12</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-14-habit/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-14-habit/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora doesn&amp;rsquo;t smoke anymore. She prefers Camel.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>School Lunch</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-13-school-lunch/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-13-school-lunch/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Read more: A Vekllei Breakfast  In Vekllei schools, they take an hour and a half for lunch most days. Food is a complicated subject here, as a ubiquitous demonstration of the Vekllei cultural tradition and its relative scarcity compared to consumer societies.
Food unable to be grown for the house is usually obtained from grocers. Those grocers put in orders for produce from agricultural companies or their representatives — usually ‘petty’ (informal) bureaus.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</guid>
	  <description>As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,
For the people hear us singing, &amp;ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&amp;rdquo;
  As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &amp;ndash;
For they are women&amp;rsquo;s children and we mother them again.
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &amp;ndash;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Private Fantasy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-14-papers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-14-papers/</guid>
	  <description>&#34;And who is this lady?&#34; &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s Tora, a Palace God who comes to Pachinki,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, stumbling over her words. &amp;ldquo;The other Goddesses don&amp;rsquo;t like her much, um, and she&amp;rsquo;s quite powerful. She goes to Pachinki to unite mortals against the Palace.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I see,&amp;rdquo; Baron said, not following but nodding politely. &amp;ldquo;She looks a lot like you, doesn&amp;rsquo;t she?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Oh, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, brushing away the question with another piece of paper pulled from her schoolbag.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Rivers of the Atlantic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-01-rivers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-01-rivers/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This character was illustrated as a gift to my friend Qweezi. Happy Birthday!  In Vekllei, you met all sorts of people. All nations passed through the Home Islands, some to visit, others to live. Tzipora met a great many of them in her time at school.
Sydney came from Kosava, an anarchist island commune in the Lesser Antilles we know as St Kitts and Nevis. Kosava is an independent member-state of the Kalina Islands, which describes a series of autonomous islands in the Caribbean.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Changes to the Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-12-reading/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-12-reading/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This post announced changes made for patrons of Vekllei. Read and discuss the changes made in this post on Patreon here.  Hello everyone,
Hobart here, creator of this whole thing. For a couple years now I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained a small Patreon for those interested in supporting my work. Like most Patreons, this has operated monthly.
From now on, patrons will only be charged on the release of a comic chapter.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Policing Anarchy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-11-police/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-11-police/</guid>
	  <description>Police in the Epoch of Rest Vekllei is a place divided between public and private spaces. The public markets are very public — centralised, controlled, documented and secure. The private markets are very private — anarchic, wide-ranging, interpersonal and unseen. Police in Vekllei work in both of these spaces, maintaining the peace and navigating their unique criminal topography.
Vekllei has three police forces, one for each of its features as a country.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>100 Days of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-03-100-days/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-03-100-days/</guid>
	  <description>Hello everyone,
This is 2022, Year of Vekllei.
For the next 100 days I’m going to do something for Vekllei every day. These &amp;lsquo;somethings&amp;rsquo; could be
 Posts you see, exploring Vekllei Articles on the website, including upcoming pages on Government and new character pages. Inking of comic pages &amp;ndash; leading up to a release soon. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming but it&amp;rsquo;ll be worth it. New illustrations for use in merchandise(!</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-01-new-year/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-01-new-year/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Welcome to 2022, year of Vekllei. Here&amp;rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love.  Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&amp;rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The West Coast of Tasmania</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/blog/2021-06-15-west/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/blog/2021-06-15-west/</guid>
	  <description>A shining beacon in the dull, uniform and largely artificial world
 &amp;ndash; Olegas Truchanas (1923-1972)
These photos were taken across two trips to the West Coast of Tasmania. The first was in September 2020. The second was in April 2021. Each time it took about four or five hours to get there, driving along the only road that cuts through the Tasmanian Wilderness World Heritage Area. It includes about a fifth of Tasmania&amp;rsquo;s landmass, covering almost all of the southwest.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>