<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>tzafi on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/tzafi/</link>
	<description>Recent content in tzafi on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/tzafi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Policing Anarchy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/police/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/police/</guid>
	  <description>Police in the Epoch of Rest # Vekllei is a place divided between public and private spaces. The public markets are very public — centralised, controlled, documented and secure. The private markets are very private — anarchic, wide-ranging, interpersonal and unseen. Police in Vekllei work in both of these spaces, maintaining the peace and navigating their unique criminal topography.
Vekllei has three police forces, one for each of its features as a country.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Welcome to 2022, year of Vekllei. Here&amp;rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love. Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&amp;rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Station Logic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/station-logic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/station-logic/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei is full of stations in the middle of nowhere; platforms for people in no hurry, alighting to places never thought of before. It is in these stations that old government infrastructure projects take on a greater meaning, and cultivate an absurd sort of spirituality that touches the lives of the people who discover them. Is there anything gentler than a concrete platform in the middle of a flower-tundra, weathered and warmed by the sun?</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>