<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pachinki on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/pachinki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pachinki on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/pachinki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Littlest Goddess in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.The Palace Gods live in decadence in an isolated and incestuous land above the mortal planes called the Palace. They do not eat and will live forever, provided they stay within the gardens of the Palace and consummate their industrial godhood occasionally with domen, an opium that they believe purifies blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mineral Lake starts absorbing Grief in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.Rena’s little boy was found in the closest town with his guts turned out and his throat cut. They didn’t tell it to Rena like that, but that’s what happened to him. His village and people, the Lehmanen, are descendants of Palace Gods forced out of the heavens some millennia ago over their refusal to smoke Domen, a sort of opium of the Gods and essential practice in the Palace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gem girl shows off her enormous strength in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.The subcontinent of Zen on the Pachinki pangea is so weathered by enormous gem deserts that there is scarcely enough space to grow wheat for bread. In places where the soil is too thin for heavy wheats, sparrowgrass is grown. This grass has large heads that can be eaten raw and taste citrusy and acidic as they only grow in toxic soils.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
