<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pachinki on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://beta.millmint.net/tags/pachinki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pachinki on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beta.millmint.net/tags/pachinki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Tzipora Christmas Story</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/kkmgdm/a_tzipora_christmas_story/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pachinki is a world of Tzipora’s own creation&lt;/strong&gt;, a dorky retreat from the difficulties she has in Vekllei. Tzipora always loved stories of wild places and adventure, and Pachinki blossomed organically from within her daydreams. Eventually she started writing and drawing it. When she was sad, bored or anxious, she would descend back into Pachinki’s world of ancient magic, edible gems and pirates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chapter she wrote in late November one year resembled her idea of a Christmas story, and so I’ve included a portion here to accompany this picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wrote,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story starts with the tale of a young Pilot Witch, whose job was to guide dead aircraft to safe airports in the shaky peace that followed the Black War. It had to be female witches, since men couldn’t see the dead. She would meet formations of heavy bombers and strike fighters stuffed with corpses out at sea and show them the safe paths to the landing strips, flying low and fast where the Palace Gods couldn’t see them. This was the safe part of the job, since the Palace Gods and Necropirates ambushed out at sea, where they could hide between the archipelagos. Over land, they were mostly safe. It was an important job. Without the witch’s guidance, these planes would navigate the world forever, circling overhead, still packed with bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witches would guide the dead airmen down to the ground, where they could finally be relieved of their duty and released with proper burial rights. The planes would be repaired and flown back to the royal palace in Lily. This young witch was glad it was once again peacetime; when the empires warred, they couldn’t keep up with the dead planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, she was told to meet a special transport delegation out at sea. They didn’t explain anything more. She flew out to the coast on her broom and the glint of a wingtip caught her eye. As it approached, her instinct flared with alarm. These were not dead planes — the crew in them were very much alive. She flew out and approached the largest aircraft in the formation, a transport bomber of a type she’d seen several times before. She landed atop the aircraft and made her way inside via a turret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s going on?” The witch asked, irritated at the break in procedure. The captain of the aircraft jumped at the noise, and straightened his shoulders as he addressed her pompously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’re here to guide us, are you? We’re from the Palace, in Lily.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I understand that; I saw your markings. But why’s it any of my business?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What do you mean, witch? We need safe passage, don’t we?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s not my trade; what are you doing this far out? Do you have any idea how dangerous these archipelagos are?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The captain snorted and resettled his cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know what time of year it is, don’t you? All five planets are above us, silly girl.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The other witches won’t like you coming in uninvited, I’ll have you warned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s nearly the time for the festival. The Queen wants fine gifts for the Princess, and she won’t do with any old hat or dress. We’re part of a military attaché that’s spent the last six months searching the lands for the finest gifts in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Gifts,” the witch said, betraying her surprise. “W-what sort of gifts?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, how about you head below deck and see for yourself. While you’re there, why don’t you pick something out? Provided we understand each other, of course.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, all right. Okay,” the witch said, and hurriedly turned away from the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, the witch was once again atop her broom, though somewhat unevenly under the weight of the largest gem necklace she’d ever seen. She couldn’t believe her luck; it was laden with Soup Gems, and they hadn’t been seen around here in nearly a hundred years. You only found them growing in the stomachs of the Kemi people, and they had been wiped out many eons ago. A gem like this would produce excellent powders, and make her very powerful for a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She resettled her pilot’s hat, and placed both hands on her broomstick. She felt the wind swirl around her as she shot to the front of the formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witch depicted here looks awfully like Tzipora, and that’s no coincidence. Tzipora is always somewhere in her own stories. She writes herself in because she likes to imagine herself living among these people, flying on broomsticks and becoming a powerful witch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These types of posts aren’t very regular, but they’re important for my health as an illustrator. Vekllei might be fantastical, but it’s a Cold War consumer society at the end of the day. Pachinki provides me (and Tzipora!) a fun holiday now and then, into a surreal world of planetoids and magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you have any questions. You can read other Pachinki posts (quite old now) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ar8jov/a_gem_girl_shows_off_her_enormous_strength_in/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ba3mb4/the_littlest_goddess_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/cudjz6/the_teeth_regents/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/b7n1uh/a_mineral_lake_starts_absorbing_grief_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/de25mz/the_mountain_witches_of_pachinki_and_the/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. That’s all of them, that’s all I’ve ever done. This project’s been going on for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart/MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mountain Witches of Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/de25mz/the_mountain_witches_of_pachinki_and_the/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pachinki is the fantastical notebook of Tzipora, in all her loneliness and thunderous imagination, shared with you all to enjoy. She&amp;rsquo;s so far constructed Pachinki posts about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ar8jov/a_gem_girl_shows_off_her_enormous_strength_in/&#34;&gt;gem children&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/user/MelonKony/comments/azmu94/the_palace_gods_attempt_to_retrieve_their_runaway/&#34;&gt;palace henchmen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/b7n1uh/a_mineral_lake_starts_absorbing_grief_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;sinister earth magics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ba3mb4/the_littlest_goddess_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;the Palace Gods&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cudfnv/the_teeth_regents/&#34;&gt;teeth regents.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Tzipora’s notebook:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[A Guide to Magic, Chapter 2: The Witch]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witches of Pachinki are an interesting affair — many books have been dedicated to their research after discovery, yet so little is known about them. They are almost universally misandrists, which is understandable considering their present illegality and persecution in the subcontinents of Zen and Domos. They serve only themselves and individuals they happen to like, and spend most of their lives exploring the canyon between the chaos of nature’s fundamental frequencies and the power of human magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are rumoured to be able to split their own minds. Using old spells long since lost to ordinary people in Zen, they are able to siphon their mental faculties into a trusted object — usually a precious gem, and relegate essential functions of the brain to it. For example, a witch might siphon a tenth of her mental ability into a necklace, which then pushes out whatever consciousness exists within then carries on a witch’s essential functions — respiration, blood circulation and pain are just a few of unconscious functions a witch might do away with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would they do such a thing? Well, it is known to all people who have ever attempted magics that powerful spells force great stress on the mind. In fact, the more thorough the subsumption of the mind towards the spell, the better the results. By dispensing with her bodily functions, a witch is able to dedicate almost all of her mental power towards the task at hand, and since a brain operating without vital functions is a very stressed brain indeed, she can become extraordinarily powerful as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such magical efforts make perfect sense for people of power — government workers, or traditional sorcerers — but witches are far more interested exploration and discovery than they are power and conquest. So again — why would they do such a thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only recently has a possible answer to this question arisen. It is disarmingly straightforward — witches are outcasts, and usually very lonely people. By siphoning enough of their own mind into a creature or pet, they replace the pet with a functioning copy of themselves. They are consequently able to make friends at will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a process is incredibly dangerous — although only a fraction of brainpower is required to make a functioning consciousness, they are in essence duplicating a human mind. To transplant a consciousness of human intuition into, say, a raven, requires powerful psychophysical drugs and gems of a correct frequency to stop a collapse of the mind (and subsequently render ten percent or so of the witch’s brain ability permanently nonfunctioning). Even upon a successful schism, her summoned consciousness is hardly a raven — it is an anthropomorphic creature, of human mind and animal body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fact of the witch, which may interest the reader, is that they do not decompose upon death. They are ordinary people in life, but ancient magic the likes of which is unobservable and unknowable keeps their body, intact or otherwise, totally preserved (though thoroughly dead). In kingdoms where witchcraft is a crime, you can find “witch towers” filled with the fresh, undead body parts of executed witches that will long outlive the grisly silos themselves…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Teeth Regents</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cudfnv/the_teeth_regents/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From the notebook of Tzipora:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total hedonism across a thousand generations produced the creature known as the ‘tooth regent’, who was a human by technicality but was built genetically only for consuming. His name was Arhen CIII, and where his ancestors had mouths, he had a thousand teeth that sat in messy rows to the back of his throat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three times a day his mouth had to be washed by palace maidens, and excess teeth brushed off. At night, as he slept, the teeth would grow back and occasionally sprout from his cheeks and chin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was one of the most powerful men in all of Zen, the land of gem deserts and magic, and tales of his brutality echoed among the large cities of the subcontinent. His jaws were mounted in his face like hunting traps, and upon bad news he would order the messenger’s hand to be placed in his mouth. That would clamp shut, the poor soul would scream, and minced meat would be spat out by the regent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a man built for consumption, luxury became lust. Like his father and his father’s father, he quickly became the richest oligarch of the Zo peninsula, acquiring old magic, artefacts, estates and fine foods like a glutton piles supper on a plate. It was not possession that motivated him, but acquisition and consumption, destroying hedonistically objects that might lift a thousand from poverty or heal the sick. The simple biological impulses of a human were so primitive compared to Arhen, who satisfied his genetics with an insatiable lust for growth and purchase. Over and over, the cycle would continue…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways, he was on his way to becoming a Palace God, in which the essence of his family dynasty was being rewritten to a higher place of purpose. But where the Palace Gods derive their powers from superstition and traditions, the Arhen bloodline cultivate godhood through industry and commodity subsumption of the orgasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arhen’s greed, or rather, his purpose, was only satisfied by the acquisition and consumption of one invaluable product — himself. He mortgaged his soul into his estate, through the aid of a spirit-banker, and set to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maidens recall hearing only snorts and ecstatic screeches from his room for days. It was not uncommon for the regent to snort — his airways were severely deformed by his posthumanism — but it soon seemed to replace his loud breathing altogether, as though he were talking to himself in pig. This went on for a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, on the eve of the new Zen calendar, his favourite maiden dared enter. She was called Zamen, and being a strong-willed woman, had attracted some level of respect from the otherwise inhuman Ahren. She found the bedroom empty, except for a pair of fine shoes and a small pile of teeth. It was suddenly clear to her what had happened — finally, the prince had completed his cycle and consumed &lt;em&gt;himself&lt;/em&gt;. His father had cycled out the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That day ushered in the regency of Ahren CIV, and the cycle of consumption would begin anew.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Littlest Goddess in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ba3mb4/the_littlest_goddess_in_pachinki/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint yellow&#34;&gt;
  ❖ This article predates the project, and &lt;strong&gt;should be considered non-canon&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Palace Gods live in decadence in an isolated and incestuous land above the mortal planes called the Palace. They do not eat and will live forever, provided they stay within the gardens of the Palace and consummate their industrial godhood occasionally with &lt;em&gt;domen&lt;/em&gt;, an opium that they believe purifies blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult Palace Gods are almost entirely women, but birthrates of boys and girls are about equal. At the onset of puberty, boys can enter rituals to become female gods, but sexual pleasure will stain their transition and thus &lt;em&gt;romentet&lt;/em&gt; (as they’re called in god-tongue) will never maintain blood parity with female Palace Gods. Boys who enter sexual acts or allow sexual thoughts will not transition correctly and instead be consigned to serfdom for the rest of their lives (and in the impurities of their blood, they will be dead by forty).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intersection of the Palace hierarchy and immortality mean that adult Palace Gods are terrified of deposition by younger generations. Older gods will often take an oath of chastity or, failing that, attempt to sabotage the blood purity of god-children to ensure they do not grow up to threaten their positions of power. Adult women often enter relationships with boys for this reason, which will prevent their transition and rise to power and instead grant them mortality. Young girls, however, cannot be dispossessed of their powers so easily. Homosexuality is strictly forbidden in the Palace, and so girls are often tricked into destroying their potential in rituals known as &lt;em&gt;bloodfits&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As inhabitants of the Palace do not need to eat, it means that they do not consume the souls of other creatures. According to their own tapestry myth, their spiritual veganism has come to be a core lifestyle on which godhood is predicated. Young goddesses are often curious about mortal pleasures like food and body functions, and so particularly manipulative adult gods will trick them into eating meat and thus consuming the soul of another creature. After the meat is consumed (the quantity rarely matters, so long as the goddess in general understands they have eaten it), their sin is revealed to them and that knowledge sparks a spiritual crisis in the young goddess that collapses their powers and their physical presence in the Palace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where they go is unknown to anyone still living in the Palace — to those unfortunate girls tricked into bloodfit, they find themselves in a land not quite Pachinki (the mortal planet) or the Palace (the central harbour for gods). Instead, there exists a realm constructed of young gods’ ideas of what mortal life might be like, complete with the idealism and fear of the unknown beyond their Palace lifestyles. They begin to breathe for the first time — a terrifying experience to a goddess previously unused to it — and will experience weather, texture, and sunlight for the first time. Their clothes will suddenly have weight, and their wings are now vestigial relics of magic-aided flight. Many girls simply pass out, unable to deal with the shock of reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most stories here end happily though, in a trend unusual for Pachinki and the Palace. The in-between world these goddesses find themselves in is constructed of their hope and curiosity of Pachinki, too. Green pastures of stunning colour and flower-meadows straight out of their wildest fantasies are never far away. A community of ex-goddesses actively look for new girls and help them integrate into the material world. With time, the Palace life simply doesn’t compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uloah, pictured here, is one of the most recent goddesses to be tricked into committing bloodfit. She was unwittingly fed her own pet peacock, and ended up in the salt lakes of the in-between realm. Any god trying to eat for the first time is a messy affair. After a day of desperate tears and despair as she wandered aimlessly, she came across two beautiful goddesses about her age in Palace clothes. They took her to a village with homes made of long grass populated entirely by her kin. A life of pressures and treachery in the Palace was replaced with the simple pleasures of quiet agriculture and play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why is so much of the magic of the Palace Gods predicated on myth and tradition? After all, it is not a potion or gemstone that strips goddesses of their power. The truth of it, understood by very few and acknowledged by fewer, is that the Palace Gods are sustained entirely by their own myth, with no future or past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Princess Torah, the revolutionary ex-goddess that would eventually liberate the mortal Pachinki from the Palace, said as such in her early writings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Palace Gods are not gods because of bloodlines, despite their insistence. They will tell you it is hereditary, and that blood is colloquial for purity, but they are misunderstanding their own myths. They preach immortality, but can be slaughtered like failing livestock if you’d only realise it. They are not gods because they are better equipped to employ ancient magic, or because they have unlocked the secret of eternal life. They are gods because they’ve fallen for the fiction that sustains them — they are monarchs because they believe in the monarchy, they are cruel because they believe in cruelty, and they subjugate because that is how they’ve read the elaborate tapestry their ancestors constructed. So when Princess Moswen, my martyr and humanist sister (rest her soul), descended to the human people and addressed them universally without regard to race or subcontinent, she called the Gods what they were — tokens writing simultaneously their past and future, failing their own present. Waxen, pastel nepotists misunderstanding their fiction as constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&amp;mdash;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pachinki isn&amp;rsquo;t a normal constructed world. It has its own canon. It is a creation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://vekllei.city/category/character/&#34;&gt;Tzipora&lt;/a&gt;, who is the character utopia of my worldbuilding project. Soon after she moves to &lt;a href=&#34;https://vekllei.city/category/landscape/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;, she&amp;rsquo;s pretty friendless and surrounded by pulpy paperback novels. Pachinki is sort of a worldbuilding project within a worldbuilding project, and it belongs to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;you can check my reddit profile (and there&amp;rsquo;s a follow button there now, because reddit is Facebook) for more posts about Vekllei and Tzipora. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the last you&amp;rsquo;ll see of Pachinki, not by a long shot!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vekllei.city/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;www.vekllei.city&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/melon.kony/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;insta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;fer more. I love questions. tahnk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mineral Lake starts absorbing Grief in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/b7n1uh/a_mineral_lake_starts_absorbing_grief_in_pachinki/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint yellow&#34;&gt;
  ❖ This article predates the project, and &lt;strong&gt;should be considered non-canon&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rena’s little boy was found in the closest town with his guts turned out and his throat cut. They didn’t tell it to Rena like that, but that’s what happened to him. His village and people, the &lt;em&gt;Lehmanen&lt;/em&gt;, are descendants of Palace Gods forced out of the heavens some millennia ago over their refusal to smoke &lt;em&gt;Domen&lt;/em&gt;, a sort of opium of the Gods and essential practice in the Palace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As descendants of Palace Gods, many still carry birthstones in their bodies — small gems buried in the heart of the gut, beneath the stomach. These birthstones are very powerful magical artefacts and fetch a high price in Pachinki’s larger and less magical kingdoms. Rena’s little boy, who was not yet ten, had been taken by pirates looking for his stone and killed. The great tragedy of it was that he was fathered by a man from Zen — the boy had not inherited a birthstone from his mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was her only child and she’d been widowed in the war. The chief of their village announced a month of mourning and fasting in his memory. Once the period had passed, life went on. Rena resumed work in the mineral swamps in which Lehmanen live. The roots and algae that grow in these waters sustain communal village life and produce potions of medicinal value, including leprosy and tuberculosis vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two months after the murder of her only child, Rena came across a stone that struck her dumb with shock. It was her boy’s face, unmistakeable in the perfection of the diorite, caught in the terror and pain of his final moments. It hadn’t been there the month before. She waded over to it but found no other indication of its origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That boy was only the first. As more people died, and the village went through its cycles of joy and grief, the swamp slowly began to fill with the forms of the dead. Heads of the fog. The Lehmanen were confused and angry by the insensitivity of the mineral swamp, and couldn’t understand why it was happening. Something was intercepting the quiet grief of these isolated people and resurrecting the memory of the dead. Was it the minerals? The wind? Something beneath the waters? Was it even a phenomena so simple as to assign to a single force of nature?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly a year after the death of Rena’s little boy, another head appeared, joining dozens already hidden in the fog of the mineral swamps. This one was identical to the diorite totems before it. But it was unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was of Rena — and she was very much alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous posts &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ar8jov/a_gem_girl_shows_off_her_enormous_strength_in/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/user/MelonKony/comments/azmu94/the_palace_gods_attempt_to_retrieve_their_runaway/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pachinki pangea is home to six subcontinents of old magic, mostly inherited from the Palace Gods, who are worshipped by urban centres to this day. The Lem subcontinent is sparsely populated, as the minerals of its many swamps are rife with disease (an illness contracted here, of which there are many, are called plaguentart in Lem or honeydeath in the Zen tongue).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lem are ignorant of the much older magic of the swamps, which predates perhaps even the Palace itself. As stupid to it as they are ultraviolets, the people of Pachinki can only react to the manifestations of it, and will never harness the raw, low-frequency power of ancient harmonics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Footnotes —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pachinki is the creation of a fourteen-year-old girl in my world, &lt;a href=&#34;https://vekllei.city&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Pachinki occasionally lurches into horror otherwise incongruous with the sweet fantasy Tzipora shows such affection for. Pachinki may be a world of peace and wonder, but just like Tzipora’s own present utopian surrounds, it belies a historical context of starvation, mass graves and political violence. Part of the wonder of Pachinki, looking back, is that Tzipora seemed keenly aware of the prohibitively dark nature of this kind of violence in her otherwise escapist whimsy, and this maternal turbulence with her own work is so obvious that even the most casual reader will be conscious of its inconsistency. A page about the pleasure of tasting fruit gems will pirouette into musings on the use of slavery in their procurement and the sabotaging of their production to justify conquest and war. The surreal dissonance of her own motivations for creating Pachinki reflect a girl who was herself living a surreal, contradictory existence — at her time of writing, she was living in a land of plenty and peace, where just a year before she was nearly killed after grocers in Cherry started poisoning their food waste to drive away homeless and vagrants. Her own existence was one of startling contrast — a rapid transition to petticoat society from the misery of the American South, where she witnessed indiscriminate slaughter, sexual violence and crippling poverty. Whatever hurts is real, and so Vekllei did not feel real to her — and consequently, Pachinki is suspended in the same internal turmoil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pachinki isn&amp;rsquo;t a normal constructed world. It has its own canon. It is a creation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://vekllei.city/category/character/&#34;&gt;Tzipora&lt;/a&gt;, who is the character utopia of my worldbuilding project. Soon after she moves to &lt;a href=&#34;https://vekllei.city/category/landscape/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;, she&amp;rsquo;s pretty friendless and surrounded by pulpy paperback novels. Pachinki is sort of a worldbuilding project within a worldbuilding project, and it belongs to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;you can check my reddit profile (and there&amp;rsquo;s a follow button there now, because reddit is Facebook) for more posts about Vekllei and Tzipora. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the last you&amp;rsquo;ll see of Pachinki, not by a long shot!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vekllei.city/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;www.vekllei.city&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/melon.kony/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;insta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;fer more. I love questions. tahnk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gem girl shows off her enormous strength in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ar8jov/a_gem_girl_shows_off_her_enormous_strength_in/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint yellow&#34;&gt;
  ❖ This article predates the project, and &lt;strong&gt;should be considered non-canon&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subcontinent of &lt;strong&gt;Zen&lt;/strong&gt; on the &lt;strong&gt;Pachinki pangea&lt;/strong&gt; is so weathered by enormous gem deserts that there is scarcely enough space to grow wheat for bread. In places where the soil is too thin for heavy wheats, sparrowgrass is grown. This grass has large heads that can be eaten raw and taste citrusy and acidic as they only grow in toxic soils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battered by gem storms, where holy winds pick up stones from the deserts and scatter them, the people of Zen live a hard and honest life. They have forsaken Palace Gods, and have consequently lost a lot of their fertility. Since marriage is dissolved upon failure of a child, Zen has many lonely and desperate spinsters. Driven nearly mad by their childlessness, it is possible to give birth to ‘gem children’ by crushing certain magic gemstones and consuming that powder with normal edible fruit gems. After a short labour of about a month, an extraordinarily painful pregnancy precedes a dangerous birth that kills about half of gem-pregnant women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The child is undeniably beautiful — with a perfect colour and a glitter like no other, gem children are otherwise just like you or me. They usually find themselves popular among other village children as objects of wonder. In poorer Zen regions beyond the large wheat kingdoms, they are targets for pirates who whisk them away in airships and sell them to slavers on mainland Pachinki, since gem children are prized as well-groomed, beautiful servants of the aristocracy. This is somewhat misguided, as the majority of gem children that live in Zen live an unglamorous, happy life in agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are extremely strong — with nearly no limit to their ability to push and crush — but are easily threatened by frequencies that shatter gems. One can easily hold themselves up with a single finger. They move gracefully though and have universally fine motor skills, so they have never harmed a fleshed human unintentionally. Grace here is caught mid-leap to a single handstand. With her fine balance and limitless energy, she could stay there forever if she chooses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gem children are kept alive by love, and as long as they are loved by someone — their mother, the community, friends — they will live forever. They also grow up, and stop physically ageing in their early twenties. Tragically, many gem children that are kidnapped die soon after as they are thrust into unloving environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Married gem children often move abroad with their partners, since their appearance makes them popular fortune-tellers, spell-casters or oath-breakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gem deserts are mesmerising and a joy to wander, but you must only walk with a low sun or at night. Even in a bright moonlight, the brilliance of the gems can easily blind you for days, sometimes forever. They symbolise Zen as a people and as a landscape, and are one of the oldest shifting monuments on Pachinki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pachinki isn&amp;rsquo;t a normal constructed world. It has its own canon. It is a creation of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://vekllei.city/category/character/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tzipora&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, who is the character utopia of my worldbuilding project. Soon after she moves to&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://vekllei.city/category/landscape/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, she&amp;rsquo;s pretty friendless and surrounded by pulpy paperback novels. Pachinki is sort of a worldbuilding project within a worldbuilding project, and it belongs to her.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;you can check my reddit profile (and there&amp;rsquo;s a follow button there now, because reddit is Facebook) for more posts about Vekllei and Tzipora. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the last you&amp;rsquo;ll see of Pachinki, not by a long shot!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vekllei.city&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;www.vekllei.city&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;fer more. I love questions. tahnk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>