<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>pachinki on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/pachinki/</link>
	<description>Recent content in pachinki on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/pachinki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>A Tzipora Christmas Story</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</guid>
	  <description>Pachinki is a world of Tzipora’s own creation, a dorky retreat from the difficulties she has in Vekllei. Tzipora always loved stories of wild places and adventure, and Pachinki blossomed organically from within her daydreams. Eventually she started writing and drawing it. When she was sad, bored or anxious, she would descend back into Pachinki’s world of ancient magic, edible gems and pirates.
A chapter she wrote in late November one year resembled her idea of a Christmas story, and so I’ve included a portion here to accompany this picture.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Mountain Witches of Pachinki</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</guid>
	  <description>Pachinki is the fantastical notebook of Tzipora, in all her loneliness and thunderous imagination, shared with you all to enjoy. She&amp;rsquo;s so far constructed Pachinki posts about gem children, palace henchmen, sinister earth magics, the Palace Gods, and teeth regents.
From Tzipora’s notebook:
[A Guide to Magic, Chapter 2: The Witch]
The witches of Pachinki are an interesting affair — many books have been dedicated to their research after discovery, yet so little is known about them.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Teeth Regents</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</guid>
	  <description>From the notebook of Tzipora:
Total hedonism across a thousand generations produced the creature known as the ‘tooth regent’, who was a human by technicality but was built genetically only for consuming. His name was Arhen CIII, and where his ancestors had mouths, he had a thousand teeth that sat in messy rows to the back of his throat.
Three times a day his mouth had to be washed by palace maidens, and excess teeth brushed off.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Littlest Goddess in Pachinki</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</guid>
	  <description>The Palace Gods live in decadence in an isolated and incestuous land above the mortal planes called the Palace. They do not eat and will live forever, provided they stay within the gardens of the Palace and consummate their industrial godhood occasionally with domen, an opium that they believe purifies blood.
Adult Palace Gods are almost entirely women, but birthrates of boys and girls are about equal. At the onset of puberty, boys can enter rituals to become female gods, but sexual pleasure will stain their transition and thus romentet (as they’re called in god-tongue) will never maintain blood parity with female Palace Gods.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Mineral Lake starts absorbing Grief in Pachinki</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</guid>
	  <description>Rena’s little boy was found in the closest town with his guts turned out and his throat cut. They didn’t tell it to Rena like that, but that’s what happened to him. His village and people, the Lehmanen, are descendants of Palace Gods forced out of the heavens some millennia ago over their refusal to smoke Domen, a sort of opium of the Gods and essential practice in the Palace.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A gem girl shows off her enormous strength in Pachinki</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</guid>
	  <description>The subcontinent of Zen on the Pachinki pangea is so weathered by enormous gem deserts that there is scarcely enough space to grow wheat for bread. In places where the soil is too thin for heavy wheats, sparrowgrass is grown. This grass has large heads that can be eaten raw and taste citrusy and acidic as they only grow in toxic soils.
Battered by gem storms, where holy winds pick up stones from the deserts and scatter them, the people of Zen live a hard and honest life.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>