<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>bulletin</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/bulletin/</link>
	<description>Recent content in bulletin </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/bulletin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Accounted Revenue</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/accounted-revenue/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/accounted-revenue/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
Vekllei businesses that operate in domestic markets do not generally use money. This includes government corporations and departments. Despite this, Vekllei maintains a kind of commercial accounting that produces accurate, if fictional, revenues, expenditures and profit/loss metrics. This is known as &ldquo;accounted revenue,&rdquo; and is a shorthand for normal money-use on this site, but refers only to calculated theoretical values. Although Vekllei does not use money in domestic markets, it has a very sophisticated system of interlinked databases to monitor and record the economy.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Vekllei businesses that operate in <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#domestic-markets">domestic markets</a> do not generally use money.</li>
<li>This includes government corporations and departments.</li>
<li>Despite this, Vekllei maintains a kind of commercial accounting that produces accurate, if fictional, revenues, expenditures and profit/loss metrics.</li>
<li>This is known as &ldquo;accounted revenue,&rdquo; and is a shorthand for normal money-use on this site, but refers only to calculated theoretical values.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Although <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> does not use money in domestic markets, it has a very sophisticated system of interlinked databases to monitor and record the economy. Physical product has a tangible presence and consequently a tangible cost, even if it not assigned a money-value. As such, Vekllei simply calculates the money-value of everything in its society, from homes to wages to toothbrushes, and uses those figures as a means to determine the health of its economy.</p>
<p>How they arrive at these figures is complicated and detached from real-world money-value. The &ldquo;accounted value&rdquo; figure, as it is called, is a combination of labour-hours at a wage calculation, exchange rates, comparative pricing in major international currencies, and scarcity. To this end, the Commonwealth uses commercial accounting practices to target waste and maintain the <em>commons</em> moneyless system.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Accounted value,&rdquo; or more specifically, &ldquo;accounted revenue&rdquo; is also used as a means of budgeting, especially for government departments. So even though Vekllei at face value appears to suppress ordinary money-value and by extension financialised markets, it is in fact deeply financialised and is closely monitored and controlled by the <a href="/cosmosol/">Ministries of Commerce</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Airline Travel</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/airline-travel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/airline-travel/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
Most people in Vekllei do not use money and are essentially unbanked. This raises interesting problems of fairness in cases of scarcity. As a common example of how ticketing works in Vekllei, we can look to airlines and how they allocate seats. Air travel is generally accessible to ordinary Vekllei people. Commonwealth Airways helps connect the distant republics of Vekllei and emphasise their shared values.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Most people in Vekllei do not use money and are essentially unbanked. This raises interesting problems of fairness in cases of scarcity.</li>
<li>As a common example of how ticketing works in Vekllei, we can look to airlines and how they allocate seats.</li>
<li>Air travel is generally accessible to ordinary Vekllei people. Commonwealth Airways helps connect the distant republics of Vekllei and emphasise their shared values.</li>
<li>Most flights use a simple 80/20 system, where 80% of seats are available six months out and 20% are allocated based on need.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Almost every <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> person flies, and some fly frequently. The country is simply too big and its islands too disparate to commute by ship regularly. Almost always, they fly with <a href="/air/">Commonwealth Airways</a>, their national airline, which does not charge a fare for the unmoneyed and unbanked Commonwealth population.</p>
<p>The process for booking is this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Up to six months prior, seats on a flight are booked on a first-come, first-served basis. On most domestic routes, demand is usually well-calculated and it&rsquo;s usually pretty easy to get a seat. In the holiday months, international routes can be more competitive.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></li>
<li>Some seats on the aircraft are reserved for priority transit. The number of seats reserved depends on the route and aircraft type, and ranges between 10-20%.</li>
<li>Priority transit encompasses a range of travel, including emergency or well-founded reasons for travel like bereavement or medical fares, as well as important business and government seats. In Vekllei, &lsquo;business class&rsquo; is not a seperate class domestically but a special ticket.</li>
<li>As the flight approaches, reserved seats are made available on a linear curve that depends on the route. There is always at least two reserved seats on a Commonwealth Airways flight right up until departure, which are sometimes used by air marshals or airline staff.</li>
</ol>
<p>Any Vekllei person can fly for any time &ndash; booking history is assigned to a customer number associated with a government ID. This information is centralised and used internally for research purposes. International routes serviced by Commonwealth Overseas Airways also take on international paying customers, who purchase from the same 80/20 pool of seats.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Due to shortages in seats during the holiday period, recreational travel in Vekllei has to be flexible. Companies are well aware of this state of affairs and most are required by law to allow employees to take their leave at any point during the year.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bankruptcy in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/bankruptcy/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/bankruptcy/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
Large parts of the Vekllei economy are ostensibly owned by the Vekllei Government. Even though these companies are government-owned, they usually operate independently and some are profitable through foreign trade. While private companies in the domestic market can only effectively go &ldquo;bankrupt&rdquo; through prolonged labour shortages, government companies with accounted revenue can and do go bankrupt. The question then is how the Vekllei state handles bankruptcy of government-owned and major industrial firms, and to what it extent it allows ailing businesses to run at a loss.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Large parts of the Vekllei economy are ostensibly owned by the Vekllei <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/government/"><span class="fi fi-min-gov fis"></span> Government</a>.</li>
<li>Even though these companies are <a href="/state-industry/">government-owned</a>, they usually operate independently and some are profitable through foreign trade.</li>
<li>While private companies in the domestic market can only effectively go &ldquo;bankrupt&rdquo; through prolonged labour shortages, government companies with <a href="/bulletin/accounted-revenue/">accounted revenue</a> can and do go bankrupt.</li>
<li>The question then is how the Vekllei state handles bankruptcy of government-owned and major industrial firms, and to what it extent it allows ailing businesses to run at a loss.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The question of bankruptcy in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> is hypothetical, since there is no legal mechanism for bankruptcy in court similar to other countries. Despite this, government-owned and public corporations interacting with foreign currencies have overt revenues and losses, and <a href="/bulletin/accounted-revenue/">accounted revenue</a> is used by the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a> to rate value and competitiveness.</p>
<p>There are many kinds of businesses, government-owned and otherwise, that are informally allowed to run at a loss and have no expectation of turning a profit. Most of these lie exclusively within the Vekllei domestic market, where revenues and expenses are only theoretical. Others, like <a style="color: rgb(245, 60, 89)" href="/air/"><span class="fi fi-min-air fis"></span> Commonwealth Airways</a> are expected to minimise expense but could reliably expect to be subsidised in perpetuity. Most such <em>de facto</em> guaranteed corporations occupy monopoly status in their market.</p>
<p>Others, however, operate competitively and consequently are expected to be able to fail. These include some government corporations, especially those that compete internationally. In this context, these corporations may be allowed to fail, which would look like this:</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ol>
<li>Freezing of debt and revenues via a court injunction.</li>
<li>Suspension of executive staff by executive council.</li>
<li>Sacking of appropriate staff, particularly those in leadership positions, and replacement by interim staff via the executive council or internally.</li>
<li>Restructuring of the company by a specialty firm, located in Vekllei or overseas, and operations reestablished by the executive council.</li>
</ol>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Executive councils in Vekllei are analogous to a corporate board overseas, and consist of persons mostly outside of the corporation. In the event the executive council is unable to assist or implicated in the bankruptcy, the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-trade/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Trade</a> can intervene and either reestablish or liquidate the company. Corporations may also be sold to foreign investors and jettisoned from the internal market entirely.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Government Ownership</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/government-ownership/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/government-ownership/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
Government-owned corporations (GOCs) are owned by the Vekllei government, which in practice often means each of the republics simultaneously. The share capital of GOCs is governed by preferred-privileged shares, which are available only to government ministries, departments and occasionally industry councils. Rather than consisting of thousands or millions of shares, GOCs have their share capital pegged to the number of relevant authorities (in most cases republic governments).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/state-industry/">Government-owned corporations</a> (GOCs) are owned by the Vekllei government, which in practice often means each of the republics simultaneously.</li>
<li>The share capital of GOCs is governed by preferred-privileged shares, which are available only to government ministries, departments and occasionally industry councils.</li>
<li>Rather than consisting of thousands or millions of shares, GOCs have their share capital pegged to the number of relevant authorities (in most cases republic governments).</li>
<li>As such, nationalised corporations like <a href="/air/">Commonwealth Airways</a> have issued only 9 shares, each being owned by a republic&rsquo;s Ministry of Transport.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The unusual ownership structure of Commonwealth GOCs<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> are a result of the federalised <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> system. While the commonwealth <a href="/councils/">councils</a> do own some corporations directly, the vast majority of Vekllei state-owned assets fall under the portfolio of the <a href="/ministries/">ministries</a> of constituent republics.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>Each republic has the same suite of ministries responsible for its own affairs. Because ministries in Vekllei are decentralised (but identical),<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> they own corporations that would be nationalised overseas jointly, as a means of representing one collective owner. This stake can be attributed a money-value but there is no legal mechanism for any one republic to exploit or leverage that value.</p>
<p>There are generally three levels of government-owned corporation in Vekllei:</p>
<ul>
<li>Federalised corporations, owned by the Commonwealth government</li>
<li>Nationalised corporations, owned jointly or singularly constituent republics</li>
<li>Municipalised corporations, owned by a Polis, territory or municipality</li>
</ul>
<p>Issued preferred-privilege shares in the case of jointly-owned GOCs do confer limited voting rights. Jointly-owned GOCs have a governing council that helps unify the policy of the individual ministries. In most cases, these GOCs operate as independent businesses within the mandate of their governing portfolio, but ministries can call votes on policy in certain cases. In this sense, the ministerial councils operate similarly to a board of directors.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>&lsquo;Government-owned corporation&rsquo; (GOC) is the preferred Vekllei term, and is interchangeable with state-owned or nationalised enterprise.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>A &lsquo;republic&rsquo; in Vekllei is similar to a state or canton overseas. They are not traditionally sovereign, but enjoy significant autonomy through standards established by the Commonwealth government.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Vekllei republics have the same set of ministries. These are functionally independent, but are also united into an organisation of mutual association called a Commonwealth Ministry, lead by a Commonwealth cabinet member. As such, the individual ministries of republics are called Republic Ministries.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Government Style</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/consensus/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/consensus/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
Vekllei is governed by an executive council of peers called Directory. The directory is made up of Prime Ministers who are forbidden from participating in political parties, as part of Vekllei&rsquo;s nonpartisan democracy. The principles of consensus are important for the Vekllei style of governance, and contribute to the stability of the country. Although policy is fought over within executive bodies in Vekllei, the principles of consensus are that results should be respected and that it is important for the government to present a unified front.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Vekllei is governed by an executive council of peers called <a href="/directory/">Directory</a>.</li>
<li>The directory is made up of Prime Ministers who are forbidden from participating in political parties, as part of Vekllei&rsquo;s <em>nonpartisan democracy</em>.</li>
<li>The principles of consensus are important for the Vekllei style of governance, and contribute to the stability of the country.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Although policy is fought over within executive bodies in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, the principles of consensus are that results should be respected and that it is important for the government to present a unified front. These principles were founded in the far-ranging and diverse nature of the Commonwealth, in which irreconcilable disagreements threatened permanent political paralysis that would destabilise Vekllei&rsquo;s fledgling postwar democracy.</p>
<p>Vekllei democracy is ostensibly <em>nonpartisan</em>, meaning that it does not have formal political parties. Instead, candidates for election present five policy points which they commit to represent in office.</p>
<p>In practice, disagreement and consensus in Vekllei mimics the cascading federalism of its political system. There are many different levels of executive, and a single executive has multiple functions within the political framework. In each case, disagreement happens privately and consensus is presented publicly.</p>
<p>For example, a <a href="/sorda/">Sorda</a> is an office of two prime ministers, usually a man and a woman, representing a republic. The <a href="/directory/">Directory</a> is made up of eight Sorda. Individual PMs may disagree about an issue, but within the Directory they are expected to represent a single office and thus present a single point of view. The Directory itself, as part of the <a href="/council/">Commonwealth Council</a> routinely has major political disagreements but presents policy as a unified government.</p>
<p>This culture is a feature of Vekllei&rsquo;s council-based society, in which workplace democracy and recreational activities alike are often governed by multiple people. In this style of decision-making, factionalism and partisan behaviour have to be restrained to prevent the paralysis of the executive. As such, private disagreement and public consensus is a natural feature of this style of government.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Natural Commodities</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/natural-commodities/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/natural-commodities/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
With islands across most of the Atlantic, Vekllei has a huge exclusive economic zone and tremendous natural commodities. Vekllei minimises their use and export of these resources for reasons outside of simple environmentalism. The Vekllei position is that resources are a source of capital, not income, and consequently their expense should be minimise. This complements a broader view of natural and physical landscapes in the country, as a distinct sovereign entity seperate from civilisation.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>With islands across most of the Atlantic, Vekllei has a huge exclusive economic zone and tremendous natural commodities.</li>
<li>Vekllei minimises their use and export of these resources for reasons outside of simple environmentalism.</li>
<li>The Vekllei position is that resources are a source of capital, not income, and consequently their expense should be minimise.</li>
<li>This complements a broader view of natural and physical landscapes in the country, as a distinct sovereign entity seperate from civilisation.</li>
<li>Nonetheless, Vekllei exploits resources as any other country does, since it is necessary to service any kind of production. The difference is mostly in its perspective of natural commodities and minimisation of their use.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Nature in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> is not simply a place or vista undeveloped by civilisation, but a constant, unconscious and legitimate valuation of things not made by people. This means that <em>nature</em> and its sovereignty apply equally to the tropical paradises and stark volcanic landscapes of its island communities as it does to its buried and lifeless commodities, like resource deposits and soil. This bulletin focuses on the Vekllei approach to its natural commodities.</p>
<p>A Vekllei economic valuation of nature recognises the money-value of crude oil and pristine white beaches, in the same way they recognise the store of value of dollars in a bank. This, and the labour of people, is the real wealth wealth of the world and its transformation into useful commodities makes up the majority of production. The distance between raw natural resource and shelf product is so great that the connection might seem abstract, or that its value derives mostly man-made techniques and machines shaping an otherwise valueless resource, but this is not fundamentally true &ndash; the majority of money-value in a product originates with the natural commodity and survives its transformation intact.</p>
<p>The inversion here is <em>capital</em> and <em>income</em>. Where raw resources are treated as income overseas, they are treated as capital in Vekllei, and so their exploitation is seen as an expense. This is a philosophical difference as much as it is an economic one &ndash; Vekllei, like many countries, has just started to exploit asteroids in space for their metals and mineral deposits, which in the scale of the universe would seem to be an unlimited resource. But even in the face of this escape route from the rapidly depleting terrestrial resources on Earth, the Vekllei instinct is to understand natural commodities as a store of capital, not income, which in its logic is undoubtedly true &ndash; crude oil cannot be found on asteroids, and is depleting rapidly here.</p>
<p>Of course, resources are necessary to service a quality of life, and so they are exploited in Vekllei as they are anywhere else &ndash; indeed, Vekllei is one of the major exporters of oil in the world thanks to its huge undersea deposits in the Arctic. The difference here is in its minimisation, and government anxiety, over their use as one would spending from their bank account. Expending capital is a necessary function to lubricate the economy and can generate income, but spending capital and treating is as income in itself is no way to run a business or an economy.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>One Person, One Factory</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/lots/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/lots/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
Automated small and medium-sized factories are called Lots in Vekllei. They are generally operated by a few people, or even a single person. Lots can develop their own production processes or (more commonly in certain industries) license them from the Commons Industrial Bureau. In most cases, these small factories are established by the municipality and then &ldquo;sold&rdquo; to individuals, usually with housing attached.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Automated small and medium-sized factories are called <em>Lots</em> in Vekllei. They are generally operated by a few people, or even a single person.</li>
<li><em>Lots</em> can develop their own production processes or (more commonly in certain industries) license them from the Commons Industrial Bureau.</li>
<li>In most cases, these small factories are established by the municipality and then &ldquo;sold&rdquo; to individuals, usually with housing attached. Existing enterprises in recently-federalised <a href="/polis/">republics</a> are also upgraded into <em>lots</em>.</li>
<li>These sole-proprietor factory supervisors generally only have a few hours of work to do in the morning, unloading raw material from trains and calibrating the machines. The intensity of work varies greatly by industry.</li>
<li>In the afternoon, the machines have to be checked and the goods are loaded into half-size rail sidings which feed into the main automatic freight system.</li>
<li><em>Lots</em> are the foundation of Vekllei manufacturing.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>What sort of thing do <em>lots</em> produce? Small factories generally produce essential products that are ubiquitous, or otherwise specialty craft items.</p>
<p>Examples of ubiquitous &ldquo;essential products&rdquo; include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Clothing items like underwear and shoes</li>
<li>Stationary like paper and pencils</li>
<li>Recycled construction materials like rebar</li>
</ul>
<p>And so on. Essential products are almost always produced on a licensed design &ndash; for example, <a href="/universal-cotton/">Universal Cotton</a> creates factory diagrams to produce cotton shirts of a certain specification. These diagrams are licensed through the Commons Industrial Bureau to allow factories all over the Commonwealth to produce identical shirts.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>Examples of &ldquo;specialty craft items&rdquo; include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Industries with signature or unique product types, including coloured pencils and paints</li>
<li>Enthusiast and hobbyist products like plastic moulds for model toys</li>
<li>Artistic and design industries including specialty textiles and fabrics</li>
</ul>
<p>In each case, the <em>lot</em> does most of the work &lsquo;itself.&rsquo; Raw materials, some of which has been pulled from space in the miracle of 21st-Century resource exploitation, are sorted and delivered on half-size freight wagons everywhere in the country. Almost every <em>lot</em> has a rail siding for import and export.</p>
<p>The primary role of the sole-proprietor is factory stewardship<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> and to improve the production processes. Labour-saving innovations are especially prized. Even though the factory may have been built and designed by the municipality or national government, it is now his factory and it is the responsibility of the proprietor to ensure smooth production and efficient operations.</p>
<p>Since <em>lots</em> are part of the commons, they do not use commercial accounting.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> Instead, they use commons <em>resource accounting</em>, which does not determine money value but labour value. So long as the steward is good at his job, the factory will be supplied with whatever it needs to assist its existing processes. In rare cases, a factory may even be expanded. In effect, small business is subsidised by the commercially-accounted and money-costed <a href="/bureaus/">bureaus</a>.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>A lot of Vekllei products are monopolised by a single design. There is a belief in the country, warranted or not, that at some point a well-made cotton shirt is good enough for a certain use, and so does not require fifteen competing designs to improve it. This applies particularly to simple consumer items like toothbrushes, underwear and notebooks. Consequently, &ldquo;staple goods&rdquo; might only have minor regional variations, since Vekllei&rsquo;s <em>commons</em> society requires the overproduction of simple, quality goods to furnish a standard of living.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Factory stewardship means to be the point of contact and representative of the <em>lot</em>, as well as the primary operator of its machines and processes. A steward is familiar with his factory and understands how to diagnose problems, which can be fixed by himself or outside specialists.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Large-scale enterprise in Vekllei uses <em>commercial accounting</em>, which uses costing exercises to determine a theoretical money-value and calculate efficiency. This is a concern for government budgets and large industry which interacts with foreign economies. In the commons, which is anarchic and does not use capital, <em>commercial accounting</em> is much rarer and is generally costed instead by <em>resource accounting</em>.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Standardisation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/standardisation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/standardisation/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
In some aspects, the republics and island-states that make up Vekllei are decentralised and retain control over their own affairs. This is not the case for the visual identity of its institutions &ndash; the federal government retains significant control over how the Commonwealth looks and feels. This control is wide-ranging, and includes flags, government logos and shields, typefaces and document standards, and uniforms.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In some aspects, the republics and island-states that make up Vekllei are decentralised and retain control over their own affairs.</li>
<li>This is not the case for the visual identity of its institutions &ndash; the federal government retains significant control over how the Commonwealth looks and feels.</li>
<li>This control is wide-ranging, and includes flags, government logos and shields, typefaces and document standards, and uniforms.</li>
<li>This level of control is practically unseen even in unitary countries, and its public nature makes it very apparent in society.</li>
<li>The Commonwealth understands the power of a strong visual identity and the importance it has in supporting <a href="/civic-commons/">civic commonhoods</a>.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Upon acceding to the Commonwealth, swarms of federal officials will arrive in the new <a href="/constituents/">constituent</a> and develop a process for federalisation.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> Their work includes critical changes including the revision of laws and the careful (and painful) restructuring of government to suit the Commonwealth. Other changes appear less material, but ultimately represent an essential feature of Commonwealth society: the standardisation of its systems.</p>
<p>Design rules supreme in Vekllei government. It is a dictatorship of a single organisation &ndash; the Commonwealth Design Bureau of the Council of Home Affairs (CDB). The CDB has studios in every <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> republic, and draws its employees from industry. Rather than a traditional department, the CDB is better thought of as a council of specialists in industry, who volunteer their time to maintain the corporate image of the Vekllei state.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> To designers and architects, it is an irresistible opportunity.</p>
<p>The axiom is this &ndash; if design matters, which it does, then the government should take seriously design as it does other aspects of government. It is not enough that design should simply be the paint used to dress up the work of government; it should be a core aspect of the Vekllei identity.</p>
<p>This is especially true in the Vekllei Commonwealth, which is a unique country. It has no common landmass, language, race or culture. It is made up of many islands that have common values. As such, standardisation is a way of reinforcing those values, and making its islands seem geographically closer together than they are.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Rules of the Commonwealth Design Bureau</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>All work must be in good taste.</li>
<li>Work must be universal within its scope.</li>
</ol>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>You can expect the same language of design used across all levels of Vekllei government, from its federal chambers in <a href="/comet/">Comet</a> to its <a href="/polis/">autonomous cities</a> and municipalities.</p>
<p>In a country as diverse as Vekllei, standards need to be flexible. As such, aspects of dozens of local cultures are integrated into the design language of the Commonwealth, and standardised into systems that give the impression of localism while being part of a larger whole. Government shields, for example, maintain a common shape and palette of colours<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> while consisting of many types of imagery and graphics, drawn in a single style.</p>
<p>This diversity-within-systems is apparent in other aspects of government too. New flags have unique colours and imagery, but are designed in relation to each other, retaining both an individual identity and their shared membership as part of a larger country. Uniforms of government, even within government schools, demonstrate common principles expressed in a shared design language that incorporate regional cultural elements.</p>
<p>The effect is obvious and acclaimed. Despite Vekllei&rsquo;s political inscrutability to foreigners, its visual motifs are widely recognisable and the careful management of its visual design has given the Vekllei government a strong and unique identity domestically and overseas. This is also effective in design&rsquo;s essential function across its many republics, as it helps familiarise disparate peoples with their common government, and allows Vekllei people feel comfortable in others parts of the country. Standardisation in Vekllei is a tremendous success.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>&lsquo;Federalisation&rsquo; is the term for integration of a new country into the Vekllei Commonwealth. It is a shorthand for all aspects of integration, including the construction of new buildings, ratification of new laws and accession to the <a href="/constitution/">Vekllei Constitution</a> and the restructuring of the government. It concludes the establishment of a commons and the abolishment of common money through a process of hyperinflation.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>The Commonwealth Design Bureau performs work only for government organisations. <a href="/assets/">State-owned enterprises</a> generally retain their own design systems as independent companies, or fuse aspects of systems as the situation requires.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>The &lsquo;Commonwealth Palette&rsquo; is a swatch of 80 colours used across almost all government design. They include both practical, political and cultural colours that draw semantic connections with real-world culture, like &lsquo;Kalina Blue&rsquo; for its Caribbean seas and &lsquo;Kalan Cream&rsquo; for its snow.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Why do Vekllei People Look Like That?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/looks/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/bulletin/looks/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the bulletin series of articles Summary
A common question about Vekllei, particularly when associated with Oslola (née Iceland), is why they do not look like the common conception of Icelanders. The simple answer is that they are not typical Icelanders, and most native Oslolans are descended from either indigenous arctic peoples (which they call &ldquo;Algic&rdquo;) and Irish or Nordic settlers. In addition, in Oslola there are substantive populations of immigrants who come from all over the world.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/bulletin/">bulletin</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A common question about Vekllei, particularly when associated with Oslola (<em>née</em> Iceland), is why they do not look like the common conception of Icelanders.</li>
<li>The simple answer is that they are <em>not</em> typical Icelanders, and most native Oslolans are descended from either indigenous arctic peoples (which they call &ldquo;Algic&rdquo;) and Irish or Nordic settlers.</li>
<li>In addition, in Oslola there are substantive populations of immigrants who come from all over the world.</li>
<li>As such, it is not accurate to describe any one group of people as &ldquo;looking like&rdquo; an Oslolan, owing to their enduring diversity.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The commonwealth called <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> is a union of island communities, but when this project started it was centred on Iceland. Indeed, Vekllei originally referred only to &ldquo;Iceland,&rdquo; and its possessions across the Atlantic were an afterthought. The worldbuilding in this project is significantly more enlightened now, and Vekllei refers equally to a commonwealth of consenting island communities, but the main characters all still live in Oslola. Picking up on this, people often ask why some of them have Asian features or darker skin, and the answer is straightforward &ndash; this is not Iceland, it is Oslola, and so its history and demographics are different.</p>
<p>Oslola has been inhabited for thousands of years, and was settled nearly simultaneously by indigenous arctic peoples (Algics) and Irish settlers. Not long after, a significant population of Nordic settlers accompanied them. This comprises, historically, the two main ethnic groups of Oslola. Algic peoples have light skin, dark hair, and asian features. Nordics, sometimes called Scandinavians, have northern European features and generally lighter hair colours.</p>
<p>If course, Oslola has undergone a series of catastrophic crises, and has changed very much in the last few hundred years. Between its colonial subjugation and its brutal civil war and atomic bombing, much of old Oslolan society &ndash; its monarchy, clan system and traditions, have been displaced by the internationalist and anarchistic Floral Period. It is now a deeply multiracial society, and is united sincerely by politics and belief as much as geography and race. To that end, it is not even accurate to characterise &ldquo;Oslolans&rdquo; (i.e. Algics and Nordics) as the primary ethnic group of Oslola. They are a majority statistically, but they live in a deeply multicultural society and that is apparent living there.</p>
<p>Appended is a summarised table demonstrating the diversity across the Commonwealth, and their nominated ancestries of origin. A deeper breakdown can be found on the <a href="/demographics/">demographics</a> article.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">❀ Read more: <span class="smallicon">👨‍👩‍👧‍👦</span> <em><a href="/demographics/">Demographics of Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Major Ancestries of Vekllei</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Oslolan (33%)</li>
<li>UK &amp; Ireland (29.9%)</li>
<li>Kalinago/Carib (9.5%)</li>
<li>Black (8.6%)</li>
<li>Commonwealth Asian (5.5%)</li>
<li>Hispanic (4.4%)</li>
<li>East Creole (4%)</li>
<li>Portuguese (3.1%)</li>
<li>Latin American (2.9%)</li>
<li>Indian/Ceylonese (1.7%)</li>
<li>French (1.6%)</li>
<li>Southern European (1.5%)</li>
<li>Slavic (1.3%)</li>
<li>Others (1%)</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
