<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cityscape on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/tags/cityscape/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cityscape on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 02:11:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wiki.millmint.studio/tags/cityscape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canal Living</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 02:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
      <description>Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad. Nothing was trucked. Fish was traded fresh in markets or turned into emulsifiers and fertiliser.
The canals were worked heavily, and few fishing vessels were incorporated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fission Cloud at Vekllei&#39;s 50th Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 01:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</guid>
      <description>In an unprecedented event, during Vekllei’s 50th Sea Festival since Independence in 2065, an 8 kiloton fission bomb was sunk to a depth of 150 meters and detonated at midday. It was an incredible sight on a day so clear you could see the gentle curve of the earth where it met the horizon. A flash of light and a spray dome surged outwards into the quiet Atlantic, which was broken apart by plumes that formed a column of water that climbed high into the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rain in the Arctic Circle</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</guid>
      <description>Tzipora had been ejected from the operations room once the guys arrived. She knew what was going down, anyway. No specifics. But you didn’t bring in uniformed soldiers for regular business. National Intelligence liked to work with their own people.
Five days prior, Baron hailed an EB/NI company car and it pulled up beside him. The electric passenger window slid down. Baron nodded at the passenger.
“Everything’s in here. There’s more if you need it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>