<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>State of Vekllei on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/</link>
	<description>Recent content in State of Vekllei on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Finance</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei  Even if they do not use money, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility.  The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &amp;ldquo;functionally moneyless,&amp;rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex.
Markets #  Domestic Markets #  The Vekllei Domestic Market is the turn-of-phrase for the unmoneyed Vekllei economy, including almost all business</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Housing</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/housing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/housing/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei  Computers are used to subsidise rather than multiply productivity in Vekllei. This does not mean that they do not make commerce or industry more efficient, or open new means of communication between people &amp;ndash; only that they are understood foremost as a social benefit that enables the more idealistic features of the Floral Period and its functional moneylessness. Vekllei is working towards participatory work, and computers are among the dream&amp;rsquo;s most valuable means in which it is being realised.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Parliaments of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/parliaments/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/parliaments/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about the Vekllei state  Vekllei is positioned uniquely between the anarchy and control. This article looks at its government, which facilitates and manages these competing instincts. As the representative of the Vekllei state, and the body of its human interests, the Vekllei Government is second only to the Sovereign in its authority over Vekllei society.  The Government of Vekllei refers to both the Administration of the Interior of the Vekllei Islands and the international governing body of the Vekllei Commonwealth.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>