<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>State of Vekllei on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/</link>
	<description>Recent content in State of Vekllei on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Finance</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei Even if they do not use money, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests. The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &amp;ldquo;functionally moneyless,&amp;rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Parliaments of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/parliaments/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/parliaments/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about the Vekllei state Vekllei is positioned uniquely between the anarchy and control. This article looks at its government, which facilitates and manages these competing instincts. As the representative of the Vekllei state, and the body of its human interests, the Vekllei Government is second only to the Sovereign in its authority over Vekllei society. The Government of Vekllei refers to both the Administration of the Interior of the Vekllei Islands and the international governing body of the Vekllei Commonwealth.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>State Assets</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/assets/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/assets/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei Large segments of the Vekllei economy are dominated by industries of the state, as both direct ministerial privileges and state-owned enterprises. In total, they form the basis of the basic Vekllei standard of living, holding back catastrophe through reliable overproduction where gaps in the participatory economy might threaten serious shortages. There is no real distinction in Vekllei between state assets, state-owned enterprises (SOE) and government-owned corporations (GOC), and the terms are used interchangeably.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>