<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0">
  <channel>
	<title>Interior Ministries</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/ministry/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Interior Ministries </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<image>
		<url>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</url>
		<title>Interior Ministries</title>
		<link>https://millmint.net/stories/</link>
	</image>
	<webfeeds:cover image="https://millmint.net/images/missile.jpg" />
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/ministry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Commerce</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commerce/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commerce/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;߷ This article is about a ministry of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/&#34;&gt;Interior Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  Overview
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag teal&#34;&gt;
  COSMOSOL
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Ministry of Commerce&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOSOL) regulates and initiates trade in the country. Despite the functional moneylessness of the Commonwealth, COSMOSOL remains among the busiest ministries of the Interior Government, since all economic policy, international trade and entitled renumeration (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for withdrawing from the &lt;a href=&#34;#bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Labour Bank&lt;/a&gt;) occurs through its subordinate commissions. Common responsibilities of COSMOSOL include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulation and taxation of international trade, particularly through Government &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/?ref=footer#white-bonds&#34;&gt;White Bonds&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; and Labour Bank &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/?ref=footer#blue-bonds&#34;&gt;Blue Bonds&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banking the Commonwealth state apparatus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advising the Parliament on economic policy and foreign trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring and reporting on the health of foreign markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Printing and transporting currency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has a reputation as a financial capital for its political neutrality and location between Europe and the Americas, and is among the largest facilitators of international commerce and exchange in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Bank of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (commonly &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;) is the central bank and currency store of Vekllei. It is operated by the Ministry of Commerce and maintains branches in most major borough capitals in the Home Islands, as well as across all member states of the Vekllei Commonwealth. It is not autonomous and is beholden to the policy decisions of COSMOSOL and, in certain cases, the Interior and Commonwealth Parliaments. Its sworn purpose, as instructed by the Floral Constitution, is to advocate for Floral Economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bank of Vekllei was founded 1642 as the Royal Bank in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/lola/&#34;&gt;Lola&lt;/a&gt;, and is the fifth oldest bank in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most banks in Vekllei are institutional or industrial, since the average Vekllei person is unmoneyed and, in a conventional definition, unbanked. Nonetheless, Vekllei maintains several commercial banks under the Bank of Vekllei umbrella, tasked primarily with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cashing and underwriting White and Blue bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling government and financial (bureau) bonds internationally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International placement and borrowing services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading, settling and selling foreign currencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei citizens are entitled to an equal share of the money stored in the Labour Bank, and in certain circumstances may withdraw their balance to emigrate or travel abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite foreign perception of Vekllei economics, the liquid and asset holdings of the Bank of Vekllei make it the second-largest bank in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;commonwealth-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Commonwealth Bank of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#commonwealth-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Commonwealth Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (COMMBANK) is an international investment subsidiary of the Bank of Vekllei, tasked primarily with banking in Commonwealth members and international markets. It has branches across every Commonwealth member-state and in most major economic hubs around the world, including throughout Europe, the Americas, and Asia. It also serves as the Central Bank of the Kalina Isles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;import-export-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Import-Export Bank of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#import-export-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Import-Export Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (VEKEXIM) is a state policy investment bank used to fund projects outside of the Commonwealth, particularly in developing countries. It is the primary investment mechanism of Vekllei foreign aid system, which uses export credits and low-interest bureau loans to build infrastructure overseas. It is among the most influential export banks in the world, and contributed to the Pan-African Railway and Hundred Dams projects as part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s ongoing Trade Democracy economic scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;development-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Development Bank of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#development-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Development Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (DEVBANK) is a policy bank designed to organise and allocate funding for large-scale political projects, particularly in infrastructure. The Development Bank works as the engine of the Interior Government&amp;rsquo;s policies, funded mostly with White Bonds issued internationally and labour-guaranteed certificates (a type of Blue Bond). It also creates loan arrangements, evaluates, and underwrites national government projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;petty-bureau-labour-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Petty Bureau Labour Bank of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#petty-bureau-labour-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Petty Bureau Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (SISTERBANK) is the commercial lending bank of &amp;lsquo;petty bureau&amp;rsquo; company syndicates and their workers. Its primary function is bureau negotiation and lending in order to facilitate the economic development of private business in Vekllei. It also acts as an intermediary between petty bureau companies and other banks or government financial apparatuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sisterbank is the primary mechanism by which private business is done in Vekllei, facilitating loans, placement and logistics for small to medium-sized businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bureau-proper-labour-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Bureau Proper Labour Bank of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#bureau-proper-labour-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Bureau Proper Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (MOTHERBANK) is the commercial lending bank of &amp;lsquo;bureau proper&amp;rsquo; company syndicates and their workers. Similar to the Sisterbank, it facilitates economic activity of bureaus and private industry primarily through asset management and mediation with the government and Bank of Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;national-mint-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  National Mint of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#national-mint-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/&#34;&gt;The Vekllei Crown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;National Mint of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (also the &lt;em&gt;Mint&lt;/em&gt;) is the sole producer of currency in Vekllei, tasked with minting and melting the Vekllei Crown. It also regulates gold bullion in the country, and manufactures bullion for use in the International Market. It is headquartered in Vekllei Proper, in the Home Islands. The Mint also produces paper government certificates and security documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mint is the custodian of the Commonwealth Bullion Depository, which holds reserves of over 6,000 tonnes of gold bullion belonging to the Commonwealth and over 60 other countries, and is among the largest such reserves in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mint is well-regarded internationally for the purity of its metals and intricate commemorative coins, leading international numismatics in colour and variety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;vekllei-securities-commission&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Securities Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#vekllei-securities-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Securities Commission&lt;/em&gt; (VECSEC) regulates securities in the Vekllei International Market. It advises fiscal decision-making to the Interior Parliament and legislates trade practices in the country, including the issuing and ownership of government bonds and bureau securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Vekllei citizens do not usually participate in the domestic securities markets, VECSEC lacks traditional legal authority over many of the foreign participants in its supervised markets, but does extradite and prosecute financial crime through the EUROVEK and USVEK extradition treaties. It includes the following departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Council&lt;/strong&gt;: Advisory board to the Commonwealth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Procuratorate&lt;/strong&gt;: Enforcement of penalties and prosecution of financial crimes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Inspectorate&lt;/strong&gt;: Investigations into fraud, abuse and corruption in Vekllei markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Financing and Stock Exchange&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulation and monitoring of the Vekllei Stock Exchange and miscellaneous securities within the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of International Markets&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulation and monitoring of the Vekllei International Market and government bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Investments and Trusts&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulation and monitoring of the investments, securities and financial contracts of Vekllei citizens and companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;vekllei-trade-commission&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Trade Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#vekllei-trade-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Trade Commission&lt;/em&gt; regulates consumer protections and antitrust law, and organises trade information from other ministries and supervisory bureaus into policy recommendations and legislation. The Trade Commission also monitors and reports the health of foreign markets, and conducts research into broader geopolitical financial interests, particularly as they compete with domestic interests. It includes the following departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Consumer Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulation of the consumer rights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Market Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Protection of fair markets and regulation of Bureau and Petty Bureau companies, including state monopolies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Market Research&lt;/strong&gt;: Analysis and research of domestic and international markets, compiled and forwarded to other Interior Ministries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bureau of Economics&lt;/strong&gt;: Macroeconomic research relevant to international trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Defence</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/defence/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/defence/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;߷ This article is about a ministry of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/&#34;&gt;Interior Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  Overview
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag teal&#34;&gt;
  COSMOKOS
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Ministry of Defence&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOKOS) represents the Sovereign Armed Forces of the Vekllei Commonwealth in the Interior Government, which are consolidated under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#commonwealth-military-command&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Military Command&lt;/a&gt;. COSMOKOS does not exercise command authority over the armed forces of Vekllei, and serves instead as the ministerial liaison between the Commonwealth Military Command and the Interior Government. Common responsibilities of COSMOKOS include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recruitment of citizens and foreigners into the Commonwealth armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procuring equipment to meet the Vekllei obligation towards the Commonwealth armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training citizens and foreigners for the branches of the Commonwealth armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducting scientific military research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Policing and security of Vekllei territories and waters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COSMOKOS also provides security services domestically, and is responsible for most internal police and security organisations in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;armed-forces-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Armed Forces of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#armed-forces-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Armed Forces of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;, arranged under the COSMOKOS ministry, are unusual in that they do not have control directly over troops or equipment. The actual armed forces of Vekllei, known as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/palace/military/&#34;&gt;Crown Armed Forces&lt;/a&gt;, are a sovereign feature of the country and as such are placed under direct supervision of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/palace/&#34;&gt;Palace of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; seperate from the Vekllei and Commonwealth governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the Armed Forces of Vekllei, an agency-level body under control of COSMOKOS, is to integrate the Crown Armed Forces with the interior government, and facilitate the employ of Vekllei people in the Armed Forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;department-of-communications&#34;&gt;
  Department of Communications
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#department-of-communications&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Communications&lt;/em&gt; is a bureau-level organisation of the Armed Forces responsible for coordinating public information about military activities. It also produces several newspapers and periodicals for servicemen through subservient publishing houses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;department-of-compulsory-service&#34;&gt;
  Department of Compulsory Service
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#department-of-compulsory-service&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Compulsory Service&lt;/em&gt; (DoCS, also CS) oversees the Vekllei Compulsory Service Scheme, a hybrid civilian/military conscription law that requires four years from each Commonwealth citizen between the ages of 18 and 32. Despite reporting to the Armed Forces of COSMOKOS, the DoCS does not facilitate widespread conscription and mobilisation of the civilian population, a role served by the &lt;a href=&#34;#department-of-mobilisation&#34;&gt;DoM&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, it is responsible primarily for supervising the fulfilment of the Compulsory Service Scheme, and administrating the conscription and training of Vekllei citizens, including in civilian and industrial roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;department-of-foreign-affairs&#34;&gt;
  Department of Foreign Affairs
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#department-of-foreign-affairs&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Foreign Affairs&lt;/em&gt; (DoFA) coordinates military affairs with states overseas, including members of the Commonwealth. Responsibilities include facilitating military exchange and cooperation with foreign militaries, as well as relations-focussed work with strategic and allied nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;department-of-mobilisation&#34;&gt;
  Department of Mobilisation
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#department-of-mobilisation&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Mobilisation&lt;/em&gt; (DoM) is responsible for recruitment in peacetime, and conscription in the outbreak of war. In the Floral Period, Vekllei defensive doctrine aims to make the country &amp;ldquo;ungovernable,&amp;rdquo; requiring widespread mobilisation and training of the civilian population. Unlike the &lt;a href=&#34;#department-of-compulsory-service&#34;&gt;DoCS&lt;/a&gt;, the DoM is concerned primarily with the combat effectiveness of the mobilised population, and is generally distinguished in its strategic military thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;department-of-peacekeeping&#34;&gt;
  Department of Peacekeeping
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#department-of-peacekeeping&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Peacekeeping&lt;/em&gt; (DoP) coordinates Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s overseas peacekeeping operations. Vekllei is among the largest contributors of men and equipment towards United Nations Peacekeeping Forces, which are responsible to and administrated by the DoP while deployed. The Department of Peacekeeping also engages with international mechanisms for peace, and contributes personnel as part of foreign aid or disaster relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;intelligence-liaison-office&#34;&gt;
  Intelligence Liaison Office
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#intelligence-liaison-office&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Intelligence Liaison Office&lt;/em&gt; is a specialised office that coordinates military intelligence between Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s security apparatuses, particularly those of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#national-intelligence-directorate&#34;&gt;National Intelligence Directorate&lt;/a&gt;. Intelligence gathering in Vekllei is performed by a variety of mostly autonomous espionage organs, and the purpose of the Liaison is to authenticate and prepare intelligence for military use. It includes the following branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Intelligence Branch&lt;/strong&gt;: Coordination of intelligence gathered by security apparatuses with Armed Forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civilian Intelligence Branch&lt;/strong&gt;: Coordination of intelligence gathered by industrial and civilian sectors (in occupied territories, for example) with Armed Forces and security apparatuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic Intelligence Branch&lt;/strong&gt;: Coordination of intelligence gathered by the Armed Forces with security apparatuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sovereign-liaison-office&#34;&gt;
  Sovereign Liaison Office
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#sovereign-liaison-office&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Sovereign Liaison Office&lt;/em&gt; is a specialised office intended to link the command of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/palace/military/&#34;&gt;Crown Armed Forces of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; with COSMOKOS, an interior ministry with no direct control over troops of the Crown. Although it is the &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; office of communication with the Crown forces, in practice communication generally occurs directly with the relevant COSMOKOS department. The purpose of the Sovereign Liaison is mostly as a democracy-advocate, supervising the COSMOKOS departments as an anti-corruption watchdog similar to other democracy-advocates. It also ensures COSMOKOS operations do not affect sovereign operations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;bureau-of-supply&#34;&gt;
  Bureau of Supply
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#bureau-of-supply&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Bureau of Supply&lt;/em&gt; is a specialised defence organ that coordinates supply and logistics for the Crown Armed Forces and security services of Vekllei, including its policing and intelligence services. The Bureau of Supply also administrates the network of Crown Ordnance Factories and the production and acquisition of aircraft and vehicles. It is not responsible for strategic decisions about the make and type of supply, only the facilitation and distribution of the purchase.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;police-of-the-parliament&#34;&gt;
  Police of the Parliament
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#police-of-the-parliament&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/stories/police/&#34;&gt;The Police of the Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Police of the Parliament&lt;/em&gt; (also National Police, or VENOPOR) are the national and paramilitary police of Vekllei, responsible for internal security, riot control, counter-terrorism, disaster response, law enforcement and maritime rights protection. The VENOPOR is made up of a variety of organisations dedicated to specialised and tactical forms of policing unavailable to the &lt;a href=&#34;#police-of-the-public&#34;&gt;Police of the Public&lt;/a&gt;. As a paramilitary force, the VENOPOR are also trained to support the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/palace/military/&#34;&gt;Crown Armed Forces&lt;/a&gt; in wartime, and coordinate broad mobilisation in the event of a defensive war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VENOPOR jurisdiction is organised within the individual theatre commands of the Crown Armed Forces. Kala, the Antilles and the Vekllei and Kalina Islands maintain their own VENOPOR police forces, and other Commonwealth members and territories are dependent on Vekllei Islands policing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sections&#34;&gt;
  Sections
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#sections&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sections&lt;/em&gt; are units directly responsible to VENOPOR command and are generally deployed in conventional policing duties. They consist of special units for different types of policing within the jurisdiction of VENOPOR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;companies-section-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Companies Section of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#companies-section-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/stories/compor/&#34;&gt;Compor, Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Special Police&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Companies Section&lt;/em&gt; (Compor) is a paramilitary and riot control unit concerned with maintaining public peace. Compor moves to meet riots, participate in counter-terrorism and counter-espionage operations, and support the Crown Armed Forces in wartime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;rifles-section-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Rifles Section of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#rifles-section-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/stories/rifles/&#34;&gt;The Rifles Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Rifles Section&lt;/em&gt; is a special weapons unit employing specially-trained officers and tactical vehicles for high-risk situations. They are tasked primarily with counter-terrorism, hostage and weapons situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;animals-section-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Animals Section of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#animals-section-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Animals Section&lt;/em&gt; employs officers trained in animal-handling and their animal companions, usually dogs and horses. It is the oldest of the National Police sections, as the successor of an animals support unit of the Royal Armed Forces in the 16th Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;guards&#34;&gt;
  Guards
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#guards&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guards&lt;/em&gt; are semiautonomous units that operate independently of VENOPOR situational command. They are not independent policing branches, and are generally supplied and trained within existing VENOPOR systems, but serve distinct and specialised policing functions outside of the conventional policing duties of VENOPOR &lt;a href=&#34;#sections&#34;&gt;sections&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;coast-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Coast Guard of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#coast-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-14-coastguard/&#34;&gt;The Vekllei Coast Guard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Coast Guard&lt;/em&gt; (also the &lt;em&gt;Navy of the Parliament&lt;/em&gt; or the &lt;em&gt;Coast Guard of the Parliament Police&lt;/em&gt;) is the maritime naval police of Vekllei responsible for search and rescue and law enforcement in the territorial waters of Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the Commonwealth Security Concordat, the Vekllei Coast Guard also provides maritime policing services to members of the Commonwealth. It is among the most well-equipped and militarised coast guards in the world, and assists in rigorous protection of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Atlantic claims and oceanic exclusive economic zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;customs-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Customs of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#customs-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Customs of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (also the &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Customs&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Customs of the Parliament Police&lt;/em&gt;) are responsible for customs and excise duties in Vekllei (and, largely, the Commonwealth). It is also the law enforcement agency responsible for the import and export of goods in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;mint-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Mint Guard of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#mint-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/&#34;&gt;Gold Sappers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Mint Guard&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;Gold Sappers&lt;/em&gt;) are responsible for the security of financial assets in Vekllei, particularly currency and gold reserves minted and held by the Vekllei National Mint. In addition to providing security for Mint sites and infrastructure, the Mint Guard also escorts the transfer of Vekllei currency and gold internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;judicial-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Judicial Guard of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#judicial-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Judicial Guard&lt;/em&gt; are responsible for the policing and security of Interior and Commonwealth courts and prisons. The Judicial Guard supply officers for correctional facilities and bailiffs for courthouses, and are also responsible for prisoner transport. Judicial Guards report directly to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/crown/courts&#34;&gt;Courts of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;crown-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Crown Guard of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#crown-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Special Guard&lt;/em&gt; (also Honour Guard) are a security unit responsible for policing high-value and high-risk targets, particularly the Interior and Commonwealth Parliaments, representatives of the Crown, and sites of particular political or historic importance. They are also responsible for the protection of the Prime Ministers and important persons, as well as foreign dignitaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;militia-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;
  Militia of the Parliament Police
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#militia-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Militia&lt;/em&gt; of the Parliament Police are an auxiliary and reserve force of the VENOPOR, and serve a similarly paramilitary function in Vekllei society. Although the miltia report to the Crown Armed Forces as part of the VENOPOR, they similarly serve a primarily policing role in peacetime consisting mostly of crowd control and support of conventional policing outfits. Militia units in Vekllei may consist of volunteers, as per the Army Reserves, or conscripts in Compulsory Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;police-of-the-public&#34;&gt;
  Police of the Public
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#police-of-the-public&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/stories/police/&#34;&gt;The Police of the Public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Police of the Public&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOPOR) are the local police in Vekllei, consisting mostly of constabulary responsible for local policing. COSMOPOR are retained on a municipal level, and divided between municipalities in neighbourhoods known as commissions. A commission is lead by an Inspector or Qualified Constable. Each neighbourhood commission, which might comprise an area of thousands of people, is further subdivided in constabularies, which are the responsibility of a constable. Constables general know each person in their constabulary, and visits each residence regularly to confirm the welfare of their community and hear their grievances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constables attend to the security and peacefulness of their jurisdictions, and are often unarmed. Most arrests and warrants are executed by Inspectors or VENOPOR officers rather than constables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Light &amp; Water</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/light-and-water/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/light-and-water/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;߷ This article is about a ministry of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/&#34;&gt;Interior Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  Overview
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag teal&#34;&gt;
  COSMOLA
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Ministry of Light &amp;amp; Water&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOLA) is responsible for the government monopoly on water and energy in Vekllei. Through its statutory corporations (SCs) and public utilities, the ministry is responsible for the vast majority of energy production in the Vekllei Islands and contributes significantly to energy research through its network of  laboratories. Increasingly, COSMOLA investment has indicated an interest in energy and water conservation. Common responsibilities of COSMOLA include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintenance and operation of utilities that provide Vekllei people with electricity and water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Production and conservation of energy and water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investment and research into emerging physical sciences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advising energy and water policy to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior&#34;&gt;Interior Parliament&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuclear energy security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COSMOLA is the third-largest ministry by persons employed, and its sub-agencies and SCs are responsible for a number of iconic pieces of Vekllei infrastructure, including the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-15-reactor/&#34;&gt;Expo &amp;lsquo;74 Experimental Reactor&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/&#34;&gt;Ou Hydroburo Complex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;vekllei-electric-commission&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Electric Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#vekllei-electric-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (VEC, also Thunderburo) is responsible for the state monopoly on electricity generation in Vekllei. Although the VEC is structured as a bureau company, its subsidiaries are state-owned and consequently operates similarly to other agency-level departments of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior&#34;&gt;Interior Parliament&lt;/a&gt;. The VEC consists of multiple subcommissions dedicated to unique types of electricity generation in Vekllei, primarily through hydro-electric, geothermal and nuclear methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;magma-electric-commission&#34;&gt;
  Magma-Electric Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#magma-electric-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Magma-Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (colloquially &lt;em&gt;The Magma&lt;/em&gt; or MEC) oversees geothermal electricity production in Vekllei. Because of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s location over the rift of the European and American continental plates, widespread geothermal electricity production is widespread and makes up the majority of commercial and domestic electricity consumption in Vekllei. Forty-six MEC plants of varying sizes supply clean renewable energy to Vekllei households, and waste heat is used to heat greenhouses Vekllei depends on for food production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hydro-electric-commission&#34;&gt;
  Hydro-Electric Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#hydro-electric-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Hydro-Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (colloquially &lt;em&gt;The Hydro&lt;/em&gt;, not to be confused with the &lt;a href=&#34;#vekllei-water-commission&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hydroburo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) oversees hydro-electric electricity generation in Vekllei, particularly in the glacial regions of the Vekllei Islands and Kala. Dramatic mountain terrain in the interior of the Vekllei Islands proved suitable candidates for hydro-electric dams, which were mostly constructed in the pre-war and immediate post-war era. Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s oldest dam in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/ou/&#34;&gt;Ou&lt;/a&gt; has been operating continuously for 156 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nuclear-electric-commission&#34;&gt;
  Nuclear-Electric Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#nuclear-electric-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Nuclear-Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;Atomic Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; or NEC) oversees nuclear electricity generation in Vekllei. Nuclear energy has proliferated in postwar Vekllei, and satisfies the Commonwealth&amp;rsquo;s growing industrial power demands. Most commercial nuclear plants in Vekllei use uranium-233 reactor fuels, processed mostly at the National Centrifuge &amp;amp; Enrichment Plant in Speidisn. Vekllei reactors mostly of a molten salt type. The NEC maintains 56 plants in total across the Commonwealth, most of which are located in the Vekllei Islands or Kala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;vekllei-water-commission&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Water Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#vekllei-water-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Water Commission&lt;/em&gt; (Hydroburo) is responsible for providing potable drinking water, wastewater and stormwater services to the Vekllei Islands and most Commonwealth members. Water in Vekllei is universal and of good quality. The Hydroburo also maintains offices for sewerage, conservation, and construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Vekllei Islands and Kala, most drinking water comes from fresh glacial runoff that requires minimal treating. Industrial water consumption is provided by nuclear desalination plants operated by the Hydroburo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;emergency-light-and-water-authority&#34;&gt;
  Emergency Light and Water Authority
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#emergency-light-and-water-authority&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Emergency Light and Water Authority&lt;/em&gt; (EVA) is a specialised department of the Ministry of Light and Water designed to mitigate interruption to electricity and water supply. Its mandate includes the security of utility infrastructure and disaster preparation. In the event of major interruption to the utilities supervised by the Ministry, the EVA would assume direct control of the Hydro and Thunderburos and coordinate their recovery. Threats include both natural disasters like volcanic eruptions and earthquakes, as well as damage from conventional or nuclear war.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of the Commonwealth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commonwealth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commonwealth/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;߷ This article is about a ministry of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/&#34;&gt;Interior Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;
  Overview
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag teal&#34;&gt;
  COSMOCOM
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Ministry of the Commonwealth&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOCOM) is the organ through which the Interior Parliament communicates and cooperates with the Commonwealth Parliament and its secretariats. Its primary responsibility is cooperation between member states and standardisation, and publishes reports and manuals towards this goal. It is also the primary ministry through which the subordinates of the Commonwealth influence the Interior Parliament. COSMOCOM is also responsible for ensuring changes made to the Floral Constitution are implemented domestically. Common responsibilities of COSMOCOM include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advising, training and auditing local accreditation and qualifications in line with Commonwealth standards and directives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensuring that the Vekllei interior state meets standards determined by the Commonwealth parliaments and international commitments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing and enforcing standards in technical, industrial and brand features of the Interior Government and its responsible state assets and bureau partners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training and maintaining the workforce for the Interior civil service and Interior state assets in line with Commonwealth standards and directives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COSMOCOM&amp;rsquo;s commitments to the transnational Commonwealth Parliaments go both ways &amp;ndash; the ministry ensures domestic compliance and also advises Commonwealth policy and standards, since the Vekllei Interior Government is the largest and most industrious member-state of the Commonwealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;accreditation-directorate&#34;&gt;
  Accreditation Directorate
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#accreditation-directorate&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Accreditation Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;Qualifications Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; or VAD) is a transnational auditor of industrial, commercial and academic qualifications in Vekllei. VAD also develops technical and procedural standards for its responsible commercial and industrial partners. VAD also interfaces directly with international standards organisations on behalf of its subordinate auditors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standards in education for teachers and staff are generally developed and audited by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#commonwealth-education-secretariat&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Education Secretariat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VDA also maintains a catalogue of products and technical manuals available to industry partners, and enforces compliance for industrial and commercial standards through its subordinate inspectorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Accreditation Directorate also represents Vekllei in the International Organisation for Standardisation and other industrial standards bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-qualifications-commission&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Qualifications Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#vekllei-qualifications-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Qualifications Commission&lt;/em&gt; (ADQC) is the primary research organ of the VAD, and develops most of the qualifications standards and procedure policies of government ministries and state assets. Its research is primarily commercial and industrial, since civil service qualifications are generally developed by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#standardisations-directorate&#34;&gt;Standardisations Directorate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-industrial-audit-committee&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Industrial Audit Committee
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#vekllei-industrial-audit-committee&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Industrial Audit Committee&lt;/em&gt; (ADIA) is the primary audit and survey body of heavy and chemical industries, and is made up of representatives and technical representatives from its responsible industries. The Industrial Audit Committee also conducts most industrial audits, escalating breaches to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#inspectorate-vekllei&#34;&gt;Inspectorate&lt;/a&gt; only where criminal prosecution is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-commons-audit-committee&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Commons Audit Committee
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#vekllei-commons-audit-committee&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Commons Audit Committee&lt;/em&gt; (ADCA) is the primary audit and survey body of commercial organisations and laboratories. Like &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#vekllei-industrial-audit-committee&#34;&gt;VADIAC&lt;/a&gt;, the Commons Audi Committee is a civilian auditor made up of industry representatives and forwards criminal breaches towards the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#inspectorate-vekllei&#34;&gt;Inspectorate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;inspectorate-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Inspectorate Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#inspectorate-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Inspectorate&lt;/em&gt; surveys and audits technical standards in business, research and industry for the Interior Parliament as the law-enforcement arm of the Accreditation Directorate. Breaches of Commonwealth standards are generally prosecuted in the Commonwealth Courts by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#industrial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;INSTA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#commercial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;COMSTA&lt;/a&gt; arms of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#standardisations-directorate&#34;&gt;Standards Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Inspectorate acts an appeals board for civil breaches of VAD technical standards. It includes the following groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey and Testing Group&lt;/strong&gt;: Superior investigative outfit designed to investigate breaches of technical standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industrial and Laboratory Safety Group&lt;/strong&gt;: Specialised health and safety compliance investigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Group&lt;/strong&gt;: Legal advisory office for prosecuting domestic breaches and preparing reports for Commonwealth prosecution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;civil-service-academy-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Civil Service Academy of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#civil-service-academy-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Civil Service Academy&lt;/em&gt; (CSA) is a training school for middle and senior civil servants and interior policy researchers. Located in the borough of Callaisn in the Home Islands, it primarily trains servants of the domestic government apparatuses, and provides tertiary courses in governance and management related to its primary disciplines. The CSA also trains directors of key state assets, and provides education resources for bureau industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Vekllei nationals in Commonwealth offices are also trained at the CSA, which has sister offices in most independent Commonwealth member-states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;research-directorate&#34;&gt;
  Research Directorate
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#research-directorate&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Research Directorate&lt;/em&gt; conducts research and prepares policy objectives for use in Commonwealth governance, and determines the curriculum of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#civil-service-academy-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;CSA&lt;/a&gt; and other civil service training organisations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of General Research&lt;/strong&gt;: Flexible, reactive policy and long-term research objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Stability&lt;/strong&gt;: Reactive and timely analysis of current affairs and events threatening the mandate and stability of the Commonwealth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Democracy&lt;/strong&gt;: Research that contributes to floral democracy, particularly as it operates at the borough and canton levels of government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Civil Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Research related to civil rights, demography and culture policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Commonwealth Economics and Trade&lt;/strong&gt;: Macroeconomic research in Commonwealth trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Reform&lt;/strong&gt;: Research related to Vekllei bureaucracy and the efficiency of its government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;standardisations-directorate&#34;&gt;
  Standardisations Directorate
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#standardisations-directorate&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Standardisations Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (SSD, also Standards Vekllei) works to unify management and supervision of state bodies and assets in Vekllei. It also mandates the responsibilities and visual identity of all departments of the Government and boroughs of the Commonwealth, including the appearance and manuals of style of Commonwealth infrastructure and publications. Its work includes both operating procedures and major brand elements like flags and logos, and specific linguistic and typographic features including typefaces, preferred punctuation and symbols. It has considerable authority over other departments, which usually lack autonomy to enforce their own visual identity independently. Most visual work for the Standardisations Directorate is performed by in-house designers and artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;standards-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Standards Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#standards-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;General Office of the Standardisations Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (GOSED), commonly &lt;em&gt;Standards Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;, administrates the directorate, and determines its operations through direct liaison with the Interior and Commonwealth Administrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;standards-press-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Standards Press of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#standards-press-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Standards Press&lt;/em&gt; is a publishing house organised vertically in the SSD to prepare and publish materials including technical manuals, standard compilation books, and industrial bulletins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;industrial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Industrial Standards of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#industrial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Industrial Standards of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (INSTA) regulates industrial regulatory and safety standards of industrial and manufacturing work. It also advises industry groups on product certification, and acts as a Commonwealth prosecutor in criminal breaches of industrial standards. INSTA is divided into sixteen technical committees that oversee particular industries. INSTA prosecutes cases of severe negligence or breach of Commonwealth standards, and advises domestic prosecution towards the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#inspectorate-vekllei&#34;&gt;Accreditation Inspectorate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;commercial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Commercial Standards of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#commercial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Commercial Standards of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (COMSTA) regulates Commonwealth standards of small and medium-sized commercial businesses that are otherwise unaffiliated with bureaus proper. It also advises &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#standards-vekllei&#34;&gt;GOSED&lt;/a&gt; on changes to its technical, safety and design committees. It also routinely interfaces with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/government/#vekllei-commons-audit-committee&#34;&gt;ADCA&lt;/a&gt; for internal standards compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since private commerce in Vekllei exists outside of the bureau framework, the license of COMSTA is broader and flexible, and regularly relies upon contracted industry contacts to fill places on its less defined technical committees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;state-assets-directorate&#34;&gt;
  State Assets Directorate
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#state-assets-directorate&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;State Assets Directorate&lt;/em&gt; manages state-owned companies across the Commonwealth, particularly those with considerable international trade. These include several major industrial firms in Vekllei, like General Reactor S.A. and International Rocketry S.A. Though the State Assets Directorate functions as an administrator, state-owned companies in Vekllei are operated independently of COSMOCOM and maintain their own budgets and finances.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;statistics-directorate&#34;&gt;
  Statistics Directorate
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#statistics-directorate&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Statistics Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (also Statistics Vekllei) collects and publishes statistics concerning the people, economy and geography of Vekllei. Along with other COSMOCOM directorates, the Statistics Directorate organises research into trends of Vekllei demography and geography. The Statistics Directorate also coordinates the Vekllei Census. Statistics Vekllei also provides broad data collection and publishing services for other Interior and Commonwealth ministries and secretariats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;statistics-press-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Statistics Press of Vekllei
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#statistics-press-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Statistics Press&lt;/em&gt; is a publishing house responsible for preparing materials relevant to the work of the Statistics Directorate, including printed editions of the Vekllei Census and ministerial reports used in the Commonwealth and Interior Parliaments. It also publishes books commercially for the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;vekllei-electoral-commission&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Electoral Commission
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#vekllei-electoral-commission&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Electoral Commission&lt;/em&gt; (VEC) conducts elections, by-elections and referendums in Vekllei. It also maintains the Vekllei Electoral Roll, and designs electorates, apportionments and redistributions in the Home Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Electoral Commission also negotiates the registration of political candidates and their funding through the Public Visibility Scheme, in collaboration with the COSMOCOM general office. In addition, the Commission provides electoral supervisory services to other Commonwealth member-states and, occasionally, monitors foreign elections as an independent auditor as part of the Interior Government&amp;rsquo;s overseas political commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
