<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Culture on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Culture on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Language</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/language/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei The language of Vekllei is an important part of the project. Utopianism cascades through every part of society, and rethinking communication is a foundational part of that instinct. In this article, we look at what makes Vekllei as a language special, and give insight into how these Atlantic people communicate with each other. Vekllei language, abbreviated to just Vekllei, has six core sublanguages that are used commonly today.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Metaphysics</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/metaphysics/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/metaphysics/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei This article draws on many concepts broadly, with meandering interest in the same way you might hold a conversation. The purpose of this article is to introduce an alternate perspective on Vekllei thinking, and provoke the buried understanding that these people understand the world in fundamentally different ways. What is history for you is not history for Vekllei, and what land means to you is not what land means in Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Religion</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/religion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/religion/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei Upen is the nondenominational animistic spiritualism of Vekllei. It is both an organised religious belief system and a decentralised local animism, localised regionally across the Home Islands and beyond. As a basis for Vekllei metaphysics and general belief systems, Upen is a central part of Vekllei cultural identity and informs most parts of life at all levels in the country. Upen is the animistic, nondenominational dominant and historical religion of Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>