<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021 on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021 on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Stamp Manufacturie</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/</guid>
      <description>You can tell a domestic Vekllei stamp from its international counterpart by two metrics:
 It has a coloured square, called a chromacode, used for sorting mail automatically within the country by a special machine called a kinosemimatia. The absence of a price in Vekllei Kroner  and no use of the Vekllei logograph to announce its origin.  These stamps, then, are all domestic stamps used for sending mail to other Vekllei people, whether they live in Antarctica, Vekllei’s lunar colonies or anywhere in-between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stamp Manufacturie</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/</guid>
      <description>Mail Week has turned into more of a “Mail Fortnight,” but that’s just how it goes sometimes. This is the 5th drawing in the Mail Week series, where we look at post and people in Vekllei.
The Stamp Manufacturie of the Royal Mail Press, located on 5th Avenue, churns millions of stamps a year out of its massive drum presses. Stamps are used on mail instead of postcodes, and as payment for the international and courier work the Royal Mail does abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3,000 MEMBERS!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-09-3000/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-09-3000/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hello,
I’m Hobart, and I’m the creator of this place. I’ve been drawing Vekllei for a few years now, and I love doing it.
To celebrate 3,000 members, use this as a cosy thread/AMA to settle in, and have any questions you might have about the project answered.
For those who are new, I encourage you to read the posts pinned to the top of the subreddit for a crash course in what’s going on here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racing the Post Office to the Station</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Day 5 of Mail Week at r/vekllei, where we look at post and people.
It was the hottest day of June so far, in that time of year where the sun never set on Vekllei. It was the first week of sleepless nights; the windows thrown open, air sticky and pungent with the smells of the rainforests, tossing and turning in the heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fairie</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Day 3 of Mail Week at r/vekllei, where we look at post and people.
The M.S. Fairie Model 54-2 “Mail Hopper” is a strange aircraft. The basic design has remained unchanged for over a hundred years, imported from the United States way back during the massive scrapping of junk warplanes after the Second World War. Even back during the Junta years the country had little respect for foreign intellectual property, and by 1949 had started rolling out Imitation Catalinas, which were among the first indigenous aircraft in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Postmistress of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   I wasn’t really planning on spending a week working my way through Vekllei’s postal service, but then again — why not? In the coming days we’ll see stamps, mail trains and all manner of transport systems. Maybe we’ll cap it with a look at the Royal Mail HQ. Then next week we’ll look at something else.
 Here we have arranged the highest-ranking and lowest-ranking members of the Royal Vekllei Mail (Mail A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Men and Women of the Royal Mail in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  There are not many postal services older than the Royal Vekllei Mail. It is so old that in the Vekllei language its title is simply ‘Mail’ — the ‘Royal’ and ‘Vekllei’ are implied by the use of its hieroglyph. Founded in 1422 as part of the military communications system between government and mercantile government holdings, it has survived various restructurings — and several wars — to remain a critical communications and cultural institution today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Puffling</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  She joined the Puffin Scouts to make friends. Tzipora was not especially rugged or outdoorsy, but she was a fresh patriot, and the idea of collecting awards for conservation, in her mind, was much like Baron collecting medals for killing reds in the War.
The green and gold of the Puffin Scouts represent nature and living blood respectively. Entwined, as here on her scarf, they mean the chaos and inhumanity of nature in Vekllei Semaphore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moments in Love</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Lava was a modern walled city. It had long lost its walls, but its florid green belt disguised a complex network of trenches, tunnels and forts that linked emplacements in the surrounding mountains. Together, these systems would ensure Vekllei would never again have to tolerate occupation by a foreign power. Lava was on the outskirts of Vekllei’s great capital city, and much of its cityscape was dispersed, affording residents a slower pace of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robots in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The Vekllei word for a robot is automasiosn, or ‘automan’. When we talk about Vekllei being a “post-scarcity society,” it is by automen through which it happens. They are found across the entire country in all types of hard and boring work, forever dutiful, forever mindless. It is not that the robot has replaced the human worker, since about 90% of Vekllei people are employed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Year</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The New Year in Vekllei rings out during its months of darkness and cold. This calendar runs the regular affairs of the country, like it does the modern world. To Vekllei people, however, it is plain that New Years occurs not in darkness but instead in the summer solstice in June, the way it has for thousands of years in the dramatic cycles of light and dark in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
