<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021 on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://beta.millmint.net/tags/2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021 on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beta.millmint.net/tags/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roadside Picnic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-09-15-picnic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-09-15-picnic/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/povzpz/roadside_picnic/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This post&lt;/strong&gt; is an animated PNG without sound. Download the video with sound &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/picnic.mov&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Such was spring&lt;/strong&gt;. The breeze was cool, but the sun was warm on the skin and everywhere. They’d been driving for a couple hours, Tzipora and Baron. They’d crossed the big glacier and come down the other side into &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/troll/&#34;&gt;Troll&lt;/a&gt;, where there was nothing much for miles around. It was about then that their tyre blew and the little Cosme M40 limped over to the side of the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lemons and lemonade; Tzipora decided it was time for lunch. They ate canned salmon in the sun. She’d baked olive bread the day before and they pulled it apart with their hands. After lunch they opened a bottle and Baron had a cigarette as he figured out how he was going to get the spare out from under the luggage in the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora had no such concerns. They had plenty of wine and didn’t have to be in Fyori until tonight. The bonnet of the Cosme had heated up in the sun and it was warm on her back. Tzipora was getting to the good part of her favourite book. The radio had a good song on. She was living one of the best moments of her life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora Meets a Spirit</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-09-11-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-09-11-spirit/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/pmcppf/tzipora_meets_a_spirit/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei is a land of spirits&lt;/strong&gt;. All things have some life to them, but spirits are something special. Up in Tiyousn, seispri (lit. spirits) wander freely, attracted by sulphur and silica waste pools discharged by the Magma-Electric Flash Plant nearby. Rich with minerals and warm to the touch, these milky ponds are gathering places for creatures of the spirit world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people do not understand spirits; they will never understand spirits. The word itself is nearly meaningless, applied broadly to any creature crossing over from unseen spatial cages. The only thing that characterises a spirit is its human intelligence and, by association, their complicated personalities. Most appreciate gestures, even misplaced ones, so it never hurts to leave offerings and announce your intentions in Vekllei’s autonomous Crown Lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was outside of Equetti, in Tiyousn, looking for mineral pools that were the right temperature to bathe in. Finding a favourite mineral pool was a right of passage in Vekllei, and locations to good ones were often secrets given only to close friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was about two kilometres south of the Flash Plant when she saw it and screamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spirits always provoke raw terror the first time. They are not of nature; they are like humans. Their intelligence distinguishes them from the physicality of their surrounds and complicates their behaviour with cultural constructions. It is not like seeing an animal. It is like seeing beyond the horizon of death and the things that live beyond it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was now looking at herself, dressed in some approximation of the things she wore. She thought it was here to kill her. Shaking, and stupidly, she spoke to it like a reflection in a mirror: “You scared me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first she thought it might be a demon — a creature that hurt people. But it — Tzipora did not know what else to call it — sat facing herself, staring unblinkingly. Demons didn’t sit; they beat you to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora had been doing a lot of reading about spirits, but had no real reference for this apparition. It would be a terrible thing to run away — she’d probably offend the spirit, and it was bad manners anyway. She did not know what to do, so Tzipora said hello and introduced herself, and then said something nice about the weather. She spoke slowly, carefully. The spirit sat there, looking at her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora asked about the mineral ponds, and if there were good springs to bathe in, but the spirit said nothing. It looked as real as herself — the lichen on the rock was disturbed beneath the spirit’s skirt. Her skirt, actually — was the spirit pulling its outfit from Tzipora’s mind? Could it sense thoughts? She kept talking politely, about how nice the walk out here was. She paused for a moment and worked up the courage for a compliment, then told the spirit she liked its clothes. She was worried it might provoke a response, but the spirit stayed still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her heart was pounding, but Tzipora could suppress fear. She opened her pack and pulled out her lunch, spreading it out next to the mineral pool before them. She had a bar of Gosmo milk chocolate. She asked if the spirit would like some. She unwrapped the foil, looking at it, and broke off a row of squares. She put two squares in her own mouth, and took the other two squares and held it out. The spirit didn’t move. Moving slowly, Tzipora reached over gently and placed the chocolate on its arm. As she did so, her fingertip brushed its arm — her own arm — and she was filled with unease. It was as real as she was; its arm was warm to the touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora had stopped chewing her chocolate. It melted on her tongue. In the back of her mind she thought about getting a cavity. A moment later, the spirit and the chocolate disappeared. It just stopped being there. Tzipora looked around, afraid it might be sneaking up on her, but it was gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She broke off two more squares, packed her sandwich back into her pack and walked briskly back to Equetti. As she passed by the ponds, her fear eased — there was some abstract sense, perhaps, that she had been invited here. Maybe spirits liked chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gun</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-08-25-gun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-08-25-gun/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/pbgzwc/the_gun/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baron had been working in the twilight of violence for over twenty years&lt;/strong&gt;. In that time he had not given much thought to children or family, except for those that lingered as ghosts from long ago. Despite popular misconception, Baron did on occasion daydream, and in those daydreams was an abstract picture of his heir — a dark-haired son not unlike himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was not a son but she was not unlike him. She gave him a new perspective on life — a reason for going on, and a universe outside of service to the state. And how she adored him. She demonstrated that in how she talked, and how she childishly defended any casual observation or guessing of him. They were old friends — war buddies, in fact — and spent many evenings talking about the world and the things in it. Yet a paternal dimension of their relationship existed. Tzipora was young and full of questions, and wanted desperately to be taught. So he guided her when she asked for it, and answered her questions. And there were so many questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his daydreams he taught his son to use the gun. There were guns in the home but Tzipora was not allowed to touch them, because she had been prescribed antipsychotics fourteen months into her life in Vekllei. She didn’t end up needing the pills; they only gave her tremors. It wasn’t until she was diagnosed properly at eighteen years of age that she as allowed to use the guns with Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They went hunting for meat, since there had been more shortages that year, and in summer Vekllei is full of a most obscure pest called a Pademelon — a type of Australian wallaby that had been introduced just prior to the War by accident. Now they were all over, inoffensive as they were. The meat was tasty and the government encouraged you to cull them, so they were hunted commonly. Tzipora had some knowledge of how to use a pistol but hadn’t fired a long gun. Baron showed her how to use the sites and hold it. She didn’t kill anything, but Baron bagged two. Tzipora figured out how to skin and clean the animal and they ate wallaby steaks that night, which tasted good but were gamey. She shared the rest of the meat with a neighbour who had helped her repair the boiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the echoes of Baron’s memory was a distant, youthful dream of riding a motorbike overseas, maybe across Asia or through the Middle East. Eating from street vendors and sleeping wherever you could. Was it so crazy? After twenty years of work he had plenty of money to withdraw for travel. He wondered if Tzipora would like to learn to ride a motorbike — and what she’d think of such an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Generation</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-08-21-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-08-21-generation/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/p8xf6b/a_new_generation/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children of the children of the bomb —&lt;/strong&gt; a generation of war-babies born in peacetime. That was how they thought of themselves. Their grandparents and great-grandparents had lived through the war and the occupation, and so they had inherited the burden of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s future as a country of long-sufferers, visionaries, and dispossessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Marxist continental intellectual had said something a half-century ago about the right way to teach children, and the idea had probably caught the ear of some commissar of the Vekllei interim government, who perhaps passed it along to some bureaucrat rebuilding the government schools. As a result, Vekllei children only go to school three or four days a week. There, they spend only a few hours a day in classrooms. There is, after all, no real workforce for which they are being primed. &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/#play&#34;&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s labour economy is a play-fantasy&lt;/a&gt;, and so they mostly learn how to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not designed to &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; children — Vekllei schools have hierarchies, punishments and are mandatory &amp;mdash; instead, the primary goal of education is self-discovery and self-respect. It is precisely these qualities that benefit most the modern Vekllei economy, which is heavily automated and competes internationally through the product of its participatory creative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no grading system in Vekllei — all classes are passed or failed. The value of compulsory education through government schools, then, is the socialisation of boys and girls with others boys and girls, and the availability of equipment and facilities to participate in extracurricular activities. This is the real body of Vekllei school life — its clubs, societies, and individual associations. Many professional photographers in this country discovered an affection for photography before they turned 15 years old, through exposure to it in school. These resources, and the need to socialise children with others, are the reasons the Vekllei government continues to universalise government schooling, even alongside home-schooling or independent/religious education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depicted here are the good-natured youth of the new generation in school uniform — &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/&#34;&gt;a topic we&amp;rsquo;ve visited before&lt;/a&gt;. All students in Vekllei wear the same uniform, including at university. The uniforms themselves are not designed specifically to regulate appearance — and to this end, schools do not have dress codes regarding hair or cultural/religious accessories including jewellery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discard any assumptions about the meaning behind the colour or style of their clothes — all variations depicted here can be worn by whomever, no matter their age, school or association. In fact, school uniforms are not provided directly by schools — they are found at department stores, on the rack alongside suits and dresses. Because of this fact, specific styles of shirt, trousers, socks and shoes vary between students — and are acceptable as long as they meet the basic requirements of the uniform. This intersection of control and anarchy can be found widely throughout broader Vekllei society, and is an interesting example of how the basic principles of the &amp;ldquo;Vekllei way of life&amp;rdquo; are reflected in the microscopic mundanities of life and foundations of national culture simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 21st, 2111</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-08-12-atomic-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-08-12-atomic-war/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/p33nu3/june_21st_2111/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDCDCD DW001 VK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HEAR THIS — THIS IS &lt;u&gt;CIVIL DEFENCE&lt;/u&gt; — THIS IS NOT AN EXERCISE.
THIS COUNTRY IS UNDER NUCLEAR ATTACK. STAY TUNED TO THIS WAVELENGTH AT 444 KHZ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IN &lt;u&gt;FIVE MINUTES&lt;/u&gt; OR LESS NUCLEAR WEAPONS WILL STRIKE THIS COUNTRY AND INFLICT …MOST CATASTROPHIC DAMAGE UNSEEN SINCE 2005…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YOU ARE IN DANGER AND MUST ACT IMMEDIATELY TO SURVIVE. &lt;u&gt;IT IS TOO LATE TO LEAVE&lt;/u&gt;. YOU MUST STAY IN YOUR OWN HOME. &lt;u&gt;FIND SHELTER NOW&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EXTINGUISH ALL FIRES AND TURN OFF ALL FUEL &amp;amp; GAS… DAMAGE TO LIFE AND PROPERTY ARE UNKNOWN AND WILL NOT BE KNOWN FOR SOME TIME…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…STAY INDOORS IN AN INTERIOR ROOM AND KEEP WELL AWAY FROM WINDOWS… ALL WINDOWS WILL BLOW OUT. CRAWL UNDER OR BEHIND SOMETHING. COVER IS THE SAME FOR BOTH HEAT AND BLAST. &lt;u&gt;DO NOT&lt;/u&gt; USE THE TELEPHONE. &lt;u&gt;DO NOT&lt;/u&gt; LEAVE YOUR HOME UNTIL THE ALL-CLEAR SIGNAL IS GIVEN…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BE-WARE RADIOACTIVE FALLOUT. YOU CAN NOT HEAR OR SEE FALL-OUT BUT IT CAN KILL YOU. &lt;u&gt;DO NOT&lt;/u&gt; STAY OUTSIDE OF YOUR PLACE OF SHELTER FOR A MINUTE LONGER THAN NECESSARY. EAT FRESH FOOD FIRST. PRESERVE WATER.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALL NEWS FROM YOUR GOVERNMENT WILL ARRIVE ON THIS WAVELENGTH AT 444 KHZ. NEWS HERE EACH HOUR EVERY HOUR. THIS IS NOT AN EXERCISE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…THIS MESSAGE WILL REPEAT…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anxiety, Utopia</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-07-27-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-07-27-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/osri2z/anxiety_utopia/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the voices we hear, isn&amp;rsquo;t there an echo of now silent ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Walter Benjamin, &lt;em&gt;On the Concept of History&lt;/em&gt;, 1942&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tzipora remembered living in the twilight of the dying world&lt;/strong&gt;, and how quiet it seemed in Vekllei in those years. It had an effect on the air; on the grass. Tzipora was very good at admiring the mundane, and the spaces it inhabited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landscape is all around us, all of the time. It does not just occur in scenery, or in nature. And it can be very difficult to see landscape for what it is, because our interiors &amp;mdash; our selves &amp;mdash; announce themselves constantly. In order to enjoy the quiet physicality of everyday life, you have to quiet that voice. What is left is the senses, and intuition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei was full of these sensory feelings, because it was full of physical things. It was breaking down, one after the other, the mental burdens of modernity. Not just in big ways; in money and in work. But in small ways too, in how we experienced places and how we thought of and understood our possessions. Upen explicitly describes an animism &amp;mdash; all things are alive. But you don&amp;rsquo;t need to believe in Upen to understand that, it&amp;rsquo;s evident throughout Vekllei. The complicated, nonsensical machinations of Vekllei society: &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/&#34;&gt;moneylessness&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/&#34;&gt;product atheism&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-07-21-fashion/&#34;&gt;antifashions&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-01-schools/&#34;&gt;childlessness&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/&#34;&gt;an absence of landscape&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/&#34;&gt;abstractionism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/&#34;&gt;a reclamation of womanhood&lt;/a&gt;, etc. &amp;mdash; they could not be more simple in Vekllei, where the beautiful products of such things are unannounced and plain to see. Simplicity is in fact complicated; Vekllei is complicated, and life there is simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She still had her anxiety, of course. She was a full-colour constellation of neuroses. But living was not hard; Vekllei was approaching its epoch of rest. When it arrives, no one will notice a thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Big things coming soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Good and Feeling Good</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-07-21-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-07-21-fashion/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/oow9ir/looking_good_and_feeling_good_the_architecture_of/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For most of her life, Tzipora dressed how she was told to dress&lt;/strong&gt;. When she was a child, her clothes were provided. When she started school, the school clothed her. After school, heading west on the trains and picking up work as she found it, she wore whatever she could afford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until her first steps inside the Cozetti Department Store in Vekllei, clothing was for gazing, not for being gazed at. Her new identity as a modern, middle-class girl had yet to emerge. It was a vacuum that needed filling in a new country where social behaviour drove your quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clothing in Vekllei is manufactured by the same ideological forces that seek to “deindustrialise” the economic processes of the country — in other words, its broad physical decommodification. This included a championing of what they indigenously called “fashion atheism” or “antifashions,” meaning fashion that was not designed to be sold. This did not necessarily require a return to the woollen jumpers and seal pelts of yesteryear — just that clothing would return to the physical immediacy of art and architecture. It became what Vekllei people call “the decoration of ordinary life;” in other words, simply decorative and exclusively physical, and unburdened by intellectual or economic fetishisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This position is inherently conservative, in the sense that it was not supposed to change quickly, but the appearance of Vekllei’s “antifashions” did not advocate for traditional native styles specifically — indeed, many antifashions were quite radical both aesthetically and ideologically, and were pioneered by some of Vekllei’s most progressive art communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employing Tzipora as an example here is not just a convenience of the project — she is a superb example of how the internationalist movement became a symbol of the global dispossessed. Her tastes were affected by her exposure to a unique style developed in the Vekllei-Italian immigrant design schools called “Nuova Grotessco Internazionale,” (Lit. International New Grotesque), which helped found her affection for simple clothing in simple colours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Grotesque” in this case comes from the Italian grotessco, a reference to forms so simple they could have been pulled from cave paintings. Although Tzipora was too sensible to ever seek them out, the showcase items of the Nuova Grotessco Internazionale movement were radical in their geometric simplicity — advocating androgynous silhouettes and “culturelessness” that looked like it came from nowhere and said nothing. Like all radical fashions, the dramatic conclusions of these ideas were moderated and filtered into general consumption in Vekllei, which went on to contribute to the popularity of new synthetic materials, space-age “cosmocorps” styles and bright geometric patterns common in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora herself was never much for the grotesque, but she was very interested in internationalist styles. She had a few choice clothing items she reproduced in most of her outfits — she liked that her pleated shirts suggested nothing about her personality, her ethnic background, or her immigrant status. The pleated shirt is simply the “decoration of ordinary life.” It was inoffensive and uncomplicated. Such is the spirit of fashion atheism and the internationalist movement: clothing should suggest nothing intrinsic about you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vekllei, this idea was seen as a critical liberator of women, and elsewhere, it was seen as an extension of international democracy and cooperation; an aesthetic of endless social mobility and freedom of expression. In Vekllei, where art was very radical and influenced heavily by continental designers, it was the ultimate symbol of postwar egalitarianism and recovery. The internationalist style has become the ‘new default’ of Vekllei fashion, obscuring its ideological origins through its presence in (and simple decoration of) everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something New is on The Horizon</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-30-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-30-june/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ob1ah0/something_new_is_on_the_horizon/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks for a great June&lt;/strong&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of different types of posts this month. About 15 in all — that&amp;rsquo;s one every two days! Not bad! I could do with some sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something very special is approaching in July. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to share it with you all — so are Tzipora and Cobian. A new chapter in Vekllei is fast approaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much love,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hobart&lt;/strong&gt; // MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;Join the Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be &amp;ldquo;petticoat.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quality of Life Surveillance Commission</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-29-qlc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-29-qlc/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/oae0ps/the_quality_of_life_surveillance_commission/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Quality of Life Surveillance Commission (Q.L.C.)&lt;/strong&gt; is part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Fair Work Authority&lt;/strong&gt;, and is one of the most important economic regulators in Vekllei today. In a country without money, you can think of it as the payroll of every Vekllei person — the body responsible for the welfare of Vekllei people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei does not use money domestically, the country is bound by the &lt;strong&gt;Floral Constitution&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Dignity&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;in Employment Act 2016&lt;/strong&gt;,and the &lt;strong&gt;Fair Work Act 2022&lt;/strong&gt; to provide regular, measurable increases in the standard of living for Vekllei people. It is the responsibility of the Q.L.C. to track and report these facts, measured by three metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The satisfaction of Vekllei people with actionable markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The availability, quality, and variety of goods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The strength and maintenance of the Thousand Roses Campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Thousand Roses Campaign&lt;/strong&gt; outlined a programme of comforts and consumer luxuries the Commission felt necessary for the satisfaction of Vekllei people and the opinion of Vekllei internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This programme, called the &lt;strong&gt;Thousand Roses Award&lt;/strong&gt;, reveals interesting tendencies within Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s cultural priorities as the country attempted to furnish its population with a standard of living suitable for twenty-first century life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few highlights. In its essence, fifty years after the war, the average Vekllei person should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Own their home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have all their children in school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work three or four days a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holiday regularly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Vekllei person should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possess three pairs of shoes, for daily, recreational and formal occasions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possess clothing for each day of the week, and for all occasions, so that hygiene and dignity may be preserved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be awarded clothing for any work considered full-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be guaranteed the provision of cosmetics and personal sanitary items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is part of the origin of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s uniformed work culture — although the Thousand Roses Award did not intend companies to specifically provide uniforms, the simplest and most affordable way of meeting the requirements of the campaign necessitated their use. Not all companies in Vekllei provide uniforms, but they must provide clothing upon request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Award also describes the basic rights of a modern Vekllei lifestyle. Any working person should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be guaranteed the provision of personal tools, with which maintenance can be carried out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy equitable and reliable access to cinema, theatre, and live music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook with fresh produce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, the Thousand Roses Award covers exactly one thousand items that contribute to the state&amp;rsquo;s vision of the postwar Vekllei lifestyle. As we can see here, some of these items are yet to be achieved universally or regularly. The basic premise of the Campaign, however, has been realised — Vekllei people do indeed work few days, own their home, send their children to school and holiday regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an independent regulator of the Vekllei Government, the Quality of Life Surveillance Commission continues to hold the promises of the past to account. In a manner closely related to the Vekllei Census, Q.L.C. agents interview people throughout the year, tallying their pleasures and grievances. At the end of each year, the Commission produces a detailed report cataloguing the successes and failures that affect the Postwar Vekllei Person, and determine what Floral Society still owes them. One day, the debt will be paid in full.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utopie ❦ Concrète</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-26-utopie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-26-utopie/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/o8i0wt/utopie_concr%c3%a8te/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This essay&lt;/strong&gt; was published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net&#34;&gt;millmint.net&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/newsdesk/essays/utopie&#34;&gt;Read it here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I write introspectively about the project sometimes,&lt;/strong&gt; as a means by which I consider what I&amp;rsquo;m doing and where my unconscious is leading me with this project. I have the instinct of someone who is over-educated and self-obsessed; someone who went to university, fell for the farce of serious media criticism, and failed to see that all media theorists are basically freaks. And there is a small truth buried in that hyperbole: it does in fact require a certain dysfunction to write books about the study of anime or television. You can become &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; close to something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Utopie concrète,&lt;/em&gt; or &amp;lsquo;concrete utopia,&amp;rsquo; is my phrase for how I work. I saw parallels with the manifesto of &lt;em&gt;musique concrète&lt;/em&gt;, as described by Pierre Schaeffer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of notating musical ideas on paper with the symbols of &lt;em&gt;solfège&lt;/em&gt; and entrusting their realisation to well-known instruments, the question was to collect concrete sounds, wherever they came from, and to abstract the musical values they were potentially containing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utopianism is much the same; it distills the concrete sentiment, concerns, and futures of a time and place and reproduces them in abstract in fiction. In a very straightforward way, my work (Vekllei, so-called) is an abstraction of real people, events, and things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also refers to the &amp;ldquo;feeling&amp;rdquo; of Vekllei, in a transcendental fashion. Utopianism is associated with very specific, loaded conceptions of perfection &amp;mdash; cleanliness, symmetry, peacefulness, goodness, and impossibility. Vekllei is not any of these things consistently; it is like the raw concrete used in &lt;em&gt;béton brut&lt;/em&gt;, and like raw concrete it discolours, weathers and crumbles in its exposure to reality and the march of time. You can see the formwork and imperfections in its product &amp;mdash; not as a result of sloppy workmanship or carelessness, but because those things are beautiful; utopian in their own right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the risk of disfiguring these notes into a manifesto, the principles of &lt;em&gt;utopie concrète&lt;/em&gt; might look something like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PRINCIPLES OF &lt;strong&gt;UTOPIE CONCRÈTE&lt;/strong&gt; ■&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All things have dignity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All things get dirty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must love it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain further:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All things have dignity&lt;/strong&gt;. You must take your &amp;ldquo;raw utopia&amp;rdquo; seriously &amp;mdash; it has to be honest. In this sense, you must always aim to do your best for it. Consider your landscape and give your characters the respect you would anyone. If you dishonour them through sloppy work, you should feel embarrassed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All things get dirty&lt;/strong&gt;. In order to &amp;lsquo;consider your landscape&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;respect your characters,&amp;rsquo; you must also recognise that these things need to live independently from your control. The activity of your utopia is what makes it alive, and also what makes it imperfect. Recognise the imperfections and celebrate them. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You must love it&lt;/strong&gt;. Utopias are very thoughtful and considered, but they can&amp;rsquo;t be intellectual. It must be intuitive &amp;mdash; follow your heart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UTOPIE CONCRÈTE&lt;/strong&gt; ■ WITH &lt;strong&gt;VEKLLEI&lt;/strong&gt; ❦ CHARACTERISTICS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You already have the tools to create your concrete utopia &amp;mdash; you just need to act on it. I have acted, and what has surfaced reveals a great deal about me, how I think and process the world, my anger and prejudices, my hopes and affections, and the pettiest of petty material interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hayao Miyazaki, a great artist I admire deeply, was asked why his films starred heroines. He said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I thought &amp;ldquo;this is no longer the era of men&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; But after ten years, I grew tired of saying that. I just say &amp;ldquo;because I like women.&amp;rdquo; That has more reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly draw women, and there is not much good reason for it other than I like women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said previously I&amp;rsquo;m deeply uncomfortable with the conceptual objectification of women, and the shallowness of girl-caricatures. Yet, when asked why my cast of characters are mostly women, I can only say that I like drawing women. That&amp;rsquo;s very revealing of the hypocritical discrepancy between essay rhetoric and my body of work. I try and give my characters dignity, but I also draw women and girls because they might look more interesting in a certain profession, or have better options for their clothes. Where is the dignity in being reproduced for how you appear in a picture? We can&amp;rsquo;t mistake &amp;ldquo;drawing women&amp;rdquo; for &amp;ldquo;representation of women.&amp;rdquo; This is a failing on my part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I also think that Tzipora, the most egregious and unusual example of &amp;ldquo;using the appearance of women&amp;rdquo; in my project, is not much of a woman at all. She carries my anger, my obsessiveness, and lives my fantasy of a meaningful life. She is quite explicitly an author surrogate, although with a life of her own. She is also not supposed to be an authentic depiction of the experience of any woman &amp;mdash; she is in fact closer to an anti-woman. She is so tomboyish, obsessive, and neurotic, that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to use her to explore conventional literary interests in &amp;lsquo;womanhood.&amp;rsquo; Thank goodness for that &amp;mdash; it&amp;rsquo;s not my place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating Vekllei is my way of processing the goings-on of the world, and my lived experience day-to-day. In this sense, I prefer the clothes and appearance of women, and so in my utopia I draw women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the interesting contradictions of utopianism. It is inherently egoistic, and can always be traced cleanly to the total worldview and personality of its author. But like most fiction, authors are eager to give life to their people and places, and would rather you not glimpse the man behind the curtain. Vekllei is fiction &amp;mdash; Tzipora is a girl, and lives in Vekllei. Vekllei is also a utopia &amp;mdash; Tzipora is me, and lives in my hopes, dreams, and anxieties. The contradiction is muted until authors start acting like the former is not a result of the latter, and that my personal experience does not affect who and what is depicted in Vekllei. This is true of all fiction &amp;mdash; so let us not pretend cuteness is not a female burden, and my desire to draw nice clothes and interesting hairstyles is not an altruistic representation of women, no matter how well-intentioned my depictions may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conversation is important only because Vekllei is important (to me), and the principles of &lt;em&gt;utopie concrète&lt;/em&gt; are worth upholding &amp;mdash; all things &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; have dignity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compor, Vekllei&#39;s Special Police</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-23-compor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-23-compor/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/o6ilso/compor_veklleis_special_police/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Tzipora lived in Lola&lt;/strong&gt;, most people remained of the working class well into the utopian period. Despite their equitable access to the fruits of the country, their housing was poorer and their problems generational. Alcoholism was very common; many of them were veterans of the War in Taiwan. Others were in great pain from their early work in the postwar years, their bodies broken by the demons of manual labour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year after Tzipora arrived, the conviction of a Polish man for two murders sparked protests in Lola along ethnic lines. Protests were very common in Vekllei. In the postwar years, the grievances were often prejudiced, and intensified by the millions of immigrants who arrived in the renewed country, one which was reestablishing itself as a place of dignity for dispossessed people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora did not like the protests because they reminded her of where she came from. Per the echoes of the past, she too found old wartime anxiety and despair resurfacing. She was feeling what we now call battle fatigue, or the neurosis of violence — but she did not look like a soldier, and so she was not treated for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that sort of thing brought out the monster in Tzipora. She grappled with her own revulsion towards the anti-immigrant protestors. It upset her hearing the protests from her home. In her mind, she would like to see them shot where they stood. How short-sighted was tolerance in abstract — why did no one seem to recognise that people needed management; they all needed management. They needed management from their own worst instincts! She had seen the wickedness of people, and now it had followed her here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protest had fizzled out by sundown. Baron watched it from the roof with a drink, apparently unconcerned. Tzipora found herself shaking with anger and had to return inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day, she passed by some riot officers on the way to school. She signed at them in her new &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#5-potenne&#34;&gt;Potenne&lt;/a&gt; to say they were doing good work. That was all she said. In her head, she was thinking &lt;em&gt;get them! Go and arrest them all. How can you just stand there and watch?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment would pass, and the thoughts would settle. She was not bloodthirsty in her heart. But that side of her threatened to surface from time to time. There was some currency to the thought that she had died overseas, and she was witnessing a life unlived in the twilight of death. There is a truthfulness to anger. That side of her felt much more ‘real’ for a long time after. That problem remained unresolved throughout most of her life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Cosmpasnie Fedecenoayan Porits&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Compor&lt;/em&gt; (lit. National Police Companies), are the special paramilitary and riot control wing of the National Police, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/&#34;&gt;venopor&lt;/a&gt;. Most police in Vekllei are stationed locally, including the National Police. The Companies, however, are mobile — they move to meet riots, participate in counter-terrorism and counter-espionage operations, and support the Royal Vekllei Armed Forces in wartime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depicted here is a riot officer in “silks,” the term for the Compor uniform including revolver and long truncheon. Besides her is an armoured officer of Special Tactics, which responds to serious threats of violence. The iconic Compor shield is displayed here for documentary purposes. Special Tactics carry powerful radios designed to work in all environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei sees protests regularly for all sorts of things, including ongoing economic grievances, cultural tension, or even more commonly political events designed to pressure government. All such occasions are met with the Compor, who are feared and reviled by a country otherwise only used to local policing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiritful</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-19-spiritful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-19-spiritful/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/o3mrum/spiritful/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There was not much different about one spirit than another&lt;/strong&gt;. Foreigners mistook Upen, the animism of Vekllei, for environmentalism — that was not the case at all. Landscapes changed, and so did the things that lived in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, humans are sentimental creatures, and they become attached to native things. It is important to seperate human desire — the protection of native plants and animals — and the interests of spirits, since they are not the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upen is at the heart of how a Vekllei person understands the world. It describes the basis of all being, and the essence of all things, called &lt;em&gt;seispri&lt;/em&gt;, lit. ‘spirits’. Some spirits are large and complex, and can resemble creatures. Others are so small and quiet, no person could ever see them. We’ll look at these later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is wearing traditional ritual dress. Spirits are attracted to interesting things, especially precious metals and fine materials, and so outfits like these are designed to attract their attention. Smart people dress for the occasion, and to talk to spirits you must look like a spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her hat is called a &lt;em&gt;kitpek&lt;/em&gt;, lit. ‘flat hat,’ precisely because you can fold it flat. A wide-brimmed version is still worn in agriculture today. This narrow-brim version is elegant and feminine, and decorated with gold and orange. In summer, shirts stitched with gold like these can be worn. In winter, elaborate capes take their place. You can also see here the earliest form of the &lt;em&gt;gi&lt;/em&gt; still in use today, resting to the right of its sister-ornament, the &lt;em&gt;jouvismoakoisnisn&lt;/em&gt; belt, with two large tassels. The &lt;em&gt;gi&lt;/em&gt; is still worn commonly, and is even part of school uniform. The &lt;em&gt;jouvismoakoisnisn&lt;/em&gt; is not so lucky, and today is only associated with Upen ritual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her special tool is called a &lt;em&gt;duapolutchi&lt;/em&gt;, lit. ‘twin lights,’ which consists of a mounting stick and two hollow wooden balls filled with seeds. You shake it to announce the start of a meeting, or express happiness. For good measure, Tzipora has also slung gold chord around her neck and arms. All in all, a captivating show for most spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ritual dress, you are supposed to only communicate via &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#6-upotenne&#34;&gt;Upotenne&lt;/a&gt;, which is the physical language of runes. It’s a form of sign language that incorporates the whole body, and is understood by most Vekllei spirits. Tzipora does not know &lt;em&gt;Upotenne&lt;/em&gt; very well, so only says a few words before waving her ball-stick around. With any luck, they’ll shower her with blessings — or at the very least, not cause her harm next time she intrudes on them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wicket-Keeper</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-15-wicket-keeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-15-wicket-keeper/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/o0k8to/wicketkeeper/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tzipora was good at cricket&lt;/strong&gt;. That surprised everyone. Her teachers called her bookish; her classmates called her a dork. She didn’t look like a girl who played much sport. In America, at her old school, she was sick from gym class so regularly that they stopped asking about her absence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vekllei, however, the sports were better. Instead of “gym class,” they had physical education — Phys Ed — that included a variety of weekly health classes, term carnivals, and daily callisthenics. They’d pile into the gymnasium, take off dark-soled shoes, and run through simple exercises before lessons. Sometimes they’d play games instead, if they had one of the cool teachers. That was a potent memory for Tzipora, actually — the jealousy of watching the homeroom next door play “crocodile” while her group were doing stretches for the second time that week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was her social environment, in the end, that got her into sports. When she didn’t know anyone, she’d read English books by the sports fields. Two weeks into watching the boys play lunchtime cricket, she took up the bat and scored six runs. It turned out Tzipora was very good at sports. She was fast and well-coordinated — an uncultivated natural gift. That year, at the athletics carnival, she scored best out of the girls in high jump and best out of anyone in long jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That made Tzipora very popular with her classmates, because she played “both sides” — she was a shy geek that was good at cricket and didn’t mind getting grass stains on her shirt. It was that duality, rather than her sportsmanship, that people liked. She was amusing enough as a character that the sports-playing boys had developed a fascination with her, and they shouted at her to join most lunchtimes. It was paternalistic, sure — they liked her in the same way they liked the retarded rough-n-ready rugby boy in their class — but it wasn’t mean-spirited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most days, she would. She’d pull off her armband, unclip her gi, and roll up her skirt and sleeves as she made her way down to the pitch. She’d come back with dirty knees right to her books, eight runs richer and radiating a casual self-confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have a very good website</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-14-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-14-website/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nzq6x4/i_have_a_very_good_website/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi everyone&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart here, informing you that I have a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;website&lt;/strong&gt;. It has every post I’ve ever made on it, for better or for worse (with the non-canon stuff marked). It has wiki pages that are growing all the time. It has fun things and essays. You can also leave comments!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/BA0nNV6&#34;&gt;Just look at the home page&lt;/a&gt;. Isn’t that the coolest shit you’ve ever seen? You can see it live at &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net&#34;&gt;https://millmint.net&lt;/a&gt; if you’re on desktop/tablet, and play with the trains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus: &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/P9j0nS3&#34;&gt;Tzipora with some flowers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular posts tomorrow &amp;amp; onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;Join the Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be “Petticoat”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hobart&lt;/strong&gt;/MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heavy Mist</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-11-mist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-11-mist/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nxnvzp/heavy_mist/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The sky was heavy with grey and water&lt;/strong&gt;, and it bled into the air. Vekllei’s moon months were here, and with it came the end of Vekllei’s bright summer season. In came the days of coats, mist and darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora here wears &lt;em&gt;rouisha&lt;/em&gt;, loose-fitting felt pants that have been worn in Vekllei for a thousand years. They’re often worn under a skirt, but can be worn alone as trousers if you like. Today they’re elasticated around the ankles to insulate your legs. She also wears the ‘student cape,’ which is well-known overseas and often held aloft by foreigners as an example of Vekllei’s cultural sophistication. It is not nearly as special in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single uniform in Vekllei often includes a variety of colours and styles, since its use is &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/&#34;&gt;social rather than conformist&lt;/a&gt;. Tzipora demonstrates that well here, in her unfortunate collision of school gold, navy, red, and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the air is mild and the wind is still, the mist feels good. It felt good to be in it. Sometimes it’s just good to be alive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generations</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nw354j/generations/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ayn was a naturally busy person&lt;/strong&gt;. She worked long, hard hours at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence, or ‘AB/NI,’ as a clerk, or specialist, or whatever they needed her to be that day. Her days off were filled with petty occupations and minor obligations — mostly tending to her plants and cleaning. She enjoyed number puzzles. A couple friends had formed a book club, and she went to that on occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora’s arrival in June of 2063 saw several disruptions to Ayn’s routines, not least of which was the surfacing of her old unsentimental boyfriend, now ten years older and much different. Tzipora herself emerged into Ayn’s personal life, and they became close — much like it was with Baron, Tzipora was both a daughter and a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had been Ayn’s recommendation, actually, that Baron should take her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At least for a while,” she said, “She talks about you all the time. No one’s talking about adoption — just take her until the system can sort her out. That’s my advice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora met Ayn’s parents later that year, and just like that, Tzipora had forged herself a new family through her force of will and good charm — Baron, the father; Ayn, the mother; and her Hong-Konger/Russian parents. And Ayn’s parents adored her; they showered Tzipora with gifts and baked goods. She was the grandchild they’d wanted so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole situation aroused an ongoing memory, foggy through shame and discomfort, about her ageing parents and her unmarried lifestyle. It was very difficult for Ayn to discuss her decision not to have children with her parents. She was an only child. How do you tell your parents their ancestors, their bloodline ends with you? It hurt them a lot. It hurt Ayn too, to make that choice and follow her heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayn lived in the same studio apartment in the Great Coast she had for a decade, though she now owned it from her work. As a childless, unmarried woman it was very difficult to find larger homes, which were usually allocated to couples and families. Real estate in Vekllei was both a reward and a punishment, and informed the social fabric of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was good at being a grandchild when she needed to be, and Ayn was very thankful for her presence in their lives. Ayn loved her parents, and found herself thinking back to her own childhood more and more as they grew older. She was still their baby, and it was sometimes difficult to reconcile her own independence as an adult with her desire to make them happy. That desire — the instinct to please — dated back to being a little girl, dumb and full of wonder, navigating her childhood with her mum and dad, much younger then, always loving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After work, she would sometimes sit and smoke, then put it out and smell the salt on the breeze. She used to come out here to think, often melancholic about her life and decisions. Nowadays, the thoughts were lighter, more straightforward. She was more self-assured. Sometimes, Tzipora sat out there with her.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shabbat Shalom</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nuk95k/shabbat_shalom/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When they met&lt;/strong&gt;, Tzipora told Baron she was Catholic. He thought that was hilarious — it was one of the few times she saw him laugh. Her name was “Tzipora”, and she gave herself the name “Zelda” — who did she think she was kidding? But that’s just how she was; Tzipora was an intricate person of many backgrounds and instincts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baron was Jewish, but he didn’t practice much. He did, however, observe shabbas as a cultural legacy of his childhood. He worked six days a week, and rested Saturdays. Sometimes, he’d put on a roast in the tradition of his late father’s recipe. Other times, Tzipora would cook some of their favourite foods. Tzipora, the insistent catholic, would respect the melakhot because she liked the idea of it. Even more unusually, she welcomed the shabbas with a prayer, even though her sabbath was Sunday. That’s just how she was; you get the idea. She was a curious and deeply spiritual person, and became more fascinated with her Jewish heritage after living with Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian didn’t know what a Jew was; she barely understood the concept of any god. Cobian’s family were indigenous Vekllei, descended from generations of animistic Upen observers. She was, however, more than willing to break bread with the girl she loved, and they enjoyed many meals together over the years in that picturesque, naive multiculturalism common to Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Around at the Swimming Carnival</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-05-swimming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-05-swimming/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nt1n9c/standing_around_at_the_swimming_carnival/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each year&lt;/strong&gt;, Lola 6th School traveled to the base of the Thanveler Glacier for its swimming carnival. There was a big thermal pool there, heated by the Earth, and students competed in races for prizes and ribbons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora told people she couldn’t swim. That was true — she sank like a stone. But she didn’t tell them the other part — that she never wanted to learn how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a very tragic and pathetic self-consciousness that afflicts kids around her age. Boys and girls went to school together here, but they weren’t the same thing, were they? She saw girls usually clothed in capes and knee skirts showing skin she’d never seen before. There was this one girl, Cherrie, who was on the heavy side, and Tzipora marvelled unconsciously at how much bigger she looked without her uniform. She realised what she was doing, and was struck with shame — and relief it wasn’t her in that stupid one-piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh my God,” Tzipora thought to herself, “That’d be me. What I’m doing now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora hadn’t worn a swimsuit since she was a kid in Colombia, and she wasn’t going to strip off in front of all these people who already judged her. In her mind, she was ugly-skinny, with scars on her shoulders and no figure to speak of. She didn’t think about these things usually, because all her clothes were a size too big, but a change room changed things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No; she wouldn’t wear a swimsuit. She wouldn’t even take her shoes off. They’d think she was weird for sitting out, but they thought she was weird anyway. Every swimming carnival from here to graduation she’d suffer from the poolside — reading her books, eating her packed lunch and lying about how well she did to Baron when she got home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Atomic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-04-air-atomic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-04-air-atomic/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ns9ltc/air_atomic/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Royal Vekllei Air Force runs nuclear these days&lt;/strong&gt;. Just fifty years ago, that would have been unthinkable. Times change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ramoin-Dupont Aircraft Company, with help from the research subsidiary of the absurdly-named “Government Aircraft Factories,” spent about two decades trying to get a reactor to fly. It was easy enough to build a plane around a fission reactor — the problem was keeping the pilot alive. Ramoin-Dupont figured out that, for every megawatt of power, you required about 8 tonnes of rubber and lead shielding — an intolerable figure for a fighter or light aircraft of any kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This changed with a breakthrough at General Reactor in Montre, which had been experimenting with sunburst-style heat exchangers but couldn’t find a way to apply the technology. In air-cooled reactor setups, already established in primitive nuclear aircraft, this reactor design could significantly reduce operating temperatures and the burden of shielding with a chromium-cadmium alloy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eventual widespread refinement and adoption of these innovations changed the role of the fighter, and the satellite appearance of theatres in air warfare. The days of the air-refuelling boom or drop-tank were gone — a nuclear bomber was now able to fly continuously around the world for up to thirty years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured here is a RD-64 Demon, built in Government Aircraft Factories Aeroyards in Montreya. Like most nuclear fighters in Vekllei, it carries its reactor beneath its fuselage, where it can be refuelled and detached for maintenance easily without grounding the aircraft for months at a time. They are tremendously fast, and thanks to the weight savings of sunburst reactors, are tremendously well-equipped for emerging air combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These jets can fly at up to 2,500km/h. They are designed for one purpose: interception. Official doctrine of Vekllei’s armed forces expects a nuclear war within a hundred years, and these jets are flown continuously over the Atlantic with powerful Horizonic radars, which talk to AEW planes and Vekllei’s navy to draw real-time maps of “Vekllei’s Atlantic.” Its weapon systems are controlled by military &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/&#34;&gt;automan wetware&lt;/a&gt;, the effectiveness of which contributes to the Demon’s reputation as a fierce opponent to the rival fighter-types currently produced in the United States and the Eastern Bloc. They also hold great affection among Vekllei pilots and daydreaming children alike, as direct descendants of the biplanes and turbojet wonders of yesteryear — bred for a fight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNR Orange</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-03-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-03-orange/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nrj90p/vnr_orange/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei takes a lot from its land&lt;/strong&gt;. That fact is the bedrock of the Vekllei way of life, in fact — land stewardship and dependency. In this sense, they owe a great debt to the physical landscape of the country, a concept usually translated as the ‘Landscape Sovereign’ in English. The human royals may be long dead, but Vekllei’s flowering petticoat society retains a monarch — the literal physical presence of the land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several times a year, their debt is paid through the dramatic interruption of ordinary life. The ground cracks, hot sulphur fills the valleys, and streams of molten rock hiss as they emerge into the cool, temperate air of Vekllei. These are the magic mountains of Vekllei, living and breathing as creatures do; violent as creatures are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured here is a commuter express train in the sparsely-populated and highly volcanic borough of Troll. It’s a Mustard-56 series in VNR orange, made during its original production run in 2056. Most passengers prefer this series over older models because of its large skylights, which immerse the cars in the strikingly beautiful landscape of their commute. They are also an example of Vekllei National Rail’s shocking disregard for profitability, as lines like these are subsidised entirely by urban centres. Their function as a social engine is priceless, however, and justified easily by the experience of riding along any of these rural lines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mossbound</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-02-mossbound/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-02-mossbound/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nqooqh/mossbound/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside of the cities&lt;/strong&gt;, sensory pleasure can be enriched by Vekllei’s oldest organism, if you know where to look. The temperate rainforest is alive, and breathing, and smells cold in its freshness. The perfume of the rainforest is earthy and chilled, swirling in a cocktail of fresh water, rich, damp soil and the scents of thick mosses and browning leaves. Out here, only water and the trees move — these sounds are the domain of spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even bird calls seem foreign here, as though the plovers and crows had been invited by the same mossbound instinct Tzipora shared. Pushing deeper into the rainforest, the risks become greater but the chance of meeting spirits swells. You are a guest, you are a guest — she keeps this in mind if she has any sense. The spirits tolerate breakage but they won’t tolerate disrespect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much as the birds nest and feed, Tzipora is welcomed by the spirits to establish a presence in the rainforest. Taking a seat on the soft floor of the forest, she opens her textbook and reads slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t wear a jacket — the cool air is good for the skin. Breathe deep — the perfume is good for the lungs. Open your senses to the peripheral stimuli of the spirit-forest, and don’t overthink it. Enjoy the sound of wind moving through the ceiling around you, and the freshwater creek that trickles sweetly. This is a good-natured place, so be good-natured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora closes her textbook and lies in the moss, listening for spirits. They’re all around her. They talk to her through the sounds of the forest. If she can fill her soul with good things, they might reveal themselves to her one day. Until then, she meets them as a guest and an admirer, and gives thanks in her heart for their continued stewardship of this place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Station Logic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nq071y/station_logic/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei is full of stations in the middle of nowhere&lt;/strong&gt;; platforms for people in no hurry, alighting to places never thought of before. It is in these stations that old government infrastructure projects take on a greater meaning, and cultivate an absurd sort of spirituality that touches the lives of the people who discover them. Is there anything gentler than a concrete platform in the middle of a flower-tundra, weathered and warmed by the sun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tzefesmiousn family in the borough of Kotaismoyeh have their very own platform — they’re the only ones with a house here. There’s a couple of farms nearby, which load wool and meat onto freight trams periodically, but otherwise they’re the only commuters at their stop. Both parents work for Vekllei National Rail — Tzafi is a platform attendant and Aleph is an engineer. The kids go to school in the town of Kotaismoyeh. Their lives are entwined with rail, and their home is serviced by their station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy enough to find quiet stations like theirs in Vekllei, since fast trams only stop on command. It’s cheap enough to pour some concrete and leave it there for a hundred years. Over time, some of these platforms take the names of their commuters. These platforms become a metaphor for home itself, as the gateway to rest. Pictured is Tzefesmiousn Station, second-last on the local line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/np7ofs/how_to_read_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an unusual post in that, a) it’s particularly text-heavy and desaturated, and b) much of its material is already available on an existing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language&#34;&gt;wiki article&lt;/a&gt; on my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above article covers the language conceptually in pretty much all the detail you’d ever want. So, despite the heavy use of labels and text, this picture is particularly concerned with the literal appearance and structure of the Vekllei written language, called &lt;a href=&#34;http://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#3-topet&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside, a basic overview of the language was given &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/&#34;&gt;in this post&lt;/a&gt;. Please check it out to make sense of some of the terminology used here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The basic process of Vekllei’s main writing script (Topet) is this:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nouns and verbs are modified extensively by associating their subject with other pictographic characters, which have no phonetic value except for the core “principle” character. For example, an “emu” might be tall, or “running” may be breathless. This grouping is called a “minor demon”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The way these groupings look depends on how many associated characters you’re using. The principle can be written alone in the centre of a space. With two, they’re arranged side-by-side. With three, the principle sits on top of the other two in a triangular shape. With four, they become a quadrant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes, these groupings are enough. If everyone already knows what the principle characters means and how to vocalise it, you can leave it alone as a pictograph — a literal picture, with meaning modified by the characters of its group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quite often, however, you have to teach the reader how to say it. The minor demon lends the initial sound, and the rest have to be written in superscript next to it, as phonetic “helper” characters called hieyerette. These aren’t used as pictures, they’re used to help spell it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, Vekllei has &lt;a href=&#34;http://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#1-overview&#34;&gt;several verbal, non-verbal, signed and written languages&lt;/a&gt;. They don’t all work like this. Rapotenne is basically pictographic and is very, very old. It’s mostly used for names and to talk to spirits. It’s never used for conventional writing. Indeed, for signatures, most use their sigils instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this post isn’t really intended to help you understand how the Vekllei language works, since the language is very complex and better served by the wiki article linked above. This is a showcase of style — the way the Vekllei language looks and feels on paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see an example of Topet styling in this picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modern, sans-serif FLORAL STYLING is most commonly used today in print, as part of the simplification and standardisation of characters. It’s designed to be easier to write for immigrants, who arrived in Vekllei by the millions after the war.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traditional, ornamented DEMONIC STYLING carries the traditional line weights and decoration of prewar Topet, and is still used in small print like novels for its better legibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most fonts in Vekllei follow in either of these two traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, this infographic makes clear the basic flow of the Vekllei language, which transforms most words into complicated, sentence-like concepts layered with designed, unique meaning. “Minor Demons” (the character groups) are not just used for poetry but in fact for all writing, as is the nature of Vekllei communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like much else in the country, a lot of the Vekllei way of thinking is deeply conceptual and abstracted, and rarely ventures into modern literalism. This is a feature built into the language, and it affects the Vekllei understanding of many cultural artefacts. For example, the Vekllei language is not really built to describe specific places — instead, the feeling and experience of mountains/beaches/streams is substituted in its place, quite literally by the pictographic nature of Topet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you read Topet, you’re not just sounding out a phonetic character — you are looking at a picture of that concept, in a transcendental fashion that prohibits specificity. This sort of indigenous conceptualisation deserves a post of its own, but hopefully this graphic has helped introduce you to the basic cadence and features of the written Vekllei word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know, as always, if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zelda&#39;s Guide to Living Forever</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nn2m5h/zeldas_guide_to_living_forever/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s no other way to put it — Tzipora is one of a kind&lt;/strong&gt;. There are others like her, but fewer and fewer of them are born healthy as the years roll on. Her life is hard, she’d agree, but it’s also sprinkled with miracles. Meeting her, you might not even know she’s set to become the oldest person in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All stories settle on remarkable people, and Tzipora — with or without her absurd long-livedness — is a person of importance, and much more than the sum of her parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those unaware, Tzipora is the 13th person in the world to be diagnosed with Gregori-Heitzfeld Disease (GHD), a genetic disorder that surfaced in the 21st Century. Many more than 13 preceded her, but few “Gregori babies,” as they’re called, ever make it to a hospital for a diagnosis. Where exactly GHD came from depends on who you ask — the synthetic preservatives in food? Residual radiation, from a century of atomic testing? The over-sexualisation of media? Tzipora accidentally swallowed a lead ball as a child — that’s as good a guess as any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gregori babies do not grow up, and they do not die of old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She makes up part of the “first wave” of Gregori discovery, comprising of about fifty individual cases across fifteen years starting in the late 2050s. These boys and girls are, on average, healthier and less affected physically by their disease than those born today. Fatal rates of GHD have increased dramatically in recent years, and very few ‘Gregori babies’ born today live beyond 24 months after onset. Like a passing comet, the miracle children seem to be vanishing as quickly as they appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is commonly misunderstood that Gregori children don’t reach puberty. This is not quite true — they do in fact undergo hormonal changes that usually signal the biological transition into sexual maturity, but are a victim of a poorly-understood protein dysfunction that affects their development and cell reproduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gregori-Heitzfeld, as poorly understood as it is, is not a single malfunction of the human body. It is the intersection of two distinct genetic failings in critical proteins that occur in the oestrogen receptors and enzymes of the body. Let’s have a look at how this works, to the best of contemporary understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oestradiol&lt;/strong&gt; is an oestrogen that binds to subtypes of the body’s oestrogen receptors. Of interest here is the agonistic reaction it exerts on a receptor known as the &lt;strong&gt;G protein-coupled oestrogen receptor&lt;/strong&gt; (GPER), a protein responsible for oestradiol’s nongenomic signalling effect on cells. After activation, GPERs exert dramatic and varied effects on the regulation of many parts of the body, including cell growth, and is found not just in oestrogen-receptive tissues but throughout the brain, lungs, skeleton, muscular system and immune cells. In persons suffering from GHD, increased production of oestradiol during puberty onset upregulate GPERs, which has cascading effects on cell production throughout the body, mostly with &lt;strong&gt;gonadotrophin-releasing hormones&lt;/strong&gt; (discussed below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As aforementioned, however, GPER dysfunction is only part of the puzzle. GHD only occurs in the presence of another malfunction of the &lt;strong&gt;telomerase enzyme&lt;/strong&gt;, a ribonucleoprotein which extends telomeres in the human chromosome. Prior to GHD onset, the function of the telomerase RNA templates are unaffected, but once malfunctioning GPER proteins are activated by oestradiol enzymes, a local protein misfolding (not dissimilar to prion diseases) occurs that disrupts part of the telomerase catalytic cycle built into the RNA template of the telomerase itself. This affects the pause signal of telomerase DNA synthesis and offsets the natural telomere loss rate in chromosomes, altering cycle lengths of DNA elongation. This is the primary event that contributes to the so-called biological immortality of some Gregori-Heitzfeld patients, since it offsets the loss of most types of somatic cells which would otherwise age and die. In many others, however, the protein misfolding in GPER-telomerase signalling develops into a fatal neurodegenerative disorder called Variant Gregori-Heitzfeld Disease (vGHD). In the last ten years, most ‘Gregori babies’ are in fact victims of vGHD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The malfunction of GPER proteins also has some kind of affect on the secretion of &lt;strong&gt;gonadotrophin-releasing hormones&lt;/strong&gt; (GnRHs), which affect physical development of the body in pubescence. The interaction between GPERs and GnRHs are still poorly understood, and the complicated effects GHD has on this relationship are almost entirely elusive. What is obvious is that most suffering from GHD do not develop physically beyond the onset of the disease, triggered in girls by pubescence sometime between the ages of 12 and 16. In Tzipora’s case, who perhaps remains the healthiest example of a ‘Gregori baby,’ her puberty is absent despite the increased production of oestrogens triggered by late thelarche. No Gregori baby has ever entered menarche — at least in part a result of GnRH suppression by faulty GPER proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extraordinary rarity of these genetic disorders intersecting contributes to a disease unlike any other. At some point while living in Sacramento, Tzipora slowly stopped ageing. At first, she was just a victim of delayed prepubescence — she was underweight, after all. Then, it was a hormone disorder. By the time she was in Vekllei, she was the country’s first “unageing lady.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of Gregori-Heitzfeld Disease remains rudimentary because, in part, Tzipora makes up most of its scholarship. She is one of the few healthy Gregori babies to voluntarily submit to public medical research, and so most of our understanding comes from her case specifically. There are many gaps in our understanding. Why are Gregori babies not riddled with rapid-growing cancers as their cells metastasise rapidly? Why are the protein misfolds linked to these specific enzymes, and why don’t they spread throughout the body and brain as they do in vGHD? And, perhaps of most interest to the public — where are they going? Why are our new so-called “immortal children” dying?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora does not consider herself a ‘Gregori baby,’ because she considers herself ‘Tzipora’. When she was diagnosed at 16, there were only 10 others like her in the world — there was no Gregori community support group. By the time there were hundreds, the disease was rapidly degenerating into vGHD and resembled something closer to a tragic prion disease. These are topics she does not like to think about much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei affords her dignity, because it does not have a cultural concept of a child. Children exist, of course. They are loved, and go to school, and learn about the world from guardians around them. But they are afforded dignity as human beings, and generally take on responsibilities at a much younger age. This doesn’t mean Tzipora’s life is easy. Her life is not easy. But if she wants to work, she may work. If she wants to travel alone, she may travel alone. And if she wants a glass of wine with dinner, restaurants will accommodate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not special luxuries afforded to her, but basic rights of all young people. In this sense, she is relieved of the inconvenience of justifying her dignity as a person continuously, and allows her to command authority and respect throughout her life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the scope of her life, immortality and youthfulness is usually the last thing on her mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gone Hollywood</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nk17w6/gone_hollywood/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You know you’re near the homeland of the Magma-Electric Commission when you smell it.&lt;/strong&gt; Somewhere between cracking a rotten egg and standing downwind of a sewerage treatment plant, the volcanic heartlands of Vekllei are the playground of the Magma-Electric Commission, often shortened to just “The Magma” or “Thunderburo”. The smell is caused by Hydrogen Sulphide, a byproduct of the naked volcanic activity Vekllei is known for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sulphur is everywhere in Vekllei — even in the cities, the drinking water smells of it. It even overpowers the perfume of a ro, the Vekllei flower-tundras. In the places where the smell is most intense, you usually find a geothermal power plant nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vekllei, The Magma pumps water deep into the belly of the Earth, so deep that the temperature and pressure cause the water to go supercritical, at which point it’s neither a liquid or a gas. Supercritical water carries much more energy than water or steam, and produces much more electricity — so much so that residences in Vekllei are powered entirely by geothermal (Magma-Electric Commission) and hydroelectric (Hydro-Electric Commission) facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a so-called “flash plant” in Miyatvousi, in the Lava region of Vekllei. Lava is full of plants like these. A rail line runs near its injection well, where fresh glacial runoff is transformed into clean, limitless electricity through the miracle of its landscape and human ingenuity. The water is recycled, but excess waste water is dumped into the surrounding ro, forming foggy pools of light blue water. The earth here is alive; in the cold, the ponds begin to steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise had complicated ambitions of becoming a filmmaker. As with all student filmmakers, he drafted his friends to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His girlfriend, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/locjnz/turning_things_around/&#34;&gt;Coretti&lt;/a&gt;, operated the compact 8mm camera. Tzipora was the production assistant, doing makeup and foley and whatever he asked of her. Cobian was going to be a star — that’s what he said to her, anyway, and he paired her up with a mate of his in what would be an epic short film about lost love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Tzipora who suggested Miyatvousi, since she’d developed a good catalogue of scenic locations in her quest to find natural shrines. There was a place where the rail line crossed a small mineral lake, near the flash plant’s turbine halls. If worked out just right, you could have a shot that’d make the whole film. It was a hell of a journey — a bullet train in the morning to Krafla, where they got breakfast, and a two-hour local train far out from the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it unfolds, you never realise how good a moment is. It was maybe the second or third-best day of Tzipora’s life. She didn’t know Coretti all that well, and it was the first time they’d talked about things other than Moise. They were on a great adventure, and they all knew it. They laughed when Moise coughed out his coffee all over himself and pretended to be interested when Tzipora talked at length about how geothermal power plants work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the gig had been sort of a joke for Cobian — she was humouring the friend of her girlfriend — but as the film progressed, she realised how talented and passionate her friends were. They were deeply odd and talented people, and they believed in what they were doing — Cobian had never had friends like that before. On the train back to Lola, as the city lights of the capital loomed, Cobian turned to Tzipora and told her that she loved her for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambitious, arrogant, naive, laughing, well-fed, tired, and in love. Looking back, Tzipora thought the candid footage of themselves made better cinema than anything in a theatre. Lights, camera — action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vekllei Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-09-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-09-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/n8hfeu/a_vekllei_breakfast/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postwar Vekllei has a problem&lt;/strong&gt;. In the old days, many hundreds of years ago, Vekllei’s long, dark winters forced subsistence farmers to preserve their dishes for six or seven months of the year. This changed under the Junta, which opened trade with the Scandinavian powers, and Vekllei soon saw its growing population dependent on fresh imports of oats and grain from Europe. These Atlantic people, whose diets were previously gamey and nomadic, were now a rough storm away from famine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the diets are the same but the pressures on food production are even more intense. This island has nearly 22 million people on it. The postwar Vekllei Government is terrified of the vulnerability of its indigenous, isolated ecosystems, and heavily restricts raw food imports. Meanwhile, Vekllei cuisine values freshness, localism and sustainability. These are facts that cannot coexist in a place that cannot reliably grow food outside for half the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simple answer, then, is that Vekllei cuts corners on its food production. It does not attempt to reliably produce meat, which effectively banishes traditional cuisine to rural areas and those willing to hunt puffins themselves. For what animals are slaughtered, all parts of their body are used, and quite often all you’ll find at a butcher is sweetbreads and black pudding. Quality meat is synthetic, grown as isolated cells in massive liquid solutions. Even blood and organs are synthesised in industrial quantities for human consumption. Vegetables, which only entered the mainstream diet of Vekllei in the 20th Century, are grown in huge quantities under sun lamps, powered by limitless fission. The factory process of synthesising foods is called &lt;em&gt;sincrestiprosmaious&lt;/em&gt; (lit. &lt;em&gt;Grown/Made Produce&lt;/em&gt;, or similar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these unusual facts in mind, let’s take a look at a breakfast feast prepared by Commis Chef Tzipora, which features a selection of indigenous Vekllei breakfast foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic composition of a Vekllei breakfast is its proteins (egg, meats, and cheese), drinks (coffee, citrus juice, or light breakfast tea), fried or raw vegetables (potato and rutabaga) and sweet items (usually a bun, pastry, or breakfast roll and honey).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The humble &lt;strong&gt;egg&lt;/strong&gt; is a staple rarely in short supply in Vekllei, and one or two are scrambled or fried most mornings, often assembled on &lt;strong&gt;rye&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;briga&lt;/strong&gt; (a soft Vekllei cheese with a taste similar to feta) and &lt;strong&gt;gos&lt;/strong&gt; (bitter Vekllei moss). Scrambled eggs are especially popular due to their availability, a result of their ease of synthesis, and flavoured with &lt;strong&gt;red spice&lt;/strong&gt; (factory chilli) or herbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genuine meat is scarce in Vekllei and eaten only occasionally, most commonly in rural areas close to livestock. Most genuine breakfast meats consist of cold, sliced &lt;strong&gt;ham&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;sausages&lt;/strong&gt;, which are packed with breadcrumbs due to meat scarcity. Vekllei has a type of blood sausage made of genuine pork blood or synthetic substitutes grown in stem cell hematopoietic vats, which are packed with oatmeal, groats and mint, making a black pudding called &lt;strong&gt;rue bouismesn&lt;/strong&gt; (lit. &lt;em&gt;Blood Sausage&lt;/em&gt;). Lamb sausages, called &lt;strong&gt;blanc oa bouismesn&lt;/strong&gt; (lit. &lt;em&gt;White Sausage&lt;/em&gt;) are also common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people drink a lot of &lt;strong&gt;tea&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;coffee&lt;/strong&gt; — about 7 pounds a year of each. They eat a lot of bread and pastry — about 200 pounds a year. They like their butter and lamb, but don’t go in much for pork. Game, like puffins, are eaten regularly, though less than seafood or lamb. All of these items are eaten with breakfast in various ways, most famously &lt;strong&gt;agne loh lebeau&lt;/strong&gt; (lit. &lt;em&gt;Lamb Butter&lt;/em&gt;) which is a delicious buttery meat spread for toast, or &lt;strong&gt;lava oa agnetunfisk&lt;/strong&gt; (lit. &lt;em&gt;Buttered Lava Tuna&lt;/em&gt;), which is cooked until it falls apart and assembled with potatoes and eggs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people like rich, sweet foods, and we can see that here at breakfast. Coffee is sweetened with condensed milk or raw sugar and stirred thoroughly with milk. Tea is much the same. We have here a &lt;strong&gt;long pastri&lt;/strong&gt;, a “long pastry” filled with fruit, which is eaten with (and often dipped in) your hot drink. A large spiced bun with coconut icing, called a &lt;strong&gt;sibun&lt;/strong&gt; (lit. &lt;em&gt;Pale Bun&lt;/em&gt;) is a native favourite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people love food. In a way, it has satisfied the vacuum of moneyless society. It is bargained for help, traded for goods, and gifted for favour. It is also one of the largest compromises of Vekllei’s way of doing things. Upen has a very clear materials hierarchy — things made by you, from things around you, which you understand and respect are best. Below that, there are high quality local things made by others. At the very bottom are synthetic, man-made, factory-produced materials churned out to meet demand. Food in Vekllei undeniably exists in this last category for the vast majority of city-dwelling people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can reclaim the spiritual purity of foods somewhat by simply loving the ingredients you obtain — the black pudding might be grown in vats, but why not transform it by crumbling it over a salad with a nice vinaigrette you’ve made yourself? To alleviate some of this metaphysical tension, most Vekllei neighbourhoods are filled with greenhouses and local shared gardens, which ensures most meals have some produce in which you have participated. That’s very important. Some people think that, because Vekllei has abolished money, it has abolished the fetishism of products. The opposite is true — Vekllei life is about the love and respect of materials, a feature built into the animism of Upen. You cannot buy the best food in Vekllei — you have to find it, in a trial of ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting down and enjoying food is a cornerstone of life in Vekllei. You cannot participate in society without it. For immigrants, the privacy of a quiet breakfast is good practice for the palettes and conventions of eating in Vekllei — so load up your plates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrine-Minded Girls</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/n6a990/shrineminded_girls/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shattered fjords make up the north of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, particularly in boroughs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/santes/&#34;&gt;Santes&lt;/a&gt; (lit. &lt;em&gt;Saint&lt;/em&gt;) which are well-regarded for their striking cliffs and sloping igneous fingers, which evidence Vekllei’s ongoing volcanism. Offshore, hundreds of islets rise and sink over the centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the tiny village of Cult, which sits on the sparse tip of the Grimsy Fjord. It has a local train, but is otherwise only serviced by the Santes regional express — a mere single step up on Vekllei’s train hierarchy. This makes it relatively isolated by Vekllei’s rail-dense metrics. Cult’s shorefront is flanked by rocky cliffs that shelter its beaches, which means most of the town is squeezed further in and higher up. By the station at sea level, only a cafe and a handful of factories greet alighting passengers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In her final year of secondary school, Tzipora had developed a fascination with Upen’s “natural shrines,” which contributed to her rapidly developing brand of Judeo-Catholic Upen mysticism. Sometimes after school, when all Cobian wanted was a snack and a movie, Tzipora would drag her onto a bullet train and seek out new shrines — unique natural features — described in Upen’s sagas. They would change trains — again, then again — and finally they’d arrive in some backwater Tzipora had read about. Then they’d go looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian keenly remembered watching two days’ worth of essay fly out of Tzipora’s arms and scatter towards the beach in Cult, and thinking that it served her right, just a little bit. It seemed to Cobian that the winds were telling Tzipora to pack up and go home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail (VNR)&lt;/strong&gt; has a straightforward scheme for the names of its trains. Each is given a regional name — usually a flower or moss, the most important plants in Upen — and then the year is appended. This here is a Lesvesn 59-Series, since it entered production with Arisdeh Coachworks in 2059. Its bright orange livery (VNR Orange, specifically) means it’s a regional train — local trains have unique colours voted on by their passengers. The Lesvesn 59-Series is a DC electric multiple unit train type used all over Vekllei, most commonly on quiet semi-express routes, since the trains most often appear in two-car or even single unit configurations. Its bigger cousin, the Mustard 56-Series, is often seen in the cities. It looks more or less the same, but is a little wider.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei National Rail</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-25-rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-25-rail/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/myad8n/the_people_of_vekllei_national_rail/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail&lt;/strong&gt;, or VNR, is one of those organisations caught somewhere between a faceless government enterprise and a family member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every Vekllei person rides a train each day, and that train is operated by VNR, which has a monopoly on rail travel and operation. Very few people know exactly what ‘VNR’ is. Is it a government department? A state-owned company? Or is it a “bureau” — the Vekllei word for a collection of companies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry about it. Someone Tzipora knew called it a state-owned, bureau-backed “organ” of Vekllei, and that was enough for her. Someone in the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic&lt;/em&gt; wrote a column the other day about horror films failing to capture sales in Vekllei. And why should they, Tzipora thought, when their lives are already a horror? Ask anyone how the Vekllei economy works and watch real terror reveal itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR runs the trains, and employs about 60,000 people in its operations, which range from locomotive engineers to copy editors for rail enthusiast periodicals. The privately-run, state-owned, bureau-backed sub-organ of the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government known as VNR maintains a fleet of rolling stock across a variety of types and track gauges, including steam locomotives and experiments in nuclear-electric maglevs. All of this bankrolled carelessly through the &lt;strong&gt;National Rail Insurance Scheme A.r.R.&lt;/strong&gt;, which prints as many labour-backed government White Bonds as VNR can spend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people illustrated here are VNR Attendants, professional people-pushers and friends of the rail-travelling public, who work on trains and platforms guiding, managing and assisting people. In Vekllei, most public-facing work is performed by the elderly, conscripted or socially-inclined. Although VNR has existed since independence, and is more or less the ancestor of the prewar Junta rail monopoly in floral-period makeup, its uniforms were overhauled in celebration of “250 years of rail” in 2055. Their jackets display Vekllei’s optimism in the future of plastic-based fabrics in fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most work in Vekllei, their appearance is professional but their manner is informal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing there?” Who, me? “Yeah, this is your line mate. Yellow, just keep following yellow, all right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their shifts are short, but platform work is boring. Most trade shifts to get as much time on the trains as they can, where they can enjoy Vekllei’s exquisite scenery from some of the world’s finest public transport.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Diplomacy</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-19-diplomacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-19-diplomacy/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/mu1v5t/living_diplomacy/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cobian first met Tzipora at Café Maz&lt;/strong&gt;, though before then she knew her as ‘Tzipora, the New Girl,’ or, less favourably, ‘Tzipora the Gypsy,’ since there was some confusion about where she’d come from. The neighbourhood had known about her for a while, since people like to talk about foreigners, and when she was spotted at the Café people talked about that too. Meeting her, Cobian understood why she had become a fascination. She had keen blue eyes that were very gentle, and quite slow-moving. She would look at you, then casually to the wall, then to her shoes, then back to you. The peacefulness in her face contrasted dramatically with the intensity of her movements, which were frenetic and unconscious. She had a tic where she would pull on her nose and shirt, which combined with her novice &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#5-potenne&#34;&gt;Potenne&lt;/a&gt;, had her hands moving almost constantly as she talked. She was aware of this, because she would notice it periodically and grab her free hand, all without breaking eye contact or the cadence of her conversation. She was very funny; Cobian immediately liked her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian was a soft-willed sort of person, unopinionated and eager to be liked. Every fact filtered down to a reasonable compromise — there was a little bit of good in everything. Some people call that way of thinking gentle. Maybe she was just a little incurious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was her opposite. She lived in a binary world of Tzipora metrics. Things were either pure and beautiful, disgusting and reprehensible, or not worth thinking about. All things passed through this process — cars, food, clothes, the shape of a curve, and the form of a kettle. Some people call that way of thinking judgemental. She was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fierce intuition applied to people too, and Tzipora had a good memory. She wasn’t afraid to confront someone if they upset her, which earned her a slap now and then from some girl too rude to take shit from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can hit me, slap me like that,” Tzipora would say, sneering and rearing back on her heels. “For you to raise your hand against me, like you would a dog — I’ll show you, bitch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She would stop by Cobian’s house, sometimes holding her collar together where a button used to be or nursing an elbow, and they’d sit out back where her mother couldn’t see them. Cobian would fold up a towelette and wipe the gravel out of her palms and knees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know where you get off, acting like a gangster,” Cobian says, dabbing her face. “It upsets me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know, but she deserved it. You know that. Calls me a &lt;em&gt;pisca&lt;/em&gt;; it makes me so angry. Not that she said it to me, but that she thinks she can say such a thing in the first place, like I’d just pretend I hadn’t heard it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora wrestled with the things she said and did constantly. In fact, the ongoing judgement of herself was perhaps the most nuanced opinion Tzipora ever had, one that didn’t fit into the pure/despicable binary. Most days, she landed on self-disgust, and yet…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora pulled on her nose and sniffed, like she did whenever she was nervous, and looked at Cobian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry,” she said. “If you don’t like me blowing up, I’ll try and stop it for you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want you to stop for me, I want you to stop for yourself. I’m just glad you’re okay,” Cobian said, and took her hand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday. Summer Rains.</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-12-cosy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-12-cosy/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/mpg8xy/saturday_summer_rains/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summer, the sun is up all night&lt;/strong&gt;. She wakes at five and spends the mornings by herself, reading the paper or a paperback. Baron works late — he wakes late. They have breakfast together, so until then she drinks coffee out of a packet and starts the fire if it’s cold. You were supposed to save power, but sometimes she ran her electric blanket all night, which kept her snug until the under-floor heating warmed up. Her concrete apartment had concrete comforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has a record player that runs compact diskettes filled with free jazz and rock ’n’ roll. What Baron calls “bongo music”. She reads shit thrillers with the sound of the lashing rain and wild drums in foreign signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above her bed is a cross, which she treats like a totem. She has a very transactional relationship with God. She doesn’t like him much, but figures doing Him a favour by hanging his cross this one time might earn her a bit of luck when she needs it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coffee is hot, and spoiled with milk and sugar. Everybody tells her that’s no good, that she’s ruined the coffee. She doesn’t care, she likes how it tastes. The rain goes on. She thinks about breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold Sappers</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/mnjo0t/gold_sappers/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venopor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Fedecenoayan porits&lt;/em&gt;, lit. Police of the Parliament) are Vekllei’s special police branch. They occupy a function somewhere between special policing and the paramilitary, linking Vekllei’s treasured infrastructure with its civilian police (“Cosmopor”), armed forces, and shadowy intelligence networks. Though they fulfil police functions today, their history is with the Royal Guards and Federal Police of yesteryear, which in turn has produced unusual units like the &lt;strong&gt;Gold Sappers&lt;/strong&gt;, which are unique in modern policing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gold Sappers are the official police/security detachment of the National Mint of Vekllei. Contrary to popular belief, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/&#34;&gt;Vekllei does in fact mint coinage&lt;/a&gt;, but the Mint is also responsible for the production of paper “Government Crowns” (i.e. labour-backed government bonds) and Vekllei’s gold bullion reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Vekllei may not use money domestically, it spends and receives huge quantities of cash through the International Market in trade with other countries. In many cases, trade is made via gold bullion, which still backs the Vekllei Crown (not the Government Crown — &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#economy&#34;&gt;click here if you’re confused&lt;/a&gt;). Although this gold is often simply moved around a vault in foreign reserves, like the Euro Bullion Exchange or Fort Knox, there are many cases where gold is moved into, out of, and around Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what the Gold Sappers are deployed to protect — Vekllei’s national wealth, in and out of transit. Their name and appearance date back to the colonial Atlantic Junta, when their historical units were deployed to pillage and steal from vulnerable infrastructure amidst war. In Vekllei’s convoluted military history, these unceremonious and criminal units were at some point folded into the Junta’s Royal Guards, then Federal Police, and now exist within the postwar Floral Period &lt;em&gt;Venopor&lt;/em&gt;. In typical fashion for Vekllei, the Gold Sappers are no longer sappers, nor are they a part of the military. Remember, we are discussing a country in which the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/#structure&#34;&gt;postal service is a military organ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the Venopor Gold Sappers retain the beards of their ancestral units, and preserve parts of their heritage through their ceremonial parade dress and traditional songs. In this image we can see illustrated two Sappers in both civilian and paramilitary dress. The redhead holds a submachine gun equipped with drum magazines, which are unusual but commonly used in security units to achieve initial fire superiority and suppress, which allows for repositioning and backup in convoy environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their vehicle is a R.V. Z-type (a military 4WD chassis used in all sorts of configurations) powered by a high-torque electric motor and charged by supercapacitors. That snorkel is for cooling, not exhaust. The Mint Z-type (called a ZMi-1 or -2) are used as escort cars in ground convoys, with bullion protected in armoured trucks. The Mint also has a train, and, in more common use, armoured helijets and jet planes. Gold Sappers accompany their gold and coins every step of the way. Otherwise, its navy livery is indicative of its authority as a &lt;em&gt;Venopor&lt;/em&gt; police wagon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gold Sappers stand out — beards are prohibited across every other armed branch except the spooks and sappers. If you see a Mint convoy coming, stand well back and let it pass — for a country without money, they take their coins seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei&#39;s New-Age Women</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/mii5xm/veklleis_newage_women/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;Lu Xun&lt;/strong&gt;, 1927&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &amp;lsquo;backward elements.&amp;rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;strong&gt;Ding Ling&lt;/strong&gt; on the long-marcher woman soldiers, 1942&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When Tzipora first arrived in Vekllei in 2063&lt;/strong&gt;, she was traumatised by the foreignness of everything. It was not just that they drove on the wrong side of the road, or that the chocolate was made by someone else, but that her whole understanding of the world — the world she’d been raised in all her life — was unravelled within weeks. It did not matter if you learned the language, or dressed like them, or worked with them — the way a Vekllei person thinks seemed totally alien, as though they were tuned into a frequency that she couldn’t hear. That was very difficult for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her clearest memory, out of all the emotional turmoil in her first few weeks, was the clothes. Tzipora was not fashionable or materialistic, but she’d never had nice things to wear. In Vekllei the things on the rack were simple, and often second-hand, but they were very well made and the department stores had a big variety. She picked out five shirts, nearly identical, and decided that these would be what she would wear from now on — it was her own way of establishing an identity; SHE IS THE GIRL WHO WEARS THIS TYPE OF SHIRT. Little things like that mattered a lot, because Tzipora was treated differently here. She was both ‘young’ and a ‘girl’, which had implications for how overseas people talked to her and how she was regarded. Here, almost no one seemed to notice. She had dignity by default, which was exciting and scary at the same time, so she needed something other than her appearance to claim as ‘hers’. And at that time, it was the shirt with the pleats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei is a place that is very much radical&lt;/strong&gt; but, either intentionally or as a byproduct of its opaque culture, suppresses the &lt;em&gt;appearance&lt;/em&gt; of radicalism in its public affairs (or as they say there, ‘sun-facing space’). This is for a few reasons. First, Vekllei uses its obscurity as a weapon against its continental neighbours, who might pull it into geopolitical tensions it wants no part of. The second is that Vekllei’s failed revolutionary movements of the early 20th Century are buried with the Junta that suppressed them. The third, and most critically, is that Vekllei people themselves are unaware of just how saturated their lives are with the cultural and political ideology of the floral period, which makes “foreign” political thinking difficult and results in a lot of empty rhetoric — for example, “petticoat socialism” describes the Bureau System, which does not have much to do with either petticoats or continental socialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paradigm makes more sense when you consider that there are really two Veklleis — the one that existed before the Atomic War, and the one that exists now, called the “Floral Period” or sometimes “Petticoat Society”. The one that existed before has little resemblance to the one that exists now, and that is the way people have continued to think in the decades of independence — anything prior to 2015 is, simply, history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake — Vekllei is tremendously radical in its culture and politics, which it tempers with conservative names and third-way politicking. Today’s post looks at how the Vekllei woman changed in the years between 2005 and 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not unlike revolutions of years past, postwar Vekllei had (for the moment, at least) lost many of its structural oppressors of women, since the structure itself had collapsed quickly. The interim government had taken an orthodox, though contrarian, communist position, which ushered a new handbook of rhetoric towards de-objectification of women and their pragmatic and social value in the workforce. The interim government had several key women figures among it, who are credited with its success in this critical, and rapidly changing period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Vekllei socialist (&lt;em&gt;socialisme oa Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;) line of thinking, there are two points of attack. There was the suppression of old models of feminine beauty, which argued against women’s independence and dignity in favour of their security with men, who made up Vekllei’s economic and social caste throughout the entirety of the Junta’s rule. But there was also a very real fear that women’s liberation by Western metrics would simply evolve indentured living into a more obtuse, and in some ways more sinister, commodity-woman (&lt;em&gt;cosmavisiousnesh&lt;/em&gt;, lit. ‘plastic woman’&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;), who was free to educate herself but found her appearance subjected to permanent scrutiny — a product for a consumer, dependent on shifting fashions and complex social constellations still fundamentally controlled by men. This fear was not unfounded, as many educated women of the interim government (who made up nearly half of its members) had spent significant time in Western Europe and the United States, and were keenly aware of who was “gazing” (&lt;em&gt;lismious&lt;/em&gt;) and who was being “gazed at” (&lt;em&gt;visimett&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution developed by the interim government was both political and spiritual, designed to demolish the external remnants of Vekllei’s pre-war and highly stratified society, and the looming threats of foreign investment, new wealth, and an import of the modern commodity-woman. Most importantly, it understood that present notions of empowerment or disempowerment were problematic unto themselves — whether it was sexual liberation, modesty, or indeed the economic role of women in abstract — their ability to empower was still fundamentally chained to old society, which was still dominated by the sexist cultural default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Cisma de Diviousmesn, First Secretary of the War Recovery Committee, described the problem as such in The &lt;em&gt;Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are nearing a precipice that all Vekllei women may fall into, should we follow unblinkingly the Visis Plan [postwar redevelopment plan], and allow foreign investment to replace English colonial governor-generals; we should be wise enough, so to speak, to not trade a king for a master and call it recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Upen&lt;/em&gt;’s discourse on womanhood, the essential virtues of a woman have always included good words, good work and good fortune — emphasising the role of women as both an alias for success/wealth and also as responsible for that fortune themselves, either in the workplace or through their innate spirituality. This has remained true throughout much of Vekllei’s history, but was obfuscated by the economic masculinity of Vekllei’s protectionist mercantile period. After the war, Upen saw a revival that would culminate in the spiritual fever of the late 2010s and early 2020s. The interim government co-opted this surge pragmatically, encouraging a shift in local perceptions of womanhood through spiritual, rather than political or ideological, methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a New Age,” the posters said. “So become a New-Age Woman.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming a New Age Woman involved two things — tearing down the external oppressions of the old and interim periods (harassment, domestic violence, and male interference in the affairs of women), and the interrogation of internalised sexisms (empowerment by male opinion [this included styles women found attractive, as inherited from men], abolishment of economic preoccupations, and the reconstruction of womanhood in abstract). This individual struggle was supported by the many social programmes developed by the interim government, with names like “economic feminisation” (abolishment of the male economic burden) and “abolishment of self-beautification for your man” (&lt;em&gt;scisimionze&lt;/em&gt;, or “self-adornment/self-beautification”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point was not to empower women by simply displacing men from male economic and social constructions — a move that was seen as disempowering because of who was setting those priorities —  but to rebuild Vekllei’s domestic understanding of “the woman” by the terms of women, legitimised by the authority of the interim government and the powerful cultural force Upen continues to have on society. Within such a culture, it was reasoned, women would be free to choose what womanhood meant to them, since it was not simply reactive to a sexist cultural default. The sum of this effort was called ‘sun-facing,’ or &lt;em&gt;semoisnesne&lt;/em&gt;, which referred to the progressive attitude of both the individual and the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei’s New Age Woman had dramatic effects and benefitted the status of women in Vekllei society tremendously, it was nonetheless fundamentally political and had obscure and surprising cultural artefacts buried within. The idea that a woman would be “free to choose” her own womanhood was a little misleading, since the interim government was rapidly developing its plan for “petticoat society,” in which Sundress Municipalism, the Bureau System and Floral Aestheticism would become such powerful cultural forces that no man nor woman would be able to escape them entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the wealth of the country grew and then exploded in the transition to Vekllei’s floral society, it was clear how the structure of petticoat society continued to influence women in Vekllei. Women can wear whatever they like — but simplicity and subtle self-decoration are common and encouraged by the uniforms system and floral aesthetics. Women can live however they like — but education is compulsory in childhood and highly valued, and young women are encouraged to fulfil ‘the female inclination for leadership’ inherited from Upen’s mother-metaphysics. And women can date whomever they like — though ideological compatibility, and not appearance, is encouraged in the &lt;em&gt;semoisnesne&lt;/em&gt; attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these things are easily argued as good — few would assume there are many feminists in the world who argue against the education of women — but they do betray the notion of truly “free” choice, insofar as Vekllei society is dominated by the economic and spiritual values of its structure. Vekllei considers capitalist economics, exponential growth, and gross historicism to be “masculine” — of course that sort of language trickles down into the social aspects of society. More directly, it prioritises form, colour, and purity in aesthetics — of course that aesthetic ideology affects how people dress, and contributes to its uniformed culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to place where the state begins and ends in Vekllei, which is how it can be argued for as an unfree and anarchic society simultaneously. So too is it difficult to determine how much of Vekllei culture originates in the centres of power in Vekllei — either political or religious — and subsequently there are problems in clarifying how women are affected by power, especially since women participate and in some cases dominate those hierarchies. Are they externalised, or internalised? Who is gazing at who?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of Vekllei’s cultural obscurity, which affects much more than politics and many people other than women, it is clear a dramatic and liberating shift occurred in Vekllei’s interim period of independence, and that shift has contributed tremendously to the status of contemporary Vekllei women, who enjoy economic and social freedoms that were unimaginable just decades prior. Even though Vekllei has not embraced political iconography to celebrate their indigenous feminism, we can see just how radical and wide-ranging the changes made were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phrase &amp;ldquo;plastic woman&amp;rdquo; was coined by author John Graves, whose work found popularity in postwar Vekllei after its translation.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cosmatsisosmiosne de Ne&lt;/em&gt;, lit. &amp;ldquo;Woman of the New Age&amp;rdquo;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Rivers</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/medv4h/city_rivers/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out in Voya Voya&lt;/strong&gt;, the gardens light the people, and distill human temperament into momentary, sequential lyrical images. A dead leaf moving by miracle across still water; an overturned bucket collecting dew along its handle; fern leaves half-curled, young and growing. Vekllei is known as a “garden city,” and Voya Voya has the best of them. Vekllei urban planning is wandering and wasteful, and in this borough the city centre is checkered by wild parks filled with silence and rainforest smells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian and Tzipora were dating, or something adjacent to it. It was an unusual thing they had going on, since they weren’t much like each other. They’d arranged to have a picnic on Sunday, but a few days out the newspaper said it would rain. Rain-dates meant a movie and lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the forecast got worse. It wasn’t just a shower— it was big rain, with high winds. A storm, anyone but Tzipora would say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We should cancel,” Cobian said on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s the big deal? The movie’s indoors, isn’t it?” — that was Tzipora, who was very eager to go out with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, they met at the Couisvisia Hills Station, the one closest to Cobian’s house. They took the train to Lola and talked as rain began to make streams down the windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This looks bad,” Cobian said, not touching the window because she was afraid of germs. “Look at the clouds in the distance, too — It’s gonna pour; I don’t want to get all wet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I brought an umbrella,” said Tzipora, whose responsibilities now included managing the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By some miracle, they reached the cinema before the first storm clouds rolled in. They listened to it whistle beneath the sounds of the film. Occasionally the rain would wash over the roof loud enough to hear it. Every time the storm made a noise Cobian sighed quietly, and Tzipora looked at her anxiously, wringing her hands like she did when she was nervous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the film, they stepped into the lobby to find the rain had ceased. In fact, it had vanished — the gutters were running like hell, and every corner of every roof dripped. But the rain had stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Look,” Tzipora said, stepping over a puddle onto the footpath and presenting the sky to Cobian. “I am a rain goddess.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They made a run to the station through the park as the wind scattered water through the air. Tzipora took about five steps into the park before splashing a puddle up herself and soaking her foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For God’s sake, let’s keep going,” she growled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another two steps and she did it again, with the other foot. In fact, the whole park was sodden, and the gutters had been overwhelmed. The picnic field had turned into a lake. Trees had wilted under the weight of raindrops. The sound of running water was everywhere. Tzipora had given up and began navigating Cobian by the hand like a conscript charging through a minefield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian followed, holding the umbrella open uselessly as the wind chilled the water on their skin. They came across a concrete staircase, now a waterfall, as the park-lake drained into the street below. Tzipora, emboldened with the strength of the sacrificial, stepped into it and helped Cobian jump across without sliding into the mud on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As she did, with water filling her shoes and her skirt dripping footpath water, she thought about how much fun this was. You didn’t go on adventures much at their age. She looked at Cobian, who was shivering in the wind and waiting for her, and thought she probably didn’t feel the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You all right?” Tzipora asked, stepping out and shaking water off her shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian gave a thumbs up as she shivered, and all was right in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sand Mage</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-19-mage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-19-mage/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/m8dxq3/the_sand_mage/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tzipora is a sand mage.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, she isn’t, but I wanted to draw something with particles and ended up doing different paint sketches for a few hours. This was the best one, and also the most stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canonically, Tzipora can’t swim, so she spends more time on the beach than in the water. The colour of the sand here suggests it’s an artificial “white beach” in Mumen or nearby. Most beaches in Vekllei are black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She’s wearing something between regular school uniform and &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/&#34;&gt;national dress&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a bit exaggerated here, but the gold plate and &lt;em&gt;gi&lt;/em&gt; quarter-pleat are common enough ceremonial items. That’s how it works in practice — school uniforms are quite literally undecorated, simpler versions of national dress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t usually work in this style. It’s fun to learn new things, and reinvent yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this is just a sketch, not part of Ocean Month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for hanging out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Killing a Sea Serpent</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-17-serpent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-17-serpent/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/m6ysgj/killing_a_sea_serpent/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ocean Month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in March 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/eyri&#34;&gt;Eyri&lt;/a&gt;, the bones of an ancient beast warp and groan in the sun&lt;/strong&gt;, red skin glinting in the whitecap churn of the shallows, oxidising, broken, ripped open by the sea. Everyone in the North of Vekllei knows about it. Mysteries abound. Even in our atomic century, the humans of Vekllei are enamoured with and terrified by the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Winter of 2018, just three years into Vekllei’s shaky, indigent independence, the TransNorth Oil Company purchased a submarine icebreaker called &lt;em&gt;Sea Serpent&lt;/em&gt; from U.S. Oil. It was a crock of shit, built in the late ‘80s to move crude through the Arctic in the difficult seasons. Submarine icebreakers were among the ugliest boats ever made, with thin necks that cut through ice and a warty conn crown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not unusual for no-name oil companies to buy up old shipping stock, but TransNorth was something else. If you tracked its company address, you came to a dilapidated warehouse in Memphis with signage affixed — totally deserted. It appears, following the paperwork, no one at all had purchased the &lt;em&gt;Sea Serpent&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two months after its sale, an unregistered vessel by chance triggered a decades-old Soviet detection buoy near Vekllei’s EEZ. The Common Interest Watchhawk programme, designed to demilitarise the Arctic after the Atomic War, allowed the Soviets to report the event to Vekllei and the U.K. — perhaps suspicious it was a clandestine U.S. nuclear sub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in a command room of Vekllei’s fledgeling secret service (back then called the Office of National Intelligence, the predecessor to HO/NI), a siren fired off. Sixty minutes later, a military helijet touched down in Basa, a northern military office. A destroyer left port in Montre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buoy was working correctly, and the quiet hum of commercial submarine tech was tracked for eight hours, all the way to Vekllei’s territorial waters. There, the mystery vessel was radioed, radioed again, and destroyed. There was no tolerance for smugglers or spooks in postwar Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirty minutes after depth charges boomed in the North Sea, the &lt;em&gt;Sea Serpent&lt;/em&gt; ran aground on an isolated beach in Eyri. It pushed itself right into the shallows, slashing its coolant pipes on the rocks as it capsized into the beach. With ionised radiation glowing faintly in the water, naval commandos stormed the conning tower, now on its side. Radio equipment, maps, chairs — it had all been flung across the dim interior in its capsizing. Inside were eight men in plain clothes, all dead. All were shot — one self-inflicted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not until fifty years later, during the Dallas Crisis and the secession of the Dallas States, that some sort of clue as to the lair of the &lt;em&gt;Sea Serpent&lt;/em&gt; emerged. As negotiations dragged on for the Dallas lend-lease of U.S. government properties and infrastructure, a building owned by the Chroma Industrial Concern, a Floridian company subsidised by Washington, was included in a trade of some 614 assets leaked to AB/NI. A young AB/NI asset named Baron Desmoisnes, part of the team filing the leaks, followed up and found Chroma had a warehouse in Memphis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears the &lt;em&gt;Sea Serpent&lt;/em&gt; was coming for Vekllei — who says snakes don’t commit suicide?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei’s Sprawling Commonwealth</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-10-commonwealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-10-commonwealth/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/m21j78/veklleis_sprawling_commonwealth/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ocean Month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in March 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome again to Ocean Month. If you have questions, just ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When we say “&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,”&lt;/strong&gt; we most often think of the &lt;em&gt;Home Island&lt;/em&gt;, the city-state to which the country owes its name. In practice, however, the state of Vekllei is portioned between many far-flung corners of the Atlantic Ocean. From tropical jungles and dry wine-making country to mossy woodlands and arctic deserts, “Vekllei” as a singular concept is obfuscated by its diversity of land and people, and better represents a coalition of disparate Atlantic states than a single, centralised city-state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, however — the power is held in the &lt;em&gt;Home Island&lt;/em&gt;, where the vast majority of Vekllei’s people live and work. Her autonomous, satellite regions are indulged and supported as any borough of the &lt;em&gt;Home Island&lt;/em&gt;, but these islands (and they are, invariably, islands) are often small, isolated and of little economic value. What makes them special is that they are populated with vibrant, unique peoples and cultures of considerable history, and are retained for precisely that fact — their cultural benefit for a city-state that considers itself a representative of indigenous Atlantic people; a “third power” between the hegemonies of Europe and America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This map depicts these places — “overseas territories” is what Vekllei calls them — as well as their exclusive economic zones (EEZs), outlined in white. Let’s take the opportunity to have a brief look at some of Vekllei’s most unique and distant regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kala&lt;/strong&gt;, or Greenland, is Vekllei’s “sister land”. Many of the indigenous Arctic people who first settled Vekllei nearly six thousand years ago crossed from or lived in &lt;em&gt;Kala&lt;/em&gt;. The massive glacial island is self-governing, and has its own regional parliament, but is otherwise a possession of Vekllei. Its largest city, &lt;em&gt;Nusc&lt;/em&gt;, reveals just how antagonist &lt;em&gt;Kala&lt;/em&gt; remains towards it inhabitants — just 250,000 people live there, compared to nearly 2.4 millions in Vekllei’s largest borough, &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Proper&lt;/em&gt;. Pack a jacket!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demon&lt;/strong&gt;, or Jan Mayen, is a tiny volcanic satellite island and full overseas territory of Vekllei. It has the smallest population of any overseas province, at just 15,600 people, who live in its only town — &lt;em&gt;Skismi&lt;/em&gt;. As an overseas territory, it receives daily postal service and full entitlements of any Vekllei person, mostly by way of flying boats and hydrofoils.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aismious Isles&lt;/strong&gt;, or the Faroe Islands, are an archipelago of charming people mostly descended from Arctic Vekllei (indigenous Algic people) and early Irish settlers, known for their seafood diets and provinciality. There’s a lot going on in the world, and the people of the Aismious Isles don’t want to know about it — or at least, that’s the consensus. For this reason, it’s popular as the “thinking man’s retreat” from society, as opposed to traditional holiday locales like the Azores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaking of the Azores&lt;/strong&gt;, these islands are unique — while self-governing, they are structured more like a &lt;em&gt;Bureau&lt;/em&gt; than a democracy. Two governments exist there at once — the &lt;em&gt;Azores Holiday Government&lt;/em&gt;, which maintains infrastructure that enables nearly a million Vekllei people to vacation there each year, and the &lt;em&gt;Mira Regional Council&lt;/em&gt;, its neighbour and electorate to which locals cast their ballots. This has, historically, made them very cranky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mira&lt;/strong&gt;, or Madeira, is situated off the coast of Africa and is one of the few places in Vekllei that requires special permits to visit. It is both heavily protected as a wildlife reserve and a major naval port for the Royal Vekllei Armed Forces at &lt;em&gt;Sumi&lt;/em&gt;, its largest city. As is encouraged throughout Vekllei, people here live the way they have for hundreds of years, just more quietly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kalina Isles&lt;/strong&gt;, made up of many islands of the Lesser Antilles, are a tropical archipelago of hundreds of small islands, many of which are unpopulated. Like &lt;em&gt;Kala&lt;/em&gt;, the Kalina Isles are self-governing, and while its old colonial towns and indigenous Caribbean culture may not at first appear “Vekllei”, you’ll find their relaxed lifestyles and deep appreciation for landscape unite them in spirit with all Vekllei territories, from the Home Island to Demon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Antarctic Territories&lt;/strong&gt; are, somehow, more isolated in feeling than her Lunar cities. During the late 2050s, when sovereignty started to be enforced in the antarctic, Vekllei retained its claim by encouraging domestic tourism to the South Pole. On the coast, an airport services a civilian city called Desma of hotels and commerce, which is marked by the dramatic, hostile desert that surrounds it. The further inland you go, the less accessible the settlements become, finally arriving at the military/scientific Polar Station at the South Pole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Lunar Territories&lt;/strong&gt; are, through the miracle of our current age, accessible to the average Vekllei person. This fact is one of the great sources of pride Vekllei people feel toward their country, and many visit at least once. Moidonnet, or “Moon City”, is one of only a handful of lunar settlements open to the public, and is unique in its accessibility to the people of its home country. Some 45,000 people live there semi-permanently, taking calcium pills to keep their bones healthy, under the large glass domes of the city. Many more visit — and are left with the memories of a lifetime, and the humbling experience of gazing upon our small blue planet from above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is clear, then, that Vekllei’s conceptual and political bias towards its northern territories is misleading, since — at least domestically — isolation and island living is a foundational aspect of how Vekllei people understand themselves. Although someone from Mira might at first be a novelty to a person of the Home Islands, it very soon becomes apparent that Mira is, in fact, Vekllei — its weather might be warmer, and its people might look different, but their lives are very similar, premised on gentle living and Vekllei’s complex metaphysics of landscape. That is what it means to be “Vekllei,” no matter where you are in the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marine Railway</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-06-marine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-06-marine/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/lz8q54/the_marine_railway/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ocean Month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in March 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint blue&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;❖ Note from the Editor&lt;/strong&gt;
Although vessels described here are written with female pronouns as per Western convention, Vekllei traditionally uses male pronouns for navy vessels.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuclear Heavy Battlecruiser V.V.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lava&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is the first of the Lava-class cruisers, the largest of Vekllei’s surface warships. Vekllei doctrine does not typically float cruisers with fleets, and so the &lt;em&gt;Lava&lt;/em&gt; often operates independently, outfitted for a variety of roles. She can be sailed into any storm-ravaged port and hook up to the local electric grid, powering tens of thousands of homes with her enormous molten salt fission reactor. She is equipped for both fire support and assault. 5 large guns of 50-100mm calibers crater the shore as missiles, torpedoes and lasers of various types fight off threats from the air and sea. She is even equipped for beach assaults and boarding, with 6 assault boats and 5 helijets available to offload hundreds of maritime commandos, which are deployed frequently in Vekllei’s ongoing fight against illegal fishing. Her multipurpose mission is reflected in the visibility of her superstructure, which boasts heliports, vertical launch systems, rack missiles, and heavy guns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, she enters the world’s largest marine railway in the port town of Cisadra. As she sits in the water here, her sailors have disembarked and her helijets are preparing to relocate as thousands of tons of ballast is pumped into a treatment facility. Once her weight is reduced to a mere 25,000 tonnes, she will be chained to the massive marine railway ‘cradle’ — the supports and bed on which she sits — and slowly pulled by massive nuclear winches into the shallow water of the Cisadra Shipyards, a naval facility owned by the Royal Vekllei Armed Forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This marine railway is the largest of its kind, and was unfathomably expensive to build. The Navy of Vekllei maintains a naval station in the Lesser Antilles to support strategic nuclear sites it retains on the Kalina Islands, and large-scale dredging and dock construction was deemed unsuitable for the sorts of harbours common to the area. Although a number of ideas, including a floating shipyard were hypothesised, the Cisadra Marine Railway was built after the success Vekllei had with similar systems in the Home Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read on for a little more information on the Kalina Islands.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Kalina Islands&lt;/strong&gt; (made up of &lt;em&gt;Anguilla&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;St Martin, St Kitts &amp;amp; Nevis&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Montserrat&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Antigua&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Barbuda&lt;/em&gt;) are an autonomous overseas territory of &lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, structured as a self-managing dependent state similar to &lt;strong&gt;Kala&lt;/strong&gt; (Greenland) and the &lt;strong&gt;Aismious&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Islands&lt;/strong&gt; (Faroe). Although their origins are colonial, today they are a full overseas state of Vekllei with the same entitlements and voting rights as any Home Islands &lt;em&gt;Borough&lt;/em&gt;. They remain autonomous in internal policy, similar to a provincial government, and across their hundreds of tropical islands there are some 350,000 people, all of them holding both Vekllei and Kalina citizenship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kalina Islands were purchased from the Spanish in the 17th century, and indicated Vekllei’s initial intention to exploit the New World. This ambition was scuppered with the collapse of the Vekllei monarchy, which established forts across them but could not muster the resources to occupy continental America. Vekllei’s colonial efforts were blunted for centuries after, and excluded the country from major participation in the slave trade and the colonisation of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leaves the Kalina Islands, named after its native peoples, in a peculiar position as both a legacy of the early colonial period while also remaining home to the only major populations of Island Carib people (&lt;em&gt;Kalinago&lt;/em&gt;) left in the world. On adjacent overseas territories, like the British Virgin Islands and Guadaloupe, they died out from murder and disease — but through the sheer failure of Vekllei’s colonial policy, they live on as an association of island territories in the 21st Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being thousands of kilometres apart with dramatically different cultures and climates, both the Home and Kalina Islands remain “Vekllei” by way of their ancient cultures, maritime histories and moneyless bureau system. In this sense, the success and prosperity of the Kalina Islands reestablish what “Vekllei” is — where once it meant the indigenous people of the Arctic North, today it represents a coalition of Atlantic territories united in their dependence on landscape and economic systems. If the Kalina Islands were to become independent, it is likely little would change — their centuries of history with the Home Islands have cemented a desire for landscape sovereignty and postindustrial localism, and along with Kala and the Aismious, Vekllei has forged an alternative way of living for indigenous Atlantic peoples caught between the hungry machines of America and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/lve4he/justice/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lin Zhi was nuts&lt;/strong&gt;. She was lovely, but she was nuts. Tzipora followed along, pleading occasionally, a squeaking voice of concern. The cricket bat dragged and bounced along the poor road sealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You could go to prison,” Tzipora said, protesting weakly. “Why not send Moise and his boys? They’ll put the fear of God in him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is stupid,” Zhi said in clumsy Vekllei, staring ahead. “You do not know what it’s like.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I do know,” Tzipora whined. Between their second-hand Vekllei and conflicting accents, they struggled to understand each other. “They call me a gypsy bitch. But I don’t hit them. And not with a bat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhi and Zelda were much alike. They were both fresh immigrants of school age, and stepped ashore with shadows of a world far beyond Vekllei’s utopian domesticity. Tzipora had spent time indigent in America, nearly lynched in Utah. Zhi had lost her father and uncle to the purges in Red China. Zhi told Tzipora she was the great-great-granddaughter of a hero of the communist party, who’d fought with Mao Tse-tung himself over a century ago. Tzipora did not enquire further, since she knew as much about China as she did the moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No one is asking you to come,” Zhi said, marching ahead as Tzipora trailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Don’t be silly, I’m coming with you. Of course I’m coming with you. I just don’t want you to ruin your life over some words.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Words add up,” Zhi said quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of Zhi’s seven sisters had taken European names to better assimilate into the hectic transcontinental &lt;em&gt;aliyah&lt;/em&gt; of postwar Vekllei. Not Zhi, though. She was wilful and clear-minded, maybe recklessly. Tzipora liked her and feared her, perhaps because she saw herself in Zhi’s frequent outbursts of anger and principled view of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Floral Period was stuffed with new citizens, many of them in disfavour of the politics of their home country. Many of them came from Asia — &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/&#34;&gt;Ayn’s&lt;/a&gt; father was a Hong Konger, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/&#34;&gt;Jiro&lt;/a&gt; was from Tokyo. Vekllei’s people were indigenously “Asiatic in appearance,” as Europe called them. Most were descended from a mixture of Arctic peoples and Irish or Scandinavian settlers. To this end, Vekllei’s complicated ethnic makeup contributes to the country’s obscurity from the U.S. and Europe, as they tend to be orientalised outside of Western concern. This discrimination does not stop Vekllei people from maintaining ignorant ideas towards its incoming East Asian and South-East Asian migrants, however, and people like Zhi often had to deal with racist abuse in public and in private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why don’t we be smart about this?” Tzipora asked, upset. “What he did to you is against school policy. He’ll be thrown out — it’ll ruin him. That’s what hurts, really. Trust me, I know. I know what it’s like for you, too. But he wants to go to the National University. If we get him thrown out, that would ruin him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhi scoffed, and shook her head. “That you could think the school would do anything shows how little you know,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Baron is powerful. He can lean on them. He does it all the time, he’d help if I asked. I know he would.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora stepped in front of her, and put her arms out. Her eyes were shining with tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was going to get expelled for putting a girl’s head through a window, and it was like this,” Tzipora said, sniffling. “She picked on me every day. Every day, she knew I was lonely and sad so she’d scare me. And one day I snapped and put her head through the window. I was going to be expelled, and my life would have ended there. But Baron knew I was right, and he stepped in. Sometimes that’s all it takes, to beat them. It just takes an outsider.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhi had stopped marching, and leaned on the bat. She was out of breath. She shook her head and tossed the bat at Tzipora’s feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Okay,” she said. “Because I like you, Zelda, that’s all. Don’t tell him anything. Don’t tell anyone anything. This is my problem. But I don’t want to upset you. We’re quite similar, I think.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Too similar,” Tzipora said, wiping her eyes. “But it’s not our fault. Not really.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post is for People</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/lpwe8j/post_is_for_people/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in February 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caught amidst sunrays in early Autumn, things are good&lt;/strong&gt;. You could call almost anyone on the telephone these days. And if you wanted to see someone, why travel? A videophone was just as good. But just as the photograph failed to displace the painter, neither did the telephone or videophone succeed in killing the hand-written letter. There was something thoughtful about it. It was intimate, but also dependent on memory. Memories of people, memories of places. It was slower, yes, but that&amp;rsquo;s just how life worked in this country. It is a good way to live.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Things Around</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-20-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-20-around/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/locjnz/turning_things_around/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His hand was hurting bad, but no one asked him about it the day after&lt;/strong&gt;. Moise always had a temper, and now he had a reputation. He got no words of sympathy from the other seniors of Lola 8th School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering his bluntness and irritability, it was funny that he could only make good friends with women. His father was a bastard and his mother was in Greece, so his sister took their place. His closest friend was Tzipora, the boyish miracle child who helped him lose weight. His love was Coretti, his high school sweetheart and, a little further along, his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti was the daughter of Congolese scientists, but was born and raised in the Soviet Union. She had a typical brief for Afro-Russians — her father had worked with the Congo Water Company, and later was brought over for the Soviet Ministry of Agriculture and Food. She spent her early years in the relative wealth of the Basmanny District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrangement collapsed quickly after the coup in Congo and the death of Party Secretary Shchusev. The office her father worked for disappeared, and the family emigrated to Vekllei when she was six. Vekllei was full of displaced people with displaced heritage. After all, Moise was himself the son of wealthy Greek folk, his mother a fascist in the shadow party there. The way their identities intersected brought about difficult dimensions to their character — often empowering, occasionally suffocating, and sometimes resurrecting ghosts from their past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise was graduating this year with Coretti, and had already landed a gig running cameras for Dovo Studios, a big deal for someone his age. His real passion was filmmaking — the creation of dreams. That was on hold, after last night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some shithead assistant-to-an-assistant was mouthing off about him to the C.A., telling him he had an attitude. Moise didn’t know what this guy’s problem was, and he kept picking at him all night. Moise didn’t take shit, and got up in his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked at his right hand, which was swollen so fat he couldn’t tuck his fingers in. It’d be right in a couple days, maybe a week. But he was off the set for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti hated his fighting. Tzipora, ever the contrarian by way of instinct, admired him for it. It was like those cartoons with the angels and devils on your shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I hate it when you fight,” says Coretti, in a white gown and halo. “You’re a better man than that, I know it in your heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Is that right?” Tzipora says, with horns and a tail. “Seems to me he’s proved exactly who he’s better than.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’d lost his job and got in trouble again, but as Moise lit a cig and sat back, the whole afternoon ahead of him, he felt pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” he said, and took a drag. “Serves me right.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philately Foolery</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/llaimo/philately_foolery/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in February 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re going to do a deep dive on stamps today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can tell a domestic Vekllei stamp from its international counterpart quite easily:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domestic stamps have a coloured square, called a &lt;em&gt;chromacode,&lt;/em&gt; used for sorting mail automatically within the country by a special machine called a &lt;em&gt;kinosemimatia&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domestic stamps do not show a price in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#5-economy&#34;&gt;Vekllei Kroner&lt;/a&gt;, and generally do not use the Vekllei hieroglyph to announce its origin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can deduce that the stamps pictured above are all &lt;em&gt;domestic&lt;/em&gt; stamps used for sending mail to other Vekllei people, regardless of whether they live in Antarctica, Vekllei’s lunar colonies or anywhere in-between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stamps are valuable records of their time, particularly as memories of celebration. You can learn a lot about a place and what it values by looking at its stamps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s take a look at some of Vekllei’s domestic postage stamps from the last few years. From the top left:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2063 marked the launch of the third generation of Vekllei rocket booster since independence in 2015. The introduction of these boosters, spaced evenly across the postwar decades, marked eras in themselves for Vekllei’s extraterrestrial ambitions. By the 2060s, most metals were mined off-world, marking one of the greatest weapons for peace in the atomic era — vast new worlds of untapped resources. This particular postage stamp was released as part of a set celebrating Vekllei rocketry, including recent expeditions to planetoids on the very periphery of our solar system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puffins are the national bird and appear everywhere. You can see why — they’re pretty birds and very common in Vekllei. They are popularly circulated on stamps in a variety of styles simply because people like to see them when sending and receiving mail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This stamp may look abstract at first, but is actually a message in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/language/#7-vekllei-semaphore&#34;&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/a&gt;. Green and gold represent nature and living blood, which alternated like this usually refers to natural chaos. But there’s more to it — this striping pattern, called a sunburst in Vekllei hieroglyphs, refers to the sun, and can mean warmth. These swooping white lines mean purity, or delicateness, and those patterned squares are used for the borders of announcements from the Prime Minister’s Office. So can you guess what this stamps says? It’s announcing Vekllei’s success in the Olympics in skiing, of course. Vekllei Semaphore is rarely straightforward — it has a thousand quirks built over a thousand years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of the Prime Minister’s Office, this is Ms. Prime Minister Jo Sismiosnah, one of two Prime Ministers in the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atomic weaponry is a fact of life in the 2060s, and Vekllei has a complex psychological relationship with nukes as both a victim and retainer of nuclear weapons. It is also the only country in the world to have detonated nuclear weapons for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/&#34;&gt;cultural purpose&lt;/a&gt;. This stamp depicts such a detonation. In the absurdity of the Royal Mail Press, antinuclear stamps are also produced simultaneously, depicting white doves urging world leaders to denuclearise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This flower, called a Lava Rose, is common to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/railmap.jpg&#34;&gt;Lumiousniyah&lt;/a&gt; region on the West of the country. Not by coincidence, its chromacode is destined for Copette.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei retains a great many nuclear icebreakers to keep shipping traffic moving in and out of its Northern regions. The country depends heavily on foreign shipping for its bizarre peripheral markets and such icebreakers are often celebrated on stamps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is Vekllei’s lovely agricultural belt throughout its rich volcanic interior, specifically based off Kyala’s wheat fields. By no coincidence, its chromacode is destined for Kyala.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we see a celebration of Anglo-Vekllei relations in the post-occupation period. Although historical tensions will linger for many generations more, and disputes over fishing rights in the Atlantic continue to threaten friendly relations, Vekllei is very keen in a political context to celebrate the diplomatic successes achieved with the U.K. since occupation, and you’ll find the U.K. generally overrepresented on Vekllei’s ‘foreign’ domestic stamps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now that’s a lot of stamp facts!&lt;/strong&gt; Before we go, Tzipora has just a couple of words on starting your own stamp collection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEVER PEEL STAMPS&lt;/strong&gt;. Cut them off the envelope and soak it in water for an hour or so, until it separates freely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dry your stamps on a tea towel. Press them with books so they don’t curl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your stamps safe by keeping them in an album, preferably.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share your stamps. Stamps are meant to be shared, so never be afraid to trade your boring Vekllei stamps to some friendly Soviet or American for theirs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s all for now&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ve got one more post left in “Mail Week” (more like Mail Month at this rate), before we head off to something new. It’s going to be very exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stamp Manufacturie</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/lhq4in/the_stamp_manufacturie/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in February 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Stamp Manufacturie of the Royal Mail Press&lt;/strong&gt;, located on 5th Avenue, churns millions of stamps a year out of its massive drum presses. Stamps are used on mail instead of postcodes, and as payment for the international and courier work the Royal Mail does abroad. Since Vekllei does not use money domestically, Vekllei people do not pay for postage and stamps are used in the automatic sorting system to determine the destination for any Vekllei territory, including its arctic, peripheral and antarctic possessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main factory, seen here, is an original &lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt; building in the simple, postwar style common in the time it was built. The street and loading area it looks over is actually just one part of the Royal Mail headquarter complex, and the surrounding city blocks have slowly been claimed for the Mail’s singular mission: reliable post for Vekllei people, anywhere in the world. In the background, the Mail Tower, so it’s called, punctuates the mid-rise skyline of the Capital. The tower is actually a vestigial artefact of a military telecommunications facility, now home to the Mail’s Office of Telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At street level, pedestrians can take lunch at the Royal Mail Press Cafeteria, tour the Royal Vekllei Philatelic Museum, or take a monorail to the Royal Mail Post Office General, where the organisation is administrated. Like many State Requisite manufacturers, these facilities are available to the public via tours, which make common day trips for the unburdened Vekllei worker/holidaymaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a closer look at why the The First Post Office of the Royal Vekllei Mail looks the way it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has throughout much of its history evolved outside of Western rationalism, and this incurs all sorts of peculiarities in its public life, not least of which its affection for the perceptual, affective, natural and other unsentimental artefacts of pre-rational thought. For Vekllei people, art is just the decoration of ordinary life. In architecture, this is catastrophic; buildings in Vekllei are not “projects,” and they have no “subject” that centres its design. This has resulted in the bizarre manifestation of a sort of postwar postmodernism, rooted in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/religion/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and valorised by &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/&#34;&gt;Vekllei Metaphysics&lt;/a&gt;, in which informal poststructural utopianism is projected onto the objects — in this case, buildings and factories — of ordinary life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei modernism is basically utopian. Not utopian in the way this whole project is; as a peculiar expression of being — but utopian in its unabashed projection of texture and emotion in place of an authentic art-form. &lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt; is utopian in the sense that buildings are not art-objects, and they serve a rational purpose agnostic to subjectivity. &lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt; is also unsentimental, as art is merely the decoration of ordinary life in Vekllei, not dissimilar to language or cooking. It is obvious, then, that architecture and art have been separated intentionally in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt; is the face of this cultural legacy, and despite its poststructural origins, is deeply modernist in appearance. It is styled in the instinct of the postwar period, as symbolic of recovery and wealth. It gives very little concern to imitation of past styles or structural gimmicks — it prioritises geometry, cleanliness, “the human face” (meaning original human construction; not biomimicry) and dependence on place. Although influenced by experiments in modernism in France and the United States, it is mostly indigenous and isolationist today, as the rest of the world rumbles amidst yet another crisis of architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3,000 MEMBERS!</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-09-3000/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-09-3000/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/lg66i4/3000_members/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m Hobart,&lt;/strong&gt; and I’m the creator of this place. I’ve been drawing Vekllei for a few years now, and I love doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate 3,000 members, &lt;strong&gt;use this as a cosy thread/AMA to settle in,&lt;/strong&gt; and have any questions you might have about the project answered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who are new, &lt;strong&gt;I encourage you to read the posts pinned to the top of the subreddit&lt;/strong&gt; for a crash course in what’s going on here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For longtime friends, come say hi! &lt;strong&gt;This is a party thread, whoo!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quik Fax:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; is a country set in what we know as &lt;strong&gt;Iceland&lt;/strong&gt;, in an alternate vision of the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s my &lt;strong&gt;utopia&lt;/strong&gt;, which means it’s an expression of everything I value in life, the good and the bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I draw all sorts of things, and write about all sorts of topics — all set in Vekllei or other countries. It’s slowly becoming a comprehensive utopia, filling in everything from &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/&#34;&gt;economics&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/&#34;&gt;love stories&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/&#34;&gt;metaphysics&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/&#34;&gt;espionage&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll notice the scope shift a lot in my posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project has a &lt;strong&gt;comic&lt;/strong&gt; being worked on, available to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;patrons&lt;/a&gt; as an ongoing series of drafts at the moment. Otherwise, “&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;” is what you see here — a collection of &lt;strong&gt;posts&lt;/strong&gt; that are snapshots of the world. It doesn’t have an end goal, it’s just what I like to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every post I have ever made&lt;/strong&gt;, plus an expanding collection of &lt;strong&gt;wiki articles&lt;/strong&gt; about this project, can be found at my website: &lt;a href=&#34;http://millmint.net/&#34;&gt;millmint.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you sincerely for paying attention and caring for my work. It’s a wonderful thing we’ve got going here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hobart&lt;/strong&gt;/MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;Join the Patreon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be “petticoat”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racing the Post Office to the Station</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ldfq1p/racing_the_post_office_to_the_station/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in February 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was the hottest day of June so far, in that time of year where the sun never set on Vekllei. It was the first week of sleepless nights; the windows thrown open, air sticky and pungent with the smells of the rainforests, tossing and turning in the heat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A stab of panic shot through her as she woke, bleary-eyed and senseless, to the quiet bedside clock. She blinked a couple of times before the terror set in. She’d overslept — 08:32 — but critically, the Travelling Post Office left at 8:30. Shit, shit shit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maybe, just maybe, she could run to the next station and catch it when it stopped to offload the grocer’s produce.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lying atop damp sheets, she rolled out of bed and made a racket on the wooden floor of her house, wiping her eyes as she looked for her friend’s package. She flew out the front door moments later in the shorts and tee shirt she’d slept in, raking a sandal across the gravel as she landed awkwardly. It was usually a fifteen minute walk to the station, so she ran as fast as she could, the package bouncing off her leg painfully as she took off down the drive. Warm raindrops started to hit the dirt around her.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As she rounded the corner where the dirt track met paved path, she met it — the No. 76 Mail Train, closing in from behind. The mist had rolled in and the hot rain was belting down. No. 76 was going to overtake her — but she still might catch it before it departed. This was going to be close.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Trains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;Rail Post Offices&lt;/strong&gt;, are a common sight in Vekllei once you leave the dense urban infrastructure of its coastal cities behind. The further you venture into Vekllei’s dramatic, tendril-like mountain ranges and igneous valleys, the smaller towns become. Some, like Montre-Lola, had their post offices closed long ago, and today are served by a series of travelling post offices that run along the ubiquitous web of commuter rail lines in the country. The advantages are obvious; one train, running along a single line, can service six or seven towns in a morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They pull into a siding, usually the platform of the local station in quiet towns, and wait for fifteen minutes or so to allow for the loading and unloading of mail. They can also perform duties of regular post offices, like the renewal of identification and travel booking, as long as you phone ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern Mail Trains are typically based on the Series 225 EMU in 2-car configurations. These are modern locomotives with electric motors in each car, allowing the 225 (known as the &lt;em&gt;RM Series&lt;/em&gt; in its Mail Train configuration) to easily run along Vekllei’s old interior rail lines, which have steep gradients and tight curves. The exception is the Siviouscopet de Desmisnion, or &lt;em&gt;Ambassador of the Postmistress&lt;/em&gt;, a special mail-sorting train based on the 6-car Series 4000 trainset that operates between the Capital and Montre. The &lt;em&gt;Ambassador&lt;/em&gt; is particularly special, since it houses a fully furnished office available to the Postmistress General for her use in running the Royal Vekllei Mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora here has encountered the simple adventures of rural living; navigating the friendly bureaucracy of her government from small towns long since forgotten in common memory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fairie</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/lbrfhk/the_fairie/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in February 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The M.S.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fairie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model 54-2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;“Mail Hopper” is a strange aircraft&lt;/strong&gt;. The basic design has remained unchanged for over a hundred years, imported from the United States way back during the massive scrapping of junk warplanes after the Second World War. Even back during the Junta years the country had little respect for foreign intellectual property, and by 1949 had started rolling out Imitation Catalinas, which were among the first indigenous aircraft in the country. A hundred years on, the Fairie is still being developed and produced, its most recent version rolling out in 2054.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Government Aircraft Factories (the actual name of the organisation and design bureau is literally “Government Aircraft Manufacturie”) produce military aircraft for Vekllei’s armed forces. And since the Royal Mail is technically a military organisation, Mail vehicle contracts are furnished by the government arms merchants of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While keeping the same basic form and fuselage of the ancient Catalinas, the &lt;em&gt;Fairie&lt;/em&gt; has been thoroughly overhauled inside and out. The twin props have been replaced by low-power Sami &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/&#34;&gt;S.p.M.&lt;/a&gt; electric pulse jets raised high off the seas to keep salt water out, which are angled slightly downwards. Though inefficient at the sorts of altitudes the &lt;em&gt;Fairie&lt;/em&gt; flies at, they are much quieter than turbofans and better suited for slow flying, benefitting the low-speed gliding tendencies of the aircraft. The aircraft is smaller overall than its predecessors, with a redesigned tail and wingspan that lower the &lt;em&gt;Fairie&lt;/em&gt;’s stall speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has many islands, and more emerge all the time. This is a violently volcanic country after all, and after a day of churning seawater whole new landmasses can appear off the coast. The archipelago communities of these landmasses are often serviced by light flying boat aircraft like the &lt;em&gt;Fairie.&lt;/em&gt; Some of them, like this one here, are seaplanes exclusively and have no landing gear (the “-2” of its designation refers to this omission). Others, especially those assigned to the arctic, are equipped with skis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail retains fourteen &lt;em&gt;Fairies&lt;/em&gt; across the Home Islands, and a further six across the Azores, Aismious (Faroe Islands) and Kala (Greenland). To the people they service, these planes represent much more than the arrival of the mail — they are a direct gesture of the mother Vekllei state; a reminder they are not forgotten by the Crown Metropole, and a pipeline to friends and relatives across oceans. These pilots are among the luckiest in the world, flying superbly engineered aircraft, refined over a century, across some of the most striking lands and oceans on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus: &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/&#34;&gt;a much larger Vekllei aircraft built by the Comen Aeroyards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Postmistress of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/lazslw/the_postmistress_of_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in February 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here we have arranged the highest-ranking and lowest-ranking members&lt;/strong&gt; of the Royal Vekllei Mail (Mail A.r.). On the left is an Office Postgirl, a precursory position tasked with distributing letters in the sprawling bureau complexes abundant in the centralised postwar period. This particular employee is Aleja Hernández, who has decided she’d rather deliver mail than spend another year studying for high school exit exams. Mail runs in her blood — her father, a Dominican, is stationed abroad in service of the Royal Mail’s Cuba Office with her mother, a native of the country. They’ll be abroad until the Spring, and by the time they get back they expect Aleja to have found full-time work with the Mail. She wears a baggy smock to keep ink and dirt off her uniform. Here, she represents a common intern of the organisation, tasked with menial and uninteresting work for a few weeks as she’s trained to be a proper Postwoman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between someone like Aleja and the Acting General Postmistress is the Postmistress does not spill letters all over the hallway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current General Postmistress of the country is Sious Desmesneh, who stands here beside Aleja. At 32, she is the youngest Postmistress in Vekllei’s history. She is also among the most cunningly ambitious people currently employed by the Mail, and scandalously usurped her immediate superiors to inherit the role after the passing of Postmaster John Iousasmor, a shock promotion formalised by a landslide company ballot in May last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is only appropriate that she ascended via coup, since the Postmaster General is a &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; military rank, equivalent to an Admiral in the navy. The Mail is a State Requisite, not a military organ, but it retains a formal military leadership and ranked hierarchy from its origins as a military communications organ many centuries ago. Although a military “General,” Sious has no actual military powers and serves less exotically as a &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; director of the Mail A.r. She wears the Postmistress’s uniform, complete with traditional Vekllei &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/&#34;&gt;floral plate&lt;/a&gt; and round &lt;em&gt;heismious&lt;/em&gt; hat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the flag of the Royal Mail is depicted above Aleja. Most bureau-sized organisations in Vekllei have their own flags, as part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/language/#7-vekllei-semaphore&#34;&gt;Vekllei semaphore&lt;/a&gt;, and the Mail Flag is flown alongside the domestic and regional standards outside every post office in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Men and Women of the Royal Mail in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/la73mx/the_men_and_women_of_the_royal_mail_in_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in February 2021
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are not many postal services older than the Royal Vekllei Mail&lt;/strong&gt;. It is so old that in the Vekllei language its title is simply ‘Mail’ — the ‘Royal’ and ‘Vekllei’ are implied by the use of its hieroglyph. Founded in 1422 as part of the military communications system between government and mercantile government holdings, it has survived various restructurings — and several wars — to remain a critical communications and cultural institution today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is the usual way with State Requisites (A.r.), the (Royal Vekllei) Mail maintains a state monopoly on all paper and electric mail in the country, serviced by a workforce of nearly fifty thousand people and two hundred thousand &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/&#34;&gt;automen&lt;/a&gt;. Peculiarly, telephones, telegrams and videophones are structured under the Mail as the Mail Bureau Office of Telecommunications, which acts as an independent organ of the Mail A.r.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people send nearly 12 million letters a day — that’s about one for every two people, and the Mail processes and delivers another 40 million mail pieces a day. It does this with a fleet of jets, automatic trucks, dedicated mail trains, intercity pneumatic systems, vehicle automen, and postmen, all wearing the red and gold colours of the organisation. It previously served the King of Vekllei, during the years of monarchy, and today serves the Royal (Land) Sovereign — the confusing name for the landscape of Vekllei and its potential for human use. It is &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; bound by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#floral-society&#34;&gt;Petticoat constitution of the Floral Period.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people love their Mail, as a patriotic analogy for the unity of the city-state. Red postboxes are visible on every street in city boroughs, and in the country Post Offices serve as critical contact points for communities isolated from urban business. The announcing of the Mail’s Postmaster General is a deeply ceremonial affair, second only to the ascension of new Prime Ministers. Vekllei was home to the world’s first Postmistress General, Mi Miou, in 2016 shortly after independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is only appropriate that the Universal Postal Union, the U.N. body responsible for the worldwide mail treaty coordinating international postage, is headquartered in Vekllei’s Capital district, two blocks away from the Mail’s luxurious &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; head post office and administration complex. As one of the oldest of Vekllei’s ancient, evolving state institutions it perhaps best symbolises the age and service of the Vekllei state to its people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Puffling</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/l69ctu/the_puffling/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She joined the Puffin Scouts to make friends&lt;/strong&gt;. Tzipora was not especially rugged or outdoorsy, but she was a fresh patriot, and the idea of collecting awards for conservation, in her mind, was much like Baron collecting medals for killing reds in the War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The green and gold of the Puffin Scouts represent nature and living blood respectively. Entwined, as here on her scarf, they mean the chaos and inhumanity of nature in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language#7-vekllei-semaphore&#34;&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/a&gt;. Puffin Scout troops are based out of a region with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kronaismioudelfia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Crown Land), which are abandoned wild areas the Vekllei state has relinquished to the natural spirits worshiped in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/religion/&#34;&gt;Upen&lt;/a&gt;. Hikes aren’t done in Crown Lands because if someone gets hurt or goes missing it can be very difficult to get them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These wildernesses captured Tzipora’s imagination, since they are often the site of gods and extranatural features. The animals you saw out there seemed deeply disturbed by the presence of people, as though they were the vessels of spirits, irritated that a human girl had made her way in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School-aged Puffin Scouts are called Pufflings. In Vekllei, puffin birds are as common as gulls, and nest in cliffs where they raise their young in burrows. Tzipora, despite being a Puffling, never had much luck with puffins. They seemed to exempt her from their natural friendliness and curiosity — they flew away whenever she came close, and when they didn’t fly away they attacked her. She joined the Puffin Scouts to make friends, and yet here she was, cast out from both the Human and Animal Kingdoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this picture, Tzipora watches a puffin in full scout regalia, wary of its intent. The birds make cute novelties for some, but Tzipora knows better. Just like Baron in the war, she sits still and watches closely, listening for movement on the wind. They are locked in a battle of the wits, waiting to see who will make the first move.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moments in Love</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/l3kbsy/moments_in_love/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lava was a modern walled city.&lt;/strong&gt; It had long lost its walls, but its florid green belt disguised a complex network of trenches, tunnels and forts that linked emplacements in the surrounding mountains. Together, these systems would ensure Vekllei would never again have to tolerate occupation by a foreign power. Lava was on the outskirts of Vekllei’s great capital city, and much of its cityscape was dispersed, affording residents a slower pace of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above Lava’s commercial heart were its terraced hills, and from up there you could see the canal ferries wind their way through the city. At the edge of a terraced park sits a bench full of memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Tzipora looked the same as ever, she was 20 now. Cobian was nearly 18, and considering more sincerely her future. She cared about what other people thought of her. To that end they were always worlds apart. Tzipora was driven by a self-sustaining obsessive intuition, not the advice of her peers. Her imitation of ordinary teen-age life was usually misguided and clumsy. She had never made a good teenager — a good much of anything, really. But she was a very good Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even now, Tzipora didn’t really think of herself as a homosexual, in the same way she didn’t consider herself a girl who wore glasses despite the near-sighted prescription specs she kept in her purse. After all, as she liked to say, there was nothing sexy about her — a good Catholic education and a miracle prepubescence saw to that. In the prejudice of the time, that’s what it meant to be a homosexual, at least to her. So this relationship — whatever it was — was not really that. She could avoid public judgement and her own ongoing prejudices if she simply pretended like her sincere feelings for Cobian did not amount to homosexuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was a funny person, capable of great emotional maturity and immaturity depending on her environs. With Baron, she was serious and independent. With Cobian, she was energetic and overeager. Cobian was in no such turmoil about her preference of partner, and unlike Tzipora she was becoming an adult woman capable of exploring a serious, adult relationship. She would grow older and older, and Tzipora would stay there, same as ever. They both knew it was coming. Tzipora was not a child, but she was also not exactly an adult either — she was Tzipora, and she would be Tzipora for as long as she lived, much as she was now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora didn’t generally talk about her feelings, but Cobian was very good at it. They travelled to the terraced park from Lola, and found the bench they’d visited years prior as junior high school students. Back then they’d seen a film at the State Cinema in town and walked for a while after, just talking about it. They’d ended up here, as night fell, and talked until the early morning. Maybe it was a date; maybe it was their first date — what constituted a date with Tzipora? Their relationship was much the same as it had ever been, just with the knowledge they loved each other. But what a revelation that had been. Tzipora had cried when she told her. Tzipora did not cry about much but gestures of affection always overwhelmed her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today they sat on that bench again and talked, and they talked for a long while. What will you study? What will we do? What will Tzipora do for the rest of her life — is she destined to drift from person to person, parasitically enjoying their friendship until they aged out of her reach? Where would Cobian live? What would Tzipora like to do for a living? Will they always be friends, and love each other?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, they both agreed, they would always be friends, and they would always love each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robots in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/kv755p/robots_in_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Vekllei word for a robot is&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;automasiosn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, or ‘automan’. When we talk about Vekllei being a “post-scarcity society,” it is by automen through which it happens. They are found across the entire country in all types of hard and boring work, forever dutiful, forever mindless. It is not that the robot has replaced the human worker, since &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#employment&#34;&gt;about 90%&lt;/a&gt; of Vekllei people are employed. Instead, the automan takes its place in the necessary evils of industrial society, fulfilling the wildest fantasies of utopian industrialists; the factory is no longer just the place of the machine, it is in fact a machine itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk about Vekllei “deindustrialising,” it is by automen through which it happens. They are neither alive nor entirely synthetic, and work to maintain the basic comforts of consumer society in secret, as the Vekllei state moves towards total deregulation of the human life experience. The more they produce, the further Vekllei people are pushed away from modernity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automen better resemble automatic machines than a synthetic person; the vast majority of them are bespoke products integrated into infrastructure for a specific purpose. Some are hidden in plain sight — the automatic train control, the system which closes and cleans public lavatories, and telephone switchboards are all operated by automen. They don’t think like a human does, because they are manufactured, not born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activity of the robot brain, called mind-genesis, emerges from artificial substrates of crystal (called command clocks) linked by vat-grown brain tissue, which organically process commands delivered by a computer. Most commands for a robot are sensory, and utilise the brain’s natural instinct for balance and orientation in processing. Most robot brains in Vekllei are completely engineered, but are based on mapped sections of ape brains and grown in pluripotent stem cell vats in an immersion fluid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Command clocks are produced in superheated ovens that are then submerged in an ionised liquid. These wafers, called “cookies”, are manufactured out of tetrachalcogenic materials that support “cartographic” (as opposed to “chaotic”) crystal pathways. Early robots used tridymite, which occurs naturally in Vekllei, but almost all robots today use synthetic crystal (usually quartz) grown in hydrothermal crystal plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tissue and command clocks are knitted together in what is basically an incredibly precise and expensive sewing machine, connecting the command clocks to their electrical components and the clocks to the living tissue by way of an axon gun. The result is a device with instincts, dumb and unthinking but highly sensitive and adaptive to inputs. When coupled with other modules, like sensor lasers, automen are able to navigate independently of programmed instruction sets. Since most of their programming and memory are offloaded, they are also relatively inexpensive compared to early overseas models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very few automen in Vekllei are functionally independent, since robotic independence requires complex and expensive command processing computational and control units. Since the vast majority of automen operate in logistics or manufacturing industries, they are usually slaved to a facility Master Computer, which offloads most processing. In the case of maintenance and infrastructure, Master Computers may be consolidated into a region-wide single supercomputer, called an Automatic Asset Command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture shows Tzipora socialising with a school maintenance robot, primarily used for vacuuming floors clean. It is connected to its Master Computer via cabling that runs in rails across the interior of the school, since radios are common enough here to interfere with communication between the automan and its computer. Behind her, a service automen used for crowd control, announcements and communication tells her to stop making friends with the maintenance droid. Incidents like these are common enough, and modern automens have security features to prevent vandalism and self-report damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A final question remains — if Vekllei has entered post-scarcity using robots, why does the rest of the world not simply replicate them? The simple answer is that they do, and the synthetic automan was not invented in Vekllei — it was invented in Poland, and copied by West Germany. They are used world-over in manufacturing and industry. But Vekllei is unique in its heavy use of vehicle automen in public areas, for the simple fact that the economics of robotics just don’t make sense anywhere else in the world. Even in economies of scale, it is too expensive to grow a brain to replace human janitors, milkmen or refuse collectors. Automen demand enormous amounts of electricity, and require complex maintenance and special nutrient fuels to work. These expenses make sense in the contexts of sophisticated manufacturing, but don’t add up in unskilled work where they would be subject to vandalism and theft. In a world of dwindling resources and a rising tide of instability, the problem is much larger than a simple lack of automen or the fact that people must work — a limit has been reached, and robots as we currently understand them will always be more expensive than human life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei, in its soviet approach to science, sees these wonders of the atomic age wandering school halls, crushing shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Year</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/kr5hch/a_new_year/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Year in Vekllei rings out during its months of darkness and cold&lt;/strong&gt;. This calendar runs the regular affairs of the country, like it does the modern world. To Vekllei people, however, it is plain that New Years occurs not in darkness but instead in the summer solstice in June, the way it has for thousands of years in the dramatic cycles of light and dark in the country. In this sense, the end of December resonates among businesses and little else, much like the financial year elsewhere. An ancient pagan festival, one of twelve each year, takes its place in summer. This event is called &lt;em&gt;Rascismion&lt;/em&gt;, or “Rebirth of the Season” in the old Vekllei usage of the word — meaning the complete cycle of seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a spiritual artefact of &lt;em&gt;Upen&lt;/em&gt;, it is no surprise that the Solstice brings good luck and rebirth to Vekllei. It marks good fortune then, that the assembly and launch of the &lt;em&gt;Desg&lt;/em&gt; met the Solstice, launching for Jupiter’s Europa just before midnight on June 21st, 2064. Constructed by the &lt;em&gt;Solar Concern of the Vekllei Commonwealth Materials Bureau&lt;/em&gt; (or Solaburo) in cooperation with the &lt;em&gt;Rocket Navy of the Vekllei Commonwealth Armed Forces&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Cosmos Office&lt;/em&gt; (or Cosmoburo), the &lt;em&gt;Desg&lt;/em&gt; will land material on Europa to prepare for human arrival in six years. It is named after the Desg creatures of Vekllei mythology, who passed messages between malicious and benevolent factions of creatures before human settlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it was nearly midnight, it was the Solstice and the sun would not set tonight. Ayn and Tzipora had spread out plates of Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Kimisosyo&lt;/em&gt; stew across a blanket just south of the Lita Cosmodrome to watch the launch. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/lita&#34;&gt;Royal Borough of Lita&lt;/a&gt; was not far from Copette (&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/railmap.jpg&#34;&gt;map of Vekllei here&lt;/a&gt;), one of the Five Crown Boroughs of Vekllei, but this was Vekllei’s glacial interior and it felt a million miles from anywhere. Its geography was ancient and violent, strikingly barren and brutally volcanic. Why visit Europa? It was alien enough here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayn had brought her portable television. Baron was supposed to meet them there, but his train was delayed and he was stuck somewhere in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/miyatvousi/&#34;&gt;Miyatvousi&lt;/a&gt; with the beer and fruit spritzers. Tzipora liked a drink, but Ayn liked it too much and had given it up years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I suppose it’s better than being drunk,” Tzipora said, nursing a fizzy drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, it’s not at all, Zelda… Getting drunk feels great, that’s why I got drunk,” Ayn said. She was watching some teen-agers cuddling further down the hill, and sighed after a moment. “That’s the trouble with it. A warm night like this, tired and with nothing to do? It’s the best feeling in the world. Let’s not kid ourselves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I like wine,” Tzipora said stupidly before erring a moment later, embarrassed at how childish she sounded. “Well, you know. I drink alcohol, but not much. I like sweet things mostly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayn felt sorry for girl as the awkwardness of the conversation settled on Tzipora. It was worse to be self-aware, sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Baron likes a drink,” Tzipora continued. “He drinks a lot. He’s okay though, I don’t think he can get drunk. He’s a cool cucumber, he doesn’t change at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Is that right? Anyway, what time is it? It’ll be launching soon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the minutes ticked closer to launch, Tzipora began to fret that Baron wouldn’t make it. The New Year was very important to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was out-of-breath and wrestling a crate of beer back under his arm as the distant boom of the atomic thrusters caught the mountaintops. He crested the hill as a dull roar invited the distant glitter of rocket engines that flickered out of the Lita Cosmodrome Launch Basin. He saw Ayn and Tzipora not far away and called to them, but they couldn’t hear him — the &lt;em&gt;Desg&lt;/em&gt; had called in the New Year, and all eyes were on it as it shined in the sky, brightest of all the stars. 2064 had became 2065, or Year 59 of the Floral Period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy New Year!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>