<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>character on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/character/</link>
	<description>Recent content in character on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/character/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Little Hyderabad</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-07-20-hyderabad/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-07-20-hyderabad/</guid>
	  <description>Little Hyderabad #  Little Hyderabad is a community in the Great Coast, and is one of the few remaining ethnic enclaves in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s postwar period. It&amp;rsquo;s not that immigrants are rare &amp;ndash; on the contrary, about half the people you see in the street were born overseas. But the chaos of British occupation was far behind them now, and the government is more considerate in how it scatters immigrants across the boroughs.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Café Diplomacy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-07-12-vista/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-07-12-vista/</guid>
	  <description>Instafilm #445. Marked &amp;ldquo;2064&amp;rdquo;. Month of the Mosses. You remembered that because it was about the same time war broke out in the Congo again. Everyone at the table had opinions about that war, but not much to do with it. Everyone asked Coretti what she thought about the war. She hated that, she hated being singled out for it. Coretti had been two years old when she left the Congo.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Panaderas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-02-panaderas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-02-panaderas/</guid>
	  <description>She was in Lo, at the end of its winding river, standing in the place where the interior rains met the warm currents of the ocean. A mechanical clicking annoyed her but she could not tell if it was coming from the telephone exchange box or the electric street light above her head. It had just rained and it was a cold rain, so the air was sharp, and hurt and excited her lungs.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Transmission Towers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-23-transmission/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-23-transmission/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora finished most school days at two in the afternoon. Her routine looked something like this. Catch the tram home. Walk if the weather is &amp;lsquo;interesting&amp;rsquo; (dramatic). Unlock the apartment and exchange her shoes for sandals. Bring in the bedding airing in the backyard and say hello to the stripy stray cat. Put away her books and rinse her lunchbox. Set the meat out to defrost and boil and refrigerate the water.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Contrails</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-17-jets/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-17-jets/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei has the some of the clearest skies in the world, and they are criss-crossed by distant vapour trails of jets coming and going. They bring the world closer together. It was funny to think that Peking and Tokyo were just a few hours away &amp;ndash; it felt very cosmopolitan; very democratic. It emphasised the smallness of the world.
Tzipora would look at the livery of the planes to figure out where they were going.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Lunch in the Park</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-15-wine/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-15-wine/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei has several cold-weather wine producing regions in its south, concentrated around the boroughs of Horn and Mopapa. Local staples are hearty reds like cabernet sauvignon and pinot noir, since whites are served with dessert or as apéritifs. Wine in Vekllei is a product of mass consumption, and is often drunk with meals even by teenagers.
Tzipora liked the drowsy, warming feeling of it. She liked it so much that she kept clear of it except on occasions.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Kicking the Habit, Pt. 1 of 12</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-14-habit/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-14-habit/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora doesn&amp;rsquo;t smoke anymore. She prefers Camel.  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Private Fantasy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-14-papers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-14-papers/</guid>
	  <description>&#34;And who is this lady?&#34; &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s Tora, a Palace God who comes to Pachinki,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, stumbling over her words. &amp;ldquo;The other Goddesses don&amp;rsquo;t like her much, um, and she&amp;rsquo;s quite powerful. She goes to Pachinki to unite mortals against the Palace.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I see,&amp;rdquo; Baron said, not following but nodding politely. &amp;ldquo;She looks a lot like you, doesn&amp;rsquo;t she?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Oh, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, brushing away the question with another piece of paper pulled from her schoolbag.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hall Notes</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-23-friends/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-23-friends/</guid>
	  <description>Cobian was a complicated person. When Tzipora met her, she was burdened by her parents and wracked by small faults that glinted openly at the other girls in the school halls. She was insecure, out of touch, a little childish, and desperate to be liked. Tzipora was a fair bit like her, but carried those traits in different ways. It was funny how people, similar in disposition, came across so differently.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei Rumba</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-18-rumba/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-18-rumba/</guid>
	  <description>Coretti Adoula was a good singer but didn’t sing much. Tzipora had regarded her politely but distantly for a while after Moise started dating her in 10th grade. It was an awkward thing. Tzipora was not quite sure how to strike up a conversation — maybe she was a little insecure.
Coretti was an Afro-Russian, but had lived in Vekllei since she was six. She spoke without an accent and was well-accustomed to life in Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy Hanukkah</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-01-hanukkah/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-01-hanukkah/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora lived among Jews in the industrial neighbourhood of Seispri in Lola. They had come over after the troubles in Tel Aviv and their persecution in the Dallas States. She had seen that; that was where she learned of her own history. It was not through faith or practice or family that she had discovered her Jewishness, but persecution — the unfolding story of all Ashkenazim.
A lot of them had come to Vekllei looking for the opportunity to establish some sort of satellite community for the diaspora too embittered or radical to return to Israel.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Best Years of Our Lives</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-04-taiwan/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-04-taiwan/</guid>
	  <description>Kaohsiung changed hands maybe four or five times. Each time the city fell, another company of Chinese burrowed themselves into the city, and each time it took about two months to drive them back into the sea. This was mostly done by the KMT and the Americans, who had heavy equipment. In Taiwan’s mountainous interior, a rainbow coalition of former colonies, indentured states and free-world ideologues fought brutally against the invasion of 2045.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>30 Minutes to Midnight</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-01-party/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-01-party/</guid>
	  <description>Moise’s father worked for Cosme Car, and a big company like that throws a big party each year to celebrate the passing of the summer solstice. It was a good excuse to dress up and drink. This time of year, the sun never sets on the north of Vekllei. It gently touches the horizon and begins to rise again. Tzipora caught a train up the coast with Moise and his dad and they arrived before seven.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Roses</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-12-gymslip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-12-gymslip/</guid>
	  <description>When she was a girl, her mum took her shopping once a year. She said it was important to keep your dignity, though they didn’t have much money. That was Mette.
When Tzipora relayed the memory to Baron, he said, “it’s strange you call your mum by her first name.”
Plastic packaging was on the floor. In the mirror, a carousel of images. A new Zelda stares back, colourless and hollowed under the burden of the future.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Recess on the Roof</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-04-roof/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-04-roof/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora had smoked since she was thirteen, and so she did for the rest of her life. What started out as a nasty habit in California’s decaying boarding school system eventually became a social medicine in the severe anxiety of her school years in Vekllei. She used her packs strategically, afraid of building a dependence that would dilute nicotine’s effects on her frayed nerves.
You were not allowed to smoke in government schools.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Roadside Picnic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-15-picnic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-15-picnic/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This post is an animated PNG without sound. Download the video with sound here.  Such was spring. The breeze was cool, but the sun was warm on the skin and everywhere. They’d been driving for a couple hours, Tzipora and Baron. They’d crossed the big glacier and come down the other side into Troll, where there was nothing much for miles around. It was about then that their tyre blew and the little Cosme M40 limped over to the side of the road.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora Meets a Spirit</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-11-spirit/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-11-spirit/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei is a land of spirits. All things have some life to them, but spirits are something special. Up in Tiyousn, seispri (lit. spirits) wander freely, attracted by sulphur and silica waste pools discharged by the Magma-Electric Flash Plant nearby. Rich with minerals and warm to the touch, these milky ponds are gathering places for creatures of the spirit world.
Vekllei people do not understand spirits; they will never understand spirits.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Gun</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-25-gun/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-25-gun/</guid>
	  <description>Baron had been working in the twilight of violence for over twenty years. In that time he had not given much thought to children or family, except for those that lingered as ghosts from long ago. Despite popular misconception, Baron did on occasion daydream, and in those daydreams was an abstract picture of his heir — a dark-haired son not unlike himself.
Tzipora was not a son but she was not unlike him.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Wicket-Keeper</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-15-wicket-keeper/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-15-wicket-keeper/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora was good at cricket. That surprised everyone. Her teachers called her bookish; her classmates called her a dork. She didn’t look like a girl who played much sport. In America, at her old school, she was sick from gym class so regularly that they stopped asking about her absence.
In Vekllei, however, the sports were better. Instead of “gym class,” they had physical education — Phys Ed — that included a variety of weekly health classes, term carnivals, and daily callisthenics.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Generations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</guid>
	  <description>Ayn was a naturally busy person. She worked long, hard hours at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence, or ‘AB/NI,’ as a clerk, or specialist, or whatever they needed her to be that day. Her days off were filled with petty occupations and minor obligations — mostly tending to her plants and cleaning. She enjoyed number puzzles. A couple friends had formed a book club, and she went to that on occasion.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Shabbat Shalom</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</guid>
	  <description>When they met, Tzipora told Baron she was Catholic. He thought that was hilarious — it was one of the few times she saw him laugh. Her name was “Tzipora”, and she gave herself the name “Zelda” — who did she think she was kidding? But that’s just how she was; Tzipora was an intricate person of many backgrounds and instincts.
Baron was Jewish, but he didn’t practice much. He did, however, observe shabbas as a cultural legacy of his childhood.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Standing Around at the Swimming Carnival</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-05-swimming/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-05-swimming/</guid>
	  <description>Each year, Lola 6th School traveled to the base of the Thanveler Glacier for its swimming carnival. There was a big thermal pool there, heated by the Earth, and students competed in races for prizes and ribbons.
Tzipora told people she couldn’t swim. That was true — she sank like a stone. But she didn’t tell them the other part — that she never wanted to learn how.
There is a very tragic and pathetic self-consciousness that afflicts kids around her age.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mossbound</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-02-mossbound/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-02-mossbound/</guid>
	  <description>Outside of the cities, sensory pleasure can be enriched by Vekllei’s oldest organism, if you know where to look. The temperate rainforest is alive, and breathing, and smells cold in its freshness. The perfume of the rainforest is earthy and chilled, swirling in a cocktail of fresh water, rich, damp soil and the scents of thick mosses and browning leaves. Out here, only water and the trees move — these sounds are the domain of spirits.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Zelda&#39;s Guide to Living Forever</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/</guid>
	  <description>There’s no other way to put it — Tzipora is one of a kind. There are others like her, but fewer and fewer of them are born healthy as the years roll on. Her life is hard, she’d agree, but it’s also sprinkled with miracles. Meeting her, you might not even know she’s set to become the oldest person in history.
All stories settle on remarkable people, and Tzipora — with or without her absurd long-livedness — is a person of importance, and much more than the sum of her parts.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Living Diplomacy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-19-diplomacy/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-19-diplomacy/</guid>
	  <description>Cobian first met Tzipora at Café Maz, though before then she knew her as ‘Tzipora, the New Girl,’ or, less favourably, ‘Tzipora the Gypsy,’ since there was some confusion about where she’d come from. The neighbourhood had known about her for a while, since people like to talk about foreigners, and when she was spotted at the Café people talked about that too. Meeting her, Cobian understood why she had become a fascination.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Saturday. Summer Rains.</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-12-cosy/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-12-cosy/</guid>
	  <description>In summer, the sun is up all night. She wakes at five and spends the mornings by herself, reading the paper or a paperback. Baron works late — he wakes late. They have breakfast together, so until then she drinks coffee out of a packet and starts the fire if it’s cold. You were supposed to save power, but sometimes she ran her electric blanket all night, which kept her snug until the under-floor heating warmed up.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>City Rivers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</guid>
	  <description>Out in Voya Voya, the gardens light the people, and distill human temperament into momentary, sequential lyrical images. A dead leaf moving by miracle across still water; an overturned bucket collecting dew along its handle; fern leaves half-curled, young and growing. Vekllei is known as a “garden city,” and Voya Voya has the best of them. Vekllei urban planning is wandering and wasteful, and in this borough the city centre is checkered by wild parks filled with silence and rainforest smells.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Justice</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</guid>
	  <description>Lin Zhi was nuts. She was lovely, but she was nuts. Tzipora followed along, pleading occasionally, a squeaking voice of concern. The cricket bat dragged and bounced along the poor road sealing.
“You could go to prison,” Tzipora said, protesting weakly. “Why not send Moise and his boys? They’ll put the fear of God in him.”
“This is stupid,” Zhi said in clumsy Vekllei, staring ahead. “You do not know what it’s like.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Turning Things Around</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-20-around/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-20-around/</guid>
	  <description>His hand was hurting bad, but no one asked him about it the day after. Moise always had a temper, and now he had a reputation. He got no words of sympathy from the other seniors of Lola 8th School.
Considering his bluntness and irritability, it was funny that he could only make good friends with women. His father was a bastard and his mother was in Greece, so his sister took their place.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Puffling</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</guid>
	  <description>She joined the Puffin Scouts to make friends. Tzipora was not especially rugged or outdoorsy, but she was a fresh patriot, and the idea of collecting awards for conservation, in her mind, was much like Baron collecting medals for killing reds in the War.
The green and gold of the Puffin Scouts represent nature and living blood respectively. Entwined, as here on her scarf, they mean the chaos and inhumanity of nature in Vekllei Semaphore.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Moments in Love</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</guid>
	  <description>Lava was a modern walled city. It had long lost its walls, but its florid green belt disguised a complex network of trenches, tunnels and forts that linked emplacements in the surrounding mountains. Together, these systems would ensure Vekllei would never again have to tolerate occupation by a foreign power. Lava was on the outskirts of Vekllei’s great capital city, and much of its cityscape was dispersed, affording residents a slower pace of life.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Tzipora Christmas Story</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</guid>
	  <description>Pachinki is a world of Tzipora’s own creation, a dorky retreat from the difficulties she has in Vekllei. Tzipora always loved stories of wild places and adventure, and Pachinki blossomed organically from within her daydreams. Eventually she started writing and drawing it. When she was sad, bored or anxious, she would descend back into Pachinki’s world of ancient magic, edible gems and pirates.
A chapter she wrote in late November one year resembled her idea of a Christmas story, and so I’ve included a portion here to accompany this picture.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Full Heart</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</guid>
	  <description>She’d dropped out of school and had the slow accent of a person too foreign to employ. She now lived in a country that did not use money. Food was everywhere and you ate until you were satisfied. Around each corner was a new cinema or basement lounge, and water trickled through the streets like all mythic garden cities. It was a paradise.
Somehow, despite her new wealth, a panic had set in.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All That’s Solid Melts into Zelda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin   My nerves are like overused sandpaper—all dull; only the eye-catching, bizarre and grotesque can excite me now.
 Tanizaki Junichirō, 1918
The wind had died and it seemed that she would follow it. Crazy shadows distorted beneath car headlights. It occurred to her in some way that, as she approached dying, she was living out the ultimate dramatic fantasy of the American misplaced girl, in the same way the townsmen were fulfilling their grotesque constellation of death by murdering women.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Atlantic Boredom</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin  For a brief period of time, Zelda and Cobian took it upon themselves to make something of their youth. Cobian fancied herself a gymnast, and though this ambition arrived too late and left too soon, she was quite good at it for a while. Tzipora was better suited on the trampoline, where her stiff leg didn’t give her as much trouble.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Baron, the Father</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  People are not sure what to make of Baron. They are not sure what to make of his daughter, Tzipora, either. To that end, they are lucky to have found each other.
His obscurity is part of a severe disposition, made obvious by his astonishing disinterest in friends and hobbies. When he finishes work, he listens to the radio, prepares supper, and goes to bed.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Memory and Death in the Flower Tundra</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  It was their first hike after Maya’s funeral. She had found adult life completely disappointing, and never moved out of home. In her last summer, she developed a desperate fascination with her receding childhood, and eventually took her own life outside of the classroom she’d studied in as a third-grade student.
Her death deeply disturbed Tzipora, who was keenly aware of how sentimental people died against metrics of their own imagination.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Cobian and Zelda &#34;head-over-heels&#34;</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  make love not lore</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Matchstick Girl</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Another paint-sketch — a painting done fast. I’m trying to learn to a) paint and b) paint on an industrial scale.
She’d missed the fast tram, caught a tiny splinter in her thumb, lost a button and now the match wouldn’t strike. It just wasn’t her day.
They were in Callaisn (pronounced ka-lane), a borough of the capital Tzipora regarded as “the worst of them” for its tall buildings and labyrinthian concrete alleys.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Road Trip</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  They showed up at the autopool, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem. Moise would drive, Tzipora bunked with Cobian in the passenger seat and Alise, Zo and Jerome could cram into the back.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Absolute Quiet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  There were plumes in the sky, sent from bunkers buried deep in the well of the Earth, killing with switches. Vekllei went to war, and so Tzipora went to war with it.
The throbbing machinery of another world began turning, and anyone who saw the bomb would hear it. Passing seconds dislocated and caught heartbeats. The plumes were pretty.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Unique among girls #  There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not realise she is unusual, or does not care.
She has a lot of endearing characteristics that give great character to her mannerisms and physicality. She has a small overbite that makes her look a little froggy, and ritually pulls on her shirt and wipes her nose in anxious conversation.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Base Camp</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Just a paint-sketch.
The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.
The Krafla high-energy communications tower was visible from all over the region.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora’s ‘Every Day Carry’</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Like a lot of girls of poverty, Tzipora was very possessive of her things. No food was ever left on her plate. There was a deep anxiety that whatever wasn’t claimed would be lost.
She was also naturally obsessive and material-oriented, keenly aware of the importance of objects measured by metrics in her own silly head. You can discover a lot about a person from their trinkets and toys — let’s discover a bit about Tzipora.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Most Beautiful Woman</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”
It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture. Tzipora was not quite sure how to describe it.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hot Rain in the Arctic Circle</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Tzipora had been ejected from the operations room once the guys arrived. She knew what was going down, anyway. No specifics. But you didn’t bring in uniformed soldiers for regular business. National Intelligence liked to work with their own people.
Five days prior, Baron hailed an EB/NI company car and it pulled up beside him. The electric passenger window slid down.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform. And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables. Out here, you paced life around the station.
There was not much to say about this, between the two of them.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Trials of Cobian</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  According to her friends, Tzipora’s contemporary afflictions were tragic. Her medical problems; her violent childhood; her sensitivity and melancholy — you could feel sorry for her, because a lot of her problems were not her fault. She invoked sympathy.
Tzipora never considered herself particularly tragic. It seemed straightforward, if difficult; she continued to live — and so she lived.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meet Cobian, a concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</guid>
	  <description>If you go back through my posts here, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice Tzipora is basically a cartoon whose only consistent characteristic is her iconography &amp;ndash; her hair fountain, bangs, round head and big smile. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really intentional. I&amp;rsquo;m just an amateur artist who is still learning to draw.
That doesn&amp;rsquo;t work so well in a comic with sequential panels, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on standardising my characters. This is a concept panel for Cobian, Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s longtime friend (and occasional girlfriend).</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora, the Princess of the Earth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</guid>
	  <description>Editor’s note — it’s getting close to 4 a.m. and I’m not sure I can even remember why I wrote this post. Everything is a fog. Expect revisions and possibly major changes in the morning.
Pictured above is Tzipora Desmoisnes, the Princess of the Earth and one of the most interesting persons of the last century. She has made good use of her 126 years on Earth (and counting), and a few samples have been chosen for your viewing pleasure.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Face to Face with Immortality</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora had never been taller than anyone in Vekllei at a meagre 5’2, but she was taller than Shizuku Kobayashi. Like Tzipora, Shizuku had not physically aged a day since she was a child.
It was summer, and six days after Tzipora had arrived in Japan as a Gregori ambassador from Vekllei. Although she would not be the oldest victim of Gregori-Heitzfeld syndrome until Quentin Cook’s (USA) infamous murder-suicide ten years later, she was one of the so-called &amp;ldquo;First Thirteen&amp;rdquo; publicised patients, and so was somewhat known to the international community.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Girls of the Last Carriage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</guid>
	  <description>She’d accidentally starched her gi quarter-pleat in the wash. She held it self-consciously against her side as she watched the clouds navigate the sharp mountains that formed Montre’s deepest valleys. Even out here, where human presence was gentle and subservient to the land, Vekllei National Railways had tracks that serviced the smallest villages. Today it was high summer, and the slopes were green and free of ice. They waited in the shade of the regional limited express carriage for train 802, which would take them home to Montre-Lola and complete a two hour ritual all Montre-Lolan university students made for their studies.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Making Trouble</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora never lost her youthful curiosity. She would swish about the apartment, chasing an idea or plan that had occurred to her. Baron would look over and say “What are you doing, Zelda? Making trouble?” He said that a lot. He would come home in the afternoon and she would be writing lists, or organising her paperbacks, or moving furniture and he’d say, “What are you up to, Zelda? Making trouble?</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Medicating despair in the pasture of plenty</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora is doing well now. She has looked into her heart and made peace with who she is. She has discovered she is a girl who likes free jazz, and milky coffee, and cotton shirts, and trains — to the surprise of no-one who knows her. She knows what things she values in a friend, and what deserves to become family. She knows what clothes she likes and how to do her hair.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>1000 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-10-1000-subscribers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-10-1000-subscribers/</guid>
	  <description>Hey everyone,
Hobart here. You might not know it, but I’m sort of a big fucking deal on the internet. No, don’t touch me. Why am I? Because my subreddit just hit 1,000 subscribers. What’s a subreddit? I’m actually laughing at you; imagine not knowing what reddit is. You ingrate.
Seriously though, this whole renewal of the project through a subreddit (rather than disconnected r/worldbuilding posts) has been an amazing thing.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The King</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-21-king/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-21-king/</guid>
	  <description>The King and Tzipora do not get along. Zelda met him through Moise, when King managed the Domepent School’s cricket team. Moise was a pretty good wicket keeper.
King had offended Zelda with an off-hand comment on her youthful appearance, and she’d retorted with a remark about his weak blood circulation. Moise, caught between his new boss and his angry Zelda, navigated these stormy waters by ignoring the dispute entirely and separating them on the walk home.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Mountain Witches of Pachinki</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</guid>
	  <description>Pachinki is the fantastical notebook of Tzipora, in all her loneliness and thunderous imagination, shared with you all to enjoy. She&amp;rsquo;s so far constructed Pachinki posts about gem children, palace henchmen, sinister earth magics, the Palace Gods, and teeth regents.
From Tzipora’s notebook:
[A Guide to Magic, Chapter 2: The Witch]
The witches of Pachinki are an interesting affair — many books have been dedicated to their research after discovery, yet so little is known about them.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Mafioso and His Witch</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-05-mafioso/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-05-mafioso/</guid>
	  <description>Hello, everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s been six days. I&amp;rsquo;d like to have been here sooner, but I had the good fortune to leave my Apple Pencil in a hotel room in Sydney. Although delighted with my welcome and surprising expense (~$150AUD, or roughly 43 bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves), I&amp;rsquo;ve consequently fallen behind with my off-daily illustrations.
However, I carry the ANZAC spirit deep within me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve made use of my time.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Puffin Attack</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-16-puffin-attack/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-16-puffin-attack/</guid>
	  <description>Although Zelda can&amp;rsquo;t have kids, she mothers whole generations of village children.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Introducing Ayn</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-14-ayn/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-14-ayn/</guid>
	  <description>The daughter of a Soviet expat and Hong Konger deckhand, Ayn Rumouisen has never stepped foot outside of Vekllei. A serious fear of flying and the open ocean has hedged her appetite for travel for all of her thirty-two years. She is well respected as an operations consultant within the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), and is close with the ABNI Operations Director Baron Desmoisnes and Vekllei’s first “Gregori Baby,” Tzipora &amp;ldquo;Zelda&amp;rdquo; Desmoisnes.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Big Mouth, Fat Lip</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-05-fat-lip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-05-fat-lip/</guid>
	  <description>For the first six months Baron had known her, Zelda was a serious and wisened young woman who carried symptoms of her troubled past as gracefully as anyone ever could. Poverty ages a person, and she’d nurtured a calm and dispirited disposition. She did not like war films or books with unhappy endings, or loud noises or arguments. She dressed conservatively and spoke quietly and uncontroversially. She had lived a lifetime already, working in exploitation in motels and supermarkets, watching as Utah unraveled around her.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Lighter Than Her Shadow</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-shadow/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-shadow/</guid>
	  <description>Zelda, for all her outward timidity and mousiness, was mostly self-assured. In the same way that a child is self-assured, in which there is no real epistemology of the self as adults know it. Zelda never grew up to become a real teen-ager, after all — her body is forever thirteen-and-a-half, despite her mature and maternal disposition — and so she had a reckless sort of confidence that never really doubted the premise of her existence.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Squish!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-01-squish/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-01-squish/</guid>
	  <description>Sorry for breaking my streak everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m on beta software and it totally shit the bed these last couple days. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing my best to hobble along until full release :)
Tzipora is easily squished. In this picture Moise would be around 16, Cobian 15, and Tzipora about 18.
Moise has lost a lot of weight and has been blessed with a hefty frame befitting his temperament. Tzipora &amp;rsquo;s tastes in clothes are specific and mostly unchanging, except for a brief phase a few years after her arrival where she started poaching neckties for her own use.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Introducing Moise</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-25-introducing-moise/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-25-introducing-moise/</guid>
	  <description>Moise was a fat kid who went to another school. Zelda only knew him from the tram, where he carried a criminal stigma because of his rumoured gang affiliations. He was a second-generation Vekllei boy of immigrant Greek heritage. There were a few ethnic gangs in his area, and most immigrant boys that didn’t do well in school quickly found other causes to fight for.
Zelda quickly antagonised the boy by offering him to her own bullies.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Teeth Regents</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</guid>
	  <description>From the notebook of Tzipora:
Total hedonism across a thousand generations produced the creature known as the ‘tooth regent’, who was a human by technicality but was built genetically only for consuming. His name was Arhen CIII, and where his ancestors had mouths, he had a thousand teeth that sat in messy rows to the back of his throat.
Three times a day his mouth had to be washed by palace maidens, and excess teeth brushed off.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Zelda, the Vigilant</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-vigilante/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-vigilante/</guid>
	  <description>I should start work on the graphic novel</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>At peace, in dark</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-21-peace/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-21-peace/</guid>
	  <description>Zelda liked to sleep beside someone, which made her feel safe and loved, but she never had many friends and she hadn’t a mother to share a bed with. And, despite her enthusiasm, she was not very easy to sleep beside. She was prone to jerking movements and night terrors, and alternated between pushing her partner to the periphery and then clutching them in comfort. Like so much of who she was, she was caught between contradictory aesthetics and ideas — at home she might sleep in days-old clothes or underwear, but at Cobian’s house she wore a neat nightdress that emphasised her simple middle-class tastes.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Puffin Logic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-18-puffin/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-18-puffin/</guid>
	  <description>i&amp;rsquo;m like that Ben Folds song about escaping your redneck past but instead of redneck it&amp;rsquo;s anime. who stands like this???
Time-lapse here.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>