<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>character on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://beta.millmint.net/categories/character/</link>
    <description>Recent content in character on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beta.millmint.net/categories/character/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roadside Picnic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-09-15-picnic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-09-15-picnic/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/povzpz/roadside_picnic/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This post&lt;/strong&gt; is an animated PNG without sound. Download the video with sound &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/picnic.mov&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Such was spring&lt;/strong&gt;. The breeze was cool, but the sun was warm on the skin and everywhere. They’d been driving for a couple hours, Tzipora and Baron. They’d crossed the big glacier and come down the other side into &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/troll/&#34;&gt;Troll&lt;/a&gt;, where there was nothing much for miles around. It was about then that their tyre blew and the little Cosme M40 limped over to the side of the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lemons and lemonade; Tzipora decided it was time for lunch. They ate canned salmon in the sun. She’d baked olive bread the day before and they pulled it apart with their hands. After lunch they opened a bottle and Baron had a cigarette as he figured out how he was going to get the spare out from under the luggage in the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora had no such concerns. They had plenty of wine and didn’t have to be in Fyori until tonight. The bonnet of the Cosme had heated up in the sun and it was warm on her back. Tzipora was getting to the good part of her favourite book. The radio had a good song on. She was living one of the best moments of her life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora Meets a Spirit</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-09-11-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-09-11-spirit/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/pmcppf/tzipora_meets_a_spirit/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei is a land of spirits&lt;/strong&gt;. All things have some life to them, but spirits are something special. Up in Tiyousn, seispri (lit. spirits) wander freely, attracted by sulphur and silica waste pools discharged by the Magma-Electric Flash Plant nearby. Rich with minerals and warm to the touch, these milky ponds are gathering places for creatures of the spirit world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people do not understand spirits; they will never understand spirits. The word itself is nearly meaningless, applied broadly to any creature crossing over from unseen spatial cages. The only thing that characterises a spirit is its human intelligence and, by association, their complicated personalities. Most appreciate gestures, even misplaced ones, so it never hurts to leave offerings and announce your intentions in Vekllei’s autonomous Crown Lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was outside of Equetti, in Tiyousn, looking for mineral pools that were the right temperature to bathe in. Finding a favourite mineral pool was a right of passage in Vekllei, and locations to good ones were often secrets given only to close friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was about two kilometres south of the Flash Plant when she saw it and screamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spirits always provoke raw terror the first time. They are not of nature; they are like humans. Their intelligence distinguishes them from the physicality of their surrounds and complicates their behaviour with cultural constructions. It is not like seeing an animal. It is like seeing beyond the horizon of death and the things that live beyond it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was now looking at herself, dressed in some approximation of the things she wore. She thought it was here to kill her. Shaking, and stupidly, she spoke to it like a reflection in a mirror: “You scared me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first she thought it might be a demon — a creature that hurt people. But it — Tzipora did not know what else to call it — sat facing herself, staring unblinkingly. Demons didn’t sit; they beat you to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora had been doing a lot of reading about spirits, but had no real reference for this apparition. It would be a terrible thing to run away — she’d probably offend the spirit, and it was bad manners anyway. She did not know what to do, so Tzipora said hello and introduced herself, and then said something nice about the weather. She spoke slowly, carefully. The spirit sat there, looking at her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora asked about the mineral ponds, and if there were good springs to bathe in, but the spirit said nothing. It looked as real as herself — the lichen on the rock was disturbed beneath the spirit’s skirt. Her skirt, actually — was the spirit pulling its outfit from Tzipora’s mind? Could it sense thoughts? She kept talking politely, about how nice the walk out here was. She paused for a moment and worked up the courage for a compliment, then told the spirit she liked its clothes. She was worried it might provoke a response, but the spirit stayed still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her heart was pounding, but Tzipora could suppress fear. She opened her pack and pulled out her lunch, spreading it out next to the mineral pool before them. She had a bar of Gosmo milk chocolate. She asked if the spirit would like some. She unwrapped the foil, looking at it, and broke off a row of squares. She put two squares in her own mouth, and took the other two squares and held it out. The spirit didn’t move. Moving slowly, Tzipora reached over gently and placed the chocolate on its arm. As she did so, her fingertip brushed its arm — her own arm — and she was filled with unease. It was as real as she was; its arm was warm to the touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora had stopped chewing her chocolate. It melted on her tongue. In the back of her mind she thought about getting a cavity. A moment later, the spirit and the chocolate disappeared. It just stopped being there. Tzipora looked around, afraid it might be sneaking up on her, but it was gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She broke off two more squares, packed her sandwich back into her pack and walked briskly back to Equetti. As she passed by the ponds, her fear eased — there was some abstract sense, perhaps, that she had been invited here. Maybe spirits liked chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gun</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-08-25-gun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-08-25-gun/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/pbgzwc/the_gun/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baron had been working in the twilight of violence for over twenty years&lt;/strong&gt;. In that time he had not given much thought to children or family, except for those that lingered as ghosts from long ago. Despite popular misconception, Baron did on occasion daydream, and in those daydreams was an abstract picture of his heir — a dark-haired son not unlike himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was not a son but she was not unlike him. She gave him a new perspective on life — a reason for going on, and a universe outside of service to the state. And how she adored him. She demonstrated that in how she talked, and how she childishly defended any casual observation or guessing of him. They were old friends — war buddies, in fact — and spent many evenings talking about the world and the things in it. Yet a paternal dimension of their relationship existed. Tzipora was young and full of questions, and wanted desperately to be taught. So he guided her when she asked for it, and answered her questions. And there were so many questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his daydreams he taught his son to use the gun. There were guns in the home but Tzipora was not allowed to touch them, because she had been prescribed antipsychotics fourteen months into her life in Vekllei. She didn’t end up needing the pills; they only gave her tremors. It wasn’t until she was diagnosed properly at eighteen years of age that she as allowed to use the guns with Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They went hunting for meat, since there had been more shortages that year, and in summer Vekllei is full of a most obscure pest called a Pademelon — a type of Australian wallaby that had been introduced just prior to the War by accident. Now they were all over, inoffensive as they were. The meat was tasty and the government encouraged you to cull them, so they were hunted commonly. Tzipora had some knowledge of how to use a pistol but hadn’t fired a long gun. Baron showed her how to use the sites and hold it. She didn’t kill anything, but Baron bagged two. Tzipora figured out how to skin and clean the animal and they ate wallaby steaks that night, which tasted good but were gamey. She shared the rest of the meat with a neighbour who had helped her repair the boiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the echoes of Baron’s memory was a distant, youthful dream of riding a motorbike overseas, maybe across Asia or through the Middle East. Eating from street vendors and sleeping wherever you could. Was it so crazy? After twenty years of work he had plenty of money to withdraw for travel. He wondered if Tzipora would like to learn to ride a motorbike — and what she’d think of such an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wicket-Keeper</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-15-wicket-keeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-15-wicket-keeper/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/o0k8to/wicketkeeper/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tzipora was good at cricket&lt;/strong&gt;. That surprised everyone. Her teachers called her bookish; her classmates called her a dork. She didn’t look like a girl who played much sport. In America, at her old school, she was sick from gym class so regularly that they stopped asking about her absence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vekllei, however, the sports were better. Instead of “gym class,” they had physical education — Phys Ed — that included a variety of weekly health classes, term carnivals, and daily callisthenics. They’d pile into the gymnasium, take off dark-soled shoes, and run through simple exercises before lessons. Sometimes they’d play games instead, if they had one of the cool teachers. That was a potent memory for Tzipora, actually — the jealousy of watching the homeroom next door play “crocodile” while her group were doing stretches for the second time that week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was her social environment, in the end, that got her into sports. When she didn’t know anyone, she’d read English books by the sports fields. Two weeks into watching the boys play lunchtime cricket, she took up the bat and scored six runs. It turned out Tzipora was very good at sports. She was fast and well-coordinated — an uncultivated natural gift. That year, at the athletics carnival, she scored best out of the girls in high jump and best out of anyone in long jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That made Tzipora very popular with her classmates, because she played “both sides” — she was a shy geek that was good at cricket and didn’t mind getting grass stains on her shirt. It was that duality, rather than her sportsmanship, that people liked. She was amusing enough as a character that the sports-playing boys had developed a fascination with her, and they shouted at her to join most lunchtimes. It was paternalistic, sure — they liked her in the same way they liked the retarded rough-n-ready rugby boy in their class — but it wasn’t mean-spirited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most days, she would. She’d pull off her armband, unclip her gi, and roll up her skirt and sleeves as she made her way down to the pitch. She’d come back with dirty knees right to her books, eight runs richer and radiating a casual self-confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generations</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nw354j/generations/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ayn was a naturally busy person&lt;/strong&gt;. She worked long, hard hours at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence, or ‘AB/NI,’ as a clerk, or specialist, or whatever they needed her to be that day. Her days off were filled with petty occupations and minor obligations — mostly tending to her plants and cleaning. She enjoyed number puzzles. A couple friends had formed a book club, and she went to that on occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora’s arrival in June of 2063 saw several disruptions to Ayn’s routines, not least of which was the surfacing of her old unsentimental boyfriend, now ten years older and much different. Tzipora herself emerged into Ayn’s personal life, and they became close — much like it was with Baron, Tzipora was both a daughter and a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had been Ayn’s recommendation, actually, that Baron should take her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“At least for a while,” she said, “She talks about you all the time. No one’s talking about adoption — just take her until the system can sort her out. That’s my advice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora met Ayn’s parents later that year, and just like that, Tzipora had forged herself a new family through her force of will and good charm — Baron, the father; Ayn, the mother; and her Hong-Konger/Russian parents. And Ayn’s parents adored her; they showered Tzipora with gifts and baked goods. She was the grandchild they’d wanted so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole situation aroused an ongoing memory, foggy through shame and discomfort, about her ageing parents and her unmarried lifestyle. It was very difficult for Ayn to discuss her decision not to have children with her parents. She was an only child. How do you tell your parents their ancestors, their bloodline ends with you? It hurt them a lot. It hurt Ayn too, to make that choice and follow her heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayn lived in the same studio apartment in the Great Coast she had for a decade, though she now owned it from her work. As a childless, unmarried woman it was very difficult to find larger homes, which were usually allocated to couples and families. Real estate in Vekllei was both a reward and a punishment, and informed the social fabric of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was good at being a grandchild when she needed to be, and Ayn was very thankful for her presence in their lives. Ayn loved her parents, and found herself thinking back to her own childhood more and more as they grew older. She was still their baby, and it was sometimes difficult to reconcile her own independence as an adult with her desire to make them happy. That desire — the instinct to please — dated back to being a little girl, dumb and full of wonder, navigating her childhood with her mum and dad, much younger then, always loving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After work, she would sometimes sit and smoke, then put it out and smell the salt on the breeze. She used to come out here to think, often melancholic about her life and decisions. Nowadays, the thoughts were lighter, more straightforward. She was more self-assured. Sometimes, Tzipora sat out there with her.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shabbat Shalom</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nuk95k/shabbat_shalom/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When they met&lt;/strong&gt;, Tzipora told Baron she was Catholic. He thought that was hilarious — it was one of the few times she saw him laugh. Her name was “Tzipora”, and she gave herself the name “Zelda” — who did she think she was kidding? But that’s just how she was; Tzipora was an intricate person of many backgrounds and instincts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baron was Jewish, but he didn’t practice much. He did, however, observe shabbas as a cultural legacy of his childhood. He worked six days a week, and rested Saturdays. Sometimes, he’d put on a roast in the tradition of his late father’s recipe. Other times, Tzipora would cook some of their favourite foods. Tzipora, the insistent catholic, would respect the melakhot because she liked the idea of it. Even more unusually, she welcomed the shabbas with a prayer, even though her sabbath was Sunday. That’s just how she was; you get the idea. She was a curious and deeply spiritual person, and became more fascinated with her Jewish heritage after living with Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian didn’t know what a Jew was; she barely understood the concept of any god. Cobian’s family were indigenous Vekllei, descended from generations of animistic Upen observers. She was, however, more than willing to break bread with the girl she loved, and they enjoyed many meals together over the years in that picturesque, naive multiculturalism common to Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Around at the Swimming Carnival</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-05-swimming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-05-swimming/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nt1n9c/standing_around_at_the_swimming_carnival/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each year&lt;/strong&gt;, Lola 6th School traveled to the base of the Thanveler Glacier for its swimming carnival. There was a big thermal pool there, heated by the Earth, and students competed in races for prizes and ribbons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora told people she couldn’t swim. That was true — she sank like a stone. But she didn’t tell them the other part — that she never wanted to learn how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a very tragic and pathetic self-consciousness that afflicts kids around her age. Boys and girls went to school together here, but they weren’t the same thing, were they? She saw girls usually clothed in capes and knee skirts showing skin she’d never seen before. There was this one girl, Cherrie, who was on the heavy side, and Tzipora marvelled unconsciously at how much bigger she looked without her uniform. She realised what she was doing, and was struck with shame — and relief it wasn’t her in that stupid one-piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh my God,” Tzipora thought to herself, “That’d be me. What I’m doing now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora hadn’t worn a swimsuit since she was a kid in Colombia, and she wasn’t going to strip off in front of all these people who already judged her. In her mind, she was ugly-skinny, with scars on her shoulders and no figure to speak of. She didn’t think about these things usually, because all her clothes were a size too big, but a change room changed things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No; she wouldn’t wear a swimsuit. She wouldn’t even take her shoes off. They’d think she was weird for sitting out, but they thought she was weird anyway. Every swimming carnival from here to graduation she’d suffer from the poolside — reading her books, eating her packed lunch and lying about how well she did to Baron when she got home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mossbound</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-02-mossbound/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-02-mossbound/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nqooqh/mossbound/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outside of the cities&lt;/strong&gt;, sensory pleasure can be enriched by Vekllei’s oldest organism, if you know where to look. The temperate rainforest is alive, and breathing, and smells cold in its freshness. The perfume of the rainforest is earthy and chilled, swirling in a cocktail of fresh water, rich, damp soil and the scents of thick mosses and browning leaves. Out here, only water and the trees move — these sounds are the domain of spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even bird calls seem foreign here, as though the plovers and crows had been invited by the same mossbound instinct Tzipora shared. Pushing deeper into the rainforest, the risks become greater but the chance of meeting spirits swells. You are a guest, you are a guest — she keeps this in mind if she has any sense. The spirits tolerate breakage but they won’t tolerate disrespect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much as the birds nest and feed, Tzipora is welcomed by the spirits to establish a presence in the rainforest. Taking a seat on the soft floor of the forest, she opens her textbook and reads slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t wear a jacket — the cool air is good for the skin. Breathe deep — the perfume is good for the lungs. Open your senses to the peripheral stimuli of the spirit-forest, and don’t overthink it. Enjoy the sound of wind moving through the ceiling around you, and the freshwater creek that trickles sweetly. This is a good-natured place, so be good-natured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora closes her textbook and lies in the moss, listening for spirits. They’re all around her. They talk to her through the sounds of the forest. If she can fill her soul with good things, they might reveal themselves to her one day. Until then, she meets them as a guest and an admirer, and gives thanks in her heart for their continued stewardship of this place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zelda&#39;s Guide to Living Forever</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/nn2m5h/zeldas_guide_to_living_forever/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s no other way to put it — Tzipora is one of a kind&lt;/strong&gt;. There are others like her, but fewer and fewer of them are born healthy as the years roll on. Her life is hard, she’d agree, but it’s also sprinkled with miracles. Meeting her, you might not even know she’s set to become the oldest person in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All stories settle on remarkable people, and Tzipora — with or without her absurd long-livedness — is a person of importance, and much more than the sum of her parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those unaware, Tzipora is the 13th person in the world to be diagnosed with Gregori-Heitzfeld Disease (GHD), a genetic disorder that surfaced in the 21st Century. Many more than 13 preceded her, but few “Gregori babies,” as they’re called, ever make it to a hospital for a diagnosis. Where exactly GHD came from depends on who you ask — the synthetic preservatives in food? Residual radiation, from a century of atomic testing? The over-sexualisation of media? Tzipora accidentally swallowed a lead ball as a child — that’s as good a guess as any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gregori babies do not grow up, and they do not die of old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She makes up part of the “first wave” of Gregori discovery, comprising of about fifty individual cases across fifteen years starting in the late 2050s. These boys and girls are, on average, healthier and less affected physically by their disease than those born today. Fatal rates of GHD have increased dramatically in recent years, and very few ‘Gregori babies’ born today live beyond 24 months after onset. Like a passing comet, the miracle children seem to be vanishing as quickly as they appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is commonly misunderstood that Gregori children don’t reach puberty. This is not quite true — they do in fact undergo hormonal changes that usually signal the biological transition into sexual maturity, but are a victim of a poorly-understood protein dysfunction that affects their development and cell reproduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gregori-Heitzfeld, as poorly understood as it is, is not a single malfunction of the human body. It is the intersection of two distinct genetic failings in critical proteins that occur in the oestrogen receptors and enzymes of the body. Let’s have a look at how this works, to the best of contemporary understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oestradiol&lt;/strong&gt; is an oestrogen that binds to subtypes of the body’s oestrogen receptors. Of interest here is the agonistic reaction it exerts on a receptor known as the &lt;strong&gt;G protein-coupled oestrogen receptor&lt;/strong&gt; (GPER), a protein responsible for oestradiol’s nongenomic signalling effect on cells. After activation, GPERs exert dramatic and varied effects on the regulation of many parts of the body, including cell growth, and is found not just in oestrogen-receptive tissues but throughout the brain, lungs, skeleton, muscular system and immune cells. In persons suffering from GHD, increased production of oestradiol during puberty onset upregulate GPERs, which has cascading effects on cell production throughout the body, mostly with &lt;strong&gt;gonadotrophin-releasing hormones&lt;/strong&gt; (discussed below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As aforementioned, however, GPER dysfunction is only part of the puzzle. GHD only occurs in the presence of another malfunction of the &lt;strong&gt;telomerase enzyme&lt;/strong&gt;, a ribonucleoprotein which extends telomeres in the human chromosome. Prior to GHD onset, the function of the telomerase RNA templates are unaffected, but once malfunctioning GPER proteins are activated by oestradiol enzymes, a local protein misfolding (not dissimilar to prion diseases) occurs that disrupts part of the telomerase catalytic cycle built into the RNA template of the telomerase itself. This affects the pause signal of telomerase DNA synthesis and offsets the natural telomere loss rate in chromosomes, altering cycle lengths of DNA elongation. This is the primary event that contributes to the so-called biological immortality of some Gregori-Heitzfeld patients, since it offsets the loss of most types of somatic cells which would otherwise age and die. In many others, however, the protein misfolding in GPER-telomerase signalling develops into a fatal neurodegenerative disorder called Variant Gregori-Heitzfeld Disease (vGHD). In the last ten years, most ‘Gregori babies’ are in fact victims of vGHD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The malfunction of GPER proteins also has some kind of affect on the secretion of &lt;strong&gt;gonadotrophin-releasing hormones&lt;/strong&gt; (GnRHs), which affect physical development of the body in pubescence. The interaction between GPERs and GnRHs are still poorly understood, and the complicated effects GHD has on this relationship are almost entirely elusive. What is obvious is that most suffering from GHD do not develop physically beyond the onset of the disease, triggered in girls by pubescence sometime between the ages of 12 and 16. In Tzipora’s case, who perhaps remains the healthiest example of a ‘Gregori baby,’ her puberty is absent despite the increased production of oestrogens triggered by late thelarche. No Gregori baby has ever entered menarche — at least in part a result of GnRH suppression by faulty GPER proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extraordinary rarity of these genetic disorders intersecting contributes to a disease unlike any other. At some point while living in Sacramento, Tzipora slowly stopped ageing. At first, she was just a victim of delayed prepubescence — she was underweight, after all. Then, it was a hormone disorder. By the time she was in Vekllei, she was the country’s first “unageing lady.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of Gregori-Heitzfeld Disease remains rudimentary because, in part, Tzipora makes up most of its scholarship. She is one of the few healthy Gregori babies to voluntarily submit to public medical research, and so most of our understanding comes from her case specifically. There are many gaps in our understanding. Why are Gregori babies not riddled with rapid-growing cancers as their cells metastasise rapidly? Why are the protein misfolds linked to these specific enzymes, and why don’t they spread throughout the body and brain as they do in vGHD? And, perhaps of most interest to the public — where are they going? Why are our new so-called “immortal children” dying?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora does not consider herself a ‘Gregori baby,’ because she considers herself ‘Tzipora’. When she was diagnosed at 16, there were only 10 others like her in the world — there was no Gregori community support group. By the time there were hundreds, the disease was rapidly degenerating into vGHD and resembled something closer to a tragic prion disease. These are topics she does not like to think about much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei affords her dignity, because it does not have a cultural concept of a child. Children exist, of course. They are loved, and go to school, and learn about the world from guardians around them. But they are afforded dignity as human beings, and generally take on responsibilities at a much younger age. This doesn’t mean Tzipora’s life is easy. Her life is not easy. But if she wants to work, she may work. If she wants to travel alone, she may travel alone. And if she wants a glass of wine with dinner, restaurants will accommodate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not special luxuries afforded to her, but basic rights of all young people. In this sense, she is relieved of the inconvenience of justifying her dignity as a person continuously, and allows her to command authority and respect throughout her life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the scope of her life, immortality and youthfulness is usually the last thing on her mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Diplomacy</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-19-diplomacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-19-diplomacy/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/mu1v5t/living_diplomacy/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cobian first met Tzipora at Café Maz&lt;/strong&gt;, though before then she knew her as ‘Tzipora, the New Girl,’ or, less favourably, ‘Tzipora the Gypsy,’ since there was some confusion about where she’d come from. The neighbourhood had known about her for a while, since people like to talk about foreigners, and when she was spotted at the Café people talked about that too. Meeting her, Cobian understood why she had become a fascination. She had keen blue eyes that were very gentle, and quite slow-moving. She would look at you, then casually to the wall, then to her shoes, then back to you. The peacefulness in her face contrasted dramatically with the intensity of her movements, which were frenetic and unconscious. She had a tic where she would pull on her nose and shirt, which combined with her novice &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#5-potenne&#34;&gt;Potenne&lt;/a&gt;, had her hands moving almost constantly as she talked. She was aware of this, because she would notice it periodically and grab her free hand, all without breaking eye contact or the cadence of her conversation. She was very funny; Cobian immediately liked her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian was a soft-willed sort of person, unopinionated and eager to be liked. Every fact filtered down to a reasonable compromise — there was a little bit of good in everything. Some people call that way of thinking gentle. Maybe she was just a little incurious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was her opposite. She lived in a binary world of Tzipora metrics. Things were either pure and beautiful, disgusting and reprehensible, or not worth thinking about. All things passed through this process — cars, food, clothes, the shape of a curve, and the form of a kettle. Some people call that way of thinking judgemental. She was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fierce intuition applied to people too, and Tzipora had a good memory. She wasn’t afraid to confront someone if they upset her, which earned her a slap now and then from some girl too rude to take shit from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can hit me, slap me like that,” Tzipora would say, sneering and rearing back on her heels. “For you to raise your hand against me, like you would a dog — I’ll show you, bitch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She would stop by Cobian’s house, sometimes holding her collar together where a button used to be or nursing an elbow, and they’d sit out back where her mother couldn’t see them. Cobian would fold up a towelette and wipe the gravel out of her palms and knees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know where you get off, acting like a gangster,” Cobian says, dabbing her face. “It upsets me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know, but she deserved it. You know that. Calls me a &lt;em&gt;pisca&lt;/em&gt;; it makes me so angry. Not that she said it to me, but that she thinks she can say such a thing in the first place, like I’d just pretend I hadn’t heard it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora wrestled with the things she said and did constantly. In fact, the ongoing judgement of herself was perhaps the most nuanced opinion Tzipora ever had, one that didn’t fit into the pure/despicable binary. Most days, she landed on self-disgust, and yet…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora pulled on her nose and sniffed, like she did whenever she was nervous, and looked at Cobian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry,” she said. “If you don’t like me blowing up, I’ll try and stop it for you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want you to stop for me, I want you to stop for yourself. I’m just glad you’re okay,” Cobian said, and took her hand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday. Summer Rains.</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-12-cosy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-12-cosy/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/mpg8xy/saturday_summer_rains/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summer, the sun is up all night&lt;/strong&gt;. She wakes at five and spends the mornings by herself, reading the paper or a paperback. Baron works late — he wakes late. They have breakfast together, so until then she drinks coffee out of a packet and starts the fire if it’s cold. You were supposed to save power, but sometimes she ran her electric blanket all night, which kept her snug until the under-floor heating warmed up. Her concrete apartment had concrete comforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has a record player that runs compact diskettes filled with free jazz and rock ’n’ roll. What Baron calls “bongo music”. She reads shit thrillers with the sound of the lashing rain and wild drums in foreign signatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above her bed is a cross, which she treats like a totem. She has a very transactional relationship with God. She doesn’t like him much, but figures doing Him a favour by hanging his cross this one time might earn her a bit of luck when she needs it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coffee is hot, and spoiled with milk and sugar. Everybody tells her that’s no good, that she’s ruined the coffee. She doesn’t care, she likes how it tastes. The rain goes on. She thinks about breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Rivers</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/medv4h/city_rivers/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out in Voya Voya&lt;/strong&gt;, the gardens light the people, and distill human temperament into momentary, sequential lyrical images. A dead leaf moving by miracle across still water; an overturned bucket collecting dew along its handle; fern leaves half-curled, young and growing. Vekllei is known as a “garden city,” and Voya Voya has the best of them. Vekllei urban planning is wandering and wasteful, and in this borough the city centre is checkered by wild parks filled with silence and rainforest smells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian and Tzipora were dating, or something adjacent to it. It was an unusual thing they had going on, since they weren’t much like each other. They’d arranged to have a picnic on Sunday, but a few days out the newspaper said it would rain. Rain-dates meant a movie and lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the forecast got worse. It wasn’t just a shower— it was big rain, with high winds. A storm, anyone but Tzipora would say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We should cancel,” Cobian said on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s the big deal? The movie’s indoors, isn’t it?” — that was Tzipora, who was very eager to go out with her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, they met at the Couisvisia Hills Station, the one closest to Cobian’s house. They took the train to Lola and talked as rain began to make streams down the windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This looks bad,” Cobian said, not touching the window because she was afraid of germs. “Look at the clouds in the distance, too — It’s gonna pour; I don’t want to get all wet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I brought an umbrella,” said Tzipora, whose responsibilities now included managing the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By some miracle, they reached the cinema before the first storm clouds rolled in. They listened to it whistle beneath the sounds of the film. Occasionally the rain would wash over the roof loud enough to hear it. Every time the storm made a noise Cobian sighed quietly, and Tzipora looked at her anxiously, wringing her hands like she did when she was nervous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the film, they stepped into the lobby to find the rain had ceased. In fact, it had vanished — the gutters were running like hell, and every corner of every roof dripped. But the rain had stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Look,” Tzipora said, stepping over a puddle onto the footpath and presenting the sky to Cobian. “I am a rain goddess.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They made a run to the station through the park as the wind scattered water through the air. Tzipora took about five steps into the park before splashing a puddle up herself and soaking her foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For God’s sake, let’s keep going,” she growled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another two steps and she did it again, with the other foot. In fact, the whole park was sodden, and the gutters had been overwhelmed. The picnic field had turned into a lake. Trees had wilted under the weight of raindrops. The sound of running water was everywhere. Tzipora had given up and began navigating Cobian by the hand like a conscript charging through a minefield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian followed, holding the umbrella open uselessly as the wind chilled the water on their skin. They came across a concrete staircase, now a waterfall, as the park-lake drained into the street below. Tzipora, emboldened with the strength of the sacrificial, stepped into it and helped Cobian jump across without sliding into the mud on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As she did, with water filling her shoes and her skirt dripping footpath water, she thought about how much fun this was. You didn’t go on adventures much at their age. She looked at Cobian, who was shivering in the wind and waiting for her, and thought she probably didn’t feel the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You all right?” Tzipora asked, stepping out and shaking water off her shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian gave a thumbs up as she shivered, and all was right in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/lve4he/justice/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lin Zhi was nuts&lt;/strong&gt;. She was lovely, but she was nuts. Tzipora followed along, pleading occasionally, a squeaking voice of concern. The cricket bat dragged and bounced along the poor road sealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You could go to prison,” Tzipora said, protesting weakly. “Why not send Moise and his boys? They’ll put the fear of God in him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is stupid,” Zhi said in clumsy Vekllei, staring ahead. “You do not know what it’s like.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I do know,” Tzipora whined. Between their second-hand Vekllei and conflicting accents, they struggled to understand each other. “They call me a gypsy bitch. But I don’t hit them. And not with a bat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhi and Zelda were much alike. They were both fresh immigrants of school age, and stepped ashore with shadows of a world far beyond Vekllei’s utopian domesticity. Tzipora had spent time indigent in America, nearly lynched in Utah. Zhi had lost her father and uncle to the purges in Red China. Zhi told Tzipora she was the great-great-granddaughter of a hero of the communist party, who’d fought with Mao Tse-tung himself over a century ago. Tzipora did not enquire further, since she knew as much about China as she did the moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No one is asking you to come,” Zhi said, marching ahead as Tzipora trailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Don’t be silly, I’m coming with you. Of course I’m coming with you. I just don’t want you to ruin your life over some words.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Words add up,” Zhi said quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of Zhi’s seven sisters had taken European names to better assimilate into the hectic transcontinental &lt;em&gt;aliyah&lt;/em&gt; of postwar Vekllei. Not Zhi, though. She was wilful and clear-minded, maybe recklessly. Tzipora liked her and feared her, perhaps because she saw herself in Zhi’s frequent outbursts of anger and principled view of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Floral Period was stuffed with new citizens, many of them in disfavour of the politics of their home country. Many of them came from Asia — &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/&#34;&gt;Ayn’s&lt;/a&gt; father was a Hong Konger, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/&#34;&gt;Jiro&lt;/a&gt; was from Tokyo. Vekllei’s people were indigenously “Asiatic in appearance,” as Europe called them. Most were descended from a mixture of Arctic peoples and Irish or Scandinavian settlers. To this end, Vekllei’s complicated ethnic makeup contributes to the country’s obscurity from the U.S. and Europe, as they tend to be orientalised outside of Western concern. This discrimination does not stop Vekllei people from maintaining ignorant ideas towards its incoming East Asian and South-East Asian migrants, however, and people like Zhi often had to deal with racist abuse in public and in private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why don’t we be smart about this?” Tzipora asked, upset. “What he did to you is against school policy. He’ll be thrown out — it’ll ruin him. That’s what hurts, really. Trust me, I know. I know what it’s like for you, too. But he wants to go to the National University. If we get him thrown out, that would ruin him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhi scoffed, and shook her head. “That you could think the school would do anything shows how little you know,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Baron is powerful. He can lean on them. He does it all the time, he’d help if I asked. I know he would.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora stepped in front of her, and put her arms out. Her eyes were shining with tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was going to get expelled for putting a girl’s head through a window, and it was like this,” Tzipora said, sniffling. “She picked on me every day. Every day, she knew I was lonely and sad so she’d scare me. And one day I snapped and put her head through the window. I was going to be expelled, and my life would have ended there. But Baron knew I was right, and he stepped in. Sometimes that’s all it takes, to beat them. It just takes an outsider.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhi had stopped marching, and leaned on the bat. She was out of breath. She shook her head and tossed the bat at Tzipora’s feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Okay,” she said. “Because I like you, Zelda, that’s all. Don’t tell him anything. Don’t tell anyone anything. This is my problem. But I don’t want to upset you. We’re quite similar, I think.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Too similar,” Tzipora said, wiping her eyes. “But it’s not our fault. Not really.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Things Around</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-20-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-20-around/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/locjnz/turning_things_around/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His hand was hurting bad, but no one asked him about it the day after&lt;/strong&gt;. Moise always had a temper, and now he had a reputation. He got no words of sympathy from the other seniors of Lola 8th School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering his bluntness and irritability, it was funny that he could only make good friends with women. His father was a bastard and his mother was in Greece, so his sister took their place. His closest friend was Tzipora, the boyish miracle child who helped him lose weight. His love was Coretti, his high school sweetheart and, a little further along, his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti was the daughter of Congolese scientists, but was born and raised in the Soviet Union. She had a typical brief for Afro-Russians — her father had worked with the Congo Water Company, and later was brought over for the Soviet Ministry of Agriculture and Food. She spent her early years in the relative wealth of the Basmanny District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrangement collapsed quickly after the coup in Congo and the death of Party Secretary Shchusev. The office her father worked for disappeared, and the family emigrated to Vekllei when she was six. Vekllei was full of displaced people with displaced heritage. After all, Moise was himself the son of wealthy Greek folk, his mother a fascist in the shadow party there. The way their identities intersected brought about difficult dimensions to their character — often empowering, occasionally suffocating, and sometimes resurrecting ghosts from their past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise was graduating this year with Coretti, and had already landed a gig running cameras for Dovo Studios, a big deal for someone his age. His real passion was filmmaking — the creation of dreams. That was on hold, after last night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some shithead assistant-to-an-assistant was mouthing off about him to the C.A., telling him he had an attitude. Moise didn’t know what this guy’s problem was, and he kept picking at him all night. Moise didn’t take shit, and got up in his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked at his right hand, which was swollen so fat he couldn’t tuck his fingers in. It’d be right in a couple days, maybe a week. But he was off the set for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti hated his fighting. Tzipora, ever the contrarian by way of instinct, admired him for it. It was like those cartoons with the angels and devils on your shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I hate it when you fight,” says Coretti, in a white gown and halo. “You’re a better man than that, I know it in your heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Is that right?” Tzipora says, with horns and a tail. “Seems to me he’s proved exactly who he’s better than.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’d lost his job and got in trouble again, but as Moise lit a cig and sat back, the whole afternoon ahead of him, he felt pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” he said, and took a drag. “Serves me right.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Puffling</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/l69ctu/the_puffling/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She joined the Puffin Scouts to make friends&lt;/strong&gt;. Tzipora was not especially rugged or outdoorsy, but she was a fresh patriot, and the idea of collecting awards for conservation, in her mind, was much like Baron collecting medals for killing reds in the War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The green and gold of the Puffin Scouts represent nature and living blood respectively. Entwined, as here on her scarf, they mean the chaos and inhumanity of nature in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language#7-vekllei-semaphore&#34;&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/a&gt;. Puffin Scout troops are based out of a region with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kronaismioudelfia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Crown Land), which are abandoned wild areas the Vekllei state has relinquished to the natural spirits worshiped in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/religion/&#34;&gt;Upen&lt;/a&gt;. Hikes aren’t done in Crown Lands because if someone gets hurt or goes missing it can be very difficult to get them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These wildernesses captured Tzipora’s imagination, since they are often the site of gods and extranatural features. The animals you saw out there seemed deeply disturbed by the presence of people, as though they were the vessels of spirits, irritated that a human girl had made her way in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School-aged Puffin Scouts are called Pufflings. In Vekllei, puffin birds are as common as gulls, and nest in cliffs where they raise their young in burrows. Tzipora, despite being a Puffling, never had much luck with puffins. They seemed to exempt her from their natural friendliness and curiosity — they flew away whenever she came close, and when they didn’t fly away they attacked her. She joined the Puffin Scouts to make friends, and yet here she was, cast out from both the Human and Animal Kingdoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this picture, Tzipora watches a puffin in full scout regalia, wary of its intent. The birds make cute novelties for some, but Tzipora knows better. Just like Baron in the war, she sits still and watches closely, listening for movement on the wind. They are locked in a battle of the wits, waiting to see who will make the first move.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moments in Love</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/l3kbsy/moments_in_love/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lava was a modern walled city.&lt;/strong&gt; It had long lost its walls, but its florid green belt disguised a complex network of trenches, tunnels and forts that linked emplacements in the surrounding mountains. Together, these systems would ensure Vekllei would never again have to tolerate occupation by a foreign power. Lava was on the outskirts of Vekllei’s great capital city, and much of its cityscape was dispersed, affording residents a slower pace of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above Lava’s commercial heart were its terraced hills, and from up there you could see the canal ferries wind their way through the city. At the edge of a terraced park sits a bench full of memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Tzipora looked the same as ever, she was 20 now. Cobian was nearly 18, and considering more sincerely her future. She cared about what other people thought of her. To that end they were always worlds apart. Tzipora was driven by a self-sustaining obsessive intuition, not the advice of her peers. Her imitation of ordinary teen-age life was usually misguided and clumsy. She had never made a good teenager — a good much of anything, really. But she was a very good Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even now, Tzipora didn’t really think of herself as a homosexual, in the same way she didn’t consider herself a girl who wore glasses despite the near-sighted prescription specs she kept in her purse. After all, as she liked to say, there was nothing sexy about her — a good Catholic education and a miracle prepubescence saw to that. In the prejudice of the time, that’s what it meant to be a homosexual, at least to her. So this relationship — whatever it was — was not really that. She could avoid public judgement and her own ongoing prejudices if she simply pretended like her sincere feelings for Cobian did not amount to homosexuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was a funny person, capable of great emotional maturity and immaturity depending on her environs. With Baron, she was serious and independent. With Cobian, she was energetic and overeager. Cobian was in no such turmoil about her preference of partner, and unlike Tzipora she was becoming an adult woman capable of exploring a serious, adult relationship. She would grow older and older, and Tzipora would stay there, same as ever. They both knew it was coming. Tzipora was not a child, but she was also not exactly an adult either — she was Tzipora, and she would be Tzipora for as long as she lived, much as she was now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora didn’t generally talk about her feelings, but Cobian was very good at it. They travelled to the terraced park from Lola, and found the bench they’d visited years prior as junior high school students. Back then they’d seen a film at the State Cinema in town and walked for a while after, just talking about it. They’d ended up here, as night fell, and talked until the early morning. Maybe it was a date; maybe it was their first date — what constituted a date with Tzipora? Their relationship was much the same as it had ever been, just with the knowledge they loved each other. But what a revelation that had been. Tzipora had cried when she told her. Tzipora did not cry about much but gestures of affection always overwhelmed her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today they sat on that bench again and talked, and they talked for a long while. What will you study? What will we do? What will Tzipora do for the rest of her life — is she destined to drift from person to person, parasitically enjoying their friendship until they aged out of her reach? Where would Cobian live? What would Tzipora like to do for a living? Will they always be friends, and love each other?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, they both agreed, they would always be friends, and they would always love each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tzipora Christmas Story</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/kkmgdm/a_tzipora_christmas_story/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pachinki is a world of Tzipora’s own creation&lt;/strong&gt;, a dorky retreat from the difficulties she has in Vekllei. Tzipora always loved stories of wild places and adventure, and Pachinki blossomed organically from within her daydreams. Eventually she started writing and drawing it. When she was sad, bored or anxious, she would descend back into Pachinki’s world of ancient magic, edible gems and pirates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chapter she wrote in late November one year resembled her idea of a Christmas story, and so I’ve included a portion here to accompany this picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wrote,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story starts with the tale of a young Pilot Witch, whose job was to guide dead aircraft to safe airports in the shaky peace that followed the Black War. It had to be female witches, since men couldn’t see the dead. She would meet formations of heavy bombers and strike fighters stuffed with corpses out at sea and show them the safe paths to the landing strips, flying low and fast where the Palace Gods couldn’t see them. This was the safe part of the job, since the Palace Gods and Necropirates ambushed out at sea, where they could hide between the archipelagos. Over land, they were mostly safe. It was an important job. Without the witch’s guidance, these planes would navigate the world forever, circling overhead, still packed with bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witches would guide the dead airmen down to the ground, where they could finally be relieved of their duty and released with proper burial rights. The planes would be repaired and flown back to the royal palace in Lily. This young witch was glad it was once again peacetime; when the empires warred, they couldn’t keep up with the dead planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, she was told to meet a special transport delegation out at sea. They didn’t explain anything more. She flew out to the coast on her broom and the glint of a wingtip caught her eye. As it approached, her instinct flared with alarm. These were not dead planes — the crew in them were very much alive. She flew out and approached the largest aircraft in the formation, a transport bomber of a type she’d seen several times before. She landed atop the aircraft and made her way inside via a turret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s going on?” The witch asked, irritated at the break in procedure. The captain of the aircraft jumped at the noise, and straightened his shoulders as he addressed her pompously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’re here to guide us, are you? We’re from the Palace, in Lily.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I understand that; I saw your markings. But why’s it any of my business?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What do you mean, witch? We need safe passage, don’t we?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s not my trade; what are you doing this far out? Do you have any idea how dangerous these archipelagos are?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The captain snorted and resettled his cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know what time of year it is, don’t you? All five planets are above us, silly girl.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The other witches won’t like you coming in uninvited, I’ll have you warned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s nearly the time for the festival. The Queen wants fine gifts for the Princess, and she won’t do with any old hat or dress. We’re part of a military attaché that’s spent the last six months searching the lands for the finest gifts in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Gifts,” the witch said, betraying her surprise. “W-what sort of gifts?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, how about you head below deck and see for yourself. While you’re there, why don’t you pick something out? Provided we understand each other, of course.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, all right. Okay,” the witch said, and hurriedly turned away from the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, the witch was once again atop her broom, though somewhat unevenly under the weight of the largest gem necklace she’d ever seen. She couldn’t believe her luck; it was laden with Soup Gems, and they hadn’t been seen around here in nearly a hundred years. You only found them growing in the stomachs of the Kemi people, and they had been wiped out many eons ago. A gem like this would produce excellent powders, and make her very powerful for a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She resettled her pilot’s hat, and placed both hands on her broomstick. She felt the wind swirl around her as she shot to the front of the formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witch depicted here looks awfully like Tzipora, and that’s no coincidence. Tzipora is always somewhere in her own stories. She writes herself in because she likes to imagine herself living among these people, flying on broomsticks and becoming a powerful witch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These types of posts aren’t very regular, but they’re important for my health as an illustrator. Vekllei might be fantastical, but it’s a Cold War consumer society at the end of the day. Pachinki provides me (and Tzipora!) a fun holiday now and then, into a surreal world of planetoids and magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you have any questions. You can read other Pachinki posts (quite old now) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ar8jov/a_gem_girl_shows_off_her_enormous_strength_in/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ba3mb4/the_littlest_goddess_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/cudjz6/the_teeth_regents/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/b7n1uh/a_mineral_lake_starts_absorbing_grief_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/de25mz/the_mountain_witches_of_pachinki_and_the/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. That’s all of them, that’s all I’ve ever done. This project’s been going on for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart/MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Heart</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/khl6um/full_heart/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She’d dropped out of school and had the slow accent of a person too foreign to employ&lt;/strong&gt;. She now lived in a country that did not use money. Food was everywhere and you ate until you were satisfied. Around each corner was a new cinema or basement lounge, and water trickled through the streets like all mythic garden cities. It was a paradise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, despite her new wealth, a panic had set in. School hadn’t worked out and she lived parasitically with a person who hadn’t really expected or wanted to take her. Desperate to justify her presence as an immigrant, she started to cook — first from the TV, then out of books. A year into her new life in utopia, she had the makings of a master home cook, serving hot suppers six days a week. On Sundays Baron made a roast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is the sort of place that rewards attention to common things, and Tzipora soon cultivated a chef’s eye for fresh ingredients and learned how to bargain with grocers for the best produce. She would plan her meals carefully and indulged her Colombian childhood, rediscovering the bandeja paisa and flatbreads of her youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was relaying her sadness at being unemployed one day when Baron asked her “why not become a cook?” Somehow the thought had never occurred to her. She began to walk into restaurants and ask for work — but most restaurants in Vekllei are run by families, and have no interest in expanding their kitchen for teenage foreigners. There was a restaurant two stops away on the Lola Main Line she liked especially: The Bull, or “Toro”, was run by a loud Spaniard called Che who’d opened his kitchen into the dining area, so you could see him cook. He was rude — Tzipora’s native fluency picked up more than your average Vekllei person — but more importantly, he was an excellent, classically-trained chef. In any other city in the world, he might have been celebrated, but here he ran his business beneath a print shop in the artist’s quarter of Lola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She asked him for work in the kitchen — any work, and he told her no. She finished her meal and left. The next time, he shouted her out of his restaurant. She continued to look around for work, but a quiet stubbornness deep in her heart had convinced her that el Toro is where she wanted to be. She started waiting until closing, where she would ambush him. Six weeks into her courting, Che told Tzipora that she should be sent to an asylum if she wanted to wash dishes so much — but if she would stop bothering him, he would expect her at 2pm the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hard work and it was unrewarding work. In her first year she was ostensibly a commis chef in a kitchen of six — but spent more time with her hands in the sink than preparing food. She would occasionally handle ingredients prep too, and had to reach the markets in the early morning to get the best produce or face having a pan thrown at her in the evening. She worked five nights a week from 2pm till the early hours of the morning. Che ran his kitchen like it was in Barcelona. Sometimes she would step out for a cigarette and fall asleep on the stair in the alley, sweat glistening under the streetlamp, cooled by the ocean stir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years into her work at el Toro she would replace the outgoing sous-chef, and her talent as a cook blossomed. It was a peculiar sight, to have someone of Tzipora’s height and appearance shouting at young men, totally secure in her authority. The years of labour had hardened her resolve, and refined her intuition. She wouldn’t be a chef all her life, but she would always be a wonderful cook. In a country of rich foods and hearty wines, that was a precious commodity. More importantly, her persistence in that kitchen earned her place in the country — Vekllei was a land of opportunity, after all. It is one thing to visit paradise, but quite another to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All That’s Solid Melts into Zelda</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/jdf5fd/all_thats_solid_melts_into_zelda/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My nerves are like overused sandpaper—all dull; only the eye-catching, bizarre and grotesque can excite me now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tanizaki Junichirō, 1918&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wind had died and it seemed that she would follow it&lt;/strong&gt;. Crazy shadows distorted beneath car headlights. It occurred to her in some way that, as she approached dying, she was living out the ultimate dramatic fantasy of the American misplaced girl, in the same way the townsmen were fulfilling their grotesque constellation of death by murdering women. To them, she was not Zelda, or an agitator, or even a maid from Motel Grande; she was just a girl of girl-form, washed out; beat in; bent before the death-bridge where the creek rolled on below. It was brutal and violent, and also the most tacky thing. It scaled up and down, because it was murdering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hearts of America are like overused sandpaper — all dull. This is how it played out in 2063, ages into the Great American Decline and well before it was put down like a sick dog by Chinese methods. The worn out bodies of the hedonistic coasts were numb to the spectacle of collapse and found themselves displaced and unfeeling, and so the neurotic motions of vampiric culture barons responded. In 2036, long before the Dallas Secession or Zelda’s birthday, the NBC under the Radio Corporation of America broadcast the first televised execution in the United States of child serial killer Wayne Graham. This enticed similar coverage across all major television networks for subsequent executions, which were viewed by millions of Americans. The format culminated in NBC’s The &lt;em&gt;American Justice Show&lt;/em&gt; programme, in which the method and subject of broadcasted executions were made participatory by public poll. It was tremendously successful but was cancelled in 2041, after the botched death of George Kovacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not necrotic; this is neurotic; it is the ultimate sucking up of human desire into the commodity-form, and it was only the beginning. It is not just a poetic coincidence that the cancellation of &lt;em&gt;American Justice&lt;/em&gt; saw the legalisation (or at the very least, decriminalisation) of prostitution in all regions but the Deep South over the next decade (which would contribute to the eventual secession). This is pleasure in its raw form, and the murder of prostituted immigrant-labourers and the eroticisation of the death of Wayne Graham’s teen-age victims was one and the same. The necroticisation would arrive later, as modernity tumoured and pleasure outpaced the sovereignty of the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was Zelda, who was a perfect caricature of the real American in the 21st century — born overseas, poor as shit, and dressed up for dying. And why shouldn’t she die? All the old things were dead. God, kings, outrage, empathy, optimism — it was all thrown in the creek, with the rest of the immigrant-labourers. Why shouldn’t a child and her sensitivity be among them? You could change the channel on television and see pornography and the brutal violence of the Secession adjacent to each other. If you clicked the knob back and forth fast enough, they could become one and the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was the last to arrive and among the first to be lynched, and maybe they would make postcards out of her dead body. She couldn’t even wonder this in her terror; the thought would only occur to her much later. It seemed like the whole Great American Decline, in all its hungry decomposition and hedonism was leading to this single moment — and all that was once solid melts into Zelda.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlantic Boredom</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/j6adwa/atlantic_boredom/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For a brief period of time&lt;/strong&gt;, Zelda and Cobian took it upon themselves to make something of their youth. Cobian fancied herself a gymnast, and though this ambition arrived too late and left too soon, she was quite good at it for a while. Tzipora was better suited on the trampoline, where her stiff leg didn’t give her as much trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They trained for about two hours, and after practice they met up to travel home together. Their gymnasium was in a coastal town called Gigayeh, in the borough of Mirah. Here, sloping lava fields were cast in the sea, buried under fine black sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an hour and a half after practice before the evening train arrived to take them back home to Lola, and so they were left with not much to do. Gigayeh had beautiful empty beaches, littered with icebergs that caught the light like jewels, but Tzipora couldn’t swim and the water was freezing. They could have enjoyed café food in the sun, but Cobian’s regimented home life had left her incapable of eating outside of her designated meals, and Tzipora could only drink so much coffee. Instead, most of these afternoons, they found themselves sitting on the ocean promenade, watching a handful of locals go about their business as they counted the minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the moment, it was stupefyingly boring. They’d spent all day at school with each other and usually couldn’t conjure a word between them. Tzipora would make a remark about a seabird, because she liked them. She had been learning a lot about birds. Sometimes they would share a comic, but they read too fast to fill time. Most of it was spent in the sea air, feeling it grow colder as the day waned, watching the same ocean foam throw itself onto glittering volcanic sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think that’s a horned puffin. That’s special,” Tzipora said out loud. Cobian didn’t even look up. Tzipora squinted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, wait, that’s just a regular one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In time, Tzipora would remember this period of her life fondly, and would visit Gigayeh to recapture that peace. As a teen-ager, however, those afternoons seemed to last forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baron, the Father</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/j23lyw/baron_the_father/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People are not sure what to make of Baron&lt;/strong&gt;. They are not sure what to make of his daughter, Tzipora, either. To that end, they are lucky to have found each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His obscurity is part of a severe disposition, made obvious by his astonishing disinterest in friends and hobbies. When he finishes work, he listens to the radio, prepares supper, and goes to bed. His unrelenting seriousness is mitigated by his general passivity — Baron is a man totally in control, who keeps to himself and does not take issue with what goes on around him. For his seriousness he is not particularly judgemental or opinionated. To call him boring would be a poor characterisation; he simply feels he has done enough and is not looking to complicate the basic equations of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora (Zelda to him) complicates this equation. She’s similar to him in many ways, with her conservative personal disposition and humble lifestyle. She does not make a very good teen-ager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s funny you say that. I was talking to her the other day, and she was talking about how nice it was to have some peace and quiet,” Baron once confided in Ayn. “Of course, she looks very young, so sometimes you have to remind yourself that she’s not a child. She’s not thirteen, she’s nineteen, and very unusual, I think. She’s very smart but she doesn’t let that on much.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora did not really have “phases” — Tzipora was Tzipora, eternal. But she was a much more emotionally attuned person, and her highs were higher and her lowers were lower than anything Baron had felt in decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was not always so unfeeling. Baron’s Ashkenazim parents were pulled straight from the bubbling diaspora of Eastern Europe. They met in the labour zionist movement, but fell out of love with professional organising and immigrated to a struggling Vekllei to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/g4wo2w/the_ou_hydroburo_office/&#34;&gt;work in the national hydroelectricity scheme&lt;/a&gt;, among thousands of immigrants employed by the Thunderburo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was born in 2027 and was not very interested in school as a child. He was rebellious and obstinate, and had only vague ambitions of acquiring a trade certificate in motorcycle repair. His sister, Amelie, died of tuberculosis when he was 11. That was about the end of school ambitions for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He started conscription early and spent his high school years in an army college. By the time he was 18, he was transferred to military police. It was 2045. He had started dating a middle school sweetheart, Ayn, two weeks before the war in Taiwan broke out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young Baron died in Taiwan, and another figure in his body returned. He was transferred almost immediately to a junior post at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), where he would spend the next decade. While he was stationed abroad, his mother died and his father followed. By this time, Baron was a significant asset for Vekllei’s deep autonomous intelligence work — apolitical, unattached, unsentimental and steady on his feet. He was destined to die in Colombia, employed indefinitely and waiting to be used up. In 2063, he met a fellow Spanish-speaking Jew by name of Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, his identity is as fractured as Tzipora’s, whose Jewish European ancestry was a novel curiosity and not much more. She considered herself a Latina-American until she was Vekllei, and since then she has not been anything more. That was how it went in Vekllei’s grand secular melting pot. Tzipora was still ta bubeleh to him, but by his mid-thirties Baron had lost most of his mother’s Yiddish.
Tzipora is his closest friend and daughter at the same time. She is a wholly energetic and independent agent in his life, and their relationship alternates awkwardly but intuitively between father-daughter and old friends. Ayn wonders if it is not a coincidence that Tzipora looks like Amelie, his sister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two of them champion the redemption of losers; the adrift, empty people of the world, acting on a chance to salvage a life and family. Tzipora expected to die in America; Baron expected nothing at all. But when Christmas comes around, and Ayn visits for supper, Taiwan and America melt into air; and their apartment houses the only Jewish Christmas tree in the neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory and Death in the Flower Tundra</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ivfcj4/memory_and_death_in_the_flower_tundra/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was their first hike after Maya’s funeral&lt;/strong&gt;. She had found adult life completely disappointing, and never moved out of home. In her last summer, she developed a desperate fascination with her receding childhood, and eventually took her own life outside of the classroom she’d studied in as a third-grade student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her death deeply disturbed Tzipora, who was keenly aware of how sentimental people died against metrics of their own imagination. She wondered if the government architects who designed schools and universities considered how those spaces gave life to memories. They were filled with lunchtimes and puppy love and old friends and your parents — and those things folded into brick and concrete and linoleum floors. Fifty years earlier, some architect designed a classroom so valuable that Maya took her own life in the memory of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their Puffling troop had set off for a camp site two hours away. Tzipora and Zo did not walk with them. They followed the flower tundra north, near where Zo and Maya had played as kids. At the base of an old oak, shrouded in a cool mist, Zo buried a pair of plastic earrings and laced school shoes, neither of which had been worn in a long time. Zo started to cry. Tzipora gave her some time to herself. After a while they drank hot tea with their feet in the creek. The mist had closed them in. There was good reason why people travelled to flower-tundras to meet with the dead. The mirror-pools and tombstone drumlins invoked the spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the tea, Zo pulled out her map and they set off again for the camp site, leaving the tree behind forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobian and Zelda &#34;head-over-heels&#34;</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/iu0c58/some_kind_of_gay_sketch_for_my_cool_subreddit/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;make love not lore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matchstick Girl</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/is6pr2/matchstick_girl/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another paint-sketch — a painting done fast. I’m trying to learn to a) paint and b) paint on an industrial scale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She’d missed the fast tram&lt;/strong&gt;, caught a tiny splinter in her thumb, lost a button and now the match wouldn’t strike. It just wasn’t her day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were in Callaisn (pronounced ka-lane), a borough of the capital Tzipora regarded as “the worst of them” for its tall buildings and labyrinthian concrete alleys. “Bad people, bad food, bad smells” she said, flashing the tact she was known for. “Let’s go home.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Callaisn was an oddity, built largely by the British during the occupation years in the fashion of London. It was nonetheless a thoroughly Vekllei borough, with its parks and tramways and rivulets, but it had a continental skyline marked by tower blocks and skyscrapers. A lot of boring business was done in Callaisn that Tzipora didn’t care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian frowned as Tzipora rotated a second match between her thumb and finger. She didn’t like this nasty little habit she’d picked up. “You’ll smell like your dad if you keep this up,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Suits me,” said Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/iqaarv/road_trip/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They showed up at the autopool&lt;/strong&gt;, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem. Moise would drive, Tzipora bunked with Cobian in the passenger seat and Alise, Zo and Jerome could cram into the back. It was a squeeze but with the top down and on the coastal highway it couldn’t have mattered less. It was the car of late summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zo had just married Jerome, and they had recently moved in with each other at age 17. Tzipora had no metrics to figure out if that was too young, but Zo was her friend and young newlyweds were lonely people. She was all too ready to volunteer her labour (and that of Cobian and Moise) to drive them down to Koisniya and pick them up a coffee machine she’d ordered six months prior. Tohs S.p.A. was a good company but Tohs himself was a disorganised bastard and he’d rung up to a few times to tell her the order had been delayed. Then she called him back a month later and he said he’d never received the order. So it was that they were on their way now, well after Zo and Jerome had married, to pick up the wedding gift. That was just how things worked in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zo’s friend Alise sat the coffee machine in her lap on the way back, and as the coastal highway reached Vik it skirted an incredible series of cliffs that they stopped to look at. The wind was out and the Atlantic churned beneath. The sun was hot on their skin. The coffee machine was left on the tiny back seat as they got out to have a look and take a picture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Quiet</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/if77nc/absolute_quiet/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were plumes in the sky, sent from bunkers buried deep in the well of the Earth, killing with switches. Vekllei went to war, and so Tzipora went to war with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The throbbing machinery of another world began turning, and anyone who saw the bomb would hear it. Passing seconds dislocated and caught heartbeats. The plumes were pretty. It was such a shame, those plumes. It was a quiet afternoon in the flower-tundras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an absolute quiet among the grasses, and peace in her heart. She had work to do. She was a warden, after all — and she’d done a good job spotting the missile before the sirens caught up. In truth, any devastation seemed incomprehensible. The flower-tundra would last forever. But that was her job, and she had to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She left her bucket by the freshwater creek, intending to retrieve it a while later. The drinking water tasted better up here. She turned from the plume and followed the moss path out of the flower-tundra. Her village was before her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So ended the old ways and so started the new.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/i1fgjd/meet_tzipora_concept_panel_for_a_vekllei_comic/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;unique-among-girls&#34;&gt;Unique among girls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not &lt;em&gt;realise&lt;/em&gt; she is unusual, or does not &lt;em&gt;care&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has a lot of endearing characteristics that give great character to her mannerisms and physicality. She has a small overbite that makes her look a little froggy, and ritually pulls on her shirt and wipes her nose in anxious conversation. She is round-headed and cuts her hair herself. She talks in a low, expressive voice. She has been poorly socialised in childhood, and is afraid of casual conversation with people she does not know. She is keenly socially attuned and feels awkwardness painfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wears the same clothes two or three days in a row. The outfits themselves are variations of the same thing, and her tastes don’t change. Everything hangs off her — she likes baggy, airy clothing, and upsizes to accomodate. She doesn’t like fashionable or voguish people, whom she regards as decadent and offensive. To Tzipora, taste is timeless and bound to the soul. In her case, this fact has held true — she has dressed the same as childhood, and very little else has changed about her in that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is paranoid and conservative, good-natured and austere, with a moral outlook bound by her deepest anxieties and obsessions. She is deeply spiritual and material, fascinated with objects and their history. She has many collections of many things she’s found. She’ll likely die a Catholic, but has a confrontational relationship with God and no longer attends mass, as a declaration of humanism. She does not know if this has pissed Him off, but it’s working out so far. Maybe that’s why He made her a homosexual — to get back at her. He must have a good sense of humour, if that’s the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora may be intense and inward-facing, but she can also be disarmingly charming and self-deprecating. She has a good sense of humour. There are not many girls that can so easily reconcile the contradictions between the peculiar and the healthy, the eccentric and the friendly, and the violent and the domestic. That’s part of her character — an essence of being that radiates decency, good taste and a respect for the spirit of all things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Camp</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hupcer/base_camp/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a paint-sketch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Krafla high-energy communications tower was visible from all over the region. It provided uninterrupted radio to most of North Lava, and could relay signals through satellites. In another country, it might have been considered a blight on a pristine view — but in Vekllei, there was no such thing as pristine. It was as much a part of the landscape as the trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They started the fire first, figuring they’d have more enthusiasm for the tent when they were warm. Warm sunrays played on the field-grasses around them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora’s ‘Every Day Carry’</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hu6k92/tziporas_every_day_carry/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like a lot of girls of poverty&lt;/strong&gt;, Tzipora was very possessive of her things. No food was ever left on her plate. There was a deep anxiety that whatever wasn’t claimed would be lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was also naturally obsessive and material-oriented, keenly aware of the importance of objects measured by metrics in her own silly head. You can discover a lot about a person from their trinkets and toys — let’s discover a bit about Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Her handbag is manufactured by Spaa S.p.A., a design firm in the capital. They’re a luxury item in the international market but readily available in Vekllei, since few other handbag makers operate on the scale of Spaa. Ayn picked it out shortly after Tzipora’s arrival for its colour, after Tzipora told her she did not own any red things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tzipora has a sweet tooth. Especially for soda, which she calls “fizzy drink”. On her person at any time, she carries a flavoured beverage from one of several brands capable of meeting her discerning tastes. She supplements them with a water bottle, since not even fizzy drink refreshes as well as water after phys-ed or a hot day. She also stocks her arsenal of snacks with good fruit picked off trees that overhang footpaths, as well as devastating salvos of Vekllei’s finest confectionary, including Fruit Tingles and chocolate pearls. Other girls in her class bemoan her childish metabolism as she drinks soda for lunch while they watch the scales.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The nostalgic whimsy of the sweets is tempered by two or three loose cigarettes that float around in her purse at any given time. She’s not a regular smoker, but she’s prone to attacks related to stress, and nothing helps as much as a drag. She carries matches, for not much reason other than that’s what Baron uses, and Tzipora is notoriously sentimental.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tzipora has a rock collection that sits on her bedroom sill, and her recent additions sit at the bottom of her purse. She’s not a rock elitist; quartz from footpaths catches her attention as easily as igneous treasures like palagonite. Her favourite is obsidian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She carries a small collection of useful books, including a contemporary paperback and a notebook. The paperback is for recess and lunch; the notebook is for language notes and phone numbers. Her Vekllei I.D. papers, which are both a passport and a reference booklet of key information and services, are carried on her at all times. It’s not really necessary in day-to-day life — but who knows when it might be, and Tzipora won’t be the one patting her pockets at the airport gate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, there are a few accessories sitting in the bag. Tzipora made a ring for Cobian in metalworking class, but Cobian is on a school trip to France at the moment and Tzipora is waiting for her return. She has a wristwatch given to her by Baron, which she wears sometimes depending on the occasion. Other items are more precautionary — a scarf for the wind, a handkerchief for sneezing, and a spare pair of socks for when she visits Cobian’s house or if she needs to double up in cold weather. As summer turns to autumn, she also carries gloves and a beanie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With everything in its place, her handbag is her anchor in the world outside her small second-floor apartment. The decommodification of society has only intensified the social value of objects, and they remain as important as ever in the life of the ordinary Vekllei person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Most Beautiful Woman</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/h1480l/a_most_beautiful_woman/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn&lt;/strong&gt;, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture. Tzipora was not quite sure how to describe it. Her beauty was very alive in the way she inhabited a space, as she walked into the hotel lounge to meet them. Maybe it was grace — maybe it was a little girl-crush — she didn’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Baron greeted her and they exchanged cheek kisses, it appeared to Tzipora that Ayn and Baron were old friends, and she was further assured in her respect for him — that Baron could know such beautiful women seemed natural! Baron was capable of anything in Tzipora’s eyes, a figure of ultimate power — it only made sense that he knew this woman!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, both Ayn and Baron were mortal, and Tzipora got to know them well during the helter-skelter weeks following her arrival in Vekllei. Baron might have rescued her, but it was Ayn who introduced her to Vekllei, as AB/NI called Baron into office for the first time in a decade. It was Ayn who took her clothes shopping and wrestled with Zelda’s obsessive-compulsive fabric requirements. It was Ayn who taught Tzipora her first Vekllei sentence. And in the end, it was Ayn who convinced Baron that he had to take responsibility for Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only years later that Tzipora began to realise that Ayn and Baron were, in a sense, married to each other through their work. They worked closely (he as recent head of operations at AB/NI, she as a research analyst in American economics) and their friendship went back decades. She was his “work wife,” which was the closest Baron could ever get to that particular institution, and so her proximity and love towards Tzipora made her a mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was a vision of everything Tzipora wanted for herself — to be capable and respected; beautiful and unassuming; intelligent and productive. And once more, it was Ayn, in the end, who convinced Tzipora that she could these things for herself, regardless of her genetic disability. “Go out there,” is what she said, “and trust in yourself.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rain in the Arctic Circle</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gqy57h/hot_rain_in_the_arctic_circle/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tzipora had been ejected&lt;/strong&gt; from the operations room once the guys arrived. She knew what was going down, anyway. No specifics. But you didn’t bring in uniformed soldiers for regular business. National Intelligence liked to work with their own people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five days prior, Baron hailed an EB/NI company car and it pulled up beside him. The electric passenger window slid down. Baron nodded at the passenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everything’s in here. There’s more if you need it. I’d appreciate a call, I’m in my office all next week, okay?” He passed over a white postage envelope. “Take care.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The British man opened the letter and read it twice as the car approached the Vekllei World Jetport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JULES WYNN IS YOUR 3RD MAN. “JEREMY” APPEARS IN ARCHIVES 2046 — ALMOST CERTAINLY WYNN. NEARLY 20 YEARS. NOTES TO USSR THRU CYPHER CLERK (UNKNOWN). RECALLED TO MOSCOW — GREAT SUSPICION OF HIM FROM CONTROLLER DOWSETT-CLARK (OXFORD). THIS IS GOOD INFO FROM PARIS ASSET. WYNN WILL DIE IN RUSSIA. GET HIM AND ANOTHER RING SURFACES. CIA KNOWS WHERE BUT NOT WHO. DO US BOTH A FAVOUR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora went for a walk to clear her head. She had a lot going on in her life — though she was sure it seemed small compared to whatever was going on in the operations room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It began to rain an hour into the walk. She’d left her umbrella with the rest of her things in Baron&amp;rsquo;s office. That was okay. She didn’t mind the shower, anyway — it was mid-summer, and the rain was warm. What a novelty that was, at 60 degrees north. This was weather from the sunny Azores, pulled north by the wind currents over the Atlantic. Within minutes her skirt was heavy and her camisole was showing at the shoulders. She blinked heavy streams of water out of her eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She passed the soldiers on their way out as she returned to AB/NI reception. A friendly receptionist had cloaked her in a towel by the time Baron had found her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Did you have a good meeting?” She asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sure,” and characteristically, he considered that a satisfactory answer. He pulled the towel off her head. “You’re completely soaked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It doesn’t matter. Are you with those guys? About that other guy?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Watch it,” he said. “Keep that talk past security. But I’m going to fly out tomorrow. I’ll be back in the evening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No cooking for me, then. Where are you going? Or can’t you say?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“England.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh,” Tzipora said, forming a gun with her fingers. “Like James Bond.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her life was a nexus of various global ambitions, it seemed — imagined only through the dreamy lens of a teen-ager too small for the world’s problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gndpwo/the_last_train_out_of_ada/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform.&lt;/strong&gt; And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables. Out here, you paced life around the station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was not much to say about this, between the two of them. Tzipora looked at Cobian and pulled a froggy smile that tried to express that it was nobody’s fault. Sure — it was Tzipora who had misplaced her purse, and it was also true that it was Tzipora who’d stopped by the orchard to steal a peach, but as to how they’d missed the train? It was simply impossible to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’re a complete idiot,” Cobian said matter-of-factly, and Tzipora wilted. They watched 416 trundle into the sunset. A picturesque vision of rural utopia — if only they were a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trials of Cobian</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gbknfu/the_trials_of_cobian/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;According to her friends&lt;/strong&gt;, Tzipora’s contemporary afflictions were tragic.  Her medical problems; her violent childhood; her sensitivity and melancholy — you could feel sorry for her, because a lot of her problems were not her fault. She invoked sympathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora never considered herself particularly tragic. It seemed straightforward, if difficult; she continued to live — and so she lived. Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s sympathy was instead reserved for her first and closest friend: Cobian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian was not well-liked at school, and it did not take long for Tzipora to find out why. She had a childish edge for a sixteen-year-old, and bitterly hated losing. She was not good at school or sports, was not particularly charming, and came across as desperately lonely. She was a quiet misandrist, which would have been fine if she could play the part of a self-assured social matriarch, but her mother’s despotic conservatism struck out that possibility early on. Such is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because her world was predicated on being liked and living a normal life, her psyche prohibited self-reflection. That was the great difference between Cobian and Tzipora. They may both have been young and neurotic, but Tzipora’s relentless self-interrogation left great space for personal growth. Cobian was instead trapped in a domestic play-fantasy, in which she could live out a mythical high-school life, and shattering that illusion would collapse her whole reason for being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora recalled visiting Cobian’s home for the first time. Cobian’s mother asked Tzipora to remove her shoes and socks and wash her feet before going to play inside. By the time Tzipora found Cobian in her room, the girl had already changed and handed over her uniform to be laundered. Tzipora, in her tomboyish indigence, had never encountered such a brutally hygienic regime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian was a different girl at home. Her anxiety and neurosis washed out a little, and her confidence was propped up by the routines her mother had set out for her since she was a child. There was a friendly, curious girl buried under a decade of loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora wondered what Cobian thought about lying in bed at night, and why the girl worried so much about things that didn’t matter. And it was precisely in the smallness of those things and the tremendous anxiety Cobian owed toward them that made Tzipora want to hug her. To be so worked up over something so pathetic was startlingly moving. The idea that the girl had deluded herself into a corner of hopelessness seemed sad — and the fact that no one would reasonably care about such a feeble, meaningless, self-inflicted state of affairs made it tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Tzipora’s friendship and the world it opened up for her, some of Cobian’s edges were sanded down. Some of it was a late maturity — some of it was Tzipora’s dismantling of the scaffolding the girl’s mother had shoved in there. With that effort, and obvious love, Cobian’s reason for being changed too. One day, in Tzipora’s presence, it didn’t seem so important to be liked by everybody anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Cobian, a concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/f4teoq/tzipora_the_princess_of_the_earth/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go back through my posts here, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice Tzipora is basically a cartoon whose only consistent characteristic is her iconography &amp;ndash; her hair fountain, bangs, round head and big smile. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really intentional. I&amp;rsquo;m just an amateur artist who is still learning to draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t work so well in a comic with sequential panels, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on standardising my characters. This is a concept panel for Cobian, Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s longtime friend (and occasional girlfriend). She&amp;rsquo;s an awkward, sympathetic sort of person, and often left out in my posts. She certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t deserve such treatment &amp;ndash; she&amp;rsquo;s one of the most interesting, complex people in the Vekllei cast and I hope to treat her with respect in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This panel is the first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on pages for the comic, but it&amp;rsquo;s slow going. I post pages as they come to my patrons (more or less!) but it&amp;rsquo;ll be a while before any chapters come together. That&amp;rsquo;s okay. I work better that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora, the Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/f4teoq/tzipora_the_princess_of_the_earth/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note — it’s getting close to 4 a.m. and I’m not sure I can even remember why I wrote this post. Everything is a fog. Expect revisions and possibly major changes in the morning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured above is Tzipora Desmoisnes, the Princess of the Earth and one of the most interesting persons of the last century. She has made good use of her 126 years on Earth (and counting), and a few samples have been chosen for your viewing pleasure. Conveniently, captions have been attached to briefly describe a few choice (but not comprehensive) depictions of her life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Years Old / 2049&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An infant Tzipora arrives in a country she would remember as her homeland. Knowing the tumultuousness of her childhood from here on, it is sobering seeing the round baby&amp;rsquo;s face staring back, red-faced and full-cheeked. Her mother, Mette Sumoisnesn from Vekllei, is a bohemian political scholar and radical looking to start fresh in South America after several life events leave her dissatisfied with life in Vekllei. With her savings secured, they move into a wealthy neighbourhood called Modelia, in Bogota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 Years Old / 2052&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At five, Tzipora speaks Spanish natively and only a handful of Vekllei phrases like many immigrant children. A naturally lithe and timid girl, she won’t make friends at school until her second year. In many ways, she is already becoming a picture of opposites from her mother; where Mette is a postmodern lady of wide social interest, Tzipora is conservatively inward-facing. She has, however, already inherited Mette’s disarming honesty and decisive mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 Years Old /2054&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Mette kept irregular hours and a laissez faire attitude towards parenting, Tzipora is already fairly independent for her age. Although hardly the only child to maintain a household in Bogotá, she is certainly unique in her social class. Mette’s Vekllei-sourced wealth goes a long way in Colombia, but her bohemian lifestyle and liberal social instincts lend to a world of contradictions and colourful schisms that leave Tzipora caught between worlds — that of the poor, artistic, and revolutionary as well as the wealthy, polite and domestic. Even at this age, Tzipora already showcases several of these contrasts in her malleable personality, which are as charming as they are awkward. Although her relationship with Mette is untraditional for a single mother and daughter, it is affectionate and Tzipora is happy in Modelia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 Years Old / 2057&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2057. President Cifuentes has been dead for six months, the communists are in power in Bogotá, and Mette has depleted ten years of Colombian wages to shelter Tzipora in a Catholic boarding school in the U.S. to keep her safe from an imminent American invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She now wears the uniform of St Mary&amp;rsquo;s Catholic College in Sacramento, California. She&amp;rsquo;s cut her hair in keeping with the American fashions and has lost some weight as she diets for what the other girls in her dorm call a “Coca Cola body”. On Tzipora’s small, girlish frame, her thinness looks pitiful and achingly neglected, not attractive. She is an Inuk-Scandinavian girl with Jewish European ancestry who knows only the language and culture of a wealthy Latina. Compounded with her little eccentricities and timidity, she does not fit in well at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 Years Old / 2061&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot can happen in four years. There was an atomic bomb in Cairo, and the Federal Government has lost control of the so-called Dallas States. Mette has stopped responding to letters and Tzipora’s out of money. She makes plans to move in with her male mathematics teacher, who predated on her near-idiotic numeracy weaknesses to foster an illicit relationship, but abandons that idea when she discovers he has been grooming multiple other girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She takes the California Zephyr to Utah instead of San Francisco on advice of a trusted priest, and quickly finds herself indigent and starving. Clothed by a charity in filthy artefacts of the previous decade, she lives in a women’s shelter that has too little to go around. There’s not even work as a strikebreaker anymore, since sporadic fighting in Southwest Utah has moved or shuttered all business that isn’t literally burrowed into the surrounding desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 Years Old / 2063&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She’s aware by now, and has been since her school days, that she has some sort of nutritional deficiency or hormone imbalance impeding her puberty. As a good Catholic girl of the faith, she does not understand anything about puberty, but it doesn’t take a doctor to figure out she looks half the age of the teen-agers in the shelter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has miraculously managed to find work as a maid at a nearby motel, and has money for little luxuries that now mean the world to her. Clean underwear, some sneakers that are good for day work, and a steady stream of penny dreadfuls from the local bookshop, operated by the mysterious “Baron”. She lives in a so-called “Women’s House” that starts attracting attention as the turbulent political climate in the Dallas States continues to destabilise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 Years Old / 2065&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora celebrates her eighteenth birthday as a student at Lola 6th School in Vekllei. She is overwhelmed with affection for the country and her new father, Baron, but is struggling to reconcile her natural inadequacies as a new immigrant with her expectations of success in a country that offers her so much. Life is busy, and is full of new things that send her reeling with excitement — friends, music, and good food are just a few. At once younger and older than her years, Tzipora’s independence and stubborn affection make raising her easy for first-time dad Baron, who never intended to have children, let alone start with a teen-ager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32 Years Old / 2079&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffering from a severe bout of seasonal depression and a deep sense of listlessness after graduating from university, Tzipora’s long-neglected existential epistemology breaks open all at once. Now a librarian in the Lola central library, she watches Baron get older and wonders about ending her life once he passes. She drowns her panic in her work, working days at a time cataloguing stock at the library while also editing the underground ‘zine &lt;em&gt;Kid Comix&lt;/em&gt;. The sardonic nihilism of the underground Comix community is her only comfort as she considers her future and the place in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86 Years Old / 2133&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Tzipora always evolved slowly, by 86 Tzipora’s turbulent youth is well behind her. Her little insecurities and aching sense of inferiority have blossomed into a gentle sense of humour and easygoing disposition common in old ladies. Does Tzipora qualify as one? By the numbers, certainly. But ask anyone in Montre-Lola, the village she’s lived in since moving there over fifty years earlier, and they’ll tell you that she retains a teen-age vitality and curiosity in her that should have been dissipated long ago. Physically, she is, of course, unchanging — and her spastic tics are as present as ever. Montre-Lola may change, and Tzipora may watch generations cycle through, but she is apparently timeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;126 Years Old / 2173&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much older, and a little wiser, Tzipora has had decades to reconcile her extended stay on Earth with the seeming immortality of the Vekllei cultural landscape. She still lives in Montre-Lola as a maternal root of the community, and resides in the little house built for her by the town over eighty years ago. For Tzipora, her sense of time has slowed to a crawl. A creature of routine, life around her goes on despite it all — the atomic war, the rebuilding, the stresses of a post-war world. A lot of her life is boring. She doesn’t mind. She finds great pleasure in the mundane, and her body is young and healthy. There are always reasons to live, and not just for the people in her life — after all, novels continue to be written and her plants need to be watered. Absorbed in her pleasant little life, it barely occurs to her that next year she will become the oldest living human being in history.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face to Face with Immortality</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ew9gb3/face_to_face_with_immortality/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tzipora had never been taller than anyone in Vekllei at a meagre 5’2, but she was taller than Shizuku Kobayashi. Like Tzipora, Shizuku had not physically aged a day since she was a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was summer, and six days after Tzipora had arrived in Japan as a Gregori ambassador from Vekllei. Although she would not be the oldest victim of Gregori-Heitzfeld syndrome until Quentin Cook’s (USA) infamous murder-suicide ten years later, she was one of the so-called &amp;ldquo;First Thirteen&amp;rdquo; publicised patients, and so was somewhat known to the international community. By the time of their meeting in 2071, there had been an estimated 250 Gregori baby births, and around 130 living across the world. Kobayashi was the 122nd ageless child, and Japan’s first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora met Kobayashi in the Ozake Ryokan outside Kamigōri, Kobayashi’s birthplace and home. It was not far from Aioi. Tzipora was 24 at the time, and Shizuku was 18, and still in school. Poor Zelda was so nervous about meeting another Gregori baby that she became overwhelmed by Japanese manners. So it was that Shizuku’s first introduction to Tzipora was via a clonk on the head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shizuku was sweet and even-tempered, and they talked for nearly five hours before she was retrieved by her mother in the late evening. She spoke okay English, because she’d dropped out of school for a year to pursue acting with an American film company based in Yokohama that operated through the NGHQ. Acting was a common profession for Gregori babies — it seemed that the miracle children of the world were quickly relegated to freaks of entertainment. Tzipora did not have the stomach for it, but she knew of several others around the world who made good money playing children in film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora excitedly relayed the awkwardness of life in Vekllei as an unageing child, from her problems at university to her dreams of the future. She had no metric for how it might differ in Japanese society, because in many ways she was still fourteen — the problems of a young teen-age girl seemed universal, even then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No one takes you seriously at first,” Tzipora said, but she acknowledged that once people got to know her she’d had no problem being treated with respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I suppose,” replied Shizuku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora could not help but notice that Shizuku looked different from her Japanese peers. It was only later that she would learn that Shizuku’s father was a GI from Okinawa, shamefully rendering her eternally “&lt;em&gt;hafu&lt;/em&gt;” despite the miracle of her existence. She could sympathise, in her own privileged way — Tzipora, too, was a girl of many ethnicities and cultures. But even with her television understanding of the land of the rising sun, Tzipora grasped that things might be more difficult here, where old-world memory collided with new-world growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora quieted her obnoxious enthusiasm and asked Shizuku what pictures she was in. Shizuku said she wasn’t in pictures, just television, and Tzipora wouldn’t have seen them anyway. Tzipora asked what she wanted to do. She said she didn’t know. As for Tzipora?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to work in a library,” Tzipora said. “I love stories, and I like the idea of being in charge of the books.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I love stories too,” Shizuku said. “I’d like to write them, really. But we’ll have to see. It’s difficult…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She trailed off, perhaps lost in her foreign vocabulary. She didn’t have to finish the point. It &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; difficult: it was difficult to make money, it was difficult to find love, and it was difficult to picture a future where the only constant was yourself. It was no wonder that Gregori children, whose personalities were often developed by the projections of those around them, ended up killing themselves when the uselessness and meaninglessness of their existence revealed itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Shizuku’s mother received money from the estranged father, and Shizuku herself had made good money through acting, a fugue settled on Tzipora in the days after their meeting. Previously she had not considered herself a “Gregori baby;” she had considered herself merely “Tzipora”. In Vekllei, that was an identity she could afford. But despite Shizuku’s outward satisfaction with her present state of affairs, Tzipora couldn’t help but feel ill thinking about the anxious, isolating existence that almost certainly awaited any girl whose childhood stretched into the decades. All at once it seemed very unfair in its quiet cruelty — the hafu girl who would never grow up to be a beautiful actress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although she’d kept in contact with Shizuku Kobayashi, Tzipora would not visit another Gregori baby for many decades.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girls of the Last Carriage</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/eu7a4h/the_girls_of_the_last_carriage/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’d accidentally starched her &lt;em&gt;gi&lt;/em&gt; quarter-pleat in the wash. She held it self-consciously against her side as she watched the clouds navigate the sharp mountains that formed Montre’s deepest valleys. Even out here, where human presence was gentle and subservient to the land, Vekllei National Railways had tracks that serviced the smallest villages. Today it was high summer, and the slopes were green and free of ice. They waited in the shade of the regional limited express carriage for train 802, which would take them home to Montre-Lola and complete a two hour ritual all Montre-Lolan university students made for their studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;802 was the second of an 800-series trainset that had been manufactured since 2003. These trains came from old society, long before Tzipora or her father had ever been born, back when VK Rail had been the Montre Regional Transport Company. It was crazy to think that the 802 had been around since before the bombs had fallen, and had survived the chaos of the atomic aftermath. It was funny how human creations became guides through history, linking young women like Tzipora to the solemn echoes of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was something sobering about that idea, she thought. She was thinking about this as she waited in the carriage, as a younger girl fidgeted in boredom and another whistled away in sleep. The sun was hot on the platform outside and the rising air distorted the bright yellow glint that signalled 802’s approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite a week between posts, I’ve been a busy little bee. I made a Tintin-style Tzipora today, &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/VJSR4mn&#34;&gt;please click here to see her&lt;/a&gt;. I also drew Tzipora causing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/hAkBZ1i&#34;&gt;ruckus in a Ryokan here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also encourage you all to come &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;join the Vekllei Discord&lt;/a&gt;, where I do a lot of sketching and a lot of nice worldbuilding discussion goes on. In the coming days I have a few projects I’d like to share, including a new animated studio title for this project!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These last few posts have been heavy on the melancholy and light on the worldbuilding. That’s all about to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Trouble</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/e20la7/making_trouble/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora never lost her youthful curiosity. She would swish about the apartment, chasing an idea or plan that had occurred to her. Baron would look over and say “What are you doing, Zelda? Making trouble?” He said that a lot. He would come home in the afternoon and she would be writing lists, or organising her paperbacks, or moving furniture and he’d say, “What are you up to, Zelda? Making trouble?” She would say “No, I’m sending out invites for Christmas/learning the Dewey Decimal/going to have a nap in the sun.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zelda had a way of attracting trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two deputies dragged the maid who worked at Motel Grande off Route 70 to a tree beyond the Kennecott salt flats. She was crying the whole time. She was very young for a maid, but girls needed money like anyone else. She was starving. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the kind of hunger you saw in the National Geographic; it was a long, slow year of starvation, where most of her muscle had wasted away and she’d been left with a bit of youthful fat around her belly and cheeks. That&amp;rsquo;s just how people looked in Utah in 2063. Atomic power collided with indigence across most of the Southwest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This girl did not have a last name, because she was some immigrant worker with a fake visa worth less than her shitty hand-me-down rayon uniform. She knew what was coming in the back of the police cruiser and started to tremble uncontrollably as they left the highway. An immigrant expects what happens to immigrants. They pulled up by a stump and a small patch of dead ashes that were visible from the highway that crossed the flats. Would they take a picture of her for a postcard? She didn’t want that. Who would cut her down? Would they bury her? Suddenly the finality of it hit her — who, at all, would remember her?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was not sure if she was being made an example or an excuse, but could not recall for her life what she’d done to deserve either. The car engine ticked over as the bigger of the cops slung a thin noose around her neck and yanked on it until it hurt her throat. She pleaded with them in good English, trying to suppress her Latina vocalisations, and cried desperately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am American,” she whined, “I’m from California. Do I look Latina? Look, I’m white. My mother is from Germany. Please, you have the wrong person.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How old are you?” The big cop asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Eighteen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you start fuckin lying I’ll string you up now. Tell me how old you are.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m sixteen. Sixteen,” she coughed. “I&amp;rsquo;m just a late grower. My father’s from Salt Lake. Please, I’m not an immigrant. I was born here. I’m American.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Shut up; I don’t give a shit. You live with some girls in town, right? In that house?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In downtown Cherry, yes. Yes, I’ll tell you about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And you work for Mr Parker at the motel?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes, I do. He’s nice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do you pay union dues?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dues? No, I don’t think so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Do you pay any tax?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s all cash,” she blinked tears out of her eyes. “I don’t know much about taxes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All right, Griselda. We’re going to talk about some of the girls in that house.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They asked her some questions and took some notes. What she was doing only occurred to her after the third name. They gave her a sandwich to eat. It wasn’t out of kindness — it was to bask in the absolute violence of their authority. You could find as much pleasure in pardoning a girl as you could beating her. For a moment, on their command, her poverty and fear was excused. She chewed through bologna as she listed out her neighbours, and after a while her tears were for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she was almost done she began to wonder again if they’d kill her. She’d finished the sandwich and was unconsciously picking crumbs off her uniform, squishing her fingers pathetically against her lips as her eyes darted nervously between them. They left her there, with the noose around her neck, beneath the dead ash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/c05k16/absolute_grotesque/&#34;&gt;Read more about Utah here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicating despair in the pasture of plenty</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/e1i710/medicating_despair_in_the_pasture_of_plenty/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is doing well now. She has looked into her heart and made peace with who she is. She has discovered she is a girl who likes free jazz, and milky coffee, and cotton shirts, and trains — to the surprise of no-one who knows her. She knows what things she values in a friend, and what deserves to become family. She knows what clothes she likes and how to do her hair. A year ago, she was a shivering little girl, but today she has become a glowing young woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A glowing pleasure though she may be, her nerves are still shot and her past is still with her. Tzipora is a habitual creature, prone to obsessions and addiction, and she’d suffered many vices by the time she met Baron. For a while it had been sleeping pills with the other girls in the Women’s House, chasing the mind-bending effects of a methaqualone high and sleep deprivation. It was about that time she picked up cigarettes, which helped with the tics she was cultivating in her violent poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She never quite kicked them. Like the tics, they stuck around. For a girl whose joy filled mountains and lows loomed cliffs, a cigarette now and then took some of that edge off. Ayn never liked her habit. Baron never asked her about it — he knew, she thought. He knew what it was like to feel the walls closing in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It made for some awkward encounters, not least of which was a moment of panic the first time Cobian stayed over. Zelda has always suffered very bad dreams most nights, and her fear of waking her friend led her out onto the frigid balcony in the early hours of the morning. Six drags in, the lights turned on and the door slid open. An awkward minute of fumbling followed, pushing Zelda into territory she was uncomfortable sharing with anyone but Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So it helps?” Cobian asked, mulling over the idea with her legs to her chest. Tzipora was fidgeting miserably in the cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Where do you get them? The cigarettes?” She asked, as though Tzipora would mistake the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They’re Baron’s.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And what happens if you stop?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know,” Zelda sniffed. “You don’t have to make it a big deal, anyway. I don’t like this. I don’t like doing it, but what helps, helps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Can I try? I’ve never tried.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A moment later Tzipora laid a hand gently across the girl&amp;rsquo;s mouth to quiet the vicious coughing and hacking for fear it would wake Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Shh. It’s okay, I know it’s not good,” she soothed. Even as a genuine teen-ager Tzipora had been maternal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s terrible,” Cobian gasped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I know. But it helps. Let’s go inside, I’ll get you some water.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Tzipora would always operate according to the charter of her various obsessions, she was always slightly self-conscious about the cigarettes. Even sixty years later she only smoked alone. It was unbecoming of a satisfied person, she supposed, let alone a woman in the body of a girl. Still, for all her quirks and all her ticks, to most people her little vices were the most normal thing about her. She was a figure of contradictions, and her weaknesses were just as precious to her loved ones as her tremendous strength and bigness of heart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1000 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-11-10-1000-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-11-10-1000-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/dtxvys/1000_subscribers/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart here. You might not know it, but I’m sort of a big fucking deal on the internet. No, don’t touch me. Why am I? Because my subreddit just hit 1,000 subscribers. What’s a subreddit? I’m actually laughing at you; imagine not knowing what reddit is. &lt;em&gt;You ingrate&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously though, this whole renewal of the project through a subreddit (rather than disconnected r/worldbuilding posts) has been an amazing thing. It gives me more wriggle room in what I can talk about, and — even better — allows me introduce you to my characters, who are very precious to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your State of the Subreddit bulletin follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’ll turn your attention to the badges on this post, I’ve scribbled up a few community awards for fun. They’re both 500 coins, the cheapest I can make it. They can’t give you premium. Reddit is garbage and they don’t really deserve your money, but some of the regulars here are pretty wonderful and if they ask a really good question or something you can reward them in a way you never could in Vekllei — with money. I made them so I can hand them out, really. You can choose from &amp;lsquo;Medal of Valour&amp;rsquo; for long-time service or &amp;lsquo;Great Question&amp;rsquo; for, uh, you can probably guess. Let me know what you think. Do I need more types?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For my new friends, of which there are many of you, it might take a while to settle into Vekllei’s world and characters. For example, Tzipora, pictured here abusing a friend, also goes by Zelda. If you get confused, you can check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/czi423/a_brief_introduction_to_vekllei/&#34;&gt;this meta intro to the project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/czi423/a_brief_introduction_to_vekllei/&#34;&gt;this brief summary of Vekllei as a country&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve got a few different projects going, in addition to the regular posts. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/melonkony&#34;&gt;I’ve made a Twitch&lt;/a&gt;, since it’s literally a single button on my iPad to stream me working. This isn’t the start of some illustrious streaming career, just something that was easy to do. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;I also have a Patreon&lt;/a&gt;, if you’d like to send a few dollars my way for the posts or food or whatever else. On the horizon is the graphic novel (no two ways about it, it’s a long-term project but it’s coming), and a few special experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for hanging around. I’m very lucky to have a community that responds to my work. So many of you have reached out personally and interrogated my posts and it’s very flattering to attract that sort of interest. I’ll keep on keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart Phillips&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The King</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-10-21-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-10-21-king/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/dkldsz/the_king/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The King and Tzipora do not get along. Zelda met him through Moise, when King managed the Domepent School’s cricket team. Moise was a pretty good wicket keeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King had offended Zelda with an off-hand comment on her youthful appearance, and she’d retorted with a remark about his weak blood circulation. Moise, caught between his new boss and his angry Zelda, navigated these stormy waters by ignoring the dispute entirely and separating them on the walk home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Moise would turn out to be a decent athlete, and she would spend more time around King, she never would come to like him. He was pompous without pomp. For his part, he regarded her as small and cranky. It was not an entirely unreasonable assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mountain Witches of Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/de25mz/the_mountain_witches_of_pachinki_and_the/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pachinki is the fantastical notebook of Tzipora, in all her loneliness and thunderous imagination, shared with you all to enjoy. She&amp;rsquo;s so far constructed Pachinki posts about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ar8jov/a_gem_girl_shows_off_her_enormous_strength_in/&#34;&gt;gem children&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/user/MelonKony/comments/azmu94/the_palace_gods_attempt_to_retrieve_their_runaway/&#34;&gt;palace henchmen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/b7n1uh/a_mineral_lake_starts_absorbing_grief_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;sinister earth magics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ba3mb4/the_littlest_goddess_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;the Palace Gods&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cudfnv/the_teeth_regents/&#34;&gt;teeth regents.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Tzipora’s notebook:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[A Guide to Magic, Chapter 2: The Witch]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witches of Pachinki are an interesting affair — many books have been dedicated to their research after discovery, yet so little is known about them. They are almost universally misandrists, which is understandable considering their present illegality and persecution in the subcontinents of Zen and Domos. They serve only themselves and individuals they happen to like, and spend most of their lives exploring the canyon between the chaos of nature’s fundamental frequencies and the power of human magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are rumoured to be able to split their own minds. Using old spells long since lost to ordinary people in Zen, they are able to siphon their mental faculties into a trusted object — usually a precious gem, and relegate essential functions of the brain to it. For example, a witch might siphon a tenth of her mental ability into a necklace, which then pushes out whatever consciousness exists within then carries on a witch’s essential functions — respiration, blood circulation and pain are just a few of unconscious functions a witch might do away with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would they do such a thing? Well, it is known to all people who have ever attempted magics that powerful spells force great stress on the mind. In fact, the more thorough the subsumption of the mind towards the spell, the better the results. By dispensing with her bodily functions, a witch is able to dedicate almost all of her mental power towards the task at hand, and since a brain operating without vital functions is a very stressed brain indeed, she can become extraordinarily powerful as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such magical efforts make perfect sense for people of power — government workers, or traditional sorcerers — but witches are far more interested exploration and discovery than they are power and conquest. So again — why would they do such a thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only recently has a possible answer to this question arisen. It is disarmingly straightforward — witches are outcasts, and usually very lonely people. By siphoning enough of their own mind into a creature or pet, they replace the pet with a functioning copy of themselves. They are consequently able to make friends at will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a process is incredibly dangerous — although only a fraction of brainpower is required to make a functioning consciousness, they are in essence duplicating a human mind. To transplant a consciousness of human intuition into, say, a raven, requires powerful psychophysical drugs and gems of a correct frequency to stop a collapse of the mind (and subsequently render ten percent or so of the witch’s brain ability permanently nonfunctioning). Even upon a successful schism, her summoned consciousness is hardly a raven — it is an anthropomorphic creature, of human mind and animal body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fact of the witch, which may interest the reader, is that they do not decompose upon death. They are ordinary people in life, but ancient magic the likes of which is unobservable and unknowable keeps their body, intact or otherwise, totally preserved (though thoroughly dead). In kingdoms where witchcraft is a crime, you can find “witch towers” filled with the fresh, undead body parts of executed witches that will long outlive the grisly silos themselves…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mafioso and His Witch</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-10-05-mafioso/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-10-05-mafioso/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ddmu3r/a_mafioso_and_his_witch/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello, everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s been six days. I&amp;rsquo;d like to have been here sooner, but I had the good fortune to leave my Apple Pencil in a hotel room in Sydney. Although delighted with my welcome and surprising expense (~$150AUD, or roughly 43 bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves), I&amp;rsquo;ve consequently fallen behind with my off-daily illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I carry the ANZAC spirit deep within me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve made use of my time. I have a document, many thousands of words long, detailing a special kind of script. &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/lL3T32R&#34;&gt;The writing is excellent.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a hint &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s not for a film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for sticking with me. I&amp;rsquo;m back. In the meantime, please enjoy this illustration and story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Moise arrived at the Desmoisnes&#39; to pick up Tzipora for the halloween festivities, he was greeted at the door by Baron, who looked tired and held a powder mirror in one hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, hello, Moise,&amp;rdquo; Baron said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How&amp;rsquo;s things?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Good, good. Say, Moise, could you tell Zelda she looks nice when you see her?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Moise could ask, Zelda&amp;rsquo;s voice rang out from behind her father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tell him I&amp;rsquo;ll be a moment! Just a moment!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; like most Zeldaic exclamations, there was panic in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, he stepped inside her room to see her. She was dressed as a witch, and wore a cardboard hat fashioned in black linen on her head. Most immediately, however, he noticed she was wearing eye-liner and rouge. He&amp;rsquo;d never seen her wear make-up before, because she looked too young to wear it. She was a teen-ager whose appearance made such feminine gestures a costume rather than daily practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You look really nice,&amp;rdquo; Moise said. &amp;ldquo;Have you done yer face?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; she beamed, &amp;ldquo;you noticed! It&amp;rsquo;s not done poorly is it? I&amp;rsquo;ve got no practice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nah, it looks great.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wasn&amp;rsquo;t lying. She&amp;rsquo;d gone a bit heavy since her lashes were so dark already, but she looked years older for it. Zelda wilted under any timid flattery and smiled genuinely at him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe I should wear it sometimes. It&amp;rsquo;s not too much trouble.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baron called from the living room: &amp;ldquo;It took &lt;em&gt;two hours&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All right!&amp;rdquo; she yelled, and after a moments of pause, followed with a kinder shout. &amp;ldquo;Thanks for helping me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The festival went until the early hours of the morning. Cold city air washed over them in waves as they passed through warm clouds of woodsmoke from fires set out for hallow&amp;rsquo;s eve. He was dressed in pinstripes as a Mafia don. He told her he had Mafia blood in him. Zelda asked if he was getting Greece confused with Italy, to which he took great offence. She started laughing as his fake moustache danced about on his upper lip when he corrected her, which made him more annoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nice night out, in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puffin Attack</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-16-puffin-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-16-puffin-attack/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/d4lfim/puffin_attack/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Zelda can&amp;rsquo;t have kids, she mothers whole generations of village children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Ayn</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-14-ayn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-14-ayn/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/d3qmnb/introducing_ayn/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The daughter of a Soviet expat and Hong Konger deckhand, &lt;strong&gt;Ayn&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Rumouisen&lt;/strong&gt; has never stepped foot outside of Vekllei. A serious fear of flying and the open ocean has hedged her appetite for travel for all of her thirty-two years. She is well respected as an operations consultant within the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), and is close with the ABNI Operations Director &lt;strong&gt;Baron Desmoisnes&lt;/strong&gt; and Vekllei’s first “Gregori Baby,” &lt;strong&gt;Tzipora &amp;ldquo;Zelda&amp;rdquo; Desmoisnes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She’s known Baron, Tzipora’s father, for nigh twenty years. They met when she was eighteen, both as cadets in Vekllei’s combat intelligence programme. They dated for a few years before the requirements of intelligence work forced them apart. Baron was sent to South America for nearly a decade, and Ayn stayed behind in the Monitoring &amp;amp; Preparations Department where she published work in the classified journals about events relevant to ABNI. She was also an associate contributor to the “Import Strangle” theoretical model, which has proven successful at plotting the collapse of major U.S. employers (like U.S. Steel in 2065 and Chrysler in 2068) for use in Vekllei foreign policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baron and Ayn exemplify quiet, uncinematic mateship — people satiated by occasional company and mutual respect, satisfied by their intermittent time together. After Tzipora’s adoption, Baron, now approaching his forties, returned to work as a senior director for the Americas Bureau, and soon found himself in Ayn’s professional orbit. In doing so, he introduced a nervous young satellite called Tzipora to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora adores Ayn. Ayn is everything Tzipora wants to be. She is even-tempered but strong-willed, graceful but not girlish, fiercely intelligent but pleasantly social. Where Baron is a product of his years in America and is totally professionalised at home and at work, Ayn has enjoyed life in Vekllei and is well-rounded and sweet. It was a shock for Tzipora to see Baron and Ayn in a photograph from their cadetship. Baron straddled a motorcycle, and did not wear spectacles. He was well-built and rough-looking. Ayn was a slender Asian woman dressed in slacks and a sunhat. Ayn today looked very much similar. Baron, in his beard and white-speckled hair, looked like an entirely different person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora and Ayn share a hardship in their infertility despite a desire to have children — Ayn suffered from endometriosis for many decades and is incapable of pregnancy. In all ways, Baron’s reluctant decision to adopt Tzipora was a wonderful blessing — it brought old friends closer together and gave Ayn a daughter. For Tzipora, whose memories of her biological mother were bittersweet and muddied with time, Ayn was a breath of womanhood and light-heartedness in a household that contained only a single hard-working middle-aged man and his teen-age daughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Baron’s immediate family is dead, Tzipora is close with Ayn’s parents in the North of Vekllei and they’ve taken to her as a granddaughter. Although Ayn and Baron are not married, and may never marry (although Tzipora gauges his response at least once a year), their lives are so thoroughly entwined that it is not uncommon that Baron will return home to Ayn and Tzipora preparing dinner together. In fact, Ayn is the reason Tzipora is such a good cook. Love takes many forms, and Tzipora enjoys several of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Normal programming will resume presently. Thanks for your patience everyone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Mouth, Fat Lip</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-05-fat-lip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-05-fat-lip/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/d0dde5/big_mouth_fat_lip/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first six months Baron had known her, Zelda was a serious and wisened young woman who carried symptoms of her troubled past as gracefully as anyone ever could. Poverty ages a person, and she’d nurtured a calm and dispirited disposition. She did not like war films or books with unhappy endings, or loud noises or arguments. She dressed conservatively and spoke quietly and uncontroversially. She had lived a lifetime already, working in exploitation in motels and supermarkets, watching as Utah unraveled around her. She was an immigrant and uneducated, homeless and independent, and so by the time she arrived in Vekllei she was ready to settle down and live quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching her psyche attempt to reconcile her sombre nature with her desire to be normal and socialise with people her own age was heartbreaking. She had this pathetic, mythical idea of normal girlish life, and it took her a long time to figure out that teen-age life worked differently from films. She had a group of people she hung around, but always on the periphery. She was blatantly disposable and socially innocent, and so she carried on pretending she could somehow rework her own image into the mythologised Coca-Cola teen dream she’d clung to since California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the idea fell apart. Where she was mousy and pitiful as a school-girl, as Zelda she was uncompromising and principled. As bullying got worse, and her school friends came to resent the parasitic relationship she&amp;rsquo;d worked her way into, things eventually came to a head and the whole thing came crashing down. She got beat up pretty bad, and ruined a new school shirt, but Zelda had fought tougher creatures than Vekllei schoolgirls and she was suspended for the rest of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Zelda would figure out that she never really needed or wanted the sort of bubbly teen-age friends she’d imagined. Zelda was, after all, not that bubbly or teen-age. Throughout her life, her closest friends were always those that required nothing and gave her space. That was how she liked to be; loved and shown affection, but left to her own devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighter Than Her Shadow</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-shadow/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cz6cyp/lighter_than_her_shadow/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zelda, for all her outward timidity and mousiness, was mostly self-assured. In the same way that a child is self-assured, in which there is no real epistemology of the self as adults know it. Zelda never grew up to become a real teen-ager, after all — her body is forever thirteen-and-a-half, despite her mature and maternal disposition — and so she had a reckless sort of confidence that never really doubted the premise of her existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She did have many weaknesses, however, and she was very conscious of them. They were almost too many to count. The biggest of them, aside from her blatant neurodivergences, was her inability to keep weight on. In her first few months in Vekllei, her skinny frame was symptomatic of her malnourishment in the States. Then, as she struggled to stay above thirty kilos, it became a question of eating habits. Finally, the question was asked — did she have some sort of problem, here? And if so, was it something to do with Gregori syndrome, the comfortable answer? Or was it something more complex — perhaps an eating disorder?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from her small portions, she did not indicate much in common with other girls her age who struggled with image. In fact, much of physical self-loathing was directed at her thinness, which only emphasised her childish lack of figure and breastlessness. The only times Zelda ever cried over a mirror was when she saw her own scrawny frame that a healthy diet should have been able to remedy. Yet even when she pushed herself, and choked down a second serving, it seemed to hardly make a difference. It was a cycle that would haunt her for a long time, until the age when Gregori women must learn to accept their girlishness in place of traditional ideas of beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case may have been, Zelda has never weighed more than forty kilos except in a winter coat, and she can still count her ribs in bath. What has changed — in a most wonderful way that alleviates much of her suffering — is her ability to love herself, and understand the limitations of her condition. Considering the fact that she has done so much, and despite her childlessness has mothered many boys and girls to adulthood, priorities shift and the importance of beauty fades. She spends more time today being the best Zelda she can be rather than worrying about her image. After all, image is a loser’s game in the life of a Gregori baby. Happiness is only ever found within.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squish!</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-01-squish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-09-01-squish/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cxxv9r/squish/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry for breaking my streak everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m on beta software and it totally shit the bed these last couple days. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing my best to hobble along until full release :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is easily squished. In this picture Moise would be around 16, Cobian 15, and Tzipora about 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise has lost a lot of weight and has been blessed with a hefty frame befitting his temperament. Tzipora &amp;rsquo;s tastes in clothes are specific and mostly unchanging, except for a brief phase a few years after her arrival where she started poaching neckties for her own use. Cobian is conscious of and struggles with the fact that she is not particularly photogenic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Moise</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-25-introducing-moise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-25-introducing-moise/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cv3w1h/introducing_moise/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moise was a fat kid who went to another school. Zelda only knew him from the tram, where he carried a criminal stigma because of his rumoured gang affiliations. He was a second-generation Vekllei boy of immigrant Greek heritage. There were a few ethnic gangs in his area, and most immigrant boys that didn’t do well in school quickly found other causes to fight for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zelda quickly antagonised the boy by offering him to her own bullies. She would point out his weight and he’d point out her clumsy Vekllei language skills and apparent lack of intelligence commonly attributed to foreigners, and so the arms race began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullying did not come naturally to either of them, since they were on the receiving end most of the time and were not particularly manipulative. She would tell Moise he stunk, he would say she was skeletal and unattractive, and they’d seethe about each other that evening. She would make fun of him for eating a chocolate on the tram, and he stole a hairclip and wouldn’t give it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day she was walking behind him after alighting the tram and had set to whacking him with her bookbag, demanding the return of her red pencil. She kept pushing him. In a fit of anger he slammed her against a garage door repeatedly, where her head bounced against the corrugated steel and nearly knocked her out. He left her incapacitated on the pavement, and fled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He buzzed her apartment the following evening after school, seeking to apologise. She weighed her own crimes against his attack, using unique Zelda metrics that gauged physical and emotional violence somewhat improportionately. She accepted his apology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus began the kind of awkward and unconventional friendship that Zelda seemed to attract. With entrepreneurial zeal she rarely displayed, she struck a deal with Moise — he would teach her to fight, and she would help him lose weight. He did not have much experience talking to girls, which was both revealing and endearing, but it helped that Zelda was socially maladjusted and not particularly girlish. On weekends he would take her to the nearest park, they’d lay out a blanket, remove their shoes, and he’d show her how to use a bigger opponent’s weight against them. During the week, she’d meet him at the tram station and they’d go for long walks until he was red and puffing. Zelda liked making food, which seemed to be the one thing she was good at, and soon after began preparing his school lunches, which she’d pass surreptitiously on the morning tram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although they grew close, they both recognised her condition would make any romantic relationship inappropriate and so they remained each other’s quiet soulmates as he went on to film school and married. Moise’s wife, an incredibly patient woman of enormous spiritual strength, would soon learn to tolerate Zelda’s presence at their life occasions. Although Zelda would often think about what might have been if she’d only been normal, they remained close for the rest of his life and she would remain a close family member and guardian of his children for decades after his passing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Teeth Regents</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cudfnv/the_teeth_regents/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From the notebook of Tzipora:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total hedonism across a thousand generations produced the creature known as the ‘tooth regent’, who was a human by technicality but was built genetically only for consuming. His name was Arhen CIII, and where his ancestors had mouths, he had a thousand teeth that sat in messy rows to the back of his throat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three times a day his mouth had to be washed by palace maidens, and excess teeth brushed off. At night, as he slept, the teeth would grow back and occasionally sprout from his cheeks and chin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was one of the most powerful men in all of Zen, the land of gem deserts and magic, and tales of his brutality echoed among the large cities of the subcontinent. His jaws were mounted in his face like hunting traps, and upon bad news he would order the messenger’s hand to be placed in his mouth. That would clamp shut, the poor soul would scream, and minced meat would be spat out by the regent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a man built for consumption, luxury became lust. Like his father and his father’s father, he quickly became the richest oligarch of the Zo peninsula, acquiring old magic, artefacts, estates and fine foods like a glutton piles supper on a plate. It was not possession that motivated him, but acquisition and consumption, destroying hedonistically objects that might lift a thousand from poverty or heal the sick. The simple biological impulses of a human were so primitive compared to Arhen, who satisfied his genetics with an insatiable lust for growth and purchase. Over and over, the cycle would continue…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways, he was on his way to becoming a Palace God, in which the essence of his family dynasty was being rewritten to a higher place of purpose. But where the Palace Gods derive their powers from superstition and traditions, the Arhen bloodline cultivate godhood through industry and commodity subsumption of the orgasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arhen’s greed, or rather, his purpose, was only satisfied by the acquisition and consumption of one invaluable product — himself. He mortgaged his soul into his estate, through the aid of a spirit-banker, and set to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maidens recall hearing only snorts and ecstatic screeches from his room for days. It was not uncommon for the regent to snort — his airways were severely deformed by his posthumanism — but it soon seemed to replace his loud breathing altogether, as though he were talking to himself in pig. This went on for a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, on the eve of the new Zen calendar, his favourite maiden dared enter. She was called Zamen, and being a strong-willed woman, had attracted some level of respect from the otherwise inhuman Ahren. She found the bedroom empty, except for a pair of fine shoes and a small pile of teeth. It was suddenly clear to her what had happened — finally, the prince had completed his cycle and consumed &lt;em&gt;himself&lt;/em&gt;. His father had cycled out the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That day ushered in the regency of Ahren CIV, and the cycle of consumption would begin anew.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zelda, the Vigilant</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-vigilante/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-vigilante/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cu8kvf/zelda_the_vigilant/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should start work on the graphic novel&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At peace, in dark</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-21-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-21-peace/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ct1wex/at_peace_in_dark/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zelda liked to sleep beside someone, which made her feel safe and loved, but she never had many friends and she hadn’t a mother to share a bed with. And, despite her enthusiasm, she was not very easy to sleep beside. She was prone to jerking movements and night terrors, and alternated between pushing her partner to the periphery and then clutching them in comfort. Like so much of who she was, she was caught between contradictory aesthetics and ideas — at home she might sleep in days-old clothes or underwear, but at Cobian’s house she wore a neat nightdress that emphasised her simple middle-class tastes. Poverty and nouveau riche, rude and sweet, boyish and cute. Her eternal schisms were put aside in sleep, where only the lithe ghost of her childhood remained, breathing quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puffin Logic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-18-puffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2019-08-18-puffin/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cruh4n/puffin_logic/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m like that Ben Folds song about escaping your redneck past but instead of redneck it&amp;rsquo;s anime. who stands like this???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/B1SRoV6D3_w/&#34;&gt;Time-lapse here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>