<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>maya</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/maya/</link>
	<description>Recent content in maya </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/maya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/chapel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/chapel/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,
For the people hear us singing, &ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&rdquo;
As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &ndash;
For they are women&rsquo;s children and we mother them again.
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &ndash;]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/gov.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p>As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,<br>
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray<br>
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,<br>
For the people hear us singing, &ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &ndash;<br>
For they are women&rsquo;s children and we mother them again.<br>
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &ndash;<br>
Hearts starve as well as bodies: Give us Bread, but give us Roses.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Vekllei people have a right to organise in their work. This principle is expressed in the structure of the economy, in which cooperative enterprises form company ballots that go on to inform commercial and industrial practice. Collections of individual trade unions may form bureaus, massive monopolies of organised workplaces cooperating and competing under the bizarre structure of the Vekllei moneyless economy. These are expressions of a mobilised democratic workforce which sustain the country in their self-interest, and are a defining characteristic of the Floral Period.</p>
<p>Organisation also exists outside the workplace. Their negotiations occur with the municipal and state authorities, and are a common means by which groups of people express their grievances and strengthen each other. The most well-known of these are Vekllei’s Chapel system — the unionisation of local women.</p>
<p>Chapels are localised by community. Tzipora was at first very sceptical of the Chapels, which had offered her membership upon her arrival in Vekllei. You have to understand, Tzipora was in a crisis of inferiority at this time, and considered the ingratitude of the ungovernable female organisers to be naïve and entitled. She was convinced otherwise by Ayn, who was a moderate and carefully-spoken person.</p>
<p>“You want to integrate in Vekllei, don’t you?” She asked Tzipora. “This is what integration looks like; the Chapels are an expression of our democracy. A means of support and celebration; to have people know and care for you. There is no political commitment.”</p>
<p>Tzipora found Chapel meetings to be friendly and informal, characterised by shared meals and conversations of joys and grievances. Local Chapel № 23 was a social club of individuals made strong by their trust in each other. Tzipora sat silently at the end of the Chapel hall, an old concrete building with a flat roof built after the war. It had the appearance of a midcentury church. She ate her bread and sausage with her fingers and listened to the women talk amongst themselves. Children ran around, playing chasings. It was not like any place she’d been before.</p>
<p><em>Well-wishes to all this International Women’s Day</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meta Moments</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/meta/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/meta/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This image was a gift to my friend Bez. Thank you Bez. Occasionally I&rsquo;ll join an &ldquo;art trade&rdquo; to change things up and break the repetition of working in one universe with one set of characters. Bez is a friend of mine and a talented artist, and so for Christmas we decided to produce secret works involving characters and places we don&rsquo;t usually draw. There&rsquo;s nothing more exciting as an artist than seeing through new eyes &ndash; that&rsquo;s the magic of having someone illustrate your people and places.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/valin.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>This image</strong> was a gift to my friend Bez. Thank you Bez.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Occasionally I&rsquo;ll join an &ldquo;art trade&rdquo;</strong> to change things up and break the repetition of working in one universe with one set of characters. Bez is a friend of mine and a talented artist, and so for Christmas we decided to produce secret works involving characters and places we don&rsquo;t usually draw. There&rsquo;s nothing more exciting as an artist than seeing through new eyes &ndash; that&rsquo;s the magic of having someone illustrate your people and places.</p>
<p>My piece, finished today three days after Christmas, depicts the Vekllei crew encountering Valin and her aphis, a sort of canine-feline hybrid creature. The setting is based on photographs I took of where I grew up, amidst temperate rainforest on my property. Bez&rsquo;s contribution is below. I love it.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/fanart/bez-1.jpg" alt="img"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>

<blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">I love the composition of it, it&rsquo;s very optimistic. Very cute.</div>
</blockquote>
</p>
<p>I like the attention to detail on Tzipora and the golden wattle on the right. Vekllei has wattle as canon &ndash; it doesn&rsquo;t make much sense, but who cares? It&rsquo;s too lovely to exclude from utopia. Bez also shared a preliminary sketch with me, seen below.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/fanart/bez-2.png" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>

<blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Bonus Tzipora with a bird. Bez likes birds.</div>
</blockquote>
</p>
<p>Thank you Bez &ndash; let&rsquo;s do it again sometime!</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
