<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>states on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/states/</link>
	<description>Recent content in states on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/states/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Stories from the Horizon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/horizon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/horizon/</guid>
	  <description> Welcome to Stories from the Horizon, Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s journey through Vekllei. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Timeline</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/timeline/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/timeline/</guid>
	  <description>This timeline is a useful curated reference of Atlantic history, but is not comprehensive. It is continuously evolving with this site. Pre-War Timeline # 6000BC Earliest evidence of human settlement 1230BC Irish settlers establish fishing communities on south coast 1100BC Scandinavians settle in Smoke Cove, aka Oslola 600BC Vekllei is politically and culturally isolated from Europe 400BC Vekllei is using Vekllei logographs
Upen is being practiced 500BC Beginning of Vekllei Common Period 200 Beginning of Vekllei Early Period 230 Language reforms are initiated by Queen Souisviasn 700 Beginning of Vekllei Middle Period</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/draft.vekllei/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/draft.vekllei/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # Welcome to Vekllei. This article introduces the essential setting of this website &amp;ndash; the Commonwealth of Vekllei. Welcome to the epilogue of the &amp;ldquo;epoch of rest.&amp;rdquo; Vekllei is best conceptualised as a commonwealth of islands across the Atlantic Ocean. This commonwealth, the fourth in a series, consists of many island republics that are connected by politics and prosperity, not geography or race. These islands range in size from the Selvas Islands of 160 people to the island of Vekllei, of 16 million.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei Vekllei is a superstate in the Atlantic Ocean that demonstrates the &amp;ldquo;social dream&amp;rdquo; of its author, Hobart. Set ostensibly in Iceland, the history and geography of Vekllei is radically different from our own. It is also the home of all of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s major characters. Overview # The Commonwealth of Vekllei, commonly Vekllei or the 4th Commonwealth, is a supranational commonwealth of constituent countries1 bound closely together by shared geographic and political features.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>