<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sketch on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/sketch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sketch on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/sketch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carry me! &gt;:(</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora and Cobian. They have not been friends for very long but they like each other a lot. Tzipora weighs nearly 10kg less than her friend, so she gets piggy backs more often.
By me! @melon.kony or r/vekllei on reddit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shōwa memories</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  new r/worldbuilding post soon, just filling in my garbage upload schedule with generic anime and shōwa nostalgia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer sex-ed</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Porno is available over-the-counter at most book stores. Some industry associations attempt to limit availability to minors but generally it&amp;rsquo;s at the discretion of the shopkeeper. Often, shame and embarassment are more powerful tools than legislation in Vekllei.
Generally it&amp;rsquo;s pretty traditional stuff supported by columns and fiction, although it varies between pornographers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of &#34;Human Decay&#34;</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Talking about utopia in landscape is easy — Vekllei is a glittering midcentury paradise that fosters human life as a wonderful dream.
Talking about utopia in character is much harder. How can you find utopia in flawed and sometimes unattractive human beings? By what metric is the vague, intuitive values of a utopia measured against a living person?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Much love to all of you</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Raid</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-25-air-raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-25-air-raid/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She loved helping out. It was important to her, as an ageless girl of ultimately transient relationships, to be able to establish for herself a family wherever she lived. So within a few years of her arrival in Vekllei, she put time in as a warden for her apartment block and undertook the medical training that went with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Long Moment</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-21-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-21-moment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The whole world gives way to a moment of silence. The other seasons are filled with noise and marrow, jerking and twisting with the pace of the clock. But a moment lasts forever — and wintertime is one long moment.
Although the uniforms got heavier and the commutes longer, Zelda would always like the wintertime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Old for Sleepovers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Even for those ageless kids, there’s a time when the charade of childhood comes to a head and begs a certain uncomfortable question: at what point does the whole thing — of immaturity, of carelessness, of sleepovers — start looking like two old women posturing around youth, indulging in a sick genetic perversion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A story of community policing and sweet militia</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-03-militia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-03-militia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  As part of sundress municipalism, Vekllei’s villages and townships are mostly self-sufficient and self-regulating. Although a walk in the capital will take you past colossal apartment blocks and cinemas, libraries and schools of great magnificence, you are really looking at a hundred different communities going about personal business at their leisure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look...!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-02-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-02-look/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Look at it!
The bastard ate the lettuce! There&amp;rsquo;s a hole in the wire!
He&amp;rsquo;s cute but he&amp;rsquo;s a bastard!
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing a train for over two weeks now and I needed to draw something alive before I shinkansenned myself. This only took an hour or two but I&amp;rsquo;m not drawing enough and it feels like I&amp;rsquo;m running out of time to get good at drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metro Days</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-11-metro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-11-metro/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Trains</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-05-rural-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-05-rural-trains/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  I caught a train out of Tokyo as far as it would go, and I ended up on a little platform in the mountains. Nice place.
Vekllei has a lot of mountains and a lot of trains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Summer Everyone</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-05-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-05-summer/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Down Under it&amp;rsquo;s coming around summer, and things are heating up. It&amp;rsquo;s not my fault Yanks broke the northern hemisphere and made the weather go wrong.
Vekllei gets warm in the summer, reaching heights of 30C occasionally. For a variety of reasons. A city of gardens and flowerbeds (the most flowers per capita in the world, actually), apartment dwellers take turns watering their local gardens and clearing weeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>real sadboi posting hours</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-29-sadboi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-29-sadboi/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Coming up on 2am here in East Australia. Had a rough day at work. Feeling pretty isolated and my other job starts in a few hours. I don’t know if it’s intrusive thoughts from OCD or just something everyone has, but four or five times a day I’ll have some sort of regret pop right into my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>summer nerds reading comix</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-29-nerds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-29-nerds/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>big mood right now</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-28-mood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-28-mood/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora&#39;s Portrait</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-08-portrait/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-08-portrait/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Practising colours. It&amp;rsquo;s always been my weakness. While you&amp;rsquo;re here, if you have any questions about Tzipora or want to chat, let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
