<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Letter on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letter on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Letter | November 2020</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/2020/nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/2020/nov/</guid>
      <description>Nov. Update for Patrons -mail  EDITOR  Letters  Hello my lovelies,
Just a short update on where I’m at as we pass mid-month. I’ve pushed a couple of things back a day or two to finish a very cool/special post. You’ll see it on the reddit soon — it’ll be a really nice painting, and nothing like I’ve ever done before. Before the weekend.
I was hesitant to promise a timeframe for the comic draft, and for good reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter | December 2020</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/2020/dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/2020/dec/</guid>
      <description>Dec. Update for Patrons -mail  EDITOR  Letters  Hello beloved patrons,
This is your monthly update for the Petticoat Project.
There’s a  new post up on the subreddit and a  new article up on the website — a big one, about Vekllei, although it’s missing a history and culture section. Those are coming soon.
I won’t be mucking around on the website forever — trust me, I have no intention of abandoning my traditional post format for dry wiki articles — but it makes good infrastructure, and good infrastructure allows for growth and it also helps support new projects, like the comic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter | February 2021</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/2021/feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/2021/feb/</guid>
      <description>Feb. Update for Patrons -mail  EDITOR  Letters  Hello beloved Patrons,
It’s been a little while. I’ve called this meeting late because I’ve been working late. Let’s run this through quick, and we can all get back to bed.
 You guys voted! Looks like our next themed ‘week’ (maybe fortnight) is Ocean Week. Great choice, lots of cool concepts coming. Mail Week (fortnight) has been a lot of fun, but it’s almost done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter | January 2021</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/2021/jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/editor/2021/jan/</guid>
      <description>Jan. Update for Patrons -mail  EDITOR  Letters  Hello beloved patrons,
The first chapter of the comic is sketched. You will see it on Monday (about two days from this message). It won&amp;rsquo;t be inked but it&amp;rsquo;ll give you a very good idea of what the final chapter will look like at the end of the month. I look forward to reading your feedback, since it&amp;rsquo;s my first try at this sort of thing (well, minus the dozens of concepts trashed over the previous few months).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
