<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>author</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/author/</link>
	<description>Recent content in author </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Five Years</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/five-years/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/five-years/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora is communicating the birthday rune in Upotenne, a warding sigil of good luck. Today, the subreddit is five years old. A better anniversary for this project would have been July 1st 2022 &ndash; the date of my first reddit post &ndash; but I missed that anniversary completely. This post is a late 5 year celebration of Vekllei. Next year I&rsquo;ll celebrate with you properly on International Tzipora Day (July 1st 2023, write it down).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/five.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">Tzipora is communicating the birthday rune in <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#upotenne">Upotenne</a>, a warding sigil of good luck.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Today, the subreddit is five years old.</strong> A better anniversary for this project would have been July 1st 2022 &ndash; the date of my <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/6kgbkb/tzipora_has_her_photo_taken_at_youth_meet_2063/">first reddit post</a> &ndash; but I missed that anniversary completely. This post is a late 5 year celebration of Vekllei. Next year I&rsquo;ll celebrate with you properly on <em>International Tzipora Day</em> (July 1st 2023, write it down).</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text"><p>Some statistics:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Number of Vekllei stories:</strong> <strong>322</strong></li>
<li><strong>First Vekllei post:</strong> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/6kgbkb/tzipora_has_her_photo_taken_at_youth_meet_2063/">Tzipora has her photo taken at Youth Meet 2063</a> (July 1, 2017 )</li>
<li><strong>First post on r/vekllei:</strong> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cr65zu/the_people_of_veklleis_railway_plus_dog/">The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</a> (August 16, 2019)</li>
<li><strong>Most upvoted post:</strong> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/if77nc/absolute_quiet/">Absolute Quiet</a> (August 23, 2020)</li>
<li><strong>Most recent post:</strong> this one</li>
</ul>
<p>Read them here: <a href="/stories/">www.millmint.net/stories</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>I write about what Vekllei means to me sometimes, and I usually regret it. Any time I insert myself into the project I regret it. Although Vekllei is deeply personal to me, I don&rsquo;t belong anywhere near it and I&rsquo;m learning to keep my mouth shut and let the work speak for itself. In the spirit of &lsquo;killing the author&rsquo; (I believe that&rsquo;s the phrase), I&rsquo;ve collected some notes in the tradition of resolutions.</p>
<p>Some notes:</p>
<ol>
<li>I am better at drawing than I was five years ago. That&rsquo;s not very impressive &ndash; more important is that I&rsquo;m better than I was a year ago. It&rsquo;s easy to look at my 2017 scribbles and smile at the silly, naive people I made. It&rsquo;s much harder to feel that way about your own work a year ago. I should be proud; that&rsquo;s a testament to the fact I&rsquo;ve become a better illustrator this year.</li>
<li>Does Vekllei feel the same as it used to? It was sillier back then; some people might prefer that. I think about that sometimes, but I am convinced that things are evolving as they should. Illustration is the demonstration of an intuition deep within me, and it is still just as authentic as it was in 2017. I think Vekllei is more serious and grounded in part because I am five years older, and boys do a lot of growing between 19 and 24. I love my characters more than ever; Tzipora is a more compelling, dignified and complete person than she was back then. It&rsquo;s easy to become nostalgic about the lightness of being a beginner.</li>
<li>In another five years, I&rsquo;d like to make my living through this work. This is an existential fear of mine &ndash; the fear of every artist &ndash; but I have the heady confidence of a creative, so I trust that things will work themselves out, so long as I work hard and consider how this project might work as a product people pay for (the comic, for example). I don&rsquo;t need to make much money, because I don&rsquo;t spend much money. I&rsquo;ve paused the Patreon until the first chapter of the comic comes out, so hopefully that will resume soon.</li>
</ol>
<p>Some other notes:</p>
<ul>
<li>I think I am getting close to a basic, commercial standard of art. That&rsquo;s exciting, as an illustrator &ndash; it&rsquo;s basically technical work. If I was a carpenter, I&rsquo;d be saying I&rsquo;m close to making a table people would pay for. Drawings are turning out how I imagine them. If I keep working hard on <em>Stories of the Horizon</em>, I should see my landscapes improve quickly.</li>
<li>I am working on a Vekllei comic. The whole thing has been a shemozzle; I&rsquo;ve been &lsquo;working&rsquo; on a comic for three years now. I announced it much too early, without realising how unprepared I was to work in that type of illustration. I&rsquo;m learning to shut my mouth &ndash; I&rsquo;m not promising a release date now. But I am getting better, and it is a critical part of this project. If it took me a decade, I&rsquo;d still be working on it.</li>
<li>Although any online community has its stresses, I have made several close friends through the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/dCE6vSU">Vekllei Discord</a>, some of whom I&rsquo;ve now met in real life. Thank you always for your attention and support, it means everything to my confidence in my work.</li>
</ul>
<p>Finally, thank you for reading. Some of you have been here for years &ndash; some of you have only been here for a few hours, after I spammed my shit to some other subs (sorry, that&rsquo;s just how the game works on reddit). Thank you sincerely for all your comments and affection over the years. This is a small community but it is tremendously insightful and well-meaning, and seeing you enjoy my work makes my day. I&rsquo;d probably still be working on Vekllei without an audience &ndash; but it wouldn&rsquo;t be nearly as much fun. It really does mean a lot.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
<p>Sincerely yours,</p>
<p>Hobart</p>
<p>(and tzipora)</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Off Again</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/uk/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/uk/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The last time I made one of these, it was January 2020. When I got back, the news was just starting to talk about a new disease outbreak in China.
It is striking to me that the shitty drawing attached to that post was the last time I went overseas. On an abstract level I can understand it&rsquo;s been two years &ndash; but wow, that drawing puts things in perspective. And since that post, I&rsquo;ve been stuck in my house in Hobart, occasionally visiting other parts of my beautiful island state of Tasmania.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/uk.jpg"/> <p>The <a href="/stories/japan/">last time I made one of these</a>, it was January 2020. When I got back, the news was just starting to talk about a new disease outbreak in China.</p>
<p>It is striking to me that the shitty drawing attached to that post was the last time I went overseas. On an abstract level I can understand it&rsquo;s been two years &ndash; but wow, that drawing puts things in perspective. And since that post, I&rsquo;ve been stuck in my house in Hobart, occasionally visiting other parts of my beautiful island state of Tasmania. That&rsquo;s a long time in the history of this project, and a long time for someone who found inspiration to draw from travelling.</p>
<p>Grounded no more. I am currently in Oxford in the U.K., and will be somewhere else soon. I&rsquo;ll let you know where I&rsquo;m going next.</p>
<p><em>Stories from the Horizon</em> is proceeding as normal, but I&rsquo;m spending a bit more time creating new styles of architecture inspired by my surrounds. Vekllei is always evolving, and it&rsquo;s evolving especially fast right now. When I&rsquo;ve left the U.K. in a few days, I&rsquo;ll write an article about my experience with pictures attached to the <a href="/news/blog/">millmint.net blog</a>.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m having such a great time and learning so much.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>Hobart</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Scouts</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/puffin/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/puffin/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Scouts de Vous Seispri Votaisre (lit. Scouts Interior Spirit Corps) is a corps of the Commonwealth Army, modelled after the worldwide scouting association. This unusual intersection &ndash; of a noncombatant youth organisation and the armed forces &ndash; is typical in Vekllei, where many aspects of the military serve social roles. For example, the Vekllei Fire Service and the Royal Mail are both corps of the Commonwealth Army. To this end, the Scouts Corps (better known as Puffin Scouts overseas) has different traditions depending on which brigade it belongs to.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/puffin.jpg"/> <p>The <em>Scouts de Vous Seispri Votaisre</em> (lit. Scouts Interior Spirit Corps) is a corps of the Commonwealth Army, modelled after the worldwide scouting association. This unusual intersection &ndash; of a noncombatant youth organisation and the armed forces &ndash; is typical in Vekllei, where many aspects of the military serve social roles. For example, the Vekllei Fire Service and the <a href="/mail/">Royal Mail</a> are both corps of the Commonwealth Army. To this end, the Scouts Corps (better known as <em>Puffin Scouts</em> overseas) has different traditions depending on which brigade it belongs to. The detached Cadet Brigades of the 1st and 2nd Scouting Divisions are youth training organisations for the armed forces, designed to prepare youths for military service. The rest of the brigades, numbering some 12 in total across 2 Divisions (or some 1,460 neighbourhood troops) are decidedly noncombatant, and exist to provide community and training in useful skills for Vekllei&rsquo;s youth.</p>
<p>Tzipora naturally belongs to <em>Scouts de Seispri</em>, her local troop. As a military branch, the Scouts follow identical organisational conventions, and so Tzipora has &rsquo;enlisted&rsquo; alongside other servicemen in the Commonwealth Army:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Civici Tzipora Desmoisnes, 77th Troop, 7th <em>Lola</em> District, 1st <em>Vekllei</em> Scouts Brigade of the 1st Scouts Division</p>
</blockquote>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/mastheads/crests/scouts.png" alt="crest"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>

<blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">The crest of the Scouts Interior Spirit Corps.</div>
</blockquote>
</p>
<p>It functions as a social club &ndash; many of her schoolmates are in it &ndash; and also provides an opportunity to learn things outside of the school curriculum. Survival skills and camping, agriculture, hunting and weapons handling, driving, and amateur radio operation are common excursions. Some troops have particular reputations, and are highly desirable &ndash; 588th Troop of the 3rd Brigade has a legendary reputation in photo-electrics and computer phreaking. The 77th is a little more local in ambition, and Tzipora spends most of her time teaching the others to cook and gardening around Seispri.</p>
<p>Instead of merit badges, scouts earn honours that are stitched to a <a href="/stories/crown/#the-gi">gi</a>. Significant honours &ndash; usually success in national competitions or academic awards &ndash; can also be transferred to troop honours, in the fashion of battle honours for combat army corps. The Scouts uniform has many coded features of army dress uniforms, including its Sam Browne belt (sloped left for Civici, right for officers), epaulettes with honours, cloth aiguillette, and troop patches. Tzipora doesn&rsquo;t wear all that every Thursday obviously &ndash; but it matters at the Games, when her honours are on display and she&rsquo;s trying to show those dicks in the 76th they&rsquo;re dealing with a better class of scout.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Story Trailer</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/trailer/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/trailer/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ No, I&rsquo;m not making an low-budget 1980s television anime (yet). Yes, I&rsquo;d like to. Click here to watch with sound. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="/video/trailer.mp4"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">No, I&rsquo;m not making an low-budget 1980s television anime (yet). Yes, I&rsquo;d like to. <a href="/video/trailer.mp4/">Click here to watch with sound.</a></div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Stories from the Horizon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/horizon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/horizon/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[A New Format for Stories from Vekllei # Vekllei has one hundred boroughs that are usually characterised as the foundation of the Vekllei city-state. Some, like Bakur, have only a few thousand people in them. Others, like the Great Coast, have over a million.
I&rsquo;ve been working on this project for a while now, about five years counting backwards, and in that time what Vekllei means to me has matured.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/stories.jpg"/> <h2 id="a-new-format-for-stories-from-vekllei">
  A New Format for Stories from Vekllei
  <a class="anchor" href="#a-new-format-for-stories-from-vekllei">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Vekllei has <a href="/boroughs/">one hundred boroughs</a> that are usually characterised as the foundation of the Vekllei city-state. Some, like Bakur, have only a few thousand people in them. Others, like the Great Coast, have over a million.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been working on this project for a while now, about five years counting backwards, and in that time what Vekllei means to me has matured. In some ways, things have calcified &ndash; a gift and a curse &ndash; but it&rsquo;s also true that the project is more complicated now than it ever was. I think it&rsquo;s more sophisticated, and it reflects a more complete person.</p>
<p>For a long time now, Vekllei has existed first as a series of pictures with stories attached &ndash; this very format you&rsquo;re reading now, which number about 315 posts since 2017. They&rsquo;re all on this site, check them out. Today, I&rsquo;m announcing <em>Stories from the Horizon</em>, a new approach to this format that will depict Vekllei&rsquo;s 100 boroughs in a series of 100 landscape pictures, woven together as a great journey featuring Tzipora.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In 2066, Tzipora is drifting between moments. Since high school, nothing has really worked out the way she&rsquo;d hoped &ndash; not university, not work, and not love. She is waiting for the shape of her life to make sense. The past seems further away and more relevant than ever before, and her future is uncertain. Rather than confront these things directly, she meets the universe on her terms, and starts a journey in the great Vekllei tradition &ndash; the <em>Visa Con</em>, or Private Pilgrimage. The Visa Con is a winding path throughout the island of Vekllei, reaching all corners of its great Atlantic landscapes. It is a testament to the goodness of living in this world.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Stories from the Horizon</em> isn&rsquo;t the upcoming &lsquo;Vekllei comic,&rsquo; but it will help me create it. The comic is a big deal for me, and it&rsquo;s forced me to rethink many aspects of how I depict Vekllei. Five years since the first Vekllei post, I&rsquo;m replacing the burden of an established format with the lightness of being a beginner again. These stories will resemble the posts you&rsquo;re familiar with, but will be more considerate in how they depict landscape and architecture in Vekllei, and will altogether produce a really important album of Vekllei landscapes that I can draw on for future projects. You&rsquo;ll notice some of my online presence changing to reflect this &ndash; new banners for social media and that sort of thing. Who knows, maybe <em>Stories from the Horizon</em> could be turned into a little picture-book when it&rsquo;s done.</p>
<p>It won&rsquo;t be fast &ndash; pictures will (probably) come out at the same pace as they do now (I want to make them faster, I really do, I&rsquo;m always trying). It won&rsquo;t be consistent &ndash; I&rsquo;ll still want to do other concepts occasionally. And I can&rsquo;t guarantee they&rsquo;ll all be good. But I want to enjoy doing something new, from a new perspective and spirit, and I hope you&rsquo;ll enjoy it too.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always loved journeys, so let&rsquo;s see where this takes us.</p>
<p>&ndash; Hobart</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Changes to the Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/reading/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/reading/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This post announced changes made for patrons of Vekllei. Read and discuss the changes made in this post on Patreon here. Hello everyone,
Hobart here, creator of this whole thing. For a couple years now I&rsquo;ve maintained a small Patreon for those interested in supporting my work. Like most Patreons, this has operated monthly.
From now on, patrons will only be charged on the release of a comic chapter.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/sketches/reading.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>This post</strong> announced changes made for patrons of Vekllei. Read and discuss the changes made in this post on Patreon <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/changes-to-61071775">here</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Hello everyone,</p>
<p>Hobart here, creator of this whole thing. For a couple years now I&rsquo;ve maintained a small <a href="https://www.patreon.com/vekllei">Patreon</a> for those interested in supporting my work. Like most Patreons, this has operated monthly.</p>
<p>From now on, <strong>patrons will only be charged on the release of a comic chapter</strong>. This could be once a month, but will more likely be a bit longer. This means a little less money for me, but also less anxiety about producing enough public work to earn the money pledged to me. It seems more fair, and the comic will be worth it.</p>
<p>So what will change? For patrons, <strong>nothing will change except that you will be charged less frequently</strong>. You will continue to recieve precisely the same benefits I&rsquo;ve promised, including future merch and roles on the Vekllei Discord.</p>
<p><strong>I will continue to produce standalone posts,</strong> much as I always have &ndash; but instead of battling a creeping anxiety of losing patrons if I don&rsquo;t meet a post quota, I&rsquo;ll be working more creatively and flexibly according to the needs of the comic. My work will be better for it, I reckon.</p>
<p><strong>In summary:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Supporters will now be charged on the release of each chapter of the comic, instead of monthly.</li>
<li>Merch and Discord rewards will be the same.</li>
<li>You won&rsquo;t pay as frequently and will get more for your money as chapters come out.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;d like to support me in other ways, maybe buy a postcard when the MillMint Shop launches!</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have any questions, just leave a comment below and I&rsquo;ll help you out.</p>
<p>Thanks always,</p>
<p>Hobart/MelonKony</p>
<p><a href="https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU">Discuss on the Vekllei Discord</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>100 Days of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/showa/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/showa/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Hello everyone,
This is 2022, Year of Vekllei.
For the next 100 days I’m going to do something for Vekllei every day. These &lsquo;somethings&rsquo; could be
Posts you see, exploring Vekllei Articles on the website, including upcoming pages on Government and new character pages. Inking of comic pages &ndash; leading up to a release soon. It&rsquo;s been a long time coming but it&rsquo;ll be worth it. New illustrations for use in merchandise(!]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/showa.jpg"/> <p>Hello everyone,</p>
<p>This is 2022, Year of Vekllei.</p>
<p>For the next 100 days I’m going to do something for Vekllei every day. These &lsquo;somethings&rsquo; could be</p>
<ul>
<li>Posts you see, exploring Vekllei</li>
<li>Articles on <a href="https://millmint.net">the website</a>, including upcoming pages on Government and new character pages.</li>
<li>Inking of comic pages &ndash; leading up to a release soon. It&rsquo;s been a long time coming but it&rsquo;ll be worth it.</li>
<li>New illustrations for use in merchandise(!)</li>
<li>Working on new website features or the upcoming MillMint shop</li>
</ul>
<p>2021 was a pretty bad year. I won’t go on about it much because it’s not very interesting and it’s not the point of my writing this. Let&rsquo;s only hope suffering makes good art!</p>
<p>This last year, I haven&rsquo;t finished what I&rsquo;ve wanted to finish, and it&rsquo;s caused some anxiety for me for months now. This is my New Year&rsquo;s resolution to you all, including my <a href="https://www.patreon.com/vekllei">beloved patrons</a>, who I thank sincerely for sticking with me through a really inconsistent creative period.</p>
<p>New Year&rsquo;s resolutions are kind of corny, and they don&rsquo;t work out for everyone. So don&rsquo;t think of this as a resolution as such &ndash; 2022 is a nice even number, and it&rsquo;s a good time, arbitrary as any other, for a change in the winds.</p>
<p>My goal is to have something to show every other day or so. I&rsquo;ve got a long list of ideas I&rsquo;m going to work through. Hopefully this will provoke a change in behaviour from me.</p>
<p>Why not join me? Pick up a pencil and I&rsquo;ll draw with you. You can come say hi at the <a href="https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU">Vekllei Discord server</a> and catch me drawing sometime.</p>
<p>Thanks again. I&rsquo;m only at the start of the journey here. But this community is where it begins.</p>
<p>Warm regards,</p>
<p>Hobart/MelonKony</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ Welcome to 2022, year of Vekllei. Here&rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love. Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/newyear2022.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>Welcome to 2022,</strong> year of Vekllei. Here&rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meta Moments</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/meta/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/meta/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This image was a gift to my friend Bez. Thank you Bez. Occasionally I&rsquo;ll join an &ldquo;art trade&rdquo; to change things up and break the repetition of working in one universe with one set of characters. Bez is a friend of mine and a talented artist, and so for Christmas we decided to produce secret works involving characters and places we don&rsquo;t usually draw. There&rsquo;s nothing more exciting as an artist than seeing through new eyes &ndash; that&rsquo;s the magic of having someone illustrate your people and places.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/valin.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>This image</strong> was a gift to my friend Bez. Thank you Bez.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Occasionally I&rsquo;ll join an &ldquo;art trade&rdquo;</strong> to change things up and break the repetition of working in one universe with one set of characters. Bez is a friend of mine and a talented artist, and so for Christmas we decided to produce secret works involving characters and places we don&rsquo;t usually draw. There&rsquo;s nothing more exciting as an artist than seeing through new eyes &ndash; that&rsquo;s the magic of having someone illustrate your people and places.</p>
<p>My piece, finished today three days after Christmas, depicts the Vekllei crew encountering Valin and her aphis, a sort of canine-feline hybrid creature. The setting is based on photographs I took of where I grew up, amidst temperate rainforest on my property. Bez&rsquo;s contribution is below. I love it.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/fanart/bez-1.jpg" alt="img"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>

<blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">I love the composition of it, it&rsquo;s very optimistic. Very cute.</div>
</blockquote>
</p>
<p>I like the attention to detail on Tzipora and the golden wattle on the right. Vekllei has wattle as canon &ndash; it doesn&rsquo;t make much sense, but who cares? It&rsquo;s too lovely to exclude from utopia. Bez also shared a preliminary sketch with me, seen below.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/fanart/bez-2.png" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>

<blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">Bonus Tzipora with a bird. Bez likes birds.</div>
</blockquote>
</p>
<p>Thank you Bez &ndash; let&rsquo;s do it again sometime!</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Something New is on The Horizon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/something-new/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/something-new/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Thanks for a great June. We&rsquo;ve had a lot of different types of posts this month. About 15 in all — that&rsquo;s one every two days! Not bad! I could do with some sleep.
Something very special is approaching in July. I&rsquo;m very excited to share it with you all — so are Tzipora and Cobian. A new chapter in Vekllei is fast approaching.
See you soon.
Much love,
Hobart // MelonKony]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/june.jpg"/> <p><strong>Thanks for a great June</strong>. We&rsquo;ve had a lot of different types of posts this month. About 15 in all — that&rsquo;s one every two days! Not bad! I could do with some sleep.</p>
<p>Something very special is approaching in July. I&rsquo;m very excited to share it with you all — so are Tzipora and Cobian. A new chapter in Vekllei is fast approaching.</p>
<p>See you soon.</p>
<p>Much love,</p>
<p><strong>Hobart</strong> // MelonKony</p>
<p><a href="https://www.patreon.com/vekllei">Join the Patreon</a>.</p>
<p>Be &ldquo;petticoat.&rdquo;</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Utopie ❦ Concrète</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/utopie/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/utopie/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This essay was published on millmint.net. Read it here. I write introspectively about the project sometimes, as a means by which I consider what I&rsquo;m doing and where my unconscious is leading me with this project. I have the instinct of someone who is over-educated and self-obsessed; someone who went to university, fell for the farce of serious media criticism, and failed to see that all media theorists are basically freaks.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/utopie.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>This essay</strong> was published on <a href="https://millmint.net">millmint.net</a>. <a href="https://millmint.net/news/essays/utopie">Read it here</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>I write introspectively about the project sometimes,</strong> as a means by which I consider what I&rsquo;m doing and where my unconscious is leading me with this project. I have the instinct of someone who is over-educated and self-obsessed; someone who went to university, fell for the farce of serious media criticism, and failed to see that all media theorists are basically freaks. And there is a small truth buried in that hyperbole: it does in fact require a certain dysfunction to write books about the study of anime or television. You can become <em>too</em> close to something.</p>
<p><em>Utopie concrète,</em> or &lsquo;concrete utopia,&rsquo; is my phrase for how I work. I saw parallels with the manifesto of <em>musique concrète</em>, as described by Pierre Schaeffer:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Instead of notating musical ideas on paper with the symbols of <em>solfège</em> and entrusting their realisation to well-known instruments, the question was to collect concrete sounds, wherever they came from, and to abstract the musical values they were potentially containing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Utopianism is much the same; it distills the concrete sentiment, concerns, and futures of a time and place and reproduces them in abstract in fiction. In a very straightforward way, my work (Vekllei, so-called) is an abstraction of real people, events, and things.</p>
<p>It also refers to the &ldquo;feeling&rdquo; of Vekllei, in a transcendental fashion. Utopianism is associated with very specific, loaded conceptions of perfection &mdash; cleanliness, symmetry, peacefulness, goodness, and impossibility. Vekllei is not any of these things consistently; it is like the raw concrete used in <em>béton brut</em>, and like raw concrete it discolours, weathers and crumbles in its exposure to reality and the march of time. You can see the formwork and imperfections in its product &mdash; not as a result of sloppy workmanship or carelessness, but because those things are beautiful; utopian in their own right.</p>
<p>At the risk of disfiguring these notes into a manifesto, the principles of <em>utopie concrète</em> might look something like this.</p>
<p>PRINCIPLES OF <strong>UTOPIE CONCRÈTE</strong> ■</p>
<ol>
<li>All things have dignity</li>
<li>All things get dirty</li>
<li>You must love it</li>
</ol>
<p>To explain further:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>All things have dignity</strong>. You must take your &ldquo;raw utopia&rdquo; seriously &mdash; it has to be honest. In this sense, you must always aim to do your best for it. Consider your landscape and give your characters the respect you would anyone. If you dishonour them through sloppy work, you should feel embarrassed. </li>
<li><strong>All things get dirty</strong>. In order to &lsquo;consider your landscape&rsquo; and &lsquo;respect your characters,&rsquo; you must also recognise that these things need to live independently from your control. The activity of your utopia is what makes it alive, and also what makes it imperfect. Recognise the imperfections and celebrate them. </li>
<li><strong>You must love it</strong>. Utopias are very thoughtful and considered, but they can&rsquo;t be intellectual. It must be intuitive &mdash; follow your heart.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>UTOPIE CONCRÈTE</strong> ■ WITH <strong>VEKLLEI</strong> ❦ CHARACTERISTICS</p>
<p>You already have the tools to create your concrete utopia &mdash; you just need to act on it. I have acted, and what has surfaced reveals a great deal about me, how I think and process the world, my anger and prejudices, my hopes and affections, and the pettiest of petty material interests.</p>
<p>Hayao Miyazaki, a great artist I admire deeply, was asked why his films starred heroines. He said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>At first, I thought &ldquo;this is no longer the era of men&hellip;&rdquo; But after ten years, I grew tired of saying that. I just say &ldquo;because I like women.&rdquo; That has more reality.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I mostly draw women, and there is not much good reason for it other than I like women.</p>
<p>I have said previously I&rsquo;m deeply uncomfortable with the conceptual objectification of women, and the shallowness of girl-caricatures. Yet, when asked why my cast of characters are mostly women, I can only say that I like drawing women. That&rsquo;s very revealing of the hypocritical discrepancy between essay rhetoric and my body of work. I try and give my characters dignity, but I also draw women and girls because they might look more interesting in a certain profession, or have better options for their clothes. Where is the dignity in being reproduced for how you appear in a picture? We can&rsquo;t mistake &ldquo;drawing women&rdquo; for &ldquo;representation of women.&rdquo; This is a failing on my part.</p>
<p>But I also think that Tzipora, the most egregious and unusual example of &ldquo;using the appearance of women&rdquo; in my project, is not much of a woman at all. She carries my anger, my obsessiveness, and lives my fantasy of a meaningful life. She is quite explicitly an author surrogate, although with a life of her own. She is also not supposed to be an authentic depiction of the experience of any woman &mdash; she is in fact closer to an anti-woman. She is so tomboyish, obsessive, and neurotic, that it&rsquo;s hard to use her to explore conventional literary interests in &lsquo;womanhood.&rsquo; Thank goodness for that &mdash; it&rsquo;s not my place.</p>
<p>Creating Vekllei is my way of processing the goings-on of the world, and my lived experience day-to-day. In this sense, I prefer the clothes and appearance of women, and so in my utopia I draw women.</p>
<p>This is one of the interesting contradictions of utopianism. It is inherently egoistic, and can always be traced cleanly to the total worldview and personality of its author. But like most fiction, authors are eager to give life to their people and places, and would rather you not glimpse the man behind the curtain. Vekllei is fiction &mdash; Tzipora is a girl, and lives in Vekllei. Vekllei is also a utopia &mdash; Tzipora is me, and lives in my hopes, dreams, and anxieties. The contradiction is muted until authors start acting like the former is not a result of the latter, and that my personal experience does not affect who and what is depicted in Vekllei. This is true of all fiction &mdash; so let us not pretend cuteness is not a female burden, and my desire to draw nice clothes and interesting hairstyles is not an altruistic representation of women, no matter how well-intentioned my depictions may be.</p>
<p>This conversation is important only because Vekllei is important (to me), and the principles of <em>utopie concrète</em> are worth upholding &mdash; all things <em>must</em> have dignity.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>I have a very good website</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/website/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/website/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Hi everyone,
Hobart here, informing you that I have a very good website. It has every post I’ve ever made on it, for better or for worse (with the non-canon stuff marked). It has wiki pages that are growing all the time. It has fun things and essays. You can also leave comments!
Just look at the home page. Isn’t that the coolest shit you’ve ever seen? You can see it live at https://millmint.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/mastheads/banner.png"/> <p><strong>Hi everyone</strong>,</p>
<p>Hobart here, informing you that I have a <strong>very</strong> <strong>good</strong> <strong>website</strong>. It has every post I’ve ever made on it, for better or for worse (with the non-canon stuff marked). It has wiki pages that are growing all the time. It has fun things and essays. You can also leave comments!</p>
<p><a href="https://imgur.com/a/BA0nNV6">Just look at the home page</a>. Isn’t that the coolest shit you’ve ever seen? You can see it live at <a href="https://millmint.net">https://millmint.net</a> if you’re on desktop/tablet, and play with the trains.</p>
<p>Bonus: <a href="https://imgur.com/a/P9j0nS3">Tzipora with some flowers</a>.</p>
<p>Regular posts tomorrow &amp; onwards.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.patreon.com/vekllei">Join the Patreon</a>.</p>
<p>Be “Petticoat”</p>
<p>Love,</p>
<p><strong>Hobart</strong>/MelonKony</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Sand Mage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sand-mage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sand-mage/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora is a sand mage.
Actually, she isn’t, but I wanted to draw something with particles and ended up doing different paint sketches for a few hours. This was the best one, and also the most stupid.
Canonically, Tzipora can’t swim, so she spends more time on the beach than in the water. The colour of the sand here suggests it’s an artificial “white beach” in Mumen or nearby. Most beaches in Vekllei are black.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/sketches/sandmage.jpg"/> <p><strong>Tzipora is a sand mage.</strong></p>
<p>Actually, she isn’t, but I wanted to draw something with particles and ended up doing different paint sketches for a few hours. This was the best one, and also the most stupid.</p>
<p>Canonically, Tzipora can’t swim, so she spends more time on the beach than in the water. The colour of the sand here suggests it’s an artificial “white beach” in Mumen or nearby. Most beaches in Vekllei are black.</p>
<p>She’s wearing something between regular school uniform and <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/">national dress</a>. It’s a bit exaggerated here, but the gold plate and <em>gi</em> quarter-pleat are common enough ceremonial items. That’s how it works in practice — school uniforms are quite literally undecorated, simpler versions of national dress.</p>
<p>I don’t usually work in this style. It’s fun to learn new things, and reinvent yourself.</p>
<p>Anyway, this is just a sketch, not part of Ocean Month.</p>
<p>Thanks for hanging out.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>3,000 MEMBERS!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/3000/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/3000/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Hello,
I’m Hobart, and I’m the creator of this place. I’ve been drawing Vekllei for a few years now, and I love doing it.
To celebrate 3,000 members, use this as a cosy thread/AMA to settle in, and have any questions you might have about the project answered.
For those who are new, I encourage you to read the posts pinned to the top of the subreddit for a crash course in what’s going on here.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/3000.jpg"/> <p>Hello,</p>
<p><strong>I’m Hobart,</strong> and I’m the creator of this place. I’ve been drawing Vekllei for a few years now, and I love doing it.</p>
<p>To celebrate 3,000 members, <strong>use this as a cosy thread/AMA to settle in,</strong> and have any questions you might have about the project answered.</p>
<p>For those who are new, <strong>I encourage you to read the posts pinned to the top of the subreddit</strong> for a crash course in what’s going on here.</p>
<p>For longtime friends, come say hi! <strong>This is a party thread, whoo!</strong></p>
<p><strong>Quik Fax:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Vekllei</strong> is a country set in what we know as <strong>Iceland</strong>, in an alternate vision of the future.</li>
<li>It’s my <strong>utopia</strong>, which means it’s an expression of everything I value in life, the good and the bad.</li>
<li>I draw all sorts of things, and write about all sorts of topics — all set in Vekllei or other countries. It’s slowly becoming a comprehensive utopia, filling in everything from <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/">economics</a> to <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/">love stories</a> to <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/">metaphysics</a> and <a href="https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/">espionage</a>. You’ll notice the scope shift a lot in my posts.</li>
<li>The project has a <strong>comic</strong> being worked on, available to my <a href="https://www.patreon.com/vekllei">patrons</a> as an ongoing series of drafts at the moment. Otherwise, “<strong>Vekllei</strong>” is what you see here — a collection of <strong>posts</strong> that are snapshots of the world. It doesn’t have an end goal, it’s just what I like to do.</li>
<li><strong>Every post I have ever made</strong>, plus an expanding collection of <strong>wiki articles</strong> about this project, can be found at my website: <a href="http://millmint.net/">millmint.net</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Thank you sincerely for paying attention and caring for my work. It’s a wonderful thing we’ve got going here.</p>
<p>Kind regards,</p>
<p><strong>Hobart</strong>/MelonKony</p>
<p><a href="https://www.patreon.com/vekllei">Join the Patreon</a></p>
<p><strong>Be “petticoat”</strong></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Little Bouncy Zelda — an animation diary</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/animation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/animation/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin It&rsquo;s been a week since I&rsquo;ve posted. Most of that was spent drawing the same thing over and over.
A painting? Please. That&rsquo;s a day&rsquo;s work — maybe two. A five second loop of Tzipora jumping in and shuffling over? A week.
It&rsquo;s difficult to grasp just how much work animation is until you try it. This runs at 12 frames per second (which dickheads will recognise as the anime frame rate).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/intro.gif"/> <blockquote class="note story">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>This article</strong> was featured in <a href="/news/bulletin/2020/5"><strong>Issue #5</strong></a> of the <em>Atlantic Bulletin</em></div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>It&rsquo;s been a week since I&rsquo;ve posted</strong>. Most of that was spent drawing the same thing over and over.</p>
<p>A painting? Please. That&rsquo;s a day&rsquo;s work — maybe two. A five second loop of Tzipora jumping in and shuffling over? A week.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s difficult to grasp just how much work animation is until you try it. This runs at 12 frames per second (which dickheads will recognise as the anime frame rate). There are maybe 38 unique frames in this tiny animation. It&rsquo;s a title card for my imaginary studio, MillMint, in case I ever make videos in the future.</p>
<p>The sketch was fun. It comes alive — your precious characters become real. Then comes the inking. 38 lines traced and polished. Then comes the colouring. Good lord, the colouring. It isn&rsquo;t just labour-intensive &ndash; it&rsquo;s mind-numbingly boring.</p>
<p>This animation has a lot of little imperfections. No, I&rsquo;m not fixing them :)</p>
<p>Regular post tomorrow to make up for a week of empty suffering. Thanks for looking. Let me know what you think!</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>2,000 members! WOW!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/2000/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/2000/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin Hello,
I’m Hobart. I’ve been working on this project for a while now. It doesn’t really have a purpose or an end goal — I just want to draw and write about nice things, and I’m learning a lot on the way. Welcome to everyone new here. I don’t really have anything to sell, I’d just like to thank you for tuning in and checking Vekllei out.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/sailorzelda.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note story">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>This article</strong> was featured in <a href="/news/bulletin/2020/4"><strong>Issue #4</strong></a> of the <em>Atlantic Bulletin</em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Hello,</p>
<p>I’m Hobart. I’ve been working on this project for a while now. It doesn’t really have a purpose or an end goal — I just want to draw and write about nice things, and I’m learning a lot on the way.
Welcome to everyone new here. I don’t really have anything to sell, I’d just like to thank you for tuning in and checking Vekllei out.</p>
<p>I’ve drawn Tzipora here as a sort of Sailor Moon knock-off. Good show that. The Japanese intro is very nostalgic, I’d love to do a little animated short in that style.</p>
<p>I post about twice a week. I do a bit of everything — machines, maps, characters, landscapes, architecture, etc. I’m truly a master of none.</p>
<p>You can come join the Discord if you’d like — it’s just a quiet community to share interests and talk: discord.gg/dCE6vSU</p>
<p>Otherwise, I’ll keep doing what I’m doing and you can keep liking my stuff (please). If you have any questions about the project, or just want to introduce yourselves, here’s a good place to do it!
Thank you kindly to all commenters, readers and friends of the project, whether you’ve been here for years or for six hours — it’s very special to have so many people interested in work that’s so close to my heart.</p>
<p>Keep on keeping on,</p>
<p>Hobart</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>What is This Project?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/what-is-this-project/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/what-is-this-project/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin What is Vekllei?
Hi, I’m Hobart and I write and draw Vekllei at Studio MillMint.
This is a pretty complex project. Not just complex insofar as there’s a lot to read about it, but that it uses concepts and terminology you might not be familiar with if this is your first time around utopian fiction.
So Vekllei is a utopia — what does this mean?]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/whatisvekllei.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note story">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>This article</strong> was featured in <a href="/news/bulletin/2020/2"><strong>Issue #2</strong></a> of the <em>Atlantic Bulletin</em></div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>What is Vekllei?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Hi, I’m Hobart and I write and draw Vekllei</strong> at Studio MillMint.</p>
<p>This is a pretty complex project. Not just complex insofar as there’s a lot to read about it, but that it uses concepts and terminology you might not be familiar with if this is your first time around utopian fiction.</p>
<p>So Vekllei is a utopia — what does this mean? It’s latin for “no place,” and I use that literally. Vekllei, in a literal sense, cannot exist. Not because I think it could never have existed, or that some part of it is completely unreasonable, or it breaks the laws of physics — but because it exists in a certain place and time that is just isn’t replicable. It’s all built from the ground up.</p>
<p>Vekllei is a very good place to live, <strong>but it is not perfect</strong>. Utopia does not mean “perfect place”. Utopia is a form of social dreaming, much like worldbuilding, linked to the values and priorities of its author. In utopian studies, “utopia” is usually broken down further:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Eutopia</strong> — “good place”</li>
<li><strong>Dystopia</strong> — “bad place”</li>
</ul>
<p>Note that both form a part of the “utopia” — this is appropriate, since Vekllei is grounded in a social realism that acknowledges the good and bad parts of life. Indeed, they are inseparable — you cannot have the light without the dark. Obviously, in my eyes, Vekllei is very much a eutopia.
You can read more about Vekllei (the country) by clicking here.</p>
<p>There are three parts to my “social dreaming”:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Landscape</strong> — the world and country of Vekllei. When you think of “utopia,” this is it — shining modernist cities against striking landscapes.</li>
<li><strong>Character</strong> — not all social dreaming takes place in spaces. Some of it is built around experiences, objects and relationships. Tzipora is a “character utopia” in the sense that she represents a utopian life experience, full of stories good and bad.</li>
<li><strong>Author</strong> — Vekllei is a representation of the problems of my life, as a form of escapism. A lot of my posts here reflect dissatisfactions and displacements in my own life — consumer society, commodification of childhood, wage labour, postmodernism, etc. I’m very much a part of this utopian dialectic.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Let’s run through some of the common queries and misunderstandings about Vekllei</strong></p>
<p>Who are you?
<em>A Tasmanian illustrator.</em></p>
<p>You’re not Japanese?
<em>お前はもう死んでいる</em></p>
<p>Why is Vekllei a utopia?
<em>It makes me feel better about my life and the world. It’s escapism; it’s a dream.</em></p>
<p>It’s a bit cringe to grandstand your political beliefs, doncha think?
<em>Vekllei is a personal utopia. That’s what I’m selling. At least you’re getting good opinions.</em></p>
<p>Where’s the tension if it’s perfect?
<em>Vekllei is very cynical and tragic in places. Utopia is just a reflection of the author, good and bad.</em></p>
<p>Is there a novel? A story? A comic?
<em>I’m working on a comic right now. I’m pretty much working on Vekllei full-time so I’m hoping to announce it soon. I’ve got a lot of different Vekllei projects going.</em></p>
<p>Where is Vekllei?
<em>Iceland.</em></p>
<p>Why does Vekllei look Japanese?
<em>Vekllei is like a country of Scandinavians speaking French with an Aussie accent in Shōwa era Japan/Maoist China/Taiwan etc. Vekllei looks however I imagine utopia looks.</em></p>
<p>How does that make sense?
<em>Why can’t it just be cool?</em></p>
<p>Is your alt-history thought out?
<em>Vekllei’s history is whatever I need it to be. I’m always trying to be realistic, but it’s all worked backwards from the setting. I’m not really “worldbuilding” in a typical sense. Very little of it is published, most of it is retrieved on request. Just ask if you have questions.</em></p>
<p>Is Vekllei communist?
<em>No.</em></p>
<p>But Vekllei calls itself “petticoat socialist”.
<em>Vekllei is set in a culture of Marxist revivalism in the 50s and 60s. A lot of Vekllei’s lexicon is set in that context. Vekllei is a decentralised democracy that doesn’t use money. It’s a sort of participatory economy.</em></p>
<p>Why the &ldquo;petticoat&rdquo;?
<em>Vekllei is a female country. Womanhood is decommodified. It&rsquo;s maternal, social and friendly where socialist rhetoric is masculine, technocratic and progressive.</em></p>
<p>Who is Zelda?
<em>Zelda is another name for Tzipora. She has two names specifically to confuse you.</em></p>
<p>What is the “bulletin”?
<em>I publish the Atlantic Bulletin once a month via email. It’s got the month’s posts in it as well as facts and tidbits from Vekllei. DM me an email if you want to join.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Announcing Tzipo-stcards</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/postcards/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/postcards/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Hello everyone. Just a little update.
As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.
How many cards will the set contain?
I’m aiming for about six cards.
How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?
I think about $20 over your pledge lifetime would cover print and shipping, though I’ll let you know if that goes up or down.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/tzipostcards.jpg"/> <p>Hello everyone. <strong>Just a little update</strong>.</p>
<p>As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.</p>
<p><strong>How many cards will the set contain?</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I’m aiming for about six cards.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I think about $20 over your pledge lifetime would cover print and shipping, though I’ll let you know if that goes up or down. I’m hoping to cover shipping, so you’ll just need to supply an address.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>What if I haven’t yet pledged enough?</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you’re a Patron who hasn’t yet pledged the $20 or whatever it is to cover print and shipping, just contact me and I’ll make… alternative arrangements for you. Don’t worry — if you want the cards, you won’t miss out.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Who would even want these?</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>People who like cute 6x4” illustrations on nice card stock will like them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s a good time to plug my Patreon if you’ve got some government stimulus bux floating around — <a href="https://www.patreon.com/vekllei">link here</a>. It produces enormous pressure for me to create new work and art, so if you’re a fan of what I do it’s a good way to position yourself as an investor and get on my ass about posting more.</p>
<p>Speaking of posts, there’s one coming tomorrow or the day after.</p>
<p>Thanks always, and best wishes.</p>
<p>Hobart</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Salad Time</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/salad/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/salad/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Despite appearances, most of the population of Vekllei are Scandinavian, not Asian.
Zhu is the first time in a long time I&rsquo;ve drawn an ethnically Chinese person. She was graciously lent to me to draw by u/boodyclap in an art trade. You can see his end of the deal here, complete with Tzipora balancing a baseball bat.
In Zhu&rsquo;s homeland she suffers a meat-heavy diet, and Vekllei is the first time she&rsquo;s seen a salad this big.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/salad.jpg"/> <p>Despite appearances, most of the population of Vekllei are Scandinavian, not Asian.</p>
<p>Zhu is the first time in a long time I&rsquo;ve drawn an ethnically Chinese person. She was graciously lent to me to draw by u/boodyclap in an art trade. <a href="https://imgur.com/a/pm6cuMH">You can see his end of the deal here</a>, complete with Tzipora balancing a baseball bat.</p>
<p>In Zhu&rsquo;s homeland she suffers a meat-heavy diet, and Vekllei is the first time she&rsquo;s seen a salad this big. You can see iconic Vekllei icebergs washing ashore on a beach of black sand behind them. I&rsquo;ll let u/boodyclap share any extra tidbits below :)</p>
<p>Follow Zhu&rsquo;s adventures at <a href="https://www.instagram.com/the_jeggy/">@the_jeggy</a> on insta.</p>
<p>If you like worldbuilding, trains or friendship please come <a href="https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU">join us at the Vekllei Discord</a>. It&rsquo;s a good time.</p>
<p>More posts soon.</p>
<p>Love,</p>
<p>Hobart</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Timeline</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/timeline/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/timeline/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This is it. The dates are laid out. I&rsquo;ve created a document that tracks the story thus far. Longtime followers might be surprised by where certain events land.
This post will be pinned and serve as a stopgap until I can complete something more professional on my site.
CLICK HERE for a timeline of the events so far, and how they line up in this story.
Last Updated: 13/7/2020
For your convenience, I&rsquo;ve embedded links to the relevant posts in each year to help you keep track of the spiralling canon.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/timeline.jpg"/> <p>This is it. The dates are laid out. I&rsquo;ve created a document that tracks the story thus far. Longtime followers might be surprised by where certain events land.</p>
<p>This post will be pinned and serve as a stopgap until I can complete something more professional on my site.</p>
<hr>
<p><a href="/files/Post-War%20Vekllei%20Timeline.pdf">CLICK HERE for a timeline of the events so far, and how they line up in this story.</a></p>
<p>Last Updated: <strong>13/7/2020</strong></p>
<hr>
<p>For your convenience, I&rsquo;ve embedded links to the relevant posts in each year to help you keep track of the spiralling canon. Please note that this is not a complete or comprehensive catalogue of events, since for the sake of storytelling (and spoilers) I&rsquo;ve deliberately excluded the bulk of events around the world in the document above.</p>
<p>This post will be updated with the most current version of the timeline.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hobart and Tzipora are off to Japan</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/japan/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/japan/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora here is wearing a simplified form of Vekllei’s national dress, which plays fast and loose with lace and showcases some of Vekllei’s more decadent iconography. Long gi (decorative quarter-pleats you’ve seen around) accompany sun petticoats, or Vekllei lace aprons. Flowers take the place of astrology or the Zodiac in Vekllei, and so they often accompany spiritual runes (in upotenne, or religious script) about the girl. Other aspects are just as unique, but not nearly as noticeable.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/japan.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p>Tzipora here is wearing a simplified form of Vekllei’s national dress, which plays fast and loose with lace and showcases some of Vekllei’s more decadent iconography. Long <em>gi</em> (decorative quarter-pleats you’ve seen around) accompany <em>sun petticoats</em>, or Vekllei lace aprons. Flowers take the place of astrology or the Zodiac in Vekllei, and so they often accompany spiritual runes (in upotenne, or religious script) about the girl. Other aspects are just as unique, but not nearly as noticeable. The loose style of shirt, folded at the elbow, is a deliberate imitation of Vekllei agricultural fashion, and three-fold socks and soft felt or leather shoes are worn by women of many ages and professions. Much like her ecology, Vekllei is also culturally atomised, and in her isolation has developed subtle variations of what might otherwise be dismissed as plain clothing items. Every part of her outfit has heritage and symbolism, often barely detectable to a foreigner.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>4 hours from now I’m off to Japan again. The last time I was in Japan (August 2019) left me inspired and enthusiastic. While I was there I started work on this subreddit. What a good time it’s been.</p>
<p>1.2k subscribers later, and I’m off again. It’s been a hectic week. I’m still unpacking into my new house. The house is quite nice. I’m hoping to return to my roots somewhat, featuring different folks around Vekllei in a rougher concept style. Hopefully, I’ll find the time to stick to the semidaily illustration routine, instead of the 4-5 days I’ve been operating on for the last month or so.</p>
<p>I’d like to invite anyone interested to the <a href="https://discord.gg/gpatU6H">Vekllei Discord</a>, which has blossomed into really great little community full of art and fashion and photography and all sorts of things. It’s much better than the r/worldbuilding Discord.</p>
<p>I’m hoping to do a drawing a day while I’m over there; the one time a year I acknowledge without caveats the Japanese influence on this worldbuilding project.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>Hobart</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>So long 2019, here&#39;s to 2020!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/dance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/dance/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the new Vekllei discord — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts. Speaking of which, this one is a substitute — the one I’m working on ended up being a bit too sad for an exciting new year, so I’ll put the sad stuff off until Jan 2nd in favour of something happier tomorrow.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/dance.jpg"/> <p>Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the <a href="https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU">new Vekllei discord</a> — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts. Speaking of which, this one is a substitute — the one I’m working on ended up being a bit too sad for an exciting new year, so I’ll put the sad stuff off until Jan 2nd in favour of something happier tomorrow.</p>
<p>While Moise sits alone and feels like a cow-handed chucklehead, let’s wind up the year with some awards I’ll hand out to myself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Runner Up: Favourite Post of 2019</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/auz580/the_forgotten_generation/"><em>The Forgotten Generation</em></a></p>
<p>Old photographs have a certain tragedy to them. Especially considering the hardships of the past. I like the maoist elements of the uniforms and the vague sense of loss.</p>
<p><strong>Runner Up: Worst Post of 2019</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/e6iykk/wallabies_of_the_arctic_veklleis_pademelon_and/"><em>Wallabies of the Arctic</em></a></p>
<p>The pademelons are cute, and were fun to draw. Somehow I managed to make Tzipora, whom I’ve been drawing since I was 15, incredibly ugly and awkward to look at. The expression I was trying to draw is fine in theory; the shape and colour of the face is wrong. You’ve got to wonder what I was thinking, posting it without alterations.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Favourite Post of 2019</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/c05k16/absolute_grotesque/"><em>Absolute Grotesque</em></a></p>
<p>As anyone who does creative work knows, you don’t usually anticipate your favourite work. This one was made in about four hours (it was the quickest landscape I ever did).</p>
<p>I don’t always like the dark stuff, but this one just turned out well. The lore doesn’t waste any words, and it says exactly what I wanted to say about the subject. It’s clear and simple and I like reading back through it. The art is much better than more recent attempts at similar subjects, and there’s a brevity to the art and lore that I usually fuck up. I’ve made many posts now trying to recreate it.</p>
<p><strong>Worst Post of 2019</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/dj5di0/uniform_ideology_in_the_arctic_north/"><em>Uniform Ideology in the Arctic North</em></a></p>
<p>You’ll have to trust me when I say the women’s uniform is extraordinarily beautiful. Despite its capes and gold, it can be stripped of ornamentation and reduced to a white shirt and red skirt, recalling images of Taiwan in the White Terror or postwar Vietnam. It has a fundamental simplicity and adaptability that’s quite important to me.</p>
<p>You’ll have to trust me about all that, because it does not carry through in this post at all. It’s not that there’s one particular element that makes a post shitty; it’s just the total half-arsed effort throughout. Uniform ideology is such an untapped concept, and I wasted it here. The girls look strange. The only good thing about this post is that it introduced me to several nice fellow worldbuilders that I would go on to collaborate with.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What is your best and worst? I know my choices might be a bit surprising. If you comment that the worst is &ldquo;every post&rdquo;, I’ll ban you.</p>
<p>Finally, cheers to all of you here and at my Patreon. I’ve had a slow month for drawing, and I’ve got to find a place to live by this weekend, but we’ve got good things ahead. I’m back in Japan on the 9th, so expect some vitality there. I love drawing on the trains there. I was inspired to make this subreddit after my last visit in August, actually.</p>
<p>I’m trying to get back to making posts every other day — it’s the best feeling in the world to put stuff up here, but sometimes life just gets in the way. January is a time of rebirth, and Tzipora is eternal — there will be lots of Vekllei to come.</p>
<p>Here’s to 2020.</p>
<p>Hobart.</p>
<p>P.S. Moise did, in fact, get his slow dance.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Merry Christmas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/christmas-2019/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/christmas-2019/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[I’m still eating pudding, but once I’m home tomorrow and settled at my drawing desk I’ll be sure to report Tzipora’s holiday adventures in full.
For the Christmasfolk out there, enjoy your presents. To everyone else, have a good holiday and be sure to celebrate the Australian way — with prawns, salmon and snags on the barbie.
(Gorgeous 25°C [77°F] yesterday)
Best,
Hobart]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/christmas2019.jpg"/> <p>I’m still eating pudding, but once I’m home tomorrow and settled at my drawing desk I’ll be sure to report Tzipora’s holiday adventures in full.</p>
<p>For the Christmasfolk out there, enjoy your presents. To everyone else, have a good holiday and be sure to celebrate the Australian way — with prawns, salmon and snags on the barbie.</p>
<p>(Gorgeous 25°C [77°F] yesterday)</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>Hobart</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sneak Sneak</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sneak/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sneak/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[He kept bad hours. Sometimes he worked so hard he came home in the early morning and fell asleep to the television with the subtitles on. Like a guerrilla sighting a commanding officer, she would approach discreetly, wearing her blanket like a cape and bouncing on her toes. With a gentle movement she&rsquo;d drape it over him and listen for a break in his snoring. If he didn&rsquo;t stir, she&rsquo;d find a nook in his shoulder and would stay there till the sunrays woke him in the morning.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/sneak.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p>He kept bad hours. Sometimes he worked so hard he came home in the early morning and fell asleep to the television with the subtitles on. Like a guerrilla sighting a commanding officer, she would approach discreetly, wearing her blanket like a cape and bouncing on her toes. With a gentle movement she&rsquo;d drape it over him and listen for a break in his snoring. If he didn&rsquo;t stir, she&rsquo;d find a nook in his shoulder and would stay there till the sunrays woke him in the morning. Those were her favourite nights.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hello everyone. Hobart here. We hit 1,000 subscribers only a month ago, and it gets a bit tedious to carry on thanking everyone, so I won’t. I’m not thanking the commenters who say nice things, and I’m definitely not thanking the lurkers who continue to validate my self-worth through subreddit metrics. It would be tiresome to mention that it really means a lot and I’m thankful, so I won’t.</p>
<p>I’ve got a few updates to share.</p>
<ol>
<li>The new website looks really good. This doesn’t really affect anything on the subreddit aside from the fact it’s crippled my output this last week or two. It’s only in alpha, if anything, but once it’s polished it’ll be mesmerising. I really mean it. It’s so fun to play with already. It&rsquo;s not like other project sites.</li>
<li>SkyMonth will wrap up this December. It’s taken longer than planned, but so what? There’s lots of planes to come.</li>
<li>I’d like to thank the handful of kind people who donate to my Patreon. I’m not much of a drinker, but I like a drop of Irish cream with my tea and coffee, and I’d have to choose between it and food if it weren’t for these nice people. I&rsquo;m &ldquo;between jobs,&rdquo; so it really does make a difference. Thank you kindly.</li>
<li>I reckon January will be a free-for-all in terms of posts. I might even pull back and do a really nice, time-intensive painting like I used to. Then we&rsquo;ll go in for a deep-dive themed month (to be revealed).</li>
<li>Comic is being written.</li>
</ol>
<p>I’ve gotten really nice feedback on a few of the character posts. Sorry if I didn’t reply — they were all written between 3-4am to get them over and done with, and I promptly disowned them when I woke up in the morning (might happen with this post too — it’s 3:26am on my clock). It’s easy to forget most of you don’t know the characters of this world.</p>
<p>So let me know. What kind of posts are your favourite? What’s working and what’s not working? Or you could just say a nice thing about me or my art, those do me just fine as well.</p>
<p>I won&rsquo;t conclude by thanking you for sticking with Vekllei.</p>
<p>Sleep tight, and see you in the morning,</p>
<p>(something about bed bugs biting)</p>
<p>Hobart.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Blue Shoes</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/blue-shoes/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/blue-shoes/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Welcome to the r/Vekllei variety hour, where the tone between posts judders so inconsistently you&rsquo;ll get whiplash of the mind. I was just drawing and thinking today. This is an author post, in case you haven&rsquo;t noticed &ndash; just a shitty blog.
You see, even today I&rsquo;m wildly jealous of the success of those slice-of-life artists on reddit and Twitter. I still don&rsquo;t understand the genre entirely, as a phenomenon. It&rsquo;s usually male artists (at least in Japan), drawing distinctly Japanese neighbourhoods and landscapes, and situating a schoolgirl in the midst of it.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/blueshoes.jpg"/> <p>Welcome to the r/Vekllei variety hour, where the tone between posts judders so inconsistently you&rsquo;ll get whiplash of the mind. I was just drawing and thinking today. This is an author post, in case you haven&rsquo;t noticed &ndash; just a shitty blog.</p>
<p>You see, even today I&rsquo;m wildly jealous of the success of those slice-of-life artists on reddit and Twitter. I still don&rsquo;t understand the genre entirely, as a phenomenon. It&rsquo;s usually male artists (at least in Japan), drawing distinctly Japanese neighbourhoods and landscapes, and situating a schoolgirl in the midst of it. They&rsquo;re usually pretty amazing scenes. It&rsquo;s almost always a schoolgirl, too &ndash; in modern Tokyo uniform or セーラー服.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m still trying to figure it out. It&rsquo;s obviously not sexual objectification, like so much elsewhere in Japanese illustration &ndash; in fact, it&rsquo;s usually nothing more than mundane or wistful scenes featuring some girl. But why is it always a girl? If it&rsquo;s supposed to evoke a nostalgia for a childhood you&rsquo;ve never had, why is it so rarely schoolboys? It&rsquo;s surely to do with cuteness &ndash; &lsquo;cuteness&rsquo; is almost always a female burden, and cute art is good, happy art. I don&rsquo;t have any stats for this, but anecdotally most of the SOL artists I follow are men, and I reckon a large chunk of the audience for it is too. It&rsquo;s boys creating cuteness for boys.</p>
<p>Maybe it&rsquo;s interesting for me because Vekllei has a lot of similarities to slice-of-life art. I&rsquo;m in the business of peddling nostalgia for places you&rsquo;ve never been, and Tzipora is very much a girl who is very much in uniform a few days a week. It almost reads as satire, in fact &ndash; Tzipora will never stop being a girl, since she is one of thirteen in the world to &rsquo;not age,&rsquo; as per her canon diagnosis. I don&rsquo;t like to think that I&rsquo;m carrying on in that tradition, or that I&rsquo;m infantilising or deliberately cutifying these characters, but does intention matter at all?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not sure there&rsquo;s anything wrong with it, anyway. It&rsquo;s just that sometimes I look back through my catalogue, see its female/male ratio, and consider if I&rsquo;m not just buying into the same kawaii currency.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a cute picture of Tzipora I made. <a href="https://imgur.com/TiBF1xe">I made a wallpaper of it</a>, if you&rsquo;d like it. Let me know what you think about the slice of life art crowd; I&rsquo;m sure I&rsquo;ve got a decent overlap, aside from the cool bros here only for the hardcore geopolitik deprezzion posts.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>From Beaches to Mountaintops</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/mountaintops/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/mountaintops/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[I had the wonderful opportunity to work with one of our resident worldbuilders on reddit, u/EpicJM, and spend a while with their world and characters. The world of Eipljord has a lot of distinct, unique cultures and characters. As a sucker for uniforms I went with the garb of the Pruscyldan Academy of Magic, and you&rsquo;ll find JM&rsquo;s character, Honora being splattered with ice cream by Tzipora on the left and in Vekllei education uniform on the right.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/mountaintops.jpg"/> <p>I had the wonderful opportunity to work with one of our resident worldbuilders on reddit, u/EpicJM, and spend a while with their world and characters. The world of Eipljord has a lot of distinct, unique cultures and characters. As a sucker for uniforms I went with the garb of the Pruscyldan Academy of Magic, and you&rsquo;ll find JM&rsquo;s character, Honora being splattered with ice cream by Tzipora on the left and in Vekllei education uniform on the right. You can see the Vekllei racing jet from a previous post face off against Pruscyldan BlackJay behind her.</p>
<p>JM&rsquo;s got a very big world and a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jm_draws_stuff/">very good instagram</a>. I&rsquo;d recommend checking out both. It&rsquo;s not often I get the chance to work with nice volcanic islands and sandy beaches (nor Tzipora to visit them!) so thanks u/EpicJM for working with me.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Like Father, Like Daughter</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/beach/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/beach/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The main beach in Mumen, the nicest of the seaside districts, is constructed out of sand imported from the dunes of Africa. Where the rest of the country has black sand, a symptom of its volcanic turbulence, Mumen has nice yellow sand.
Baron doesn’t like the water, and getting him down to the sea at all was a trial. Zelda, for her part, sinks faster than lead in water and only ventures into the shallows with Ayn, who herself is afraid of the deeper ocean.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/beach.jpg"/> <p>The main beach in Mumen, the nicest of the seaside districts, is constructed out of sand imported from the dunes of Africa. Where the rest of the country has black sand, a symptom of its volcanic turbulence, Mumen has nice yellow sand.</p>
<p>Baron doesn’t like the water, and getting him down to the sea at all was a trial. Zelda, for her part, sinks faster than lead in water and only ventures into the shallows with Ayn, who herself is afraid of the deeper ocean. She spends most of her time on the beach in her clothes, watching the other girls splash and compare suits.</p>
<p>Baron here is reading his paper, <em>The Atlantic</em>. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cw44hm/sweat_and_ink_in_the_vekllei_news_agency/">I wrote a bit about that organisation here</a>. Zelda is reading a horror gazette. A naturally curious girl who enjoys newsreels and documentary, she swaps with him when they’re done. He claims he doesn’t like her horror gazettes, but he keeps taking them, and he keeps reading them.</p>
<p>The sunsets of Vekllei are nearly as legendary as the Aurora, and when the end of the day is at their backs it’s finally dark enough to face the sun and watch it settle. They take the tram home and finish reading in the warmth of their eighth-floor apartment.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>… where did I leave all the uploads?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/uploads/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/uploads/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Hello everyone,
Thanks again for subscribing to this subreddit. I’m playing a game of chicken right now pitting my little Vekllei projects against my university work.
Vekllei boys uniforms (and school architecture) is coming later this week, turning Study Week into a Study Month!
Starting from next week, several exciting projects are getting kicked into gear. One is the graphic novel. There’s also the Vekllei wiki, which is under construction. There will be a lot more art.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/uploads.jpg"/> <p>Hello everyone,</p>
<p>Thanks again for subscribing to this subreddit. I’m playing a game of chicken right now pitting my little Vekllei projects against my university work.</p>
<p>Vekllei boys uniforms (and school architecture) is coming later this week, turning Study Week into a Study Month!</p>
<p>Starting from next week, several exciting projects are getting kicked into gear. One is the graphic novel. There’s also the Vekllei wiki, which is under construction. There will be a lot more art. And a secret, special project that’s gonna be <em>really</em> exciting. I can’t wait to share it with you all.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.patreon.com/vekllei">I have a Patreon now</a> — not that you need to donate! It’s like a priority inbox. If you want me to print out illustrations and send them to you, see drafts of upcoming projects (like the graphic novel script and preview the special secret), or you want a little drawing of your own, sending me a dollar is a good way get my attention. It just goes towards server costs and keeping me from malnutrition, nothing exciting.</p>
<p>So there’s a lot on the way. I know most shouldn’t care, but I get nervous if I’m not here every other day or so. And lurkers, just so you know — Tzipora and I appreciate you.</p>
<p>On with Study Month.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Challenger Has Appeared!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/challenger/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/challenger/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Well isn’t this exciting! The talented u/Herald_of_Zena decided to draw Isabelle from his world in the uniforms I posted the other day. It was too much fun not to join in. It turned out to be a classic story told in two parts &ndash; shit weather, put on coat.
It’s a pleasure seeing such a unique style that’s really one of a kind in the worldbuilding scene. It&rsquo;s painterly and soft where a lot of worldbuilders favour a determined, blocky, concept art look.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/skytrade.jpg"/> <p>Well isn’t this exciting! The talented u/Herald_of_Zena decided to draw Isabelle from his world in the uniforms I posted the other day. It was too much fun not to join in. It turned out to be a classic story told in two parts &ndash; shit weather, put on coat.</p>
<p>It’s a pleasure seeing such a unique style that’s really one of a kind in the worldbuilding scene. It&rsquo;s painterly and soft where a lot of worldbuilders favour a determined, blocky, concept art look. <a href="https://www.artstation.com/skyhornet">Check out some other pieces on Isabelle while you’re here</a> — she’s a really intriguing character with a stoic sort of disposition, not unlike our Zelda.</p>
<p>It’s just so cool to see an item or outfit from my world appear in someone else’s style. Thanks a lot mate, it was a blast.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>500 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/500/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/500/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Thank you very much everyone. It&rsquo;s very exciting for me. I ordered a cake from Banjos to celebrate but Tzipora got it all over the floor and herself.
Thanks for subscribing. I&rsquo;ve been pushing myself a bit too hard and my writing&rsquo;s suffered for it. I&rsquo;m not sure I can slow down, I&rsquo;m just not that kind of guy, but I want to promise some exciting adventures in the future as we hang out with Zelda and her loved ones.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/500.jpg"/> <p>Thank you very much everyone. It&rsquo;s very exciting for me. I ordered a cake from Banjos to celebrate but Tzipora got it all over the floor and herself.</p>
<p>Thanks for subscribing. I&rsquo;ve been pushing myself a bit too hard and my writing&rsquo;s suffered for it. I&rsquo;m not sure I can slow down, I&rsquo;m just not that kind of guy, but I want to promise some exciting adventures in the future as we hang out with Zelda and her loved ones.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s to a thousand! My goal is to get bigger than the main worldbuilding subreddit. Only a few hundred thousand to go.</p>
<p>In the meantime, feel free to stick around, enjoy the party, scrape whatever cake you can off the floor and have a good time with Zelda and me.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>I like bread</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/bread/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/bread/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[I have a research proposal due today, and since I&rsquo;m pretending to still be a university student I suppose I&rsquo;d better do it.
I spend a lot of time thinking about what the hell I&rsquo;m doing with my life, and after a while I get hungry. Banjos &ndash; a very Australian name for a bakery chain &ndash; satiates my existential hunger with two bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves for $10. I don&rsquo;t know what that would be in American money.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/bread.jpg"/> <p>I have a research proposal due today, and since I&rsquo;m pretending to still be a university student I suppose I&rsquo;d better do it.</p>
<p>I spend a lot of time thinking about what the hell I&rsquo;m doing with my life, and after a while I get hungry. Banjos &ndash; a very Australian name for a bakery chain &ndash; satiates my existential hunger with two bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves for $10. I don&rsquo;t know what that would be in American money. Probably like $6.80 or some bullshit because our exchange rate is absolutely not very fair dinkum at the moment.</p>
<p>I suppose what I&rsquo;m saying is I eat as lot of bread, and I appreciate you guys being here for it. I despise the idea of myself blogging but sometime I need an outlet.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Brief Introduction to Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/an-introduction/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/an-introduction/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Editor&rsquo;s note: this article, while ready for reading, is still under construction.
Considering both the length and convoluted terminology that embroil this project, there was only so long I could carry on before people started getting lost. The truth of it is that Vekllei is not a particularly complex or difficult project to summarise, despite the snapshot &ldquo;lore in scenes&rdquo; approach that kneecaps a complete understanding. I&rsquo;m just lazy.
In fact, Vekllei is not a particularly challenging idea.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/lola.jpg"/> <p><em>Editor&rsquo;s note: this article, while ready for reading, is still under construction.</em></p>
<p>Considering both the length and convoluted terminology that embroil this project, there was only so long I could carry on before people started getting lost. The truth of it is that Vekllei is not a particularly complex or difficult project to summarise, despite the snapshot &ldquo;lore in scenes&rdquo; approach that kneecaps a complete understanding. I&rsquo;m just lazy.</p>
<p>In fact, Vekllei is not a particularly challenging idea. It is unique, but some days that&rsquo;s about all it has going for it. The word itself — <strong>Vekllei</strong> — refers to both the landscape and the people of an island we know as Iceland. This project looks at that country and its people across a span of about fifty years, mostly between 2070 and 2120. As an alt-history, timelines diverge between our world and theirs in the 1940s, although Vekllei&rsquo;s history is much older.</p>
<p><em>Vekllei is utopia, but Vekllei is not perfect</em>. It is constructed under a framework of <em>utopie concrète</em>, where dreamlike landscapes and characters collide with the dirt and dysfunction of reality. To some people, the contradictions and imperfection of Vekllei society would disqualify it as utopia, especially in an orthodox understanding of the idea, but Western cultural orthodoxy is not the metric used by a Vekllei person.</p>
<p>Vekllei people instead use Vekllei cultural metrics, and to a Vekllei person it is the patina of things — its imperfections and tragedy — that recognise the beauty in life itself, as markers of both existence and usefulness. This cultural intuition is a central tenant of <strong>Upen</strong>, Vekllei&rsquo;s nondenominational animism and universal spirituality.</p>
<p>Simultaneously, Vekllei is undeniably heavenly. It is a gorgeous country of spiritual satisfaction and earnest friendship. Your first day in Vekllei is a dizzying spiritual experience. The weight of the world seems to shift, and then rise off your shoulders. Colour and vitality disentangle themselves from injustice and consumption and pivot to meet you. Food is good and free, strangers are friendly and bursting with lively purposefulness.</p>
<p>Vekllei understands itself as a city-state. This colours a lot of how Vekllei people think of themselves. In practice, there are many distinct &lsquo;cities&rsquo; — the Capital, Little Vekllei, Copette, Ro, Montre and Adouisneh are the largest of them — but they are not recognised as such or federated in Vekllei geographic lexicon. Vekllei is a single continuous neighbourhood, circling nearly the entire coast of their island. Vekllei is also the land on which they sit, which predates the country by millions of years and informs many principles of Upen, which go on to manifest in public policy.</p>
<p>Vekllei cities are almost entirely built according to a single architectural school, <strong>Newda</strong>, which manifests in many different ways but is almost always obviously a flavour of midcentury modernism. Water and concrete define Vekllei cities.</p>
<p>The Vekllei flag is an unornamented purplish red, known as the &lsquo;Domestic Standard&rsquo;. Internationally, they employ a highly decorated flag called the &lsquo;International Standard,&rsquo; which features both the <em>Oa</em> national flower (and omnipresent symbol in every corner of society) and Vekllei logographic script, called <em>Topet</em>.</p>
<p>Vekllei has five language systems, which contribute to the single national language &ndash; also called Vekllei. There is spoken Vekllei,  <strong>Topet</strong> (logographic Vekllei script), <strong>Rapotenne</strong> (name-script), <strong>Vekllei semaphore</strong>, and <strong>Potenne</strong> (hand-talk) or <strong>Upotenne</strong> (spirit-hand-talk). Potenne is a sign language used with or in place of speech, and Upotenne is a way of manifesting physical runes specifically.</p>
<p>Vekllei cities are very colourful, because colour has great meaning. You can construct sentences using only colour and shapes through Vekllei semaphore.</p>
<p>This sort of lifestyle is possible because of Vekllei&rsquo;s abolishment of work, commodity and consumption. In the case of Vekllei, this means that people do not use money and work only for personal benefit, as both ways of actualising themselves and keeping useful or socialising. Not all work is equally difficult or interesting, but everyone must work in fairness. For some, that means as little as a few hours a week copy-editing neighbourhood newsletters. For others, they may work weeks without days off. The consequence of this is that value and products are valueless in any real sense, as post-scarcity relegates the functioning Vekllei economy to autonomous overproduction and waste.</p>
<p>The question of why people work is not an especially difficult one. In Vekllei, where money has not existed for a long time and generations are raised without it, basic premises of motivation have been reconsidered. Life in Vekllei is mostly a largely individual march towards actualisation, through several avenues of pleasure. There is the enjoyment of food and culture, the intimacy of love and marriage, the heritage in family and blood, and the power of work and professional legacy. Only a handful of these contribute to the pleasure of work, but in a society that has mostly done away with menial work through automation and advanced robotics, pleasure is mostly what you make of it. In Vekllei, this is called <strong>Product Socialism</strong>, an inaccurate nominer that describes both the bureau system of work and distribution and Vekllei&rsquo;s fundamental syndicalism. In politics, it is called <strong>Sundress Municipalism</strong>.</p>
<p>The quality of life for almost any other person in today&rsquo;s world, however, has declined slowly by nearly any metric. People are, on average, poorer and hungrier than they were fifty years ago. Various contradictions — in startling contrast to Vekllei&rsquo;s own schisms — have left previously dignified superpowers in disorienting cycles of bloodshed and madness. In the U.S., a large number of confederate states have reasserted their sovereignty following the collapse of the Ford Motor Company and the Northrop corporation. Cultural reforms in Red China have left vast wings of the CCP disatissfied with current leadership, with whispers of a coup. Western Europe has rediscovered her reactionary heritage and indulged in a serious of increasingly authoritarian traditionalist movements, and the export economy of the Soviet Union has collapsed after the shift towards atomic fuels. Vekllei rejects millions of applications for asylum each year.</p>
<p>The circumstance of the world is only made more tragic by the relative peace and stability of Vekllei, and the simplicity and carefree lifestyle of the average Vekllei person. Vekllei has the most flowers per capita of any country in the world. The last fifty years has seen the melting of much of the poles and the the introduction of el nino summers and instant winters that wrack Germany, Austria, Italy, and much of temperate Europe. The Adriatic seems to see more gloom than mediterranean sun these days. The equatorial deserts of the world, Nevada included, are mere degrees away from unsurvivable. With temperatures frequently breaking 50C (125F) throughout the year, it thins the population of Southerners too old or too poor to avoid the heat. North Africa is a husk. There is no water and no food. There is a reason there are mass graves all across the shores of the Black Sea, and why Europe tastes the boot. There is a reason the southern African states are crumbling.</p>
<p>In Vekllei, with her extreme daylight cycles and polar latitude, the weather has improved significantly. Summers are warm enough to host outdoor activities for much of the season and winters are milder than previously, rarely dropping below freezing. Vekllei life, in its insular fashion, has been somewhat improved by the destabilisation of the climate. Lush temperate rainforests cover much of its lowlying basins, and rich volcanic soils spoil agricultural endevour in the warm seasons.</p>
<p>Vekllei&rsquo;s current prosperity has enabled the country to embark on her final project. The benefits of industrialisation and contemporary post-scarcity are employed in a serious effort to reestablish localised, agrarian life built upon the unit of the community.</p>
<p>Vekllei understands the the achievements of industry as a liberationist tool to return to preindustrial, satisfying life. It is not as though the country will abolish three centuries of tremendous progress — quite the contrary, in fact. But understood through petticoat ideology, the marriage of labour and the ordinary person can only occur through self-satisfying, personal work. This is in contrast, one can suppose, to mechanised, industrial labour to which we owe our enormous wealth. To a Vekllei person, work is social, productive, creative and satisfying. The simple pleasures of agriculture; specialised craftsman and tradesman; artistry — these are the fruits only of a society that can afford them, since they necessitate the deindustrialisation of agriculture, factory manufacturing and mass media simultaneously.</p>
<p>So even though Vekllei is by all measures an industrial society; a land of helijets and plenty; the people of this country see automation as the deindustrialisation of society, at least culturally — a return to community employment, decentralised agriculture and tending of the land.</p>
<p>Vekllei is a fundamentally female country. This is what <strong>petticoat society</strong> means. There are plenty of men in it, and quite distinct social constructs for men and women exist in a way that distinguishes the country from traditional progressive projects, but the feminisation of the economy and politics remains. Vekllei economic gender theory understands masculinity as first and foremost a  value to be consumed in industrial society, in a perverse sort of value exchange. Men are first commodified and then broken through work, killed in wars, are suffocated emotionally, and so forth. The very premise of  manhood, as the 1950s understands it (which this world is very much immersed in) is not just a biological or social construct, but an economic one. As Vekllei progresses, and erases these identifiers of masculinity, men will become female first in an economic sense (in a process called economic feminisation), and will eventually become females socially also. These are gender constructs that are essentially still prescribed by traditional Vekllei values, but are tied to the  deindustrialisation of the country. The perfect Vekllei society is one in which the man dies with the machine.</p>
<p>Although Vekllei is not a traditional egalitarian experiment, and is often a land of absurd contradiction in Western political tradition, Vekllei women enjoy a society built for them. Womanhood in the country is not defined by commodity or appearance, but by ideas the culture associates with womanhood — compassion, bravery, intelligence, grace, etc. They are defined not by their relationships or their economic circumstance, but by their friends, political opinions, ability, etc. The decommodification of society has also decommodified womanhood. Vekllei is not simply a good place to be a woman, but is in fact a female country.</p>
<p>Finally, you might have notices a certain set of recurring characters. The girl with short dark hair is Tzipora Desmoines, the character of utopia in this project. Her adoptive father, Baron, is bearded and wears half-framed spectacles. Her friend, Cobian, wears round spectacles and her hair in a ponytail. Their mutual friend, Moise, is heavy-set and has curly hair. Together, they represent a broad demographic of Vekllei people. Baron is descended from Nordic caucasians; vikings from Vekllei&rsquo;s initial settlement. Tzipora and Cobian are descended from both inuits and Scandinavians, in the population explosion that followed Inuit settlement in the Danish territory. Moise is descended from Greek immigrants in the tide of immigration that followed the immediate postwar era. Although there are Vekllei people of colour, they make up a minority of the population.</p>
<p>Hopefully, this guide has helped to introduce you to the world in which Vekllei is situatated. I&rsquo;m likely to expand in the coming days on this section, so stay tuned.</p>
<p>It is a world of nuclear power, gingham and moon colonisation wrapped in the aesthetic of the 50s/60s. There&rsquo;s a lot of poverty and suffering in it, but also tremendous hope. Vekllei is utopia.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>What is Vekllei?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/what-is-vekllei?/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/what-is-vekllei?/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Vekllei is a country in my alt-world; a utopian fever dream of googie aesthetics, participatory economics and nostalgia.
Welcome to the ‘Petticoat Project’, a collection of stories about a country and a girl. The concept is broken down into three sections:
Author: for blog posts and articles on the Petticoat Project, utopian fiction, personal news item, etc. Character: for posts about Tzipora, people in her life, or otherwise events that occur during her time on Earth.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/map.jpg"/> <p>Vekllei is a country in my alt-world; a utopian fever dream of googie aesthetics, participatory economics and nostalgia.</p>
<p>Welcome to the ‘Petticoat Project’, a collection of stories about a country and a girl. The concept is broken down into three sections:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Author:</strong> for blog posts and articles on the Petticoat Project, utopian fiction, personal news item, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Character:</strong> for posts about Tzipora, people in her life, or otherwise events that occur during her time on Earth.</li>
<li><strong>Landscape:</strong> for articles on Vekllei and her society, incorporating all that goes with it.</li>
</ol>
<p>Otherwise, read on for an introduction to this project and what I intend to do with it.</p>
<h2 id="the-epilogue-to-the-epoch-of-rest">
  The Epilogue to the Epoch of Rest
  <a class="anchor" href="#the-epilogue-to-the-epoch-of-rest">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The core of the Vekllei project is in understanding utopian fiction as a viable means for expressing yourself in two arenas. Creative, as a way of articulating a worldview, and personal, as a way of introspection and projection.</p>
<p>In this case, the creative worldview is that of Vekllei  — a thought experiment in economics, socialpolitik, infrastructure, architecture, demographics, spirituality, language, actualisation, etc. The personal product is Tzipora — a character of good mannerisms, language, sense of fashion, ideological disposition, personality and body.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The premise of an epoch of rest is that the problems unique to an author, the conductor of the orchestra, can be reasoned with and turned into beautiful monuments in a way they can’t in reality.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Running low on money? Vekllei does not use money  — go to a cinema, eat out; have a nice time. Likewise, are you shameful of your body or your ability? Tzipora is fraught with problems, too — but look at her! She is beautiful. Repeat this process for all creative arenas and you will find a world you can escape to, away from the problems of your reality.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that utopia and perfection are two different things. A city can be utopian without it being perfect  — a relative judgement. Carrying on in this sense, the concept of utopia can equally be applied to a person. The character is not necessarily a romantic interest or charming or intelligent or sexual product, because none of those things really describe utopia  — instead, a person (a utopian?) is perfect as a collection of ideas and experience. Vekllei is a place of utopia, Tzipora is utopian. And so there are three actors in this project.</p>
<h2 id="the-author">
  The Author
  <a class="anchor" href="#the-author">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The producer of the whole thing, the creative and personal products are theirs, as unique as a fingerprint. They most likely produce a lot of different societies and characters in trying to tell a story, or flesh out an idea they’ve had  — but for the purposes of the idea of an epoch of rest, there are two perfect utopias: landscape (society and the world), and character (personality and appearance).</p>
<h2 id="vekllei-vɛklaɪ">
  Vekllei [/vƐk.laɪ/]
  <a class="anchor" href="#vekllei-v%c9%9bkla%c9%aa">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Vekllei is a country in which the external burdens of the world can be shifted. Worries are relegated to the personal  — an arena in utopian fiction that conveniently still falls under the domain of the author. In Vekllei, self-actualisation is tangible, vivid, only metres away. It might be in creativity or power or love, but it is attainable, because the economic and cultural orchestra of the country is in the imagination of the author, and so it is perfect as by definition of utopia.</p>
<h2 id="tziporazelda-desmoines-dzɪpˈɔːrədɛmwəːnɛːh">
  Tzipora/Zelda Desmoines [/dzɪpˈɔːr.ə’dƐm.wəːn.Ɛːh/]
  <a class="anchor" href="#tziporazelda-desmoines-dz%c9%aap%cb%88%c9%94%cb%90r%c9%99d%c9%9bmw%c9%99%cb%90n%c9%9b%cb%90h">#</a>
</h2>
<p>If Vekllei is the arena of external burden, Tzipora is a girl on which the internal pressures of self-doubt and conscious flaw are cast aside like a rag. In the sense of a narrative, Tzipora might suffer because of her behaviours (her nervous tics, her jealousy, her body and image), but they are adopted in a way that is graceful. So despite her fierce problems, it fades away in the fact that she will not die; she will not be unsuccessful; she will not be unloved. As long as those core premises are true, then every other nervous tic or obsessive-compulsive behaviour are commodity; window-dressing to an aesthetic taste.</p>
<p>This project is sort of what I want to do, and I can’t imagine slowing down anytime soon. Stick around and I’ll do my best materialise the world and story of Vekllei. Thanks for stopping by.</p>
<p>Kind regards,</p>
<p>Hobart Phillips</p>
<p><strong>MelonKony</strong></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
