<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>author on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/author/</link>
	<description>Recent content in author on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Changes to the Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-12-reading/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-12-reading/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This post announced changes made for patrons of Vekllei. Read and discuss the changes made in this post on Patreon here.  Hello everyone,
Hobart here, creator of this whole thing. For a couple years now I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained a small Patreon for those interested in supporting my work. Like most Patreons, this has operated monthly.
From now on, patrons will only be charged on the release of a comic chapter.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>100 Days of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-03-100-days/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-03-100-days/</guid>
	  <description>Hello everyone,
This is 2022, Year of Vekllei.
For the next 100 days I’m going to do something for Vekllei every day. These &amp;lsquo;somethings&amp;rsquo; could be
 Posts you see, exploring Vekllei Articles on the website, including upcoming pages on Government and new character pages. Inking of comic pages &amp;ndash; leading up to a release soon. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming but it&amp;rsquo;ll be worth it. New illustrations for use in merchandise(!</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-01-new-year/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-01-new-year/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Welcome to 2022, year of Vekllei. Here&amp;rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love.  Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&amp;rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meta Moments</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-29-meta/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-29-meta/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This image was a gift to my friend Bez. Thank you Bez.  Occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll join an &amp;ldquo;art trade&amp;rdquo; to change things up and break the repetition of working in one universe with one set of characters. Bez is a friend of mine and a talented artist, and so for Christmas we decided to produce secret works involving characters and places we don&amp;rsquo;t usually draw. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing more exciting as an artist than seeing through new eyes &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s the magic of having someone illustrate your people and places.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Something New is on The Horizon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-30-june/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-30-june/</guid>
	  <description>Thanks for a great June. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of different types of posts this month. About 15 in all — that&amp;rsquo;s one every two days! Not bad! I could do with some sleep.
Something very special is approaching in July. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to share it with you all — so are Tzipora and Cobian. A new chapter in Vekllei is fast approaching.
See you soon.
Much love,
Hobart // MelonKony</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Utopie ❦ Concrète</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-26-utopie/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-26-utopie/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This essay was published on millmint.net. Read it here.  I write introspectively about the project sometimes, as a means by which I consider what I&amp;rsquo;m doing and where my unconscious is leading me with this project. I have the instinct of someone who is over-educated and self-obsessed; someone who went to university, fell for the farce of serious media criticism, and failed to see that all media theorists are basically freaks.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>I have a very good website</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-14-website/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-14-website/</guid>
	  <description>Hi everyone,
Hobart here, informing you that I have a very good website. It has every post I’ve ever made on it, for better or for worse (with the non-canon stuff marked). It has wiki pages that are growing all the time. It has fun things and essays. You can also leave comments!
Just look at the home page. Isn’t that the coolest shit you’ve ever seen? You can see it live at https://millmint.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Sand Mage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-19-mage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-19-mage/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora is a sand mage.
Actually, she isn’t, but I wanted to draw something with particles and ended up doing different paint sketches for a few hours. This was the best one, and also the most stupid.
Canonically, Tzipora can’t swim, so she spends more time on the beach than in the water. The colour of the sand here suggests it’s an artificial “white beach” in Mumen or nearby. Most beaches in Vekllei are black.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>3,000 MEMBERS!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-09-3000/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-09-3000/</guid>
	  <description>Hello,
I’m Hobart, and I’m the creator of this place. I’ve been drawing Vekllei for a few years now, and I love doing it.
To celebrate 3,000 members, use this as a cosy thread/AMA to settle in, and have any questions you might have about the project answered.
For those who are new, I encourage you to read the posts pinned to the top of the subreddit for a crash course in what’s going on here.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Little Bouncy Zelda — an animation diary</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  It&amp;rsquo;s been a week since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted. Most of that was spent drawing the same thing over and over.
A painting? Please. That&amp;rsquo;s a day&amp;rsquo;s work — maybe two. A five second loop of Tzipora jumping in and shuffling over? A week.
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to grasp just how much work animation is until you try it. This runs at 12 frames per second (which dickheads will recognise as the anime frame rate).</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>2,000 members! WOW!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Hello,
I’m Hobart. I’ve been working on this project for a while now. It doesn’t really have a purpose or an end goal — I just want to draw and write about nice things, and I’m learning a lot on the way. Welcome to everyone new here. I don’t really have anything to sell, I’d just like to thank you for tuning in and checking Vekllei out.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>What is This Project?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  What is Vekllei?
Hi, I’m Hobart and I write and draw Vekllei at Studio MillMint.
This is a pretty complex project. Not just complex insofar as there’s a lot to read about it, but that it uses concepts and terminology you might not be familiar with if this is your first time around utopian fiction.
So Vekllei is a utopia — what does this mean?</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Announcing Tzipo-stcards</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</guid>
	  <description>Hello everyone. Just a little update.
As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.
How many cards will the set contain?
 I’m aiming for about six cards.
 How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?
 I think about $20 over your pledge lifetime would cover print and shipping, though I’ll let you know if that goes up or down.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Salad Time</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-11-salad/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-11-salad/</guid>
	  <description>Despite appearances, most of the population of Vekllei are Scandinavian, not Asian.
Zhu is the first time in a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn an ethnically Chinese person. She was graciously lent to me to draw by u/boodyclap in an art trade. You can see his end of the deal here, complete with Tzipora balancing a baseball bat.
In Zhu&amp;rsquo;s homeland she suffers a meat-heavy diet, and Vekllei is the first time she&amp;rsquo;s seen a salad this big.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Timeline</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-05-timeline/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-05-timeline/</guid>
	  <description>This is it. The dates are laid out. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a document that tracks the story thus far. Longtime followers might be surprised by where certain events land.
This post will be pinned and serve as a stopgap until I can complete something more professional on my site.
 CLICK HERE for a timeline of the events so far, and how they line up in this story.
Last Updated: 13/7/2020</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hobart and Tzipora are off to Japan</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora here is wearing a simplified form of Vekllei’s national dress, which plays fast and loose with lace and showcases some of Vekllei’s more decadent iconography. Long gi (decorative quarter-pleats you’ve seen around) accompany sun petticoats, or Vekllei lace aprons. Flowers take the place of astrology or the Zodiac in Vekllei, and so they often accompany spiritual runes (in upotenne, or religious script) about the girl. Other aspects are just as unique, but not nearly as noticeable.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>So long 2019, here&#39;s to 2020!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</guid>
	  <description>Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the new Vekllei discord — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts. Speaking of which, this one is a substitute — the one I’m working on ended up being a bit too sad for an exciting new year, so I’ll put the sad stuff off until Jan 2nd in favour of something happier tomorrow.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Merry Christmas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-26-christmas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-26-christmas/</guid>
	  <description>I’m still eating pudding, but once I’m home tomorrow and settled at my drawing desk I’ll be sure to report Tzipora’s holiday adventures in full.
For the Christmasfolk out there, enjoy your presents. To everyone else, have a good holiday and be sure to celebrate the Australian way — with prawns, salmon and snags on the barbie.
(Gorgeous 25°C [77°F] yesterday)
Best,
Hobart</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sneak Sneak</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-11-sneak/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-11-sneak/</guid>
	  <description>He kept bad hours. Sometimes he worked so hard he came home in the early morning and fell asleep to the television with the subtitles on. Like a guerrilla sighting a commanding officer, she would approach discreetly, wearing her blanket like a cape and bouncing on her toes. With a gentle movement she&amp;rsquo;d drape it over him and listen for a break in his snoring. If he didn&amp;rsquo;t stir, she&amp;rsquo;d find a nook in his shoulder and would stay there till the sunrays woke him in the morning.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Blue Shoes</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-18-blue-shoes/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-18-blue-shoes/</guid>
	  <description>Welcome to the r/Vekllei variety hour, where the tone between posts judders so inconsistently you&amp;rsquo;ll get whiplash of the mind. I was just drawing and thinking today. This is an author post, in case you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed &amp;ndash; just a shitty blog.
You see, even today I&amp;rsquo;m wildly jealous of the success of those slice-of-life artists on reddit and Twitter. I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand the genre entirely, as a phenomenon. It&amp;rsquo;s usually male artists (at least in Japan), drawing distinctly Japanese neighbourhoods and landscapes, and situating a schoolgirl in the midst of it.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>From Beaches to Mountaintops</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-15-mountaintops/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-15-mountaintops/</guid>
	  <description>I had the wonderful opportunity to work with one of our resident worldbuilders on reddit, u/EpicJM, and spend a while with their world and characters. The world of Eipljord has a lot of distinct, unique cultures and characters. As a sucker for uniforms I went with the garb of the Pruscyldan Academy of Magic, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find JM&amp;rsquo;s character, Honora being splattered with ice cream by Tzipora on the left and in Vekllei education uniform on the right.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Like Father, Like Daughter</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-09-beach/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-09-beach/</guid>
	  <description>The main beach in Mumen, the nicest of the seaside districts, is constructed out of sand imported from the dunes of Africa. Where the rest of the country has black sand, a symptom of its volcanic turbulence, Mumen has nice yellow sand.
Baron doesn’t like the water, and getting him down to the sea at all was a trial. Zelda, for her part, sinks faster than lead in water and only ventures into the shallows with Ayn, who herself is afraid of the deeper ocean.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>… where did I leave all the uploads?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-23-uploads/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-23-uploads/</guid>
	  <description>Hello everyone,
Thanks again for subscribing to this subreddit. I’m playing a game of chicken right now pitting my little Vekllei projects against my university work.
Vekllei boys uniforms (and school architecture) is coming later this week, turning Study Week into a Study Month!
Starting from next week, several exciting projects are getting kicked into gear. One is the graphic novel. There’s also the Vekllei wiki, which is under construction. There will be a lot more art.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Challenger Has Appeared!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-19-challenger/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-19-challenger/</guid>
	  <description>Well isn’t this exciting! The talented u/Herald_of_Zena decided to draw Isabelle from his world in the uniforms I posted the other day. It was too much fun not to join in. It turned out to be a classic story told in two parts &amp;ndash; shit weather, put on coat.
It’s a pleasure seeing such a unique style that’s really one of a kind in the worldbuilding scene. It&amp;rsquo;s painterly and soft where a lot of worldbuilders favour a determined, blocky, concept art look.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>500 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-24-500-subscribers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-24-500-subscribers/</guid>
	  <description>Thank you very much everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s very exciting for me. I ordered a cake from Banjos to celebrate but Tzipora got it all over the floor and herself.
Thanks for subscribing. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pushing myself a bit too hard and my writing&amp;rsquo;s suffered for it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I can slow down, I&amp;rsquo;m just not that kind of guy, but I want to promise some exciting adventures in the future as we hang out with Zelda and her loved ones.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>I like bread</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-09-bread/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-09-bread/</guid>
	  <description>I have a research proposal due today, and since I&amp;rsquo;m pretending to still be a university student I suppose I&amp;rsquo;d better do it.
I spend a lot of time thinking about what the hell I&amp;rsquo;m doing with my life, and after a while I get hungry. Banjos &amp;ndash; a very Australian name for a bakery chain &amp;ndash; satiates my existential hunger with two bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves for $10. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what that would be in American money.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Brief Introduction to Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-an-introduction/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-an-introduction/</guid>
	  <description>Editor&amp;rsquo;s note: this article, while ready for reading, is still under construction.
Considering both the length and convoluted terminology that embroil this project, there was only so long I could carry on before people started getting lost. The truth of it is that Vekllei is not a particularly complex or difficult project to summarise, despite the snapshot &amp;ldquo;lore in scenes&amp;rdquo; approach that kneecaps a complete understanding. I&amp;rsquo;m just lazy.
In fact, Vekllei is not a particularly challenging idea.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>What is Vekllei?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei is a country in my alt-world; a utopian fever dream of googie aesthetics, participatory economics and nostalgia.
Welcome to the ‘Petticoat Project’, a collection of stories about a country and a girl. The concept is broken down into three sections:
 Author: for blog posts and articles on the Petticoat Project, utopian fiction, personal news item, etc. Character: for posts about Tzipora, people in her life, or otherwise events that occur during her time on Earth.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>