<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>andre on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/andre/</link>
    <description>Recent content in andre on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/andre/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei Rumba</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-18-rumba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-18-rumba/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/rjcqpl/vekllei_rumba/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coretti Adoula was a good singer but didn’t sing much&lt;/strong&gt;. Tzipora had regarded her politely but distantly for a while after Moise started dating her in 10th grade. It was an awkward thing. Tzipora was not quite sure how to strike up a conversation — maybe she was a little insecure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti was an Afro-Russian, but had lived in Vekllei since she was six. She spoke without an accent and was well-accustomed to life in Vekllei. Tzipora had been born in Vekllei, but here she stood, short and stupid with the clumsy, childish accent of a foreigner. She was very self-conscious about her foreignness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a contest of appearances. Moise was Tzipora’s first male friend, and so she paid attention to who he liked. Coretti was tall, sweet-natured, pretty and had dark skin of the kind Tzipora hadn’t seen before. Every time she saw Coretti, Tzipora was suddenly aware of how short, bad-mannered and pale she was. In some ways, they were opposed in his orbit, competing for Moise’s time and affection as satellites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the time Moise and Coretti started dating, Tzipora was spending a lot of time in clubs, immersing herself in the Lola jazz scene. It was a fantastic time to be in it — Lola is a neighbourhood of migrants, and you had all the sounds of the world ringing out across the borough. Tzipora loved jazz — she liked any kind of interesting, syncopated and percussive music — and Coretti’s brother was the drummer in a Congolese rumba band called &lt;em&gt;Rats de Brazzaville&lt;/em&gt;. His name was Andre. Tzipora knew him well. &lt;em&gt;Rats de Brazzaville&lt;/em&gt; were a big band with a big sound, which made them a big deal for dance clubs. She had probably seen them play a dozen times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk about a small world. When Coretti brought it up, the usually quiet Tzipora looked up — &lt;em&gt;Andre Adoula? From the Brazzaville Rats? How do you know him?&lt;/em&gt; All it took was that coincidence and a love of rumba, and all of Tzipora’s misgivings about Coretti were forgotten. Why should she sit here and pity herself? It feels better to dance, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>