<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Republic</title>
	<link>/series/republic/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Republic </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/series/republic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Aismious</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/aismious/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/aismious/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Aismious is part of the Volcanic Aismious Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of the Volcanic Commonwealth Capital Thor&#39;s Harbour Population 64,337 Area 1,393 km2 Languages Aismious, English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Aismious Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the North Atlantic Ocean. It comprises a group of 17 inhabited islands between Oslola and the Shetland Islands of the United Kingdom, as well as numerous islets and reefs.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Aismious is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/fo.svg);"></span> Aismious Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/aismious.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of the <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic Commonwealth</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Thor&#39;s Harbour</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>64,337</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>1,393 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Aismious, English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-fo"></span> <strong>Aismious Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the North Atlantic Ocean. It comprises a group of 17 inhabited islands between <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a> and the Shetland Islands of the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(200, 16, 47); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(200, 16, 47) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/uk/"><span class="fi fi-gb"></span> United Kingdom</a>, as well as numerous islets and reefs. The people there are mostly of Celtic-Scandinavian stock descended from Irish settlers and Norsemen. The republic is known for its conspicuous and perpendicular cliffs and flat summits, and its gothic medieval cathedral in the village of Magnus.</p>
<p>About a third of the population live in the capital and largest city, Thor&rsquo;s Harbour. The remainder live in small communities scattered across the islands, which are characterised by fjords, river valleys and dramatic volcanic terrain. The climate is mild, though rain and fog is common. Treeless, mossy and without indigenous land mammals or reptiles, the Aismious Islands have a stark, volcanic appearance similar to <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>.</p>
<p>The economy remains dependent on cod fishing and raising livestock, though undersea oil drilling has recently begun and attracted investment in the capital. The islanders have a strong tradition of oral storytelling and history, which have carried stories for over a thousand years. Islanders speak Aismious, a language similar to Scandi-Oslolan with Celtic elements.</p>
<p>The islands are serviced by hydrofoils and an water airport in the capital, as well as trams between the larger settlements.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Allia</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/allia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/allia/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Allia is part of Kalina Allia Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Athlone Population 16,302 Area 102 km2 Languages Irish, Allia Creole, English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Allia Republic is a constituent republic in the Caribbean Sea, and part of the Lesser Antilles island chain that make up the Kalina Commonwealth, which is part of Vekllei. Its closest neighbour, Antigua, is just under 50km to its northeast.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Allia is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/ms.svg);"></span> Allia Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/allia.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Athlone</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>16,302</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>102 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Irish, Allia Creole, English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-ms"></span> <strong>Allia Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> in the Caribbean Sea, and part of the Lesser Antilles island chain that make up the Kalina Commonwealth, which is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. Its closest neighbour, <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(133, 122, 187); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(133, 122, 187) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/antigua/"><span class="fi fi-antigua"></span> Antigua</a>, is just under 50km to its northeast.</p>
<p>Often called the &ldquo;Emerald Isle&rdquo; of the Caribbean, Allia&rsquo;s history and culture is heavily influenced by British settlement of indebted and enslaved Irish and African peoples, whose descendants make up almost all of the 16,000 people who live there today. Like all Vekllei <a href="/republics/">republics</a>, the language of government and business is English, but Alliot households speak Irish primarily and many speak Allia Creole, a combination of Irish and indigenous Kalinago languages influenced by neighbouring islands. As such, Allia has the largest population of Irish speakers outside of Ireland. They are mostly Roman Catholic.</p>
<p>Allia was uninhabited during the time of its settling by the British in the 17th Century. It was during this first century that the plantation economy started receiving shipments of slaves from Africa and later Ireland, a practice that continued up until the abolishment of slavery in the early 19th Century. It remained part of the UK in various forms until the independence of the British Atlantic Territories and subsequently became part of Vekllei. Today, its economy is mostly agricultural, but its strong music scene and creative industries are thriving in the capital of Athlone, and contribute to Allia&rsquo;s outsized cultural influence in Vekllei. Its unique history makes it a popular destination for Vekllei tourists, as well as some foreigners.</p>
<p>The island is about 18km long by 10km wide and resembles a pear. It has rugged, volcanic mountains with long pyroclastic slopes that stretch to the water. These mountains are thickly forested with jungle typical of its tropical Caribbean region. The island is actively volcanic and eruptions occur periodically, most recently in the mid-1990s when the Soufrière Hills erupted and destroyed mostly uninhabited areas in the island&rsquo;s southwest.</p>
<p>Most Alliots live in the capital of Athlone, but there are estates and villages that circumnavigate the entire coast. They are connected by a mainline train service, as well as small trams and funiculars. Allia is connected to the rest of Kalina by fast hydrofoils and flying boats.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Aloi</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloi/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloi/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Aloi is part of Kalina Aloi Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Concordia Population 12,404 Area 154 km2 Languages English, Arawak Creole Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Aloi Republic (also Alli) is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Kalina archipelago. It is a small, cashew-shaped island defined by two conspicuous mountains in its north and south. The majority of its 12,000 people live in the saddle of flat land between them.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Aloi is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/aloi.svg);"></span> Aloi Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/aloi.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Concordia</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>12,404</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>154 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Arawak Creole</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-aloi"></span> <strong>Aloi Republic</strong> (also <em>Alli</em>) is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Kalina archipelago. It is a small, cashew-shaped island defined by two conspicuous mountains in its north and south. The majority of its 12,000 people live in the saddle of flat land between them.</p>
<p>Aloi has scarce natural resources and historically was known for its maritime commerce, particularly for its part in the trans-Atlantic slave trade and the sale of weapons to the U.S. during its revolution. It was discovered and colonised by the British in the 17th Century, who displaced native Caribs and exercised limited control over its population of mostly Jewish and Dutch traders.</p>
<p>The capital of Condordia is a historic and beautiful maritime town, iconic for its old stone warehouses along the waterfront and the British fort in its centre. Almost every employed person on Aloi works for the <a href="/government/">government</a>, either in its administration, schools, or the power company. It is closely connected to the nearby islands of Liamuiga and Saba by hydrofoil, and by the airstrip on the Atlantic side for longer journeys.</p>
<p>A dormant volcano known as The Quill marks the highest point on the island, and its crater conceals a dark forest filled with tropical vegetation and flowers. Trade winds strike the Atlantic side of the island and little grows there, but the Caribbean side is home to breadfruit and banana groves. The island suffers poor rainfall and common cisterns collect it for domestic use. Most Aloians grow their own produce, and speak English and an Arawak Creole.</p>
<details open>
	<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Quill</strong>: a dormant volcano and national park with trails and a forested crater.</li>
<li><strong>Fort Elizabeth</strong>: Historic British naval fort, now a museum.</li>
<li><strong>Boven Botanical Garden</strong>: European-style botanical garden with examples of almost every kinds of vegetation on Aloi.</li>
<li><strong>Aloi United Banana Company</strong>: Oldest banana company in continuous operation in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Golden Rock Memorial Graves Site</strong>: Burial ground of enslaved peoples on the site of the former Golden Rock plantation.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Aloubaera</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloubaera/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloubaera/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Aloubaera is part of Kalina Aloubaera Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Scarborough Population 72,045 Area 300 km2 Languages English, Creole, Spanish Vekllei Accession 1930, as part of the Alford Agreement The Aloubaera Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei, and parts of the Kalina Commonwealth. It is just 35km northeast of its neighbour republic of Kairi.
Aloubaera has a tropical climate cooled substantially by its exposure to the sea.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Aloubaera is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/aloubaera.svg);"></span> Aloubaera Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/aloubaera.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Scarborough</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>72,045</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>300 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Creole, Spanish</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1930, as part of the Alford Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-aloubaera"></span> <strong>Aloubaera Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and parts of the Kalina Commonwealth. It is just 35km northeast of its neighbour republic of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(215, 18, 45); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(215, 18, 45) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/"><span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> Kairi</a>.</p>
<p>Aloubaera has a tropical climate cooled substantially by its exposure to the sea. Most of the island is hilly, and reaches 550m above sea level at its highest point. Its interior is home to dense biodiverse rainforest, most of which is protected within the Aloubaera National Forest. It is vulnerable to seasonal hurricanes moving along the south hurricane belt.</p>
<p>Most Aloubaerans are black or mixed-race of African descent, though minority populations of Whites, Caribs and Indians also live there. The republic remains dependent on <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(215, 18, 45); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(215, 18, 45) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/"><span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> Kairi</a> for electricity and tertiary education. A local creole and English are widely spoken.</p>
<p>The republic&rsquo;s economy consists of municipal goods, light agriculture in communal smallholdings, and some domestic tourism. It has spectacular coral reefs in its south, and there is a hotel there. Nonetheless, island life on Aloubaera is insular and close-knit, and many young Aloubaerans leave for Kairi or other parts of Vekllei for study and work.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Anguilla</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/anguilla/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/anguilla/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Anguilla is part of Kalina Anguilla Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital The Valley Population 35,722 Area 91 km2 Languages English, Arawak Creole Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Anguilla Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Kalina archipelago, east of Virgin and north of Soualiga. It is a long, slender island resembling an eel, from which its name is derived.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Anguilla is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/ai.svg);"></span> Anguilla Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/anguilla.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/ai.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/ai.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>The Valley</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>35,722</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>91 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Arawak Creole</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-ai"></span> <strong>Anguilla Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Kalina archipelago, east of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(241, 112, 30); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(241, 112, 30) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/virgin/"><span class="fi fi-vg"></span> Virgin</a> and north of Soualiga. It is a long, slender island resembling an eel, from which its name is derived. It is best known in Vekllei for its easygoing, maritime culture and architecture. Its population of 35,000 are scattered across the main coral island, which is flat and lacks fresh water. A handful of satellite islands and islets remain uninhabited.</p>
<p>Anguilla was originally settled by Arawaks from South America, who comprise about a fifth of the population today. Like most of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a>, it was occupied by the British during the colonial period and served a plantation economy based on tobacco and later on sugar. Slaves traded from Africa were forced to work in this economy, whose descendants make up most of the remaining population today. Anguillan culture is informal and easygoing, and in industrial terms the island provides little to the overall economy of its commonwealth. It is a popular day-trip for Soualigans, who visit for the music, sport and food. Anguilla is also famous for its boat racing, which culminates in the West Indies Boat Race each February.</p>
<p>Today, Anguilla&rsquo;s economy is dominated by municipal goods, salt, fish, lobster, and some experiments in seawater power generation conducted by <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a>. It has little arable land and imports most of its food, though common vegetable plots are found throughout their communities. A train line runs from West End to East End, with branched tram lines in The Valley and towards the village of Island Harbour.</p>
<p>The surface of Anguilla is pockmarked by saltwater pools, and the coral island has exquisite beaches that are enjoyed by residents and visitors alike. It lacks a traditional colonial capital, since it was administered in Soualiga during the colonial period. Consequently, Anguilla built many fine examples of Caribbean Modernist architecture during its redevelopment as part of postwar <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and good quality architecture is ubiquitous throughout the republic.</p>
<details open>
	<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>Anguilla Republic Council Building</strong>: A mammoth modernist seat of government famous for its intricate brickwork and mosaics.</li>
<li><strong>Dauphine Estates</strong>: Acclaimed tower block complex in the Caribbean Prairie style.</li>
<li><strong>Rendezvous</strong>: Popular bar and restaurant that has produced many regionally famous musicians.</li>
<li><strong>Shoal Bay</strong>: Popular tourist beach with pristine white sand.</li>
<li><strong>Leeward Salt Company</strong>: Local salt company and largest private employer on the island.</li>
<li><strong>Island Harbour Docks</strong>: Public boat construction and repair facilities.</li>
<li><strong>Anguilla Electric Laboratories</strong>: Seawater electricity generation complex operated by the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a>.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Antigua</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/antigua/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/antigua/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Antigua is part of Kalina Antigua Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Caribbea Population 327,800 Area 281 km2 Languages English, Arawak Creole Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Antiguan Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Kalina archipelago, northeast of Allia and south of Barbary. It is roughly triangular, with an intricate coastline ringed by smaller islands and islets.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Antigua is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/antigua.svg);"></span> Antigua Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/antigua.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/antigua.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/antigua.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Caribbea</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>327,800</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>281 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Arawak Creole</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-antigua"></span> <strong>Antiguan Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Kalina archipelago, northeast of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(6, 136, 72); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(6, 136, 72) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/allia/"><span class="fi fi-ms"></span> Allia</a> and south of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(110, 110, 110); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(110, 110, 110) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/barbary/"><span class="fi fi-barbary"></span> Barbary</a>. It is roughly triangular, with an intricate coastline ringed by smaller islands and islets. Redonda, a small uninhabited island used historically for guano mining, lies between Allia and Oualie.</p>
<p>Antigua was originally inhabited by Arawaks, who were displaced by Caribs in the 12th Century. Antigua still has a large indigenous Carib minority population today. It was discovered by Europeans in the 15th Century and colonised by the British 200 years later. Antigua acted as a gateway for British interests in the Caribbean, and became a very successful sugar plantation with the labour of enslaved Caribs and Africans. Production there was disturbed by slave rebellions, but remained lucrative until the abolishment of slavery in the 19th Century, from which it declined for the next 100 years.</p>
<p>In place of sugar, Antigua has had to leverage its history as an entrepôt and invested in its education sector. Antigua is the site of the original Commonwealth National University of the West Indies (CUWI) campus, founded in 1849. Today, education makes up most of the Antiguan economy, and is a primary destination for students relocating from smaller neighbouring islands like <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(6, 136, 72); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(6, 136, 72) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/allia/"><span class="fi fi-ms"></span> Allia</a> and Karu. It is also a major sponsor of foreign exchange and overseas study for the wider Caribbean, and hosts several prestigious international schools.</p>
<p>Antigua is mostly flat, with hills in its southwest culminating in Independence Peak at 400m. Settlements and agriculture cover most of the flat land, the largest of which is the capital, Caribbea. Its prosperous colleges and universities are located there, and the settlements leading southeast are involved in tropical crops and textiles. Cosgrove, in Antigua&rsquo;s southwest coast, is the site of a major Universal Cotton factory.</p>
<p>Fast hydrofoils leave Caribbea&rsquo;s port daily, collecting students from neighbouring islands. V.C. Bird International is its major airport and has daily service to other parts of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a>. Two main rail lines run across and around the island respectively, and both Caribbea and Cosgrove have tram networks. Caribbea is also home to Naval Station Antigua, the second-largest naval service base and dockyard in Kalina.</p>
<details open>
	<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>Commonwealth National University of the West Indies</strong>: Historic and thriving main campus of Kalina&rsquo;s oldest university, second only to Vekllei National University in its size.</li>
<li><strong>Universal Cotton Plant of the West Indies</strong>: Large textiles manufacturer that produces much of Vekllei&rsquo;s clothing output in the Kalina region.</li>
<li><strong>Naval Station Antigua</strong>: Large naval service base and dockyard, and home of the Kalina Auxiliary Fleet.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Industrial Caribbean Bank</strong>: Modernist bank headquarters that regularly hosts visitors from the US and Central America.</li>
<li><strong>Antigua Recreational Grounds</strong>: Large cricket stadium and host of the North Kalina Regional Cup.</li>
<li><strong>Dickenson Bay</strong>: Beautiful white beach with old-fashioned promenade and arcade.</li>
<li><strong>Nelson&rsquo;s Dockyard</strong>: Historic British naval dockyard open to the public, now part of Naval Station Antigua.</li>
<li><strong>Devil&rsquo;s Bridge</strong>: Eroded limestone arches, rumoured to be the site of mass suicides during the slavery era.</li>
<li><strong>Antigua National Gallery</strong>: Cosmopolitan and modern art, and the stomping ground of emerging student artists.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ascension</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/ascension/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/ascension/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Ascension is part of Antarctic Ascension Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Antarctica Capital Adara Population 14,232 Area 88 km2 Languages English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Ascension Republic is a constituent republic in the Atlantic Ocean, and part of Antarctic. Rocky, isolated and arid, Ascension is over 1,000km away from Helena, its closest neighbour.
Ascension is home to around 14,000 people, most of whom work for or are associated with the Vekllei World Astroport and the air service base outside the capital, Adara.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Ascension is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Antarctic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/ac.svg);"></span> Ascension Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/ascension.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/ascension.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Commonwealth Antarctica</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Adara</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>14,232</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>88 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-ac"></span> <strong>Ascension Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> in the Atlantic Ocean, and part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Antarctic</a>. Rocky, isolated and arid, Ascension is over 1,000km away from <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(24, 117, 71); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(24, 117, 71) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/helena/"><span class="fi fi-sh"></span> Helena</a>, its closest neighbour.</p>
<p>Ascension is home to around 14,000 people, most of whom work for or are associated with the <a href="/cosmodrome/">Vekllei World Astroport</a> and the <a href="/military/">air service</a> base outside the capital, Adara. Its proximity to the equator and strategic centrality in the Atlantic have encouraged military development of the island republic, including air bases, telecommunications facilities, intelligence systems and satellite tracking. It is also home to a large naval dockyard, and rumoured to be part of the Vekllei air-delivered strategic nuclear arsenal.</p>
<p>Ascension was first settled by the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(200, 16, 47); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(200, 16, 47) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/uk/"><span class="fi fi-gb"></span> United Kingdom</a> in 1815, but remained a military outpost until the late 19th Century during the formation of the British Atlantic Territories. When the British Atlantic Territories became the independent Commonwealth of Oceans in 1935, Ascension became a dependent territory of the new country, and eventually inherited membership as a <a href="/republics/">republic</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the postwar period.</p>
<p>Around 90 square km, Ascension is a desert of volcanic lava flows and craters. Green Mountain has most of the island&rsquo;s vegetation, including small forests and land for growing fruits and vegetables, which are watered by small springs and catchment basins.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Barbados</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/barbados/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/barbados/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Barbados is part of Kalina Barbados Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Indian Bridge Population 1,420,421 Area 439 km2 Languages English, Bajan Creole Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Barbados Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Kalina archipelago, east of Youloumain and northeast of the Aloubaera. Although it is grouped with the rest of Kalina, it is technically an Atlantic rather than Caribbean island, and is relatively flat for an island of its size.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Barbados is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/bb.svg);"></span> Barbados Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/barbados.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/bb.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/bb.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Indian Bridge</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>1,420,421</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>439 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Bajan Creole</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-bb"></span> <strong>Barbados Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Kalina archipelago, east of Youloumain and northeast of the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(46, 114, 225); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(46, 114, 225) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloubaera/"><span class="fi fi-aloubaera"></span> Aloubaera</a>. Although it is grouped with the rest of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a>, it is technically an Atlantic rather than Caribbean island, and is relatively flat for an island of its size. It is roughly triangular and densely populated, with most of its residents clustered around the capital of Indian Bridge on the southwest coast.</p>
<p>Uninhabited upon European discovery, Barbados has a long history as a gateway to the Lesser Antilles and South America. The island was settled by the British in the 17th Century and was reincorporated as part of the British Atlantic Territories in 1836. It gained independence along with the rest of the Territories a century later. Like the rest of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a>, the culture and demography of Barbados is heavily influenced by the legacy of slavery, and the majority of Barbadians are descended from Africans.</p>
<p>Sugar production dominated the Barbadian economy until the mid-20th Century, but the island was forced to diversify as prices and demand fell. It was supplemented by minor reserves of oil and natural gas, as well as fish and sugar derivatives like molasses. In the postwar <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> period, the export-heavy economy was corrected to better support its large and urban population through the development of hydroponic and agricultural cooperatives, and municipal manufacturing. Barbados is home to the largest robotics factory in Vekllei, which produces mostly industrial and construction automatons for <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(224, 40, 35); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(224, 40, 35) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/national-machines/"><span class="fi fi-min-national-machines fis"></span> National Machines</a>.</p>
<p>A patchwork of farms, mostly privately owned, quilt the wide tracts of arable land outside the capital. Barbados is the most densely-populated island in the Eastern Caribbean, and consequently is well-served by sophisticated Vekllei transport infrastructure. A coastal and interior rail line serve medium-distance routes, and trams and a metro are available in Indian Bridge. Travel to the island is primarily served by Sobers International Jetport and hydrofoils to neighbouring republics, and long-distance cruises also operate from the capital.</p>
<details open>
<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>Kensington Oval</strong>: Historic stadium with a strong cricket tradition.</li>
<li><strong>Gun Hill Barracks</strong>: Largest territorial service military base in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a> with historic, colonial-era barracks and signal station in use.</li>
<li><strong>Farley Hill Estate &amp; National Park</strong>: Hilltop mansion with lush colonial gardens.</li>
<li><strong>Barbados National Robotics Plant</strong>: Largest robotics manufacturing complex in Vekllei owned by <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(224, 40, 35); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(224, 40, 35) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/national-machines/"><span class="fi fi-min-national-machines fis"></span> National Machines</a>.</li>
<li><strong>National Machines Laboratories</strong>: <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(224, 40, 35); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(224, 40, 35) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/national-machines/"><span class="fi fi-min-national-machines fis"></span> National Machines</a> robotics testing and development firm.</li>
<li><strong>Barbados Museum</strong>: Large, multi-interest museum and headquarters of the local historical society.</li>
<li><strong>Combermere School</strong>: Among the oldest schools in the Caribbean, founded in 1695. Still operating as a public secondary school today.</li>
<li><strong>Bloomsbury Botanical Gardens</strong>: Beautiful horticultural gardens maintained by Barbados University.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Barbary</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/barbary/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/barbary/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Barbados is part of Kalina Barbary Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Freetown Population 58,629 Area 160.56 km2 Languages English, Barbary Creole Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Barbary Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei on the northeast periphery of the Kalina archipelago, north of Antigua. It is a flat, wooded coral island without a source of fresh water. Its capital and only settlement, Freetown, lies on the edge of Barbary Lagoon in the northwest.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Barbados is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/barbary.svg);"></span> Barbary Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/barbary.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/barbary.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/barbary.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Freetown</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>58,629</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>160.56 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Barbary Creole</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-barbary"></span> <strong>Barbary Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> on the northeast periphery of the Kalina archipelago, north of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(133, 122, 187); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(133, 122, 187) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/antigua/"><span class="fi fi-antigua"></span> Antigua</a>. It is a flat, wooded coral island without a source of fresh water. Its capital and only settlement, Freetown, lies on the edge of Barbary Lagoon in the northwest.</p>
<p>Originally inhabited by Arawaks, Barbary was known during the colonial period as Codrington&rsquo;s Island, named for the absentee family that operated it as a slave estate between the 17th and 19th centuries. It was never part of the sugar plantation system, and was struck by two major slave rebellions prior to the outlawing of slavery in the British Empire in 1834. After incorporation into the British Atlantic Territories, Codrington&rsquo;s formerly enslaved residents had autonomy from the dominion and established common farms and fishing grounds. Land during this period was held communally, a practice that continues in the present day. Most residents are black, descended from enslaved people, but there are growing populations of Verde whites and Chinese.</p>
<p>Barbary has a small, close-knit community that works mostly in local agriculture and municipal goods. The civil service makes up most of its formal revenues, which operates a single hospital and a few schools. Most locals go to <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(133, 122, 187); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(133, 122, 187) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/antigua/"><span class="fi fi-antigua"></span> Antigua</a> for university. An airstrip in the south offers transport to larger airports as well as a base for recreational flying. Barbary has only has a single commuter rail service &ndash; a tram from Freetown to Coco Point &ndash; and bicycles and mopeds are typically used to get around. The interior of the island is well-wooded, and fringed by accessible beaches of high quality.</p>
<details open>
<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>Barbary Frigate Bird Sanctuary</strong>: Protected nesting grounds for the magnificent frigate bird, located in the mangroves on Barbary Lagoon.</li>
<li><strong>Darby Sinkhole</strong>: Large, 20 meter sinkhole with vegetation.</li>
<li><strong>Indian Cave</strong>: Coastal cave with freshwater pools and Arawak petroglyphs inside.</li>
<li><strong>River Fort</strong>: British colonial fort with a tower for gun emplacements.</li>
<li><strong>Government House</strong>: Colonial-era government house, now the seat of the Barbary Parliament.</li>
<li><strong>The Ginnery</strong>: Historic warehouse built in the 19th Century, now part of the Barbary Secondary School.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Caimanas</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/antilles/caimanas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/antilles/caimanas/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the territories series of articles The Republic of Caimanas is a constituent country of Vekllei consisting of three island city-states in the West Caribbean.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/territories/">territories</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Republic of Caimanas</strong> is a constituent country of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> consisting of three island city-states in the West Caribbean.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Cama</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/cama/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/cama/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Cama is part of Kalina Cama Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Assumpción Population 454,820 Area 348.5 km2 Languages English, Cama Creole, French Vekllei Accession 1930, as part of the Alford Agreement The Cama Republic (Isle of Spice) is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Caribbean. It lies about 130km northwest of Aloubaera, and its northernmost island of Petite Martinique is just south of the southernmost part of the Youloumain island chain.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Cama is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/gd.svg);"></span> Cama Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/cama.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/gr.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/gr.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Assumpción</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>454,820</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>348.5 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Cama Creole, French</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1930, as part of the Alford Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-gd"></span> <strong>Cama Republic</strong> (Isle of Spice) is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Caribbean. It lies about 130km northwest of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(46, 114, 225); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(46, 114, 225) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloubaera/"><span class="fi fi-aloubaera"></span> Aloubaera</a>, and its northernmost island of Petite Martinique is just south of the southernmost part of the Youloumain island chain. It comprises three inhabited islands, and countless islets numbering at least 600. The capital, Assumpción, is situated on the southwest coast of the island of Cama.</p>
<p>The origin of Cama is volcanic, and the interior of its main island is mountainous. The capital has a good deepwater harbour and is renowned for its beautiful and bright-coloured waterfront area and homes. Grand Etang, a lake in the crater of an extinct volcano at 530 meters, provides some fresh water to its municipalities. Like much of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> Caribbean, about four fifths of Camans are descended from black slaves brought there by the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(200, 16, 47); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(200, 16, 47) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/uk/"><span class="fi fi-gb"></span> United Kingdom</a> to work Cama&rsquo;s plantation economy. Other populations, including indigenous Caribs and Indians descended from indebted labourers who replaced the slave system, make up the remainder. They are mostly Christian, with minor Islamic and Hindu populations. They enjoy a tropical climate with a dry and rainy season, tempered by ocean breezes.</p>
<p>By Vekllei standards, life on Cama remains remarkably agrarian and agricultural products make up much of its economy. The municipalisation of the republic in the postwar period has seen many of its plantations converted into co-operative farms, which grow a variety of citrus fruits and tropical plants including nutmeg, of which Cama contributes about 40% of the world&rsquo;s total supply. The transition from subsistence farming to the <a href="/social-economy/">commons</a> has reduced the overall participation of labour in agriculture, which now is mostly undertaken to maintain a claim on land. Most other products are &lsquo;municipal goods,&rsquo; comprising staple crops and some light industry. Manufacturing, found mostly in the capital, is dominated by brewing, cigarette manufacturing and textiles.</p>
<p>The island of Cama is home to the Vekllei National Medical University, the most prestigious medical institution in Vekllei. Its students make up about an eighth of the republic&rsquo;s total population. Cama and its minor inhabited islands of Carriacou and Petite Martinique are linked by hydrofoil. The capital has a tram network, and narrow-gauge rail circumnavigates its coastline. The only civilian airport is located southwest of the capital. Cama is also the headquarters of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(60, 120, 200); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(60, 120, 200) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/atlantis/"><span class="fi fi-min-atlantis fis"></span> Atlantis</a>, the primary shipping <a href="/bureaus/">bureau corporation</a> of the country, which also operates a port in Assumpción.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Major Industries</summary>
* **Agriculture**
	* Cocoa
	* Nutmeg
	* Mace
	* Bananas
	* Lemons & Limes
	* Mangoes
	* Passionfruit
	* Tamarind
	* Guava
* **Manufacturing**
	* Textiles & Clothing
	* Brewing
	* Sugar Milling
	* Copra Processing
	* Mace & Nutmeg Processing
	* Canning
	* Soapmaking
	* Cigarette & Cigar Manufacturing
</details>
<details open>
  <summary>Major Corporations</summary>
* <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(60, 120, 200); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(60, 120, 200) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/atlantis/"><span class="fi fi-min-atlantis fis"></span> Atlantis</a>
* Caribbea Cooperative Breweries
* Cama Nutmeg (bureau)
* The Virgin Chocolate Company
* Cama Bottling Company
* Meridian Paints
* Marine Cama
* Federal Textiles
* Island Foods Cannery
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Demon</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/demon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/demon/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Demon is part of the Volcanic Demon Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Capital Aran Population 13,947 Area 377 km2 Languages English, Latin, Irish Vekllei Accession 1840, gifted to the British Atlantic Territories The Republic of Demon is an island republic in the North Atlantic, and part of the country of Vekllei. It was discovered by Irish settlers in the 13th Century, where they settled at the base of the Birianvik, or Mt Birian Volcano.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Demon is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/demon.svg);"></span> Demon Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/demon.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Aran</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>13,947</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>377 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Latin, Irish</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1840, gifted to the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-demon"></span> <strong>Republic of Demon</strong> is an island republic in the North Atlantic, and part of the country of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It was discovered by Irish settlers in the 13th Century, where they settled at the base of the Birianvik, or Mt Birian Volcano. Its capital, Aran, exists on this site and is home to about 14,000 people today.</p>
<p>Desolate, windy and cold, Demon is isolated by 500km of water from Kala, its closest neighbour. Its economy is dominated by fishing, community agriculture, the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Armed Forces</a> and tourism. Demon has few trees but a little tundra, and is home to arctic foxes, seabirds and all manner of North Atlantic sea life.</p>
<p>After Irish settlers established Aran in the 13th Century, a monastery was built by monks on the slope of Birianvik, making it the oldest in Vekllei. It continues to operate today on the site of the original monastery, which was destroyed by an eruption in the 18th Century. The town of Aran was abandoned twice in the 15th and 18th centuries, but the monastery has operated continuously since its founding. This heritage, collections of relics and strong religiosity among its citizens are part of the culture of Demon, and contribute to its flag which features a Black Madonna.</p>
<p>Demon can be accessed by hydrofoil or ship at Port Aran in its capital and only major settlement, and there is a combined civilian and military aerodrome on the southern region with a couple regional flights each day. A single tramline connects Aran with the farms and villages in the south.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Falklands</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/falklands/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/falklands/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Falklands are part of Antarctic Falklands Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Antarctica Capital Stanley Population 8,682 Area 12,173 km2 Languages English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Falklands Republic is a constituent republic in the South Atlantic Ocean, and part of the commonwealth of Antarctica. A densely vegetated, though treeless country comprising two main islands and hundreds of smaller ones, the Falklands is among the southernmost Vekllei republics.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">The Falklands are part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Antarctic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/fk.svg);"></span> Falklands Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/falklands.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Commonwealth Antarctica</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Stanley</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>8,682</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>12,173 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-fk"></span> <strong>Falklands Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> in the South Atlantic Ocean, and part of the commonwealth of Antarctica. A densely vegetated, though treeless country comprising two main islands and hundreds of smaller ones, the Falklands is among the southernmost Vekllei republics. It is located around 400km northeast of the southern tip of South America.</p>
<p>Four-fifths of its British-descended population live in the capital, Stanley, and the remainder are mostly sheep farmers. The Falklands are a major producer of real lamb in Vekllei, and Falklanders consume on average much more non-synthesised meat than other Vekllei republics.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Habacoa</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/lucaya/habacoa/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/lucaya/habacoa/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Habacoa is part of the Lucayan Commonwealth. Habacia Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Capital Kipri Population 204,038 Area 5,957 km2 Languages English, Lucayan Creole Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Habacoan Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei on the northeast periphery of the Lucayan archipelago, west of Nema and south of Lucayoneque. It is the largest island of the Lucayan Commonwealth, and is fragmented by many inlets and cays.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Habacoa is part of the Lucayan Commonwealth.</span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/habacoa.svg);"></span> Habacia Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/habacoa.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/habacoa.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/habacoa.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Kipri</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>204,038</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>5,957 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Lucayan Creole</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-habacoa"></span> <strong>Habacoan Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> on the northeast periphery of the Lucayan archipelago, west of Nema and south of Lucayoneque. It is the largest island of the Lucayan Commonwealth, and is fragmented by many inlets and cays.</p>
<p>Comprising flat, wooded limestone islands linked by mangroves, Habacoa is sparsely populated for an island of its size. It has a fifth of the population of neighbouring Nema, and so its modest settlements are mostly spread up and down the east coast. The Habacoan Barrier Reef to its east is the third largest reef in the world, and is recognised internationally for its significance and diversity.</p>
<p>The Habacoan economy is municipal and agricultural, and its major employers are all institutions of Commonwealth government. The <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a> operates the National Marine Establishment in the town of Mars, and the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Armed Forces</a> maintains the National Ocean Test Facility at the capital of Kipri. The republic is known for its seafood, and fishing is still the most common registered occupation on the island. This diet is supplemented by local crops of vegetables and tropical fruit.</p>
<p>A rail line runs from north to south on the east coast. The west and interior of the island is mostly protected by the Habacoa National Park, which has boardwalks and paths for visitors. Increasingly, the island is a popular place to dive among <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> people, who travel from all over the country to visit its reefs. An airstrip with basic facilities is found outside the town of Mars and within the military facility in Kipri, but realistically most Habacoans transit to Nema for air journeys.</p>
<details open>
<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>National Marine Establishment</strong>: Scientific marine studies centre and base of operations for the Marine Division of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a> in the Lucayan Commonwealth.</li>
<li><strong>National Ocean Test Facility</strong>: Military testing facility and underwater sonic research complex.</li>
<li><strong>Kipri Town Beach</strong>: Gorgeous and guarded beach found on the coast of the capital city.</li>
<li><strong>Habacoa National Park</strong>: Large and accessible national park that encompasses most of the west side of the island.</li>
<li><strong>Blue Holes</strong>: Deep underwater cave systems that manifest on the surface as blue pools found within the National Park.</li>
<li><strong>Habacoa Barrier Reef</strong>: Third-largest barrier reef in the world teeming with coral and aquatic animals.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Helena</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/helena/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/helena/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Helena is part of Antarctic Helena Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Antarctica Capital Plover Population 19,844 Area 121.8 km2 Languages English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Helena Republic is a constituent republic in the Atlantic Ocean, and part of the commonwealth of Antarctica. Of volcanic origin but with volcanic activity now extinct, Helena is home to around 20,000 people, most of whom live in the capital Plover.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Helena is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Antarctic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/sh.svg);"></span> Helena Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/helena.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Commonwealth Antarctica</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Plover</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>19,844</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>121.8 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-sh"></span> <strong>Helena Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> in the Atlantic Ocean, and part of the commonwealth of Antarctica. Of volcanic origin but with volcanic activity now extinct, Helena is home to around 20,000 people, most of whom live in the capital Plover. Its closest neighbour is the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> republic of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(48, 106, 175); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(48, 106, 175) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/ascension/"><span class="fi fi-ac"></span> Ascension</a>.</p>
<p>Helena is dominated by steep, conspicuous terrain with dramatic volcanic features. It has a pleasant, temperate climate cooled by the South Atlantic trade winds, that range 15-30°C across seasons. Its flora has evolved for millions of years in isolation, and has extraordinary biodiversity across its unique species. Human settlement is concentrated in the highlands and in narrow valleys on its coast.</p>
<p>Helenians are descended mostly from British, South Asians and Africans most of whom were brought over as slaves and servants in the early colonial history of the island. The practice of slavery continued until the late 18th Century when it was outlawed across the British Empire.</p>
<p>Helena was among the islands transferred to the British Atlantic Territories, which would eventually become the first Commonwealth of Oceans. It inherited membership in Vekllei upon independence.</p>
<p>The Helena economy is dominated by municipal goods (green vegetables, land stewardship, crafts) as well as the Port of Helena in Plover that is an important supply station between other Vekllei Antarctic territories. Helena is also home to the South Atlantic Radar Array. It has a single airport on the east of the island, and is serviced by small tramlines and funiculars.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Helvasia</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/helvasia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/helvasia/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Helvasia is part of the Arctic Helvasia Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of the Commonwealth Arctic Capital Romsa Population 7,400 Area 62,045 km2 Languages Northern Sami, English, Norwegian Vekllei Accession 2026, as part of the Arctic Agreement The Helvasia Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Atlantic Ocean north of the Arctic Circle, nearly 1000km north of Norway. It comprises an archipelago of nine main islands, the largest of which is nearly 40,000 km2 and is home to most of the republic&rsquo;s small population.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Helvasia is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/"><span class="fi fi-arctic"></span> Arctic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/sj.svg);"></span> Helvasia Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/helvasia.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of the <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/arctic/"><span class="fi fi-arctic"></span> Commonwealth Arctic</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Romsa</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>7,400</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>62,045 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Northern Sami, English, Norwegian</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>2026, as part of the Arctic Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-sj"></span> <strong>Helvasia Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Atlantic Ocean north of the Arctic Circle, nearly 1000km north of Norway. It comprises an archipelago of nine main islands, the largest of which is nearly 40,000 km2 and is home to most of the republic&rsquo;s small population. It is the northernmost Vekllei republic, and holds several records for its latitude, including its capital of Romsa as the northernmost permanent settlement in the world.</p>
<p>According to <a href="/sagas/">sagas</a> in <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, Helvasia was discovered by Scandinavians in the 12th Century, who observed tribespeople living there &ndash; most likely arctic Sami. After the island was rediscovered by Europeans in the 17th Century, whaling stations were established on Bear Island in its south. After quarrels over whaling rights resulted in conflict between Dutch and English settlers, the UK effectively exercised control over Svalbard thereafter, though a small Russian settlement on the main island remained uncontested throughout the 18th Century. In 1836, the archipelago was absorbed into the British Atlantic Territories and later acceded to <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> after the Atomic War.</p>
<p>Because the whale oil industry was largely confined to Bear Island, the indigenous Sami peoples of Helvasia have retained relative independence from foreign powers for over a thousand years. They remain the predominant ethnic and linguistic group on Helvasia, and Northern Sami and English are taught in schools. Sami culture characterises life in Helvasia, and many traditional and animistic practices remain commonplace. Sami culture and language is distinct from both Scandinavian and Algic languages spoken elsewhere in Veklllei.</p>
<p>Life on Helvasia is cold and harsh, and pack ice in its surrounding shallows prohibit access by sea in the winter months to all vessels except nuclear icebreakers. Its climate is Arctic and ranges from around 15 °C in summer to -40 °C in winter. Its extreme latitude means Helvasia experiences midnight sun and polar night for nearly a hundred days in both summer and winter respectively. Polar Bears remain dangerous there and many Helvasians carry rifles outdoors. Outside of company towns and nomads nearly all Helvasians live in the capital of Romsa.</p>
<p>Helvasia has economic zone disputes with Norway and the Soviet Union, and confrontation between the Vekllei Littoral Service and the navies of those countries occur periodically. The country exploits coal, oil and gas reserves on and around the archipelago. Minor industries include domestic tourism, trapping, fishing and municipal goods. The republic also serves as a base for Vekllei polar research and expeditions, and its isolation has encouraged the establishment of initiatives like the Commonwealth Research Bunkers and the International Knowledge Vault.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Kairi</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Kairi is part of Vekllei Kalina Kairi Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Conquerabia Population 2,480,384 Area 4831 km2 Languages English, Creole, Hindustani, Spanish Vekllei Accession 1930, as part of the Alford Agreement The Kairi Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Caribbean. It is the southernmost part of the Kalina island group, and adjacent to Aloubaera. At its nearest point, Kairi is 11km off the coast of Venezuela, making it the closest border Vekllei has to a continental landmass.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Kairi is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> Kalina</span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/kairi.svg);"></span> Kairi Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/kairi.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/kairi.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/kairi.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Conquerabia</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>2,480,384</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>4831 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Creole, Hindustani, Spanish</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1930, as part of the Alford Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> <strong>Kairi Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Caribbean. It is the southernmost part of the Kalina island group, and adjacent to <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(46, 114, 225); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(46, 114, 225) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/aloubaera/"><span class="fi fi-aloubaera"></span> Aloubaera</a>. At its nearest point, Kairi is 11km off the coast of Venezuela, making it the closest border Vekllei has to a continental landmass. It comprises a single large island and a few smaller ones, and enjoys a tropical climate cooled by sea breezes year-round.</p>
<p>Kairi is home mostly to ethnic Indians and Africans, as well as Caribs who had settled the island prior to colonisation by European powers. About a third are descended from African slaves brought over to work sugar and cocoa plantations, and another third are Indian descended from indentured labourers brought over from South Asia by the British. The Indian population is the largest South Asian community in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and retain their own language, religion and customs.</p>
<p>Kairi is the industrial heart of the Kalina island group and has substantial oil, gas, electricity, steel, aluminium, fertiliser, textiles and chemical industries. It is home to Vekllei&rsquo;s second fusion power plant, opened in 2024, which supplies its heavy industries and neighbouring republics with power.</p>
<p>The capital of Conquerabia is home to <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(219, 37, 21); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(219, 37, 21) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/state/oil/"><span class="fi fi-min-oil fis"></span> Commonwealth Oil</a> and the Cherry Automobile Plant, which manufactures consumer and commercial vehicles. <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(237, 1, 0); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(237, 1, 0) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/private/cateral/"><span class="fi fi-min-cateral fis"></span> Cateral</a>, the largest firearms manufacturer in Vekllei, is also headquartered there. The islands are well-serviced by a dense network of small trains and trams typical of the Vekllei Caribbean.</p>
<p>Thanks to its relative wealth, development and ready accession with Commonwealth government, Kairi has long been an example republic of Vekllei governance and planning in the Caribbean. It is host to several international schools and missions, and contributes substantially to the overall prosperity of the Vekllei Caribbean. Kairi is the site of the southern campus of the Commonwealth University of the West Indies, which ranks highly among national tertiary schools. It is also the administrative capital of the Kalina Commonwealth state.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Oslola</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Oslola is part of the Volcanic Oslola Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of the Volcanic Commonwealth Capital Oslola Population 8,131,426 Area 103,125 km2 Languages Oslolan Algic, English, Oslolan Islandi Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Oslola Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the North Atlantic Ocean. It is the most populous Vekllei republic, and is historically its centre of industry, education and administration.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Oslola is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/oslola.svg);"></span> Oslola Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/oslola.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/oslola.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/oslola.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of the <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic Commonwealth</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Oslola</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>8,131,426</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>103,125 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Oslolan Algic, English, Oslolan Islandi</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> <strong>Oslola Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the North Atlantic Ocean. It is the most populous Vekllei republic, and is historically its centre of industry, education and administration. The large island sits atop the border of the European and North American tectonic plates and is famous for its volcanic activity and striking landscapes characterised by flower tundras, glaciers, hot geysers and and temperate rainforests.</p>
<p>Oslola has been continuously inhabited for over 4,000 years by Algic Inuits, who are a distinct ethnic and linguistic group from other Arctic Inuits. Archaeological evidence suggests Irish settlers established fishing communities on the south coast in 1200BC, and Scandinavians arrived a hundred years later. Since that time, Algic and Scandinavian/Irish populations (commonly &ldquo;Scandis&rdquo;) have participated in united and seperate kingdoms. Oslola is the site of the world&rsquo;s oldest democracy, which has varied in structure and power through succeeding kingdoms and councils. Oslola was a major centre of power in the British Atlantic Territories and the First Commonwealth that followed it, and in the postwar Fourth Commonwealth retains an important though diminished role.</p>
<p>Oslola has historically been a major entrepôt for trans-Atlantic traffic, and a trade metropole for Vekllei. It enjoys a maritime subarctic climate, with strong warm currents anchored by the Oslola Low Pole warming the southern coast. Summer typically average between 12-25 °C, and about 0-10°C in winter. The high latitude of the republic means it features midnight sun for a couple of weeks in summer. Forests of birch and eucalyptus dominate mossy, cold-weather rainforests that populate the south coast. In the glacial interior and north tundras, scrub and flowers cover mostly treeless valleys and dramatic terrain.</p>
<p>Oslola is densely populated, and the metropolitan region in the south-east comprises one continuous city broken up by mountains and crown lands. The main city, also called Oslola, has a varied character of narrow medium-height streets, railways, canals and street vegetation. It is home to many Vekllei institutions, including Vekllei National University, as well as international organisations like the new UN building and the International Federation of Journalists.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rum</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/lucaya/rum/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/lucaya/rum/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Rum is part of the Lucayan Commonwealth Rum Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Capital Conception Population 4,910 Area 241 km2 Languages English, Lucayan Vekllei Accession 1930, as part of the Alford Agreement The Rum Republic (also Rummy) is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Lucayan archipelago. It comprises two inhabited islands, San Salvador and Rum Island, the islet of Conception (now a Commonwealth Preservation) as well as some minor islets and rocks.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Rum is part of the Lucayan Commonwealth</span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/rum.svg);"></span> Rum Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/rum.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Conception</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>4,910</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>241 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Lucayan</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1930, as part of the Alford Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-rum"></span> <strong>Rum Republic</strong> (also <em>Rummy</em>) is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Lucayan archipelago. It comprises two inhabited islands, San Salvador and Rum Island, the islet of Conception (now a Commonwealth Preservation) as well as some minor islets and rocks. It is situated in the west of the Lucayan archipelago, and the eastern coast of San Salvador is exposed to the open Atlantic.</p>
<p>About three fifths of its people, mostly ethnic Lucayans and some whites, live in the capital of Conception on San Salvador. The remainder live around its coast or in the settlement of Travesty on Rum Island. The islands are mostly flat with some minor hills, and San Salvador is characterised by small lakes and ponds across its surface. Both are fringed by picturesque coral reefs that attract some tourists from other parts of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>.</p>
<p>While San Salvador has a minor airport and a single tramline circumnavigating its coast, Rum Island is accessible only by its pier. The republic is comparatively isolated from the larger Lucayan islands, and lives there are typically relaxed, characterised by municipal farming, some fishing, and recreational island activities. The capital of Conception is home to all major infrastructure, including the post office, power station, police station and the republic&rsquo;s only secondary school. Minor tourism is facilitated by inns and guesthouses.</p>
<p>The island of Conception is an uninhabited preservation, and is home to a unique species of Boa. It has a research station from the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a> there. The navy also maintains a naval station, primarily used for monitoring and navigation, on the north point of San Salvador.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li>Salvador Research Centre, Commonwealth University of the West Indies</li>
<li>Salvador Naval Station</li>
<li>Conception Island Research Station, <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a></li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Santes</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/santes/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/santes/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Helena is part of Antarctic Santes Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Antarctica Capital Glass Town Population 1,802 Area 207 km2 Languages English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Santes Republic is a constituent republic in the Atlantic Ocean, and part of Antarctic. Its closest neighbour is Helena, which lies over 2,000km north of the territory. As such, Santes is considered the most remote inhabited archipelago in the world.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Helena is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Antarctic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/santes.svg);"></span> Santes Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/santes.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Commonwealth Antarctica</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Glass Town</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>1,802</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>207 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-santes"></span> <strong>Santes Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> in the Atlantic Ocean, and part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Antarctic</a>. Its closest neighbour is <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(24, 117, 71); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(24, 117, 71) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/helena/"><span class="fi fi-sh"></span> Helena</a>, which lies over 2,000km north of the territory. As such, Santes is considered the most remote inhabited archipelago in the world.</p>
<p>The republic comprises six small islands, of which five are closely grouped together. Gough island, a UNESCO world heritage site, lies 320km southeastwards of the main island group and is home only to seabirds and a small Vekllei Weather Service station. The main and only permanently-inhabited island of Santes is roughly circular in shape and rises dramatically from the sea in a volcanic cone.</p>
<p>The climate is mild and windy, and the islands are home to significant biodiversity. Many Santesians are descended from the original European male settlers who had mixed-race wives from <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(24, 117, 71); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(24, 117, 71) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/helena/"><span class="fi fi-sh"></span> Helena</a>, and the majority of the local population is now mixed-race. Almost all live in Glass Town, the capital, which is home to the government, a hospital, two schools and a Maritime Service naval station.</p>
<p>Their society is communal, even by <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> standards. All local food sources are shared, consisting of potatoes and coastal shellfishing. Livestock are also raised for consumption. Aside from a VTOL landing site at the naval station, Santes is inaccessible by air and has to be reached by ship. Historically an ageing, shrinking population, the republic has been rejuvenated by interest in the Vekllei localism movement.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sude</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/sude/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/sude/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Sude is part of Antarctic Sude Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Antarctica Capital Godthul Population 3,422 Area 3,903 km2 Languages English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Sude Republic is a constituent republic in the Southern Atlantic Ocean, and part of Antarctic. Its closest neighbour is the Falklands, which lies 1,300km northwest of the island group. It is a cold, barren territory with permanent snow across much of its land area, and is home to a few thousand people, hardy grasses, and introduced reindeer.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Sude is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Antarctic</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/gs.svg);"></span> Sude Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/sude.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Commonwealth Antarctica</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Godthul</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>3,422</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>3,903 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-gs"></span> <strong>Sude Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> in the Southern Atlantic Ocean, and part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/"><span class="fi fi-antarctic"></span> Antarctic</a>. Its closest neighbour is the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(60, 122, 184); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(60, 122, 184) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/falklands/"><span class="fi fi-fk"></span> Falklands</a>, which lies 1,300km northwest of the island group. It is a cold, barren territory with permanent snow across much of its land area, and is home to a few thousand people, hardy grasses, and introduced reindeer. It comprises the island of Georgia, where nearly all of its people live, and the Candlemas island chain to its south of around 11 islands.</p>
<p>Historically the main island of Georgia was used by the British and Norwegians as stations for whaling and blubber rendering, and most of these former stations form the core of the seven towns on the most populous island of Georgia. The capital, Godthul, was originally a Norwegian station founded in the early 20th Century, but whales have not been hunted around Sude for over a hundred years and their populations are in recovery.</p>
<p>Georgia has a mountainous interior consisting of stepped flats and windswept, barren peaks. It is a breeding ground for fur seals and king penguins, which can occasionally cause trouble near human settlements. The Candlemas islands are almost entirely uninhabited except for a weather and scientific station on Thule Island, and are prone to strong earthquakes. The climate there is characterised by long, cold winters and cool summers, with weather that changes quickly.</p>
<p>Georgia has a good port in its capital, and serves as a staging point for antarctic expeditions in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. Seven towns, mostly based at former whaling stations, serve the Sudenese population, which are linked by trams. The population are hardy, descended from British and Norwegian whalers as well as settlers from the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(60, 122, 184); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(60, 122, 184) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/falklands/"><span class="fi fi-fk"></span> Falklands</a>. They have a close-knit, communal society dependent on fishing and government interest in the antarctic.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Summers</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/lucaya/summers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/lucaya/summers/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the territories series of articles Summers Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Capital Aran Population 13,947 Area 53.2 km2 Languages English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Republic of Summers is a constituent republic in the western North Atlantic, and part of the country of Vekllei. It is an island city state consisting of an archipelago of 7 main islands and about 170 charted islets and rocks, situated about 1,000km off the east coast of the United States and about 3,120km southwest of the Vekllei capital in Comet.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/territories/">territories</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/summers.svg);"></span> Summers Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/summers.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Aran</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>13,947</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>53.2 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-summers"></span> <strong>Republic of Summers</strong> is a constituent republic in the western North Atlantic, and part of the country of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is an island city state consisting of an archipelago of 7 main islands and about 170 charted islets and rocks, situated about 1,000km off the east coast of the United States and about 3,120km southwest of the Vekllei capital in Comet.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Verde</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/verde/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/verde/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Verde is part of the Atlantic Commonwealth Verde Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Capital Green Cape Population 246,820 Area 744.55 km2 Languages English, Portuguese, Sinhala Vekllei Accession 1976, as part of the Azores Delegation The Verde Republic (also the Green Island) is a constituent republic of Vekllei and part of the Atlantic Commonwealth. It is the largest and most populous island of the Azores archipelago, and seats the executive of the regional commonwealth.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Verde is part of the Atlantic Commonwealth</span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/verde.svg);"></span> Verde Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/verde.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Green Cape</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>246,820</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>744.55 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Portuguese, Sinhala</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1976, as part of the Azores Delegation</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-verde"></span> <strong>Verde Republic</strong> (also the <em>Green Island</em>) is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> and part of the Atlantic Commonwealth. It is the largest and most populous island of the Azores archipelago, and seats the executive of the regional commonwealth. It is a narrow, verdant island of volcanic origin.</p>
<p>Verde was originally colonised by the Portuguese, who discovered the island in the 15th Century and established a small fishing colony thereafter. Throughout its history, Verde has been vulnerable to earthquakes and tidal waves, and the capital of Green Cape has been rebuilt several times. In the 19th Century, Verde rose to prominence as citrus traders, selling mostly to Southern Europe and the British Empire. Verde, along with the rest of the Azores, voted to secede from Portugal in the 1960s and after its interim government collapsed joined the Atlantic Federation in 1976. It inherited membership in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in 2015.</p>
<p>Verde enjoys a mild climate, and is renowned for its lush vegetation and scattered, lake-filled craters. Its peaks culminate in Vara Mountain at 1,100 meters above sea level. In the postwar period, its beauty and climate has seen many people from others parts of Vekllei move there.</p>
<p>Verde is the headquarters of the anti-Vekllei Azores Independence League, and has been responsible for attacks on police and federal buildings. They enjoy some political support in the Verde parliament but their influence has been waning.</p>
<p>Verde is a major producer of citrus and tea, and also exports significant amounts of pineapples and wine. Agriculture, shipbuilding and sugar refining are the primary components of its economy. It is also home to Atlantic University, the largest university in the Azores archipelago. The republic&rsquo;s settlements are connected by both passenger and freight rail as well as trams.</p>
<details open>
	<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>Holy Christ of the Miracles Church</strong>: the site of an important pilgrimage in the Roman Catholic Church, culminating in an annual procession.</li>
<li><strong>Sete Cidades</strong>: Municipality known for its beautiful volcanic lakes</li>
<li><strong>Furnas Geysers</strong>: Volcanic baths, geysers, and hot springs available for swimming.</li>
<li><strong>Verde Fruit Company</strong>: Oldest and largest pineapple plantation in Vekllei.</li>
<li><strong>Formoso Tea Plantations</strong>: Historic black and orange tea plantation.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Virgin</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/virgin/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/virgin/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Virgin is part of Kalina Virgin Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of Commonwealth Kalina Capital Roadie (administrative) Population 182,295 Area 472.75 km2 Languages English, French, Spanish Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Virgin Republic is a constituent republic of the Kalina Commonwealth in the Caribbean Sea, and is part of Vekllei. It is the westernmost part of the Kalina island group.
It comprises ten large islands in an archipelago extending eastwards of Puerto Rico (U.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Virgin is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-blue); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-blue) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/vg.svg);"></span> Virgin Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/virgin.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/vg.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/vg.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Commonwealth Kalina</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Roadie (administrative)</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>182,295</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>472.75 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, French, Spanish</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-vg"></span> <strong>Virgin Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of the Kalina Commonwealth in the Caribbean Sea, and is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is the westernmost part of the Kalina island group.</p>
<p>It comprises ten large islands in an archipelago extending eastwards of Puerto Rico (U.S.), as well as about 123 smaller islets and cays. Although these islands are situated on the fault-block mountains of the Puerto Rico trench, they are usually considered part of the Lesser Antilles due to their size and proximity of that chain. Virgin&rsquo;s westernmost island, Vieques, forms the second-closest sea border to another country (Puerto Rico, part of the U.S.) after <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(215, 18, 45); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(215, 18, 45) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/"><span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> Kairi</a>.</p>
<p>Before consolidation under the British Atlantic Territories, the Virgin archipelago was subject to competing colonial settlement and claims. English, Spanish, French and Danish ownership at various times contribute to the linguistic and cultural diversity within Virgin today. About three-quarters of its 182,000 people are black, descended from slaves who worked plantations in the colonial period. Substantial minority populations of Arawaks, Indians, Chinese and Europeans also exist. Protestant christianity is the majority religion.</p>
<p>Virgin&rsquo;s climate is subtropical and pleasant, with warm weather cooled by trade winds crossing south. Individual islands are varied, often characterised by dense tropical forest that cover steep mountain interiors, and low-lying coastal plateaus that has been cleared for agriculture. Many natural harbours exist, many of which host major settlements including the capital of Roadie, and the cities of Charlotte Amalie and Christiansted.</p>
<p>Water scarcity across the islands has been historically severe, but alleviated in the 21st Century by desalination plants powered by nuclear fusion projects on the islands of St Croix and Tortola. The economy is dominated by the civil service, financial services and petrochemicals. Virgin refineries process oil from other parts of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> for the Caribbean region. Virgin depends heavily on imports from other parts of the country, especially for machinery and manufactured goods.</p>
<p>Virgin University is the second-largest university in Kalina, and the fourth largest in Vekllei. It is common for students from smaller Commonwealth islands to travel to Virgin for study. The republic is also popular as a domestic holiday destination thanks to its excellent climate and world-renowned beaches.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
