<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Letters</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Letters </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Nov 2020</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2020/nov/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2020/nov/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in November 2020 Hello my lovelies,
Just a short update on where I’m at as we pass mid-month. I’ve pushed a couple of things back a day or two to finish a very cool/special post. You’ll see it on the reddit soon — it’ll be a really nice painting, and nothing like I’ve ever done before. Before the weekend.
I was hesitant to promise a timeframe for the comic draft, and for good reason.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/mastheads/letters/1.jpg" alt="img"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in November 2020</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Hello my lovelies,</p>
<p>Just a short update on where I’m at as we pass mid-month. I’ve pushed a couple of things back a day or two to finish a very cool/special post. You’ll see it on the reddit soon — it’ll be a really nice painting, and nothing like I’ve ever done before. <strong>Before the weekend</strong>.</p>
<p>I was hesitant to promise a timeframe for the comic draft, and for good reason. I haven’t done anything like this before, so I don’t have a reference for how much work and time these things take. I’ve had three years now to narrow down and figure out what sort of schedule works for posts via reddit, and I’ve got a big of an adjustment period here. <strong>I’m hoping to have the draft up for patrons here soon, within a week</strong>. In future, I think a chapter a month is perfectly feasible, but there’s a lot to learn — formats, comic stylisation, and even black and white illustration are pretty new to me. So stay tuned for the draft.</p>
<p>The stamps are coming along well! I’ve had to redraw the post office post since the original didn’t really work out, and that will be out before the end of the month. Little sketches and hopefully another post or two are also mapped out between here and then.</p>
<p>Finally, since we’ve hit $100/month on Patreon, that means <strong>we can start talking about a fun reward</strong>. Previously, I reached out to a print company, tabulated how much it would cost per unit, then simply subtracted your lifetime donation to the project from your order. The Tzipo-stcards cost around $20 to print and ship, so anyone who had donated a total of $20 over their Patreon pledge would get them for “free”. The same system will work here. Any patron is entitled to one — if your total pledges are under the cost of manufacture, you can simply make up the difference. You won&rsquo;t miss out if you don&rsquo;t want to.</p>
<p>I’m currently looking into little enamel pins, since <strong>I love pins</strong>, but I’ll have a poll up within the next week to see if you’d prefer any alternatives.</p>
<p>As always, sincere thanks for your patronage. It means a lot.</p>
<p>Love</p>
<p>Melon</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Dec 2020</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2020/dec/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2020/dec/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in December 2020 Hello beloved patrons,
This is your monthly update for the Petticoat Project.
There’s a new post up on the subreddit and a new article up on the website — a big one, about Vekllei, although it’s missing a history and culture section. Those are coming soon.
I won’t be mucking around on the website forever — trust me, I have no intention of abandoning my traditional post format for dry wiki articles — but it makes good infrastructure, and good infrastructure allows for growth and it also helps support new projects, like the comic.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/mastheads/letters/2.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in December 2020</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Hello beloved patrons,</p>
<p>This is your monthly update for the Petticoat Project.</p>
<p>There’s a <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/khl6um/full_heart/">new post up on the subreddit</a></strong> and a <strong><a href="https://millmint.net/vekllei/">new article up on the website</a></strong> — a big one, about Vekllei, although it’s missing a history and culture section. Those are coming soon.</p>
<p><strong>I won’t be mucking around on the website forever</strong> — trust me, I have no intention of abandoning my traditional post format for dry wiki articles — but it makes good infrastructure, and good infrastructure allows for growth and it also helps support new projects, like the comic. The website and its articles will launch over the New Year.</p>
<p>Guess what else is launching over the new year? <strong>The comic</strong>. You’ll see it before that, of course, as I’m sketching the remaining pages now. But I hope to have it <strong>ready and inked by early January</strong>. Does it keep getting delayed? Yes. But that’s the unglamorous thing about infrastructure — it’s just work, and it’s not that visible. Hopefully regular posts fill the ache in the meantime.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://millmint.net/images/comics/test.jpg">You can see a page I’ve inked here!</a></strong> This was a sort of test of style, and needs a bit of tweaking. Overall, I&rsquo;ve ascertained that I like screen tones.</p>
<p>I am very excited for <strong>Patreon milestone merch</strong> (in the form of beautiful little enamel pins), and will release a poll concerning designs <strong>in the coming days</strong>. I’ll also have a price-point — like last time, your lifetime pledge is deducted from the cost + shipping, and any difference can be made up easily. So no one will miss out who doesn’t want to.</p>
<p>Last of which, I’d like to wish the observers among us a <strong>very Merry Christmas</strong> and to everyone else a <strong>Happy New Year</strong>. Stay tuned for a special issue of The Atlantic Bulletin to celebrate 2021.</p>
<p>Your support is very important to me and is always deeply humbling.</p>
<p>Man, I can’t wait for this comic.</p>
<p>Love</p>
<p>Melon</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Jan 2021</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2021/jan/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2021/jan/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in January 2021 Hello beloved patrons,
The first chapter of the comic is sketched. You will see it on Monday (about two days from this message). It won&rsquo;t be inked but it&rsquo;ll give you a very good idea of what the final chapter will look like at the end of the month. I look forward to reading your feedback, since it&rsquo;s my first try at this sort of thing (well, minus the dozens of concepts trashed over the previous few months).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/mastheads/letters/3.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in January 2021</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Hello beloved patrons,</p>
<p>The first chapter of the comic is sketched. You will see it on Monday (about two days from this message). It won&rsquo;t be inked but it&rsquo;ll give you a very good idea of what the final chapter will look like at the end of the month. I look forward to reading your feedback, since it&rsquo;s my first try at this sort of thing (well, minus the dozens of concepts trashed over the previous few months).</p>
<p>Thank you dearly for your patience. It was a source of some trouble for me as I figured out how to put these people and this environment to paper for the first time. It&rsquo;s come out great &ndash; I hope you&rsquo;ll enjoy it. It took a long time but it&rsquo;s finally starting. This will be a monthly thing.</p>
<p>In the first chapter you will see trains, planes and automobiles and some great landscapes too.</p>
<p>In other news, the archive on millmint.net is finally finished. This is a complete collection of all Vekllei posts I have ever posted to reddit, going way back to 2017. Each post had to be painstakingly copied to the site, and it took days. Over 200 posts and pictures. At least it&rsquo;s done. Let us never speak of it again.</p>
<p>Pencil in Monday on your calendars. How exciting.</p>
<p>Thank you always for your continued support. A mid-month letter will follow soon, as well as a special post.</p>
<p>Much love,</p>
<p>Hobart/Melon</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Feb 2021</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2021/feb/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2021/feb/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in February 2021 Hello beloved Patrons,
It’s been a little while. I’ve called this meeting late because I’ve been working late. Let’s run this through quick, and we can all get back to bed.
You guys voted! Looks like our next themed ‘week’ (maybe fortnight) is Ocean Week. Great choice, lots of cool concepts coming. Mail Week (fortnight) has been a lot of fun, but it’s almost done.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/sketches/thinking.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<blockquote class="hint blue">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in February 2021</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Hello beloved Patrons,</strong></p>
<p>It’s been a little while. I’ve called this meeting late because I’ve been working late. Let’s run this through quick, and we can all get back to bed.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>You guys voted!</strong> Looks like our next themed ‘week’ (maybe fortnight) is Ocean Week. Great choice, lots of cool concepts coming.</li>
<li><strong>Mail Week (fortnight)</strong> has been a lot of fun, but it’s almost done. I’ve got one post left in it, maybe two depending on how this painting works out. Then we’re done for the month. Ocean Week starts in March.</li>
<li><strong>There’s a new article</strong> on the site about the mail in Vekllei: <a href="https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/mail/">https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/mail/</a>. I’m going to write one of these for each themed week. It might seem silly to write a whole article about the mail considering more important areas desperately need attention, but as we do more of these themed weeks it’ll fill out the site nicely. These articles aren’t just posts copied and pasted into a long doc; they’re all original content, and link to posts from that week. Check it out!</li>
<li><strong>What comes next?</strong> Well, for the rest of this month I’ll be getting the next chapter of the comic out and I’ll have one or two regular posts too. Thanks for the patience with the comic; I’ve been doing some experimenting and I’ve got a great “first chapter” coming up.</li>
<li><strong>Merch? Working on it.</strong> Pins are a fantastic idea, but very expensive at this scale (we’re talking about $500 minimum or so, and I don’t really want to run a store right now!). So I’ll have a poll here soon to figure out what you’d like to see — postcard sets are cheap and fun, but why not tee shirts or other bric a brac?</li>
<li><strong>The Atlantic Bulletin?</strong> I got swamped with work, and it was a real pain to format for email. But it’s not dead. I’m going to relaunch it as a “whenever I can” periodical with better stuff and original content, rather than just a list of posts of each month. I’ll be looking for contributions too, I’ll let you know when I do.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s about it, nice and quick.</p>
<p>Thank you always for your continued support. I can’t wait to get the comic out.</p>
<p>Kind regards,</p>
<p><strong>Hobart</strong>/Melon</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>May 2021</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2021/may/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2021/may/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in May 2021 Hello beloved patrons,
It&rsquo;s been a little while since my last direct communiqué. I laid off these for a bit, since I realised you probably didn&rsquo;t need to have your inbox full of blog posts and delay announcements from me. Time better spent drawing I reckon.
I&rsquo;ve had a couple things going on in my personal life, so I&rsquo;ve had to put some of my wilder ambitions on hold for a bit.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/mastheads/letters/4.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in May 2021</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Hello beloved patrons,</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been a little while since my last direct communiqué. I laid off these for a bit, since I realised you probably didn&rsquo;t need to have your inbox full of blog posts and delay announcements from me. Time better spent drawing I reckon.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve had a couple things going on in my personal life, so I&rsquo;ve had to put some of my wilder ambitions on hold for a bit. I&rsquo;m hoping I&rsquo;m nearing the end of this rough patch and you&rsquo;ll see some crazy good stuff in future, in addition to regular posts.</p>
<p>This message is just me saying I&rsquo;m still around, and I&rsquo;m always thankful. I&rsquo;ve got a couple really good train posts around the corner. Tzipora loves the trains.</p>
<p>In the meantime, enjoy this picture I made for you.</p>
<p>Warm regards,</p>
<p>Melon/Hobart</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Jul 2021</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2021/july/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/letters/2021/july/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in July 2021 Hello beloved patrons,
Just checking in after a quiet July. It’s been quiet for several reasons, most of them good.
We had a few posts this month, but I’ve also been working on larger things — the comic, of course, but I have also spent many days working on a special map of Vekllei, to be revealed soon.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/mastheads/letters/5.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ This letter was sent out to Patrons in July 2021</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Hello beloved patrons</strong>,</p>
<p>Just checking in after a quiet July. It’s been quiet for several reasons, most of them good.</p>
<p>We had a few posts this month, but I’ve also been working on larger things — the comic, of course, but I have also spent many days working on a special map of Vekllei, to be revealed soon.</p>
<p>This is me checking in to let you know I’m around and grateful. Tzipora, a dedicated puffin scout, is pictured here doing the puffin salute.</p>
<p>Look forward to exciting things soon.</p>
<p>Much love,</p>
<p><strong>Hobart</strong>/Melon</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
