<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>History</title>
	<link>/factbook/history/</link>
	<description>Recent content in History </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Council of Roses</title>
	  <link>/factbook/history/rosecouncil/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/history/rosecouncil/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the history series of articles The Council of Roses was the informal cabinet of the Interim Prosperity Government, formed in 2015 to the establish the shape of a future independent Vekllei Commonwealth. Made of up of so-called &ldquo;loveable radicals,&rdquo; the council was created by British administrators as a strategic concession to rising communist activity in Vekllei. For this reason, the Council was majority-women, since they were poorly represented among communist leadership, and consisted mostly of leaders in arts, science and industry.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/history/">history</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>The Council of Roses</strong> was the informal cabinet of the <a href="/interim/">Interim Prosperity Government</a>, formed in 2015 to  the establish the shape of a future independent Vekllei Commonwealth. Made of up of so-called &ldquo;loveable radicals,&rdquo; the council was created by British administrators as a strategic concession to rising communist activity in Vekllei. For this reason, the Council was majority-women, since they were poorly represented among communist leadership, and consisted mostly of leaders in arts, science and industry.</p>
<p>The Council of Roses drafted the <a href="/constitution/">Vekllei Constitution</a>, which would become the foundational legal text of the independent 4th Vekllei Commonwealth. It was approved with minor alterations by Westminster on May 6th 2015, and was ratified in August that year. The Council of Roses was dissolved in 2017, and replaced by the first Cabinet of the independent Vekllei Parliament.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Interim Prosperity Government</title>
	  <link>/factbook/history/interim/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/history/interim/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the history series of articles The Interim Vekllei Government (also the Interim Parliament and Interim Prosperity Government) was a temporary puppet state of the United Kingdom, established in 2015 as a means to Vekllei independence after twenty years of British occupation in the country. It consisted of approved leaders in the arts and industry, who developed proposals for a new democratic Vekllei state.
Included was a majority female Council of Roses, many of whom were socialists opposed to communist unrest in British-occupied Vekllei and were seen as a strategic alternative to a hostile communist government upon British withdrawal.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/history/">history</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Interim Vekllei Government</strong> (also the <em>Interim Parliament</em> and <em>Interim Prosperity Government</em>) was a temporary puppet state of the United Kingdom, established in 2015 as a means to Vekllei independence after twenty years of British occupation in the country. It consisted of approved leaders in the arts and industry, who developed proposals for a new democratic Vekllei state.</p>
<p>Included was a majority female <a href="/rose-council/">Council of Roses</a>, many of whom were socialists opposed to communist unrest in British-occupied Vekllei and were seen as a strategic alternative to a hostile communist government upon British withdrawal. The council were responsible for draughting the Vekllei Constitution and establishing Interim Ministries in anticipation of independence.</p>
<p>After independence in 2017, the Vekllei Interim Government became the 4th Commonwealth of Vekllei.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
