<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Snapshots on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/snapshots/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Snapshots on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/snapshots/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Polyester</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/snapshots/polyester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/snapshots/polyester/</guid>
      <description>Polyester -atom  SNAPSHOT  Apr 4, 2020  People across the world are very excited by the possibilities and emerging styles in new synthetic materials, including polyester, plastic, and new-nylon. In keeping with her meticulous and mildly neurotic character, Tzipora cannot stand synthetic fibres and refuses wear anything that isn&amp;rsquo;t soft, loose-fitting and hand-washable.
Like most metrics kept in her head, it&amp;rsquo;s largely arbitrary and fluctuates depending on the visibility of materials and her awareness of it, but does invariably inform her sense of fashion, leaving her conservative and old-fashioned in appearance as her peers take on increasingly colourful (and avant garde) styles made possible by a materials revolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welts</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/snapshots/welts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/snapshots/welts/</guid>
      <description>The Cane -atom  SNAPSHOT  Apr 4, 2020  The years that were supposed to be Tzipora’s finest were falling apart. She was fourteen, out of money and out of options. Her tuition laboured on, paid in advance, but there was nothing left over for her. Her mother didn’t send money or letters anymore. So Tzipora lived on the free dinners provided by the Sisters of Charity and gifts from people who pitied her, mostly wealthy migrants associated with the church.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
