<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Ministry of Commerce</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Ministry of Commerce </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Bureau of Securities</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/bureau-of-securities/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/bureau-of-securities/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This bureau is part of the Ministry of Commerce. The Bureau of Securities (VECSEC) regulates securities in the Vekllei International Market. It advises fiscal decision-making to the Interior Parliament and legislates trade practices in the country, including the issuing and ownership of government bonds and bureau securities. It is part of the Ministry of Commerce.
Since Vekllei citizens do not usually participate in the domestic securities markets, VECSEC lacks traditional legal authority over many of the foreign participants in its supervised markets, but does extradite and prosecute financial crime through the EUROVEK and USVEK extradition treaties.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This bureau is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <em>Bureau of Securities</em> (VECSEC) regulates securities in the Vekllei International Market. It advises fiscal decision-making to the Interior Parliament and legislates trade practices in the country, including the issuing and ownership of government bonds and bureau securities. It is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</p>
<p>Since Vekllei citizens do not usually participate in the domestic securities markets, VECSEC lacks traditional legal authority over many of the foreign participants in its supervised markets, but does extradite and prosecute financial crime through the EUROVEK and USVEK extradition treaties. It includes the following departments.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li><strong>General Council</strong>: Advisory board to the Commonwealth.</li>
<li><strong>General Procuratorate</strong>: Enforcement of penalties and prosecution of financial crimes.</li>
<li><strong>General Inspectorate</strong>: Investigations into fraud, abuse and corruption in Vekllei markets.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Financing and Stock Exchange</strong>: Regulation and monitoring of the Vekllei Stock Exchange and miscellaneous securities within the country.</li>
<li><strong>Department of International Markets</strong>: Regulation and monitoring of the Vekllei International Market and government bonds.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Investments and Trusts</strong>: Regulation and monitoring of the investments, securities and financial contracts of Vekllei citizens and companies.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bureau of Trade</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/bureau-of-trade/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/bureau-of-trade/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This bureau is part of the Ministry of Commerce. The Bureau of Trade regulates consumer protections and antitrust law, and organises trade information from other ministries and supervisory bureaus into policy recommendations and legislation. The Trade Commission also monitors and reports the health of foreign markets, and conducts research into broader geopolitical financial interests, particularly as they compete with domestic interests. It is part of the Ministry of Commerce, and includes the following departments.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This bureau is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <em>Bureau of Trade</em> regulates consumer protections and antitrust law, and organises trade information from other ministries and supervisory bureaus into policy recommendations and legislation. The Trade Commission also monitors and reports the health of foreign markets, and conducts research into broader geopolitical financial interests, particularly as they compete with domestic interests. It is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>, and includes the following departments.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Key Staff</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Permanent Secretary</strong>, Commonwealth Trade Commission</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><ul>
<li><strong>Department of Consumer Affairs</strong>: Regulation of the consumer rights.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Market Affairs</strong>: Protection of fair markets and regulation of Bureau and Petty Bureau companies, including state monopolies.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Market Research</strong>: Analysis and research of domestic and international markets, compiled and forwarded to other Interior Ministries.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Intelligence</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Office of Foreign Assets Control</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Bank</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-bank/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-bank/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ The Commonwealth Bank is part of the Ministry of Commerce. The Commonwealth Bank (also Bank of Vekllei) is the central bank and currency store of Vekllei. It is operated by the Ministry of Commerce and maintains branches in all Vekllei republics and in many countries around the world. It is not autonomous and is beholden to the policy decisions of Ministry of Commerce and, in certain cases, the republic and commonwealth parliaments.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ The Commonwealth Bank is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Commonwealth Bank (also <em>Bank of Vekllei</em>) is the central bank and currency store of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is operated by the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a> and maintains branches in all Vekllei republics and in many countries around the world. It is not autonomous and is beholden to the policy decisions of Ministry of Commerce and, in certain cases, the republic and commonwealth parliaments. Its sworn purpose, as instructed by the Floral Constitution, is to advocate for encourage growth and benefit Vekllei people.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Bank was founded 1642 as the Royal Bank in <a href="/lola/">Lola</a>, and is the fifth oldest bank in the world.</p>
<p>Most banks in Vekllei are institutional or industrial, since the average Vekllei person is unmoneyed and, in a conventional definition, unbanked. Nonetheless, Vekllei maintains several commercial banks under the Bank of Vekllei umbrella, tasked primarily with:</p>
<ul>
<li>Cashing and underwriting White and Blue bonds.</li>
<li>Selling government and financial (bureau) bonds internationally.</li>
<li>International placement and borrowing services.</li>
<li>Trading, settling and selling foreign currencies.</li>
</ul>
<p>Vekllei citizens are entitled to an equal share of the money stored in the Labour Bank, and in certain circumstances may withdraw their balance to emigrate or travel abroad.</p>
<p>Despite foreign perception of Vekllei economics, the liquid and asset holdings of the Bank of Vekllei make it the second-largest bank in the world.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-atlantic-bank">
  Commonwealth Atlantic Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-atlantic-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Atlantic Bank</em> (COMMBANK) is an international investment subsidiary of the Bank of Vekllei, tasked primarily with banking in Commonwealth members and international markets. It has branches across every Commonwealth member-state and in most major economic hubs around the world, including throughout Europe, the Americas, and Asia. It also serves as the Central Bank of the Kalina Isles.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-import-export-bank">
  Commonwealth Import-Export Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-import-export-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Import-Export Bank</em> (VEKEXIM) is a state policy investment bank used to fund projects outside of the Commonwealth, particularly in developing countries. It is the primary investment mechanism of Vekllei foreign aid system, which uses export credits and low-interest bureau loans to build infrastructure overseas. It is among the most influential export banks in the world, and contributed to the Pan-African Railway and Hundred Dams projects as part of Vekllei&rsquo;s ongoing Trade Democracy economic scheme.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-development-bank">
  Commonwealth Development Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-development-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Development Bank</em> (DEVBANK) is a policy bank designed to organise and allocate funding for large-scale political projects, particularly in infrastructure. The Development Bank works as the engine of the Commonwealth&rsquo;s policies, funded mostly with White Bonds issued internationally and labour-guaranteed certificates (a type of Blue Bond). It also creates loan arrangements, evaluates, and underwrites national government projects.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-commercial-bank">
  Commonwealth Commercial Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-commercial-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Commercial Bank</em> (SISTERBANK) is the commercial lending bank of &lsquo;petty bureau&rsquo; company syndicates and their workers. Its primary function is bureau negotiation and lending in order to facilitate the economic development of private business in Vekllei. It also acts as an intermediary between petty bureau companies and other banks or government financial apparatuses.</p>
<p>Sisterbank is the primary mechanism by which private business is done in Vekllei, facilitating loans, placement and logistics for small to medium-sized businesses.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-industrial-bank">
  Commonwealth Industrial Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-industrial-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Industrial Bank</em> (MOTHERBANK) is the industrial lending bank of &lsquo;bureau proper&rsquo; company syndicates and their workers. Similar to the Sisterbank, it facilitates economic activity of bureaus and private industry primarily through asset management and mediation with the government and the Commonwealth Bank.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Mint</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-mint/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-mint/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ The Mint is part of the Ministry of Commerce. ✿ Read more: The Vekllei Crown The Commonwealth Mint (also the Mint) is the sole manufacturer of physical currency in Vekllei, tasked with minting and melting the Vekllei Crown. It also regulates gold bullion in the country, and produces bullion for use in the International Market. It is headquartered in Summers, in the western North Atlantic. The Mint also produces paper government certificates and security documents.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ The Mint is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/currency/">The Vekllei Crown</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Mint</strong> (also the <em>Mint</em>) is the sole manufacturer of physical currency in Vekllei, tasked with minting and melting the Vekllei Crown. It also regulates gold bullion in the country, and produces bullion for use in the International Market. It is headquartered in <a style="color: rgb(69, 81, 202)" href="/summers/"><span class="fi fi-summers"></span></span> Summers</a>, in the western North Atlantic. The Mint also produces paper government certificates and security documents.</p>
<p>The Mint is the custodian of the Commonwealth Bullion Depository, which holds reserves of over 6,000 tonnes of gold bullion belonging to the Commonwealth and over 60 other countries, and is among the largest such reserves in the world.</p>
<p>The Mint is well-regarded internationally for the purity of its metals and intricate commemorative coins, leading international numismatics in colour and variety.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Executive Staff</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Exchequer</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-commbank)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></li>
<li><strong>Chancellor</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/mint/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Mint</a></li>
<li>Permanent Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Treasury</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-treasury/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-treasury/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ The Treasury is part of the Ministry of Commerce. The Commonwealth Treasury, commonly The Treasury, is the national treasury, financial department and monetary authority of Vekllei. The Treasury is ultimately responsible for the Vekllei tax system, government revenue and expenditure, and broad economic planning. The Treasury also maintains the GAIA automatic financial relay computer system, which has been the automatic mechanism for microeconomic policy in Vekllei since 2055.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ The Treasury is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Treasury</strong>, commonly <em>The Treasury</em>, is the national treasury, financial department and monetary authority of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The Treasury is ultimately responsible for the Vekllei tax system, government revenue and expenditure, and broad economic planning. The Treasury also maintains the GAIA automatic financial relay computer system, which has been the automatic mechanism for microeconomic policy in Vekllei since 2055.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="executive-staff">
  Executive Staff
  <a class="anchor" href="#executive-staff">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>State Secretary</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a>
<ul>
<li>Permanent Secretary</li>
<li>Undersecretary for Commonwealth Economics</li>
<li>Undersecretary for Foreign Affairs</li>
<li>Chief Analyst</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Permanent Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-securities/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Securities</a></li>
<li>Permanent Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-trade/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Trade</a></li>
<li>Permanent Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmocom)" href="/bureau-of-commonwealth-corporations/"><span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> Bureau of Commonwealth Corporations</a></li>
<li>Permanent Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmocom)" href="/bureau-of-statistics/"><span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> Bureau of Statistics</a></li>
<li><strong>Exchequer</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-commbank)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></li>
<li><strong>Chancellor</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/mint/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Mint</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="departments">
  Departments
  <a class="anchor" href="#departments">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Department of the Treasury</strong>: General department.
<ul>
<li>State Secretariat: Office of the Treasury&rsquo;s State Secretary</li>
<li>General Secretariat: Office of the Treasury&rsquo;s Permanent Secretary</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Commonwealth Economics</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Office of General Seizure</li>
<li>Office of Fiscal Service</li>
<li>Office of Debt</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Revenue &amp; Customs</strong>:</li>
<li><strong>Department of Foreign Affairs</strong>:</li>
<li><strong>Department of Government Accounts</strong>:</li>
<li><strong>Department of Commonwealth Corporations</strong>:</li>
<li><strong>Department of Automatic Systems</strong>: Development and maintenance of economic computers, software and systems.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Economic Information</strong>: Compiles economics data in cooperation with the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmocom)" href="/bureau-of-statistics/"><span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> Bureau of Statistics</a>.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="boards--commissions">
  Boards &amp; Commissions
  <a class="anchor" href="#boards--commissions">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Community Development Board</strong>:</li>
<li><strong>Institute for Economics Research</strong>: Macroeconomic research relevant to international trade.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
