<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Ministry of Commerce</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Ministry of Commerce </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Bureau of Securities</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/bureau-of-securities/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/bureau-of-securities/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This bureau is part of the Ministry of Commerce The Bureau of Securities (VECSEC) regulates securities in Vekllei, mostly in the Commonwealth Securities Exchange. It advises fiscal decision-making to the Treasury and legislates trade practices in the country, including the issuing and ownership of government bonds and bureau securities. It is part of the Ministry of Commerce.
Since Vekllei citizens do not usually participate in the domestic securities markets, the bureau lacks traditional legal authority over many of the foreign participants in its supervised markets, but does extradite and prosecute financial crime through the EUROVEK and USVEK extradition treaties.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This bureau is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> <strong>Bureau of Securities</strong> (VECSEC) regulates securities in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, mostly in the <a style="color: rgb(2, 121, 190)" href="/commsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-commsec fis"></span> Commonwealth Securities Exchange</a>. It advises fiscal decision-making to the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a> and legislates trade practices in the country, including the issuing and ownership of government bonds and bureau securities. It is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</p>
<p>Since Vekllei citizens do not usually participate in the domestic securities markets, the bureau lacks traditional legal authority over many of the foreign participants in its supervised markets, but does extradite and prosecute financial crime through the EUROVEK and USVEK extradition treaties.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="executive-council">
  Executive Council
  <a class="anchor" href="#executive-council">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-securities/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Securities</a>
<ul>
<li>Secretary for Prosecution</li>
<li>Secretary for Investments
<ul>
<li>Undersecretary for Public Investments</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Secretary for Risk &amp; Analysis</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(2, 121, 190)" href="/commsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-commsec fis"></span> Commonwealth Securities Exchange</a></li>
<li><strong>Assistant Secretary</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></li>
<li><strong>Assistant Secretary</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a></li>
<li><strong>Assistant Secretary</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-trade/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Trade</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="departments">
  Departments
  <a class="anchor" href="#departments">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>General Council</strong>: Advisory board to the Commonwealth.</li>
<li><strong>General Procuratorate</strong>: Enforcement of penalties and prosecution of financial crimes.</li>
<li><strong>General Inspectorate</strong>: Investigations into fraud, abuse and corruption in Vekllei markets.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Financing &amp; Stock Exchange</strong>: Regulation and monitoring of the <a style="color: rgb(2, 121, 190)" href="/commsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-commsec fis"></span> Commonwealth Securities Exchange</a> and miscellaneous securities within the country.</li>
<li><strong>Department of International Markets</strong>: Regulation and monitoring of foreign investment and government bonds.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Investments and Trusts</strong>: Regulation and monitoring of the investments, securities and financial contracts of Vekllei citizens and companies.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="boards--commissions">
  Boards &amp; Commissions
  <a class="anchor" href="#boards--commissions">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>National Patent &amp; Trademark Office</strong>: Registration authority for commercial patents and marks.</li>
<li><strong>Intellectual Property Arbitration Board</strong>: Mediator for copyright, patent and trademark disputes before litigation.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Commercial Service</strong>: Promotion of Vekllei products abroad and liaison between industry and foreign partners.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Trade Commission</strong>: Industrial and commodity liaison for foreign companies.</li>
<li><strong><a style="color: rgb(32, 97, 241)" href="/ratings/"><span class="fi fi-min-ratings fis"></span> Commonwealth Ratings Corporation</a></strong>: Independent ratings agency for global private and public debt, which also maintains the CRC/CSX 50 index for the <a style="color: rgb(2, 121, 190)" href="/commsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-commsec fis"></span> Commonwealth Securities Exchange</a>.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bureau of Trade</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/bureau-of-trade/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/bureau-of-trade/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This bureau is part of the Ministry of Commerce The Bureau of Trade regulates consumer protections and antitrust law in Vekllei, and organises trade information from other ministries and supervisory bureaus into policy recommendations and legislation. The Trade Commission also monitors and reports the health of foreign markets, and conducts research into broader geopolitical financial interests, particularly as they compete with domestic interests. It is part of the Ministry of Commerce, and reports primarily to the Treasury.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This bureau is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> <strong>Bureau of Trade</strong> regulates consumer protections and antitrust law in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and organises trade information from other ministries and supervisory bureaus into policy recommendations and legislation. The Trade Commission also monitors and reports the health of foreign markets, and conducts research into broader geopolitical financial interests, particularly as they compete with domestic interests. It is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>, and reports primarily to the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a>.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="executive-council">
  Executive Council
  <a class="anchor" href="#executive-council">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-trade/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Trade</a>
<ul>
<li>Secretary for Trade
<ul>
<li>Undersecretary for Internal Markets</li>
<li>Undersecretary for Tourism</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Secretary of Market Analysis
<ul>
<li>Undersecretary for Market Intelligence</li>
<li>Undersecretary for Foreign Affairs</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Assistant Secretary</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a></li>
<li><strong>Assistant Secretary</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-securities/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Securities</a></li>
<li><strong>Executive</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(2, 121, 190)" href="/commsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-commsec fis"></span> Commonwealth Securities Exchange</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="departments">
  Departments
  <a class="anchor" href="#departments">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Department of Consumer Affairs</strong>: Regulation of the consumer entitlements and protections.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Market Affairs</strong>: Protection of fair markets and regulation of industrial and petty bureau companies, including state monopolies.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Market Research</strong>: Analysis and research of domestic and international markets.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Import &amp; Export</strong>: Analyse and regulation of trade with foreign countries, including harmful trade practices.
<ul>
<li>Export Controls Office</li>
<li>Information Security Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Intelligence</strong>: Monitoring of foreign investment and corporations, as well as overseas research and policy.
<ul>
<li>Office of Foreign Assets Control</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>National Tourism Bureau</strong>: Promotion, research, facilitation and branding of domestic and international travel.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="boards--commissions">
  Boards &amp; Commissions
  <a class="anchor" href="#boards--commissions">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>National Patent &amp; Trademark Office</strong>: Registration authority for commercial patents and marks.</li>
<li><strong>Intellectual Property Arbitration Board</strong>: Mediator for copyright, patent and trademark disputes before litigation.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Commercial Service</strong>: Promotion of Vekllei products abroad and liaison between industry and foreign partners.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Trade Commission</strong>: Industrial and commodity liaison for foreign companies.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Bank</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-bank/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-bank/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ The Commonwealth Bank is part of the Ministry of Commerce The Commonwealth Bank (also Bank of Vekllei) is the central bank and currency store of Vekllei. It is operated by the Ministry of Commerce and maintains branches in all Vekllei republics and in many countries around the world. It is not autonomous and is beholden to the policy decisions of Ministry of Commerce and, in certain cases, the republic and commonwealth parliaments.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ The Commonwealth Bank is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Bank</strong> (also <em>Bank of Vekllei</em>) is the central bank and currency store of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is operated by the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a> and maintains branches in all Vekllei republics and in many countries around the world. It is not autonomous and is beholden to the policy decisions of Ministry of Commerce and, in certain cases, the republic and commonwealth parliaments. Its sworn purpose, as instructed by the Floral Constitution, is to advocate for encourage growth and benefit Vekllei people.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Bank was founded 1642 as the Royal Bank in <a href="/lola/">Lola</a>, and is the fifth oldest bank in the world.</p>
<p>Most banks in Vekllei are institutional or industrial, since the average Vekllei person is unmoneyed and, in a conventional definition, unbanked. Nonetheless, Vekllei maintains several commercial banks under the Bank of Vekllei umbrella, tasked primarily with:</p>
<ul>
<li>Cashing and underwriting White and Blue bonds.</li>
<li>Selling government and financial (bureau) bonds internationally.</li>
<li>International placement and borrowing services.</li>
<li>Trading, settling and selling foreign currencies.</li>
</ul>
<p>Vekllei citizens are entitled to an equal share of the money stored in the Labour Bank, and in certain circumstances may withdraw their balance to emigrate or travel abroad.</p>
<p>Despite foreign perception of Vekllei economics, the liquid and asset holdings of the Bank of Vekllei make it the second-largest bank in the world.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-atlantic-bank">
  Commonwealth Atlantic Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-atlantic-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Atlantic Bank</em> (COMMBANK) is an international investment subsidiary of the Bank of Vekllei, tasked primarily with banking in Commonwealth members and international markets. It has branches across every Commonwealth member-state and in most major economic hubs around the world, including throughout Europe, the Americas, and Asia. It also serves as the Central Bank of the Kalina Isles.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-import-export-bank">
  Commonwealth Import-Export Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-import-export-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Import-Export Bank</em> (VEKEXIM) is a state policy investment bank used to fund projects outside of the Commonwealth, particularly in developing countries. It is the primary investment mechanism of Vekllei foreign aid system, which uses export credits and low-interest bureau loans to build infrastructure overseas. It is among the most influential export banks in the world, and contributed to the Pan-African Railway and Hundred Dams projects as part of Vekllei&rsquo;s ongoing Trade Democracy economic scheme.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-development-bank">
  Commonwealth Development Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-development-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Development Bank</em> (DEVBANK) is a policy bank designed to organise and allocate funding for large-scale political projects, particularly in infrastructure. The Development Bank works as the engine of the Commonwealth&rsquo;s policies, funded mostly with White Bonds issued internationally and labour-guaranteed certificates (a type of Blue Bond). It also creates loan arrangements, evaluates, and underwrites national government projects.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-commercial-bank">
  Commonwealth Commercial Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-commercial-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Commercial Bank</em> (SISTERBANK) is the commercial lending bank of &lsquo;petty bureau&rsquo; company syndicates and their workers. Its primary function is bureau negotiation and lending in order to facilitate the economic development of private business in Vekllei. It also acts as an intermediary between petty bureau companies and other banks or government financial apparatuses.</p>
<p>Sisterbank is the primary mechanism by which private business is done in Vekllei, facilitating loans, placement and logistics for small to medium-sized businesses.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="commonwealth-industrial-bank">
  Commonwealth Industrial Bank
  <a class="anchor" href="#commonwealth-industrial-bank">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Commonwealth Industrial Bank</em> (MOTHERBANK) is the industrial lending bank of &lsquo;bureau proper&rsquo; company syndicates and their workers. Similar to the Sisterbank, it facilitates economic activity of bureaus and private industry primarily through asset management and mediation with the government and the Commonwealth Bank.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Mint</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-mint/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-mint/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ The Mint is part of the Ministry of Commerce ✿ Read more: The Vekllei Crown The Commonwealth Mint (also the Mint) is the sole manufacturer of physical currency in Vekllei, tasked with minting and melting the Vekllei Crown. It also regulates gold bullion in the country, and produces bullion for use in the International Market. It is headquartered in Summers, in the western North Atlantic. The Mint also produces paper government certificates and security documents.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ The Mint is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/currency/">The Vekllei Crown</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Mint</strong> (also the <em>Mint</em>) is the sole manufacturer of physical currency in Vekllei, tasked with minting and melting the Vekllei Crown. It also regulates gold bullion in the country, and produces bullion for use in the International Market. It is headquartered in <a style="color: rgb(69, 81, 202)" href="/summers/"><span class="fi fi-summers"></span></span> Summers</a>, in the western North Atlantic. The Mint also produces paper government certificates and security documents.</p>
<p>The Mint is the custodian of the Commonwealth Bullion Depository, which holds reserves of over 6,000 tonnes of gold bullion belonging to the Commonwealth and over 60 other countries, and is among the largest such reserves in the world.</p>
<p>The Mint is well-regarded internationally for the purity of its metals and intricate commemorative coins, leading international numismatics in colour and variety.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Executive Staff</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Chancellor</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/mint/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Mint</a>
<ul>
<li>Comptroller of the Crown</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Exchequer</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></li>
<li>Permanent Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Treasury</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-treasury/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-treasury/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ The Treasury is part of the Ministry of Commerce The Commonwealth Treasury, commonly The Treasury, is the national treasury, financial department and monetary authority of Vekllei. The Treasury is ultimately responsible for the Vekllei tax system, government revenue and expenditure, and broad economic planning. The Treasury also maintains the GAIA automatic financial relay computer system, which has been the automatic mechanism for microeconomic policy in Vekllei since 2055.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ The Treasury is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Treasury</strong>, commonly <em>The Treasury</em>, is the national treasury, financial department and monetary authority of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The Treasury is ultimately responsible for the Vekllei tax system, government revenue and expenditure, and broad economic planning. The Treasury also maintains the GAIA automatic financial relay computer system, which has been the automatic mechanism for microeconomic policy in Vekllei since 2055.</p>
<p>Departments of the Treasury inform the monetary policy established by the <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a>, and advises money supply and rate adjustments.</p>
<p>The Treasury is lead by the State Secretary for the Treasury, a member of the <a href="/cabinet/">cabinet</a>, but is governed by the Treasurer. Its departments are mostly autonomous, and coordinate through the Department of the Treasury.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="executive-council">
  Executive Council
  <a class="anchor" href="#executive-council">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>State Secretary</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a></li>
<li><strong>Treasurer</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a>
<ul>
<li>Permanent Secretary</li>
<li>Undersecretary for Commonwealth Economics</li>
<li>Undersecretary for Foreign Affairs</li>
<li>Chief Analyst</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Permanent Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-securities/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Securities</a></li>
<li>Permanent Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-trade/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Trade</a></li>
<li>Assistant Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmocom)" href="/bureau-of-commonwealth-corporations/"><span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> Bureau of Commonwealth Corporations</a></li>
<li>Assistant Secretary, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmocom)" href="/bureau-of-statistics/"><span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> Bureau of Statistics</a></li>
<li><strong>Exchequer</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></li>
<li><strong>Chancellor</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/mint/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Mint</a></li>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(2, 121, 190)" href="/commsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-commsec fis"></span> Commonwealth Securities Exchange</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="departments">
  Departments
  <a class="anchor" href="#departments">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Department of the Treasury</strong>: General department and office of the Treasurer.
<ul>
<li>State Secretariat: Office of the Treasury&rsquo;s State Secretary, responsible for implementing government policy.</li>
<li>General Secretariat: Office of the Treasury&rsquo;s Permanent Secretary, regular management of Treasury affairs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Commonwealth Economics</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Office of General Seizure</li>
<li>Office of Fiscal Service</li>
<li>Office of National Debt</li>
<li>National Finance &amp; Investment Corporation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Revenue &amp; Customs</strong>:
<ul>
<li>General Taxation Inspectorate</li>
<li>Office of Government Debt &amp; Liabilities</li>
<li>Office of Financial Services</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Foreign Affairs</strong>: National stakes and accounts in foreign countries.
<ul>
<li>Office of the Americas</li>
<li>Office of Europe</li>
<li>Office of Africa</li>
<li>Office of the Orient</li>
<li>Special Markets Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Government Accounts</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Office of Government Expenditure</li>
<li>National Expenditure Research Organisation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Commonwealth Corporations</strong>: Government-owned corporation management and development.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Automatic Systems</strong>: Development and maintenance of economic computers, software and systems.</li>
<li><strong>Department of Economic Information</strong>: Compilation of economics data in cooperation with the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmocom)" href="/bureau-of-statistics/"><span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> Bureau of Statistics</a>.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="boards--commissions">
  Boards &amp; Commissions
  <a class="anchor" href="#boards--commissions">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Community Development Board</strong>: Special investment vehicle for underprivileged Commonwealth communities.</li>
<li><strong>Institute for Economics Research</strong>: Macroeconomic research relevant to international trade in conjunction with the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmocom)" href="/bureau-of-policy-research/"><span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> Bureau of Policy Research</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Productivity Commission</strong>: Economic productivity research and standards.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Taxation Service</strong>: Revenue collection and registry for taxable business.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Securities Exchange</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-securities-exchange/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-securities-exchange/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Commsec is part of the Ministry of Commerce ✿ Read more: Finance in Vekllei The Commonwealth Securities Exchange (Commsec, or CSX) is a government corporation that operates the national securities and commodities market in Vekllei. It is supervised by the Bureau of Securities. The corporation is itself listed on the CSX.
The CSX is measured by two common indexes: the CSX All Ordinaries and the CRC/CSX 50.
The CSX All Ordinaries index lists the top 500 constituents by market capitalisation, reflecting the size of the overall CSX share market.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Commsec is part of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/finance/">Finance in Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commsec fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Securities Exchange</strong> (Commsec, or CSX) is a <a href="/state-industry/">government corporation</a> that operates the national securities and commodities market in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is supervised by the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-securities/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Securities</a>. The corporation is itself listed on the CSX.</p>
<p>The CSX is measured by two common indexes: the CSX All Ordinaries and the CRC/CSX 50.</p>
<ul>
<li>The CSX All Ordinaries index lists the top 500 constituents by market capitalisation, reflecting the size of the overall CSX share market.</li>
<li>The <a href="/ratings/">CRC/CSX 50</a> indexes only the top 50 constituents and implements liquidity requirements to improve tradability and act as a benchmark for investor returns.</li>
</ul>
<p>The All Ordinaries is rebalanced annually, whereas the CRC/CSX 50 is rebalanced quarterly.</p>
<p>The CSX maintains systems to aid foreign investment, and is often characterised as the entry point to the Vekllei industrial economy. Since most Vekllei people are unbanked and do not handle money, the CSX is primarily a mechanism for government, industry, and private foreign investors.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="executive-council">
  Executive Council
  <a class="anchor" href="#executive-council">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(2, 121, 190)" href="/commsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-commsec fis"></span> Commonwealth Securities Exchange</a>
<ul>
<li>Executive, International Firms Office</li>
<li>Executive, Automatic Trading Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/bureau-of-securities/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Bureau of Securities</a>
<ul>
<li>Director, Commonwealth Commercial Service</li>
<li>Director, Commonwealth Trade Commission</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></li>
<li><strong>Executive</strong>, <a style="color: rgb(32, 97, 241)" href="/ratings/"><span class="fi fi-min-ratings fis"></span> Commonwealth Ratings Corporation</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="constituent-markets">
  Constituent Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#constituent-markets">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>CSX Equity Market</strong>: 8th-largest equity market worldwide, with an average of ❦VK 700 billion secondary trading daily. The CSX equity market currently retains a market capitalisation of ❦VK 600 trillion.</li>
<li><strong>CSX Bond Market</strong>: 4th-largest debt market worldwide, trading mostly foreign debt held by Vekllei companies.</li>
<li><strong>CSX Derivatives Market</strong>: 4th-largest derivates market worldwide.</li>
<li><strong>CSX Foreign Exchange Market</strong>: 6th-largest currency exchange in the world by global turnover, and the Vekllei Crown (❦VK) and U.S. Dollar are the 5th most traded currency pair.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><h4 id="boards--commissions">
  Boards &amp; Commissions
  <a class="anchor" href="#boards--commissions">#</a>
</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Sovereign Wealth Corporation</strong>: State investment corporation that acts as a sovereign wealth fund.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
