<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Borough on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/borough/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Borough on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/borough/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Boroughs</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This page lists completed articles on Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s boroughs ⚠️ This list is evolving, and will be expanded in future. Over the next year I&amp;rsquo;ll be completing this list of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s 100 boroughs, and linking them to images and posts produced in the project. Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s five Crown Boroughs (once included) will be highlighted in bold. A Vekllei borough is an unusual administrative designation, portioned originally by a set of vague criteria that includes size, history, its unique geography, culture, and its spiritual value.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Eyri</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/eyri/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/eyri/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Eyri is an administrative region on the far northwest coast of Vekllei, located in the Afouismeh Region north of Bakur and south of Basa. It is named after Eyri, an isolated coastal community employed mostly in controlled aquaculture by the Ocean Bureau. This quiet borough abounds with myth and legend related to its long seafaring history, emphasised only by the colossal wreck of the nearby icebreaking submarine Sea Serpent.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mirah</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/mirah/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/mirah/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Mirah is an administrative region on the west coast of Vekllei, located east of Tohs and south of Geame. It is named after Mirah, its largest population centre and fishing town dependent largely on deepwater trawling in the Vekllei Sea. It is also home to the Vekllei International Casino, a hotel and resort available only to foreigners, which resides in the town of Gigayeh.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Miyatvousi</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/miyatvousi/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/miyatvousi/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Miyatvousi is an administrative region in northern Vekllei, located in the Lava Region north of Groisniyah and southwest of Lita. Its area is highly volcanic and is home to several natural features, including the Gismavik Dome and the Miyatsimi Geyser Fields. The area outside of the city of Miyatvousi is sparsely populated and mostly claimed by flower-tundras and Crown Land.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Troll</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/troll/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/troll/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Troll is an administrative region in southwest Vekllei, located in the Lava Region directly north of the glacier of Vatnayoskusl. Situated on the sloping north face of the Vekllei Glacier Highlands, the borough is home to several outlet glaciers flowing out of Vatnayoskusl&amp;rsquo;s ice cap.
Troll is sparsely-populated, and only includes the minor town of Troll and several smaller informal settlements.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Voya Voya</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/voya-voya/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/voya-voya/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Voya Voya is an administrative region in southwest Vekllei, located in the Capital Region north of Coyenstisn and east of Lo. It covers the entire area of Voya Voya, a city of some 450,000 people in the capital&amp;rsquo;s extended metro area renowned for its parkland and green spaces. Voya Voya makes up part of the capital&amp;rsquo;s satellite belt of boroughs, characterised by green space and mixed-use residential planning.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bakur</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/bakur/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/bakur/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Bakur is an administrative region on the far northwest coast of Vekllei, located in the Afouismeh Region north of Tanger and south of Eyri. It is named after Bakur, an ancient fishing town with history that predates unified settlement in Vekllei. It has the smallest population of any borough in Vekllei, at only 7,500 permanent residents, which fluctuates seasonally.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Holsyim</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/holsyim/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/holsyim/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Holsyim is an administrative region in the east of Vekllei, located north-east of Seisyo and south-west of Fyell. It is named after Holsyim, its largest population centre. The town of Holsyim borders the Holsyim lo Kronaismioudelfia (Holsyim Crown Land), an isolated natural and spiritual preserve home to some of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s oldest temperate rainforests. It is also a popular resort town, and receives many domestic tourists each year.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Krafla</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/krafla/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/krafla/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Krafla is an administrative region in the north of Vekllei, located in the Lava Region around the Joskuslsa river, north of Lita and south of Kotaismoyeh. The town of Krafla makes up part of a belt of borough capitals along the banks of the Joskuslsa river, formed by glacial runoff from the Vatnayoskusl glacier. It is a sparsely-populated and agricultural borough, and most notable as the site of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s first hydroelectric power plant, which was destroyed in the Krafla Dam Disaster in 1911.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Lita</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/lita/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/lita/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Lita is an administrative region in the east of Vekllei, located in the Lava Region west of Copette and south-east of Krafla. It is named after Lita, its largest population centre and science town nestled in the glacial basins made by millions of years of freshwater runoff. It is well-known in Vekllei as the site of the Lita Cosmodrome, the primary launch site for industrial and scientific spacecraft.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Lola</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/lola/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/lola/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Lola is an administrative region in southwest Vekllei, located in the Capital Region on the ancient city of Reykyavic, south of Sojiya and east of Lava. It includes several of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s oldest inhabited urban neighbourhoods, including Reykjavic, Hosfyourd and Seispri. Characterised by historical architecture and a dense low-rise cityscape, Lola is among Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s most well-known boroughs and makes up part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;original city&amp;rdquo; boundary along its southwest coast.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mumen</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/mumen/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/mumen/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Mumen is an administrative region on the southwest coast of Vekllei, located in the Capital Region south of Pharos and west of Little Vekllei. It is named after Mumen, the city neighbourhood to which it belongs. It is home to one of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s primary immigrant processing centres, and now hosts a thriving immigrant community populated mostly by Southern Europeans.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ou</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/ou/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/ou/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Ou is an administrative region in the central Ro Highlands of Vekllei, located southwest of Laisiyo and north of Kyala. It is named after Ou, a prominent agricultural town of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Middle Period that was transformed in the 20th Century into the cultural and military centre of the Ro Region. At nearly 1.2 million residents, Ou was narrowly excluded from becoming one of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s five Crown Boroughs in 2021, but remains the second-largest borough of the Ro Highlands, after Lonne.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Pharos</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/pharos/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/pharos/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Pharos is an administrative region in the south-west of Vekllei, located in the Capital Region on the Coast of the Americas, north of Mumen and west of Lola. It is best known for its World Jetport, which supports much of its aerospace industry. Despite its international reputation as the masthead of Vekllei aerospace, Pharos is a deeply cultural borough with a rich history, and is home to residents with descendants from all over the world.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Santes</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/santes/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/santes/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Santes is an administrative region in northern Vekllei, located in the Lava Region west of Moma and east of Hoaedesnen. Its area includes several isolated and sparsely-populated towns along Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s northern coast, particularly along the Grimsy and Mus Mus Fjords. The city of Santes is well-served by Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s rail network, but the majority of its coastal and inland towns are somewhat difficult to reach.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Yana</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/yana/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/yana/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about a borough of Vekllei The borough of Yana is an administrative region in central Vekllei, located in the far-western Lava region north of Tiyousn and east of Laisiyo. It is named after Yana, a city of some 45,000 people isolated along Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s sparse, moonlike volcanic interior for which the Lava region is named. Yana makes up part of an agro-belt of depopulated boroughs that sit along the Sesmiousvianneh river, which washes rich igneous minerals north to towns downstream.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>