<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Merce</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/characters/merce/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Merce </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/characters/merce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Chief Inspector</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/patrol/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/patrol/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Local police are one of the basic agents of a Vekllei community. They know their people, and their people know them. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/patrol.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Local police are one of the basic agents of a Vekllei community. They know their people, and their people know them.</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Nabbed</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/nabbed/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/nabbed/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This dumbass got caught setting off fireworks in a bin with some boys behind the school. Constables in Vekllei are servants of their community, and know everyone by name. Misdemeanours are usually punished by something much worse than the courts: the shame and embarrassment.
Vekllei is a federal country that spans the Atlantic, so self reliance and localism are essential aspects of their way of life.
Their police reflects this; local cops have broad informal powers unthinkable overseas, but are kept in check by community and social codependence.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/nabbed.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">This dumbass got caught setting off fireworks in a bin with some boys behind the school.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Constables in Vekllei are servants of their community, and know everyone by name. Misdemeanours are usually punished by something much worse than the courts: the shame and embarrassment.</p>
<p>Vekllei is a federal country that spans the Atlantic, so self reliance and localism are essential aspects of their way of life.</p>
<p>Their police reflects this; local cops have broad informal powers unthinkable overseas, but are kept in check by community and social codependence.</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><p>The Vekllei policing system is informal locally, and so municipal constables have autonomy to fulfil their charter to their community. In this case, Tzipora wasn&rsquo;t breaking a law, but she should be in class so the constable is within her rights to drag her back to it.</p>
<p>The village raises the child, and municipal cops are very much a part of the community, similar to how neighbourhood general practitioners form the bedrock of Vekllei healthcare. They serve important and diverse roles in the community. Most Vekllei neighbourhoods have very low crime, so a lot of what they do is community organising and mediation.</p>
<p>As such, a constable&rsquo;s word on a matter is often a social contract you&rsquo;re expected to obey before it gets litigated formally in court, i.e. disputes between neighbours.</p>
</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Towers in the Park</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/towers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/towers/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Merce was one of seven sisters but she didn’t know it. Like many Vekllei people in young adulthood, her parents were born overseas, and so her Spanish heritage was somewhat obscured.
Growing up in postwar Vekllei, you develop an unusual esprit de corps which supersedes almost everything about you — a civic mission to establish a place in the world regardless of your prior circumstance or heritage. This well-intentioned internationalism cut both ways; you were not much judged about where you came from, but you also did not talk much about where you came from.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/towers.jpg"/> <p><strong>Merce was one of seven sisters</strong> but she didn’t know it. Like many Vekllei people in young adulthood, her parents were born overseas, and so her Spanish heritage was somewhat obscured.</p>
<p>Growing up in postwar Vekllei, you develop an unusual esprit de corps which supersedes almost everything about you — a civic mission to establish a place in the world regardless of your prior circumstance or heritage. This well-intentioned internationalism cut both ways; you were not much judged about where you came from, but you also did not talk much about where you came from.</p>
<p>It did not help that many immigrants in Vekllei were not particularly sentimental about where they came from — they were often outcasts or persecuted back home, and so only treacly childhood nostalgia survived integration. Foods, styles of dress, religious traditions and folk songs were all Merce knew of Spain — the actual lived memory of her father were mostly suppressed. This is how a whole other marriage and six sisters fade away. Stories like these are very common in Vekllei today.</p>
<p>Merce worked as a <a href="/posts/2022-01-11-police/">constable</a> in the <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/pharos/">Pharos</a> neighbourhood of Uclo. Uclo is a big place full of migrants, so she mostly patrolled where she lived in East Uclo, which neighboured <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/pharos/#copetpek">Copetpek</a>. These were pleasant, poor boroughs of the Capital lighted by all corners of the world. They are also strikingly diverse in landscape — West Uclo is mostly pre-war, filled with low-rise Junta-era row houses and coffee shops. East Uclo contains some of Vekllei’s rare “towers in the park” — vertical neighbourhoods in the sky.</p>
<p>The <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/pharos/#uclo-experimental-social-housing-project">Uclo Experimental Social Housing Project</a>, called The Towers by its residents, are the result of direct intervention by the <a href="/factbook/society/government/#vekllei-housing-commission">Vekllei Housing Commission</a>. Most homes are built by municipalities with municipal-sized budgets, since they best know their neighbourhoods, but the catastrophic housing shortages of the early postwar years demanded national intervention. The Towers were built between 2022 and 2024 by innovative British contractors under the recovery lend-lease, and still dominate the landscape today. The six tower blocks are surrounded by gardens, and are closely linked to shops and transport on their periphery to other parts of the city. The <a href="/factbook/society/industry/rail/">VNR</a> Metro has a station directly beneath them.</p>
<p>The Towers are unlike other examples of utopian ‘radiant cities’ because they do not function like other high-rise blocks. Distinctive in their architecture are ways to provide their inhabitants with control over their homes and corridors through great streets in the sky, full of light wells and sunlight. The spaces between apartments are used and cherished, and are extensions of living space for residents Instead of narrow, anonymous corridors and sterile lobbies, the Towers have libraries and food gardens.</p>
<p>This ‘defensible space,’ so-called, is not an initiative of municipal benevolence but in fact a foundational aspect of Newda. Home ownership is an essential feature to the Vekllei way of life, and so apartments are designed in ways that encourage residents to retain social and physical control over their residences and shared spaces — corridors are spacious and communal in the Towers, and crime rates have remained low decades after their construction.</p>
<p>The Towers today are highly desirable but largely filled with owner-occupiers unwilling to vacate. They are also a kind of post-war architecture that is now exceedingly rare in Vekllei. The Housing Commission now prefers mid-rise housing from which you can view the street, and considers more carefully the density of new construction. The success of The Towers was not enough — municipal architects are continuously experimenting with new ways of building homes for the country.</p>
<p>This suits Merce just fine, since she hates waiting for the bloody lifts anyway.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
