<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Technology</title>
	<link>/factbook/society/technology/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Technology </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/society/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Assembly Language</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/common-assembly-language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/common-assembly-language/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Common Assembly Language (commonly Assembly or COMAS) is the common low-level programming language of computers in Vekllei and around the world. It was established by Bell Electric in 1977 and was developed from prior experimentation with machine code translation as early as the 1940s. It translates low-level instructions addressed to the processor of an optical-electric computer into an alphabet mnemonic system more easily understood by humans.
Each command is represented by a unique sequence of balanced ternary digits called a trit.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <p><strong>Common Assembly Language</strong> (commonly <em>Assembly</em> or <em>COMAS</em>) is the common low-level programming language of <a href="/computers/">computers</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> and around the world. It was established by Bell Electric in 1977 and was developed from prior experimentation with machine code translation as early as the 1940s. It translates low-level instructions addressed to the processor of an optical-electric computer into an alphabet mnemonic system more easily understood by humans.</p>
<p>Each command is represented by a unique sequence of balanced ternary digits called a <em>trit</em>. The commands cover basic operation of a computer, including arithmetic, data allocation, control flow and logical operations. These trits represent one of three states, which in optical computing can be executed in parallel:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>+</code>: positive, otherwise represented as <code>+1</code></li>
<li><code>o</code>: zero, otherwise represented as <code>0</code></li>
<li><code>-</code>: negative, otherwise represented as <code>-1</code></li>
</ul>
<p>The following table lists the common commands of mnemonic Assembly and its equivalent machine-code representation as trits.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th><strong>Assembly Command</strong></th>
<th><strong>Mnemonic</strong></th>
<th><strong>Trit Representation</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Add</strong></td>
<td><code>ADD</code></td>
<td><code>+++</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Subtract</strong></td>
<td><code>SUB</code></td>
<td><code>---</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Move</strong></td>
<td><code>MOV</code></td>
<td><code>+--</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Load</strong></td>
<td><code>LOD</code></td>
<td><code>-+-</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Store</strong></td>
<td><code>STO</code></td>
<td><code>--+</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Jump</strong></td>
<td><code>JMP</code></td>
<td><code>+0+</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Jump if Zero</strong></td>
<td><code>JIZ</code></td>
<td><code>0++</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Jump if Negative</strong></td>
<td><code>JIN</code></td>
<td><code>0--</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>And</strong></td>
<td><code>AND</code></td>
<td><code>+-+</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Or</strong></td>
<td><code>OR</code></td>
<td><code>0+0</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Not</strong></td>
<td><code>NOT</code></td>
<td><code>0-0</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Increment</strong></td>
<td><code>INC</code></td>
<td><code>00+</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Decrement</strong></td>
<td><code>DEC</code></td>
<td><code>00-</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Compare</strong></td>
<td><code>CMP</code></td>
<td><code>+0-</code></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>No Operation</strong></td>
<td><code>NOP</code></td>
<td><code>000</code></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Baker-class Air Escort Destroyer</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/baker-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/baker-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Baker-class Air Escort Destroyer Class No. 11 Baker-class Type Air escort destroyer Built 2029-39 Home Station N.S. Mira Crew 320 Displacement 8,500 tons Length 160 meters Speed 32 knots No. in service 15 The Baker-class air escort destroyer is a class of aerial warfare destroyer of the Marine Services of Vekllei. They were constructed at Naval Station Mira in the late 2020s and throughout the 2030s to improve the air defence of Vekllei fleets.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Baker-class Air Escort Destroyer</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>No. 11 Baker-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Air escort destroyer</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2029-39</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-mira/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Mira <span class="fi fi-mira"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>320</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>8,500 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>160 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>32 knots</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>15</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Baker-class air escort destroyer</strong> is a class of aerial warfare destroyer of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. They were constructed at <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/places/ns-mira/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Naval Station Mira</a> in the late 2020s and throughout the 2030s to improve the air defence of Vekllei fleets. They serve with the Commonwealth, Arctic and Antarctic fleets to provide air defence and escort capabilities for naval task groups. With a displacement of 8,500 tons and a length of 160 meters, the ship is equipped to operate independently in contested maritime environments. Its production has been succeeded by the <a href="/swordfish-class/"><em>Swordfish</em></a> class.</p>
<p>Propelled by a <a href="/nmpr/"><em>Vampire</em></a> marine nuclear power plant, the Baker-class can maintain a speed of 35 knots, making it among the fastest large Vekllei warships. The crew complement of 320 personnel includes a mix of officers and enlisted sailors trained in various combat and support roles. The class is also equipped with a hanger capable of stowing two naval aviation helijets for anti-submarine and surface combat roles.</p>
<p>Armament includes the No. 3 <em>Rackham</em> air defence system, utilising its powerful radar dome and to intercept aerial threats at medium ranges. A refit in the 2050s also equipped the class with upgraded dual-launchers for newer No. 6 <em>Shemozzle</em> anti-ship missiles, enhancing its ability to engage large surface targets. For close-range defence, the Baker-class is equipped with a 76 mm gun and a CIWS system to counter incoming missiles and aircraft.</p>
<p>In addition to its combat capabilities, the Baker-class performs roles such as surveillance and reconnaissance, operating alongside aircraft carriers (like the <em><a href="/volcanic-class">Volcanic</a></em>-class) and other surface ships to protect naval formations.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Capricorn-class Attack Submarine</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/capricorn-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/capricorn-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Capricorn-class Attack Submarine Class Capricorn-class Type Attack submarine Built 2052-present Home Station N.S. Oslola Crew 100 Displacement 7,500 tons (submerged) Length 95 meters Speed 35 knots (submerged) No. in service 13 The Capricorn-class Attack Submarine is a class of submarine of the Marine Services of Vekllei. The class is a nuclear-powered vessel designed for a variety of underwater combat missions, including anti-ship, anti-submarine, and reconnaissance roles. With a submerged displacement of 7,500 tons and a length of 95 meters, the submarine is a key asset in Vekllei naval formations, capable of operating independently for extended periods without surfacing.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Capricorn-class Attack Submarine</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Capricorn-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Attack submarine</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2052-present</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-oslola/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Oslola <span class="fi fi-oslola"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>100</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>7,500 tons (submerged)</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>95 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>35 knots (submerged)</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>13</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Capricorn-class Attack Submarine</strong> is a class of submarine of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The class is a nuclear-powered vessel designed for a variety of underwater combat missions, including anti-ship, anti-submarine, and reconnaissance roles. With a submerged displacement of 7,500 tons and a length of 95 meters, the submarine is a key asset in Vekllei naval formations, capable of operating independently for extended periods without surfacing.</p>
<p>Powered by a variant of the <a href="/nmpr/"><em>NMPR</em></a> marine nuclear propulsion system, the Capricorn-class can achieve submerged speeds of up to 35 knots with its magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) jets. Its quiet propulsion system is designed for stealth, allowing it to remain undetected while conducting patrols or approaching enemy fleets. The submarine has a typical crew of 100, including officers and specialists trained for long-duration underwater missions.</p>
<p>The submarine’s armament includes six 533 mm torpedo tubes capable of launching the No. 8 <em>Orca</em> heavy torpedoes, designed for both anti-submarine and anti-surface warfare. In addition to torpedoes, the Capricorn-class can launch No. 2 <em>Lancet</em> cruise missiles from these tubes, providing a secondary strike capability against land-based or large surface targets.</p>
<p>The vessel is also equipped with a sophisticated sonar suite, including passive and active sonar systems for detecting enemy submarines and ships at long ranges. Electronic warfare systems and decoys, among other countermeasures, form part of its defensive complement.</p>
<p>Unlike missile submarines, the <em>Capricorn</em>-class primarily serves larger naval formations in hunter-killer and carrier-defence roles. To these ends, they may stray hundreds of kilometres away from their fleets in search of threats.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Computers</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/computers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/computers/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about computing in Vekllei, but most of these technologies are available world-over Computers are used to subsidise rather than multiply productivity in Vekllei. This does not mean that they do not make commerce or industry more efficient, or open new means of communication between people &ndash; only that they are understood foremost as a social benefit that enables the more idealistic features of the Floral Period and its functional moneylessness.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about computing in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, but most of these technologies are available world-over</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><strong>Computers</strong> are used to subsidise rather than multiply productivity in Vekllei. This does not mean that they do not make commerce or industry more efficient, or open new means of communication between people &ndash; only that they are understood foremost as a social benefit that enables the more idealistic features of the Floral Period and its functional moneylessness. Vekllei is working towards participatory work, and computers are among the dream&rsquo;s most valuable means in which it is being realised.</span>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Vekllei uses electric computers in a range of industrial and commercial applications, which contributes to the increasing automation of the Vekllei Commonwealth workforce. Contemporary computing, known as the photo-electric generation, relies on optical technologies developed by the U.S. military in the 1980s, and were subsequently revolutionised by holographic memory by the U.K. in the 2030s. Vekllei computer science inherits much of its technology database from the U.K. through the Twin Electric research programme, and has contributed significantly to the efficiency and reliability of holographic data storage.</p>
<p>Vekllei has several computer manufacturers, including Votraitey Electrics and <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(224, 40, 35); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(224, 40, 35) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/national-machines/"><span class="fi fi-min-national-machines fis"></span> National Machines</a><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> Votraitey provides commercial imaging services for holographic memory, particularly the DataPlex Photovolumes, and National Machines construct photo-electric mainframes suitable for enterprise-scale networking. The home of Vekllei computer science is the National Photonic Laboratories at Vekllei National University, with industrial research contributed by National Computer&rsquo;s Logic Mechanics division. The Commonwealth aims to be independent of foreign-made components and circuitry by the end of the century.</p>
<h2 id="types-of-computing">
  Types of Computing
  <a class="anchor" href="#types-of-computing">#</a>
</h2>
<p>There are two types of commercial computing in use in Vekllei.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Photo-Electric Computers</strong> (PEC), which are electric machines that are capable of <a href="/factbook/society/technology/computers/#ternary-logic-systems">ternary</a> parallel arithmetic and logical operations.</li>
<li><strong>Fabricated Live Robotics</strong>, which combine computers with synthetic biological components to unlock adaptive and sensory functions.</li>
</ul>
<p>Computing in Vekllei happens at a civic or industrial scale, and rarely interacts with individuals for personal purposes. Most ordinary Vekllei people interact with computers through work or in schools and libraries, where they serve data-lookup and communication purposes. Civilian life in Vekllei is decidedly analogue.</p>
<h3 id="photo-electric-computing">
  Photo-Electric Computing
  <a class="anchor" href="#photo-electric-computing">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="note advice">
  <span class="text">Read more: <a href="/photovolumes/"><em>Photovolumes</em></a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>All programmable Vekllei computers use photo-electric circuits<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> instead of electric transistors and semiconductors. In a Vekllei photo-electric computer, micro-lasers are produced by a wafer made up of mirrors and a cavity to perform digital computations. In place of silicon transistors are photonic crystals called <em>Syncretic Crystal Mechanisms</em>, which reflect light at different wavelengths and form an optical integrated circuit. Devices called spatial light modulators<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> moderate the intensity and phase of these light beams, which are stored as holograms within a crystal as a form of digital memory. These holographic crystals, called <em>Photovolumes</em>, are able to be written and read in parallel, allowing instant access to records in a networked computer system. Most computers contain a protected archive system that duplicates and write-protects data.</p>
<p>Because photo-electric computers require large processing elements to facilitate nonlinear computing and its unique signal-processing devices, computers in Vekllei are heavily centralised and are not found in households. Most large industrial and commercial enterprises maintain a single room-sized &lsquo;Master Computer&rsquo; that networks satellite terminals concurrently. Some centralised industries consolidate master computers into a single photo-electric-robotic system (PER) called an Automatic Asset Command. Famous examples are the Automatic Train Control, which automates <a href="/factbook/society/industry/rail/">Vekllei National Rail</a> operations and programmes robots that can automate train service, and the Vekllei State Archives which maintain a written record of all items in several archival Photovolumes, managed by the Archival Master Computer.</p>
<p>The size, speed and accessibility of data storage in Vekllei means that more data than ever is recorded and preserved, making Vekllei one of the most recorded societies in history. As the site of the Atlantic Telephone and Data Exchange, Vekllei also handles tremendous amounts of trans-Atlantic data regeneration and processing.</p>
<h3 id="ternary-logic-systems">
  Ternary Logic Systems
  <a class="anchor" href="#ternary-logic-systems">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="note advice">
  <span class="text">Main article: <em><a href="/common-assembly-language/">Common Assembly Language</a></em></span>
</blockquote>

<p>Rather than binary logic, in which a state is interpreted as either true or false by a processor,  Vekllei computers use ternary logic. There are three digits that can represent a state, which are called a trit: as such, there are three trits in Vekllei.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>+</code>: positive, otherwise represented as <code>+1</code></li>
<li><code>o</code>: zero, otherwise represented as <code>0</code></li>
<li><code>-</code>: negative, otherwise represented as <code>-1</code></li>
</ul>
<p>Since Vekllei uses optical computers, its systems are naturally able to interpret three different states. In low-level programming, trits are assigned alphabetic mnemonics for basic functions. Some of these include:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>ADD → +++
SUB → ---
MOV → +--
JMP → +0+
</code></pre><p>Optical ternary computers allow simplified and parallel computing, and makes certain arithmetic operations more efficient (especially those involving negative numbers).</p>
<h3 id="fabricated-live-robotics">
  Fabricated Live Robotics
  <a class="anchor" href="#fabricated-live-robotics">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="note advice">
  <span class="text">Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-01-11-automen/">Robots in Vekllei</a></em></span>
</blockquote>

<p>Although processing is usually offloaded to more powerful master computers, Vekllei makes extensive use of organic robotics to automate processes and functions where adaptivity to sensory input is required. These robots, called <em>automasiosn</em> or &lsquo;automen,&rsquo; combine fabricated organic brains with photo-electric circuits to create a programmable, adaptive robot.</p>
<p>Artificial substrates of crystal, called command clocks, are knitted into vat-grown brain tissue to organically process commands. These commands are sometimes digital-optical signals from a master computer, or can be produced by onboard circuitry in response to sensory stimulus. The fabricated brain has natural instincts for balance and orientation, but otherwise bears little resemblance to living, sentient brains. Command clocks in Vekllei are generally made from synthetic quartz and are ionised in manufacturing to enable cartographic crystal pathways, which pass information to axon guns. These guns propel electric signals into the organic tissue, combining the reactivity of organic reflexes with sterile programmability. Newer automen are capable of parallel operations through vertical command wafers.</p>
<p>Automen are used in a variety of roles in Vekllei, including as independent robotic machines and as processing units for systems and data. They are most well known as independent machines, usually tracked or on wheels, that perform a variety of low-skill labour in Vekllei in public places and factories.</p>
<h2 id="accessibility-and-utility">
  Accessibility and Utility
  <a class="anchor" href="#accessibility-and-utility">#</a>
</h2>
<p>All Vekllei people can access computers through public libraries, universities and some schools. These facilities are networked into the National Bulletin System (NBS), a sort of digital bulletin board that allows for real-time communication, content sharing and electronic mail. The National Bulletin System makes up part of the Vekllei Public Intranet, which can be accessed through terminals found in many schools, post offices and libraries. The Vekllei Government and large businesses also maintain their own intranets for use among staff. Computer subcultures exist in Vekllei and participate in unsanctioned network access through home-built relays and primitive hobby computers, a practice known as &lsquo;phreaking.&rsquo;</p>
<p>The Public Intranet is anonymous, but terminals signal their hardware address to the public mainframe, which allows users to specify the location of others. The NBS displays these addresses as postcodes by default.</p>
<p>Vekllei computers use calligraphic displays<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>, which allow primitive vector graphics. Most Vekllei file systems, including the Public Intranet, are text-only and use the VEKSCOPE character encoding standard.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>National Machines S.A. manufactures a range of products outside of computing, and most National computer products are sold under the Voscom and Civic Systems brands.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Also known as optical computing.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>All Vekllei spacial light modulators are optically-addressed.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Also known as vector displays, which use an electron beam that illuminates glowing phosphor to display an image on-screen.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Federal-class Battleship</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/federal-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/federal-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Federal-class Battleship Class Federal-class Type Battleship Built 2027-37 Home Station N.S. Oslola Crew 1,100 Displacement 50,000 tons Length 260 meters Speed 26 knots No. in service 1 The Federal-class battleship is a class of battleship of the Marine Services of Vekllei. The class is a modern take on the traditional battleship, repurposed for fire support roles in amphibious operations and naval engagements. With a displacement of 45,000 tons and a length of 260 meters, it is one of the largest non-carrier surface combatants in the world, designed to deliver sustained heavy firepower in support of ground forces, as well as against naval and coastal targets.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/battleship.jpg"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Federal-class Battleship</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Federal-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Battleship</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2027-37</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-oslola/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Oslola <span class="fi fi-oslola"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>1,100</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>50,000 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>260 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>26 knots</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>1</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Federal-class battleship</strong> is a class of battleship of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The class is a modern take on the traditional battleship, repurposed for fire support roles in amphibious operations and naval engagements. With a displacement of 45,000 tons and a length of 260 meters, it is one of the largest non-carrier surface combatants in the world, designed to deliver sustained heavy firepower in support of ground forces, as well as against naval and coastal targets.</p>
<p>The battleship is powered by two <a href="/nmpr/">NMPR</a> reactors, enabling a top speed of 26 knots. The ship is designed for long-range operations with minimal logistical support, and employs autonomous systems with onboard replenishment capabilities. A crew of 1,100 operates the Federal-class, with most personnel working in fire control and aircraft operations.</p>
<p>The <em>Federal</em>-class is heavily armed with six 406 mm (16-inch) naval guns, housed in two triple turrets. These guns are capable of providing long-range bombardment of shore targets and enemy vessels. It has several other smaller guns for close-in and flak defence. The ship also features two large twin-arm launch-rail systems capable of fielding No. 2 <em>Lancet</em> cruise missiles, among a variety of other large anti-ship missiles and rocket-launched torpedos. For defence, the class is equipped with a mix of short-range anti-air missiles and CIWS to counter incoming missile threats. The <em>Federal</em>-class also includes a range of medium and long-range torpedoes, fired from launchers in its midship.</p>
<p>The <em>Federal</em>-class retains a complement of helijets &ndash; a hybrid aircraft capable of vertical takeoff and landing (VTOL) operations, combining the roles of helicopters and jet fighters. The ship’s flight deck, located aft, can accommodate up to six helijets that are typically used for reconnaissance, air support, and anti-submarine warfare.</p>
<p>The <em>Federal</em>-class primarily serves in a fire support role, delivering heavy bombardment during amphibious operations or coastal sieges. It is also capable of engaging in surface combat, providing area defence for larger task groups. While its role in modern naval warfare is more specialised compared to earlier eras, the <em>Federal</em>-class is a formidable platform for sustained, high-volume firepower in maritime and littoral zones. Its size and armament also imposes a significant psychological effect, a reputation readily exploited by the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> during shore bombardment trials. The only vessel of its class, <em>CVN Commonwealth</em>, serves with the Commonwealth Fleet.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hera-class Minelayer</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/hera-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/hera-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Hera-class Minelayer Class Hera-class Type Minelayer/Minesweeper Built 2055-present Home Station N.S. Java Crew 140 Displacement 4,000 tons Length 115 meters Speed 25 knots No. in service 6 The Hera-class minelayer/minesweeper is a class of minelayer of the Marine Services of Vekllei. The class was designed for both deploying and clearing naval mines, particularly in gulfs and channels of strategic interest to Vekllei. With a displacement of 4,000 tons and a length of 115 meters, the class was designed for operations in littoral and coastal waters, but is also capable of operating in deeper waters when necessary.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Hera-class Minelayer</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Hera-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Minelayer/Minesweeper</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2055-present</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-java/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Java <span class="fi fi-java"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>140</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>4,000 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>115 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>25 knots</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>6</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Hera-class minelayer/minesweeper</strong> is a class of minelayer of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The class was designed for both deploying and clearing naval mines, particularly in gulfs and channels of strategic interest to Vekllei. With a displacement of 4,000 tons and a length of 115 meters, the class was designed for operations in littoral and coastal waters, but is also capable of operating in deeper waters when necessary.</p>
<p>The ship is powered by a <a href="/nmpr/"><em>Vampire</em></a> marine nuclear power plant, allowing a maximum speed of 22 knots. The relatively small crew of 140 is complemented by a range of automated systems.</p>
<p>The Hera-class is equipped with a modular mine-laying system capable of deploying up to 150 naval mines of various types. This includes both defensive minefields to protect strategic locations and offensive minefields intended to deny access to enemy shipping routes. For mine-clearing operations, the ship is fitted with advanced sonar systems and remotely operated vehicles (ROVs) designed to detect, neutralise, or recover naval mines.</p>
<p>In terms of armament, the ship carries a basic self-defence package, including a 30 mm auto-cannon and short-range No. 4 <em>Lucaya</em> anti-aircraft missiles to defend against aerial or surface threats. In Vekllei, the minelayers serve a support role alongside warships, and may be allocated to other fleets as required. Its dual-role design allows it to transition quickly between mine-laying and minesweeping missions.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mantle-class Ballistic Missile Submarine</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/mantle-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/mantle-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Mantle-class Ballistic Missile Submarine Class Mantle-class Type Ballistic Missile Submarine (SSBN) Built 2054-present Home Station N.S. Oslola Crew 140 Displacement 18,000 tons (submerged) Length 170 meters Speed 30 knots (submerged) No. in service 6 The Mantle-class Ballistic Missile Submarine is a class of submarine of the Maritime Service of the Marine Services of Vekllei. The class was designed to serve as a strategic deterrent, capable of launching nuclear-armed ballistic missiles from underwater and ensuring Vekllei&rsquo;s second-strike capability.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/submarine.jpg"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Mantle-class Ballistic Missile Submarine</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Mantle-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Ballistic Missile Submarine (SSBN)</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2054-present</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-oslola/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Oslola <span class="fi fi-oslola"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>140</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>18,000 tons (submerged)</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>170 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>30 knots (submerged)</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>6</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Mantle-class Ballistic Missile Submarine</strong> is a class of submarine of the Maritime Service of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The class was designed to serve as a strategic deterrent, capable of launching nuclear-armed ballistic missiles from underwater and ensuring Vekllei&rsquo;s second-strike capability. With a submerged displacement of 18,000 tons and a length of 170 meters, the Mantle-class is the largest Vekllei submarine and is a cornerstone of its nuclear deterrent. Its home station is <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/places/ns-oslola/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Naval Station Oslola</a>.</p>
<p>Powered by the same <a href="/nmpr/"><em>NMPR</em></a> hydromagnetic propulsion system as the smaller <a href="/capricorn-class/"><em>Capricorn</em></a>-class attack submarine, the <em>Mantle</em>-class can operate at submerged speeds of up to 30 knots. Its reactor allows it to remain submerged for extended periods, offering considerable operational flexibility and stealth in global patrol areas. A crew of 140 operates the submarine, including specialists in missile systems, nuclear operations, and submarine warfare.</p>
<p>The submarine’s primary armament consists of 10 vertical launch tubes capable of firing No. 2 <em>Oceanic</em> ballistic missiles, each of which can be fitted with multiple independently targetable reentry vehicles (MIRVs). These missiles give the <em>Mantle</em>-class significant strike range and capability.</p>
<p>In addition to its missile armament, the <em>Mantle</em>-class is equipped with No. 8 <em>Orca</em> heavy torpedoes in four tubes, enabling it to engage hostile submarines or surface ships if necessary. The vessel also carries advanced sonar and countermeasure systems to evade detection and attacks.</p>
<p>The Mantle-class SSBN is designed for long-duration patrols, operating undetected in the Atlantic (and elsewhere) while remaining a potent nuclear deterrent. Its role is primarily strategic, ensuring that retaliatory nuclear strikes remain possible in the event of an initial attack.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Nike-class Missile Cruiser</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/nike-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/nike-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Nike-class Missile Cruiser Class Nike-class Type Missile cruiser Built 2045-54 Home Station N.S. Verde Crew 250 Displacement 9,500 tons Length 180 meters Speed 30 knots (nuclear) No. in service 6 The Nike-class Missile Cruiser is a class of cruiser of the Marine Services of Vekllei. It was designed as a strategic offensive fleet component with multi-role capabilities, primarily focusing on fleet air defence and limited anti-submarine warfare. They were commissioned and constructed at Oslola Naval Docks beginning in 2025, and offer a robust platform for command and control operations across Vekllei&rsquo;s far-flung Atlantic territories.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Nike-class Missile Cruiser</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Nike-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Missile cruiser</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2045-54</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-verde/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Verde <span class="fi fi-costa-verde"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>250</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>9,500 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>180 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>30 knots (nuclear)</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>6</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Nike-class Missile Cruiser</strong> is a class of cruiser of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It was designed as a strategic offensive fleet component with multi-role capabilities, primarily focusing on fleet air defence and limited anti-submarine warfare. They were commissioned and constructed at Oslola Naval Docks beginning in 2025, and offer a robust platform for command and control operations across Vekllei&rsquo;s far-flung Atlantic territories. The home station of the class is <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/places/ns-verde/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Naval Station Verde</a>.</p>
<p>Powered by a nuclear steam propulsion system, the <em>Nike</em>-class can sustain prolonged deployments with minimal logistical support, though they almost always serve as a fleet component. Its maximum speed of 30 knots allows for rapid repositioning in response to emerging threats. The ship&rsquo;s displacement of 9,500 tons provides ample space for advanced weaponry and onboard facilities, and houses around 250 crew.</p>
<p>Armament includes the No. 3 <em>Rackham</em> missile system, capable of engaging both air and surface targets at ranges exceeding 100 kilometres from four twin-arm launchers at its fore and aft. In regular sailing it carries an armament of about 60 Type 22s. The cruiser is also outfitted with launch tubes for No. 5 <em>Spearhead</em> anti-ship missiles. A 76 mm dual-purpose gun serves as the primary close-in weapon system, complemented by two No. 3 <em>Seascope</em> torpedo launchers for anti-submarine operations.</p>
<p>The <em>Nike</em>-class was designed to support carriers within task groups, conducting patrols, deterrent operations, and strategic reconnaissance missions. Its capabilities make it an integral component of Vekllei naval strategy, aiming to maintain maritime security and project power across the Atlantic.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Nuclear Marine Propulsion Reactor</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/nmpr/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/nmpr/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Vekllei Nuclear Marine Propulsion Reactor (VNMPR, Vampire or NMPR) is a marine propulsion system developed by General Reactor designed for large oceangoing vessels, including warships. Developed to standardise and simplify Vekllei marine power plants, the NMPR is used across most large commercial and military vessels in Vekllei, and variants of its design have been licensed to Argentina, Singapore, the Balkan Federation, India and several other emerging naval construction markets.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <p>The <strong>Vekllei Nuclear Marine Propulsion Reactor</strong> (VNMPR, <em>Vampire</em> or NMPR) is a marine propulsion system developed by <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(53, 156, 103); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(53, 156, 103) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/general-reactor/"><span class="fi fi-min-general-reactor fis"></span> General Reactor</a> designed for large oceangoing vessels, including warships. Developed to standardise and simplify <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> marine power plants, the NMPR is used across most large commercial and military vessels in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and variants of its design have been licensed to Argentina, Singapore, the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(180, 0, 3); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(180, 0, 3) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/balkan/"><span class="fi fi-balkan"></span> Balkan Federation</a>, <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(255, 153, 51); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(255, 153, 51) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/india/"><span class="fi fi-in"></span> India</a> and several other emerging naval construction markets.</p>
<p>The NMPR features a compact design with high-density mixed-oxide (MOX) fuel rods arranged in a hexagonal lattice. The core employs a liquid metal coolant (typically sodium) which offers superior heat transfer capabilities compared to water-based systems. This design allows for higher operational temperatures and thermal efficiencies, generating significant thermal energy for propulsion.</p>
<p>The propulsion system integrates Magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) technology, which converts thermal energy from fission into electrical energy. This energy ionises seawater, propelling it through electromagnetic fields. The MHD system is capable of producing thrust levels exceeding 100 kilonewtons, suitable for both military submarines and commercial vessels. It compares favourably to competing overseas MHD systems in speed and thermal efficiency.</p>
<p>Because of its broad implementation, safety and ease-of-maintenance is a critical component of the reactor&rsquo;s design. It includes robust containment structures made from advanced steel composites and high-temperature ceramics, engineered to withstand extreme conditions. NMPR reactors are equipped with redundant fail-safe systems that automatically initiate shutdown and cooling processes during anomalies. Radiation shielding of the plant structure is enhanced through boron-infused concrete barriers and active radiation absorption technologies. The reactor uses materials to improve durability and corrosion resistance, including advanced titanium alloys and nickel-based superalloys.</p>
<p>The basic design of the reactor is modular, and its installation in standardised vessel plant rooms facilitate straightforward component upgrades. Although first introduced in 2045, the NMPR has seen multiple revisions over its lifespan, and new designs are backwards-compatible with plants already in service.</p>
<p>Energy management is optimised through a computerised grid system powered by an atomic master computer (AMC), which continuously monitors reactor performance and adjusts energy output in real time. High-capacity superconducting magnetic energy storage (SMES) units are utilised to stabilise the power supply and improve overall efficiency, which provides effective load levelling across varying operational demands.</p>
<p>With virtually unlimited operational range, the Nuclear Marine Propulsion Reactor can sustain missions limited only by crew endurance and supplies. It can achieve sub-surface speeds exceeding 30 knots, and its introduction effectively enabled the development of submarine commercial cargo vessels under the Arctic. All large vessels of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Armed Forces</a> and most Vekllei-built commercial shipping use a variant of the NMPR in some form.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Palm-class Submarine Chaser</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/palm-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/palm-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Palm Class Palm-class Type Submarine Chaser Built 2026-36 Home Station N.S. Java Crew 85 Displacement 1,500 tons Length 80 meters Speed 28 knots No. in service 2 The Hera-class minelayer/minesweeper is a class of anti-submarine patrol ship of the Marine Services of Vekllei. The class is a compact and highly manoeuvrable vessel designed for anti-submarine warfare (ASW) operations in both coastal and open waters. With a displacement of 1,500 tons and a length of 80 meters, it is smaller than traditional destroyers and designed specifically for detecting and engaging submarines.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Palm</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Palm-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Submarine Chaser</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2026-36</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-java/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Java <span class="fi fi-java"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>85</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>1,500 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>80 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>28 knots</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>2</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Hera-class minelayer/minesweeper</strong> is a class of anti-submarine patrol ship of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The class is a compact and highly manoeuvrable vessel designed for anti-submarine warfare (ASW) operations in both coastal and open waters. With a displacement of 1,500 tons and a length of 80 meters, it is smaller than traditional destroyers and designed specifically for detecting and engaging submarines.</p>
<p>Powered by the small variant of the <a href="/nmpr/"><em>NMPR</em></a> marine nuclear propulsion system, the Palm-class can reach speeds of up to 35 knots, allowing it to move quickly in response to submarine threats. Its crew of 85 operates the various ASW systems onboard, which are the primary focus of the class’s design.</p>
<p>The ship is equipped with the No. 12 <em>Triton</em> towed sonar array system, which provides long-range detection of submarines. For close-range engagements, it uses a bank of No. 3 <em>Seascope</em> anti-submarine torpedoes, launched from four fixed tubes. The <em>Palm</em>-class also features depth charge racks at the stern, allowing for more traditional anti-submarine attacks in shallow waters.</p>
<p>The ship’s self-defence armament is relatively minimal, with a single 30 mm auto-cannon and short-range No. 4 <em>Lucaya</em> anti-aircraft missiles to fend off aerial threats. It is also equipped with countermeasure systems, including decoys and noisemakers, to evade torpedo attacks.</p>
<p>The <em>Palm</em>-class operates primarily as part of larger ASW task groups in the Commonwealth Fleet, escorting convoys or patrolling known submarine hunting grounds. Its size and agility make it well-suited to engaging enemy submarines in confined areas or near strategic waterways.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Photovolumes</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/photovolumes/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/photovolumes/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Computer data in Vekllei is stored in crystals known as photovolumes. Lasers record and retrieve data from these crystals, which convert the information into electrical signals for use in a computer.
Photovolumes are remarkable devices comprising many complex components. Since Vekllei computers do not use bitmapped screens, all graphics and images accessed electronically are effectively stored in miniature as holograms in the structure of the crystals, which are called photocrystals. In addition to images, regular ternary data can be written and read in parallel, and together form the basic memory components of a Vekllei computer.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/photovolume.jpg"/> <p>Computer data in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> is stored in crystals known as <em>photovolumes</em>. Lasers record and retrieve data from these crystals, which convert the information into electrical signals for use in a computer.</p>
<p>Photovolumes are remarkable devices comprising many complex components. Since Vekllei computers do not use bitmapped screens, all graphics and images accessed electronically are effectively stored in miniature as holograms in the structure of the crystals, which are called <em>photocrystals</em>. In addition to images, regular <a href="/factbook/society/technology/computers/#ternary-logic-systems/">ternary</a> data can be written and read in parallel, and together form the basic memory components of a Vekllei <a href="/computers/">computer</a>.</p>
<h2 id="operation">
  Operation
  <a class="anchor" href="#operation">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Photovolumes can store all kinds of data encoded as light wavelengths, including images. It first has to be recorded (encoded) into a light pattern, usually by projecting the image onto a photosensitive material like laserfilm.</p>
<p>This is done with a laser beam fired by a device called a <strong>light gun</strong>. It produces a laser that is split with a prism to form two distinct beams with different functions:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>A signal beam</strong>, which is pointed at an object and shines at its surface. This light scatters around and carries information about the object, like its shape, texture and details. This laser shines between the object and the photocrystal recording medium.</li>
<li><strong>A reference beam</strong>, which is pointed at the photocrystal. This is a clean, unaltered signal.</li>
</ul>
<p>When the two beams meet at a superposition, they interfere with each other, creating what is called an <strong>interference pattern</strong>. This pattern is a complex map of the image (or data) including its shape, texture and details. The pattern encodes the amplitude (brightness) and phase (wave shape) information of the object into the crystal. This works like a pen and ink, with the <em>reference beam</em> providing a steady flow of unaltered ink and the <em>signal beam</em> shaping it.</p>
<p><strong>Light interference</strong> occurs where the waves of both beams meet, creating bright spots. <strong>Dark interference</strong> occurs where the waves are misaligned, where the peaks of one amplitude meet the troughs of another, creating dark spots. These light and dark spots are known as <strong>constructive</strong> and <strong>destructive</strong> interference patterns respectively. These light and dark spots affect the photocrystal, and form a pattern that can be read back to reconstruct the data.</p>
<p>In Vekllei, there are two main types of photocrystal in use in commercial photovolumes:</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li><strong>Photorefractive photocrystals</strong> can be read and overwritten over and over again, making them useful to store data that needs to be updated, moved or deleted. There are two kinds of photorefractive photocrystal used in commercial photovolumes in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>:
<ul>
<li><em>Lithium Niobate</em> (LiNbO₃), which is more durable and well-suited for the nonlinear optical computing used in Vekllei thanks to its good piezoelectric and photoelectric properties.</li>
<li><em>Barium Titanate</em> (BaTiO₃), which is more photorefractive and faster to read and write from, at the expense of durability. This is often used as a form of cache in large memory archives.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Photopolymer photocrystals</strong> are written to once before hardening, permanently fixing the data patterns in place. In this state, it is able to be read over and over again. These photocrystals form the basis of Vekllei archive volumes, and will last a very long time. Once written to, however, they typically cannot be overwritten.</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<p>As the beams move across the surface of the photocrystal, they affect its physical properties. Depending on the type of crystal, constructive interference may affect its density, refraction index or its light absorption qualities. This occurs on a microscopic scale, in billionths of a meter.</p>
<p>To retrieve the information, the <em>reference beam</em> is pointed at the crystal at the same angle and conditions. As it strikes the <em>interference pattern</em> it refracts the reference beam, which reconstructs the original signal beam&rsquo;s wavefront. This wavefront is fed into a photodetector, which translates the shape of the waves into ternary data that a computer can understand. Images signals are passed through directly, cached and positioned by metadata.</p>
<h2 id="design">
  Design
  <a class="anchor" href="#design">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Vekllei commercial photovolumes are typically the size of a paperback novel. They can interface with optical computers and are plugged in via a photovolume port, which contains the photodetector required to parse the wave data from a photocrystal.</p>
<p>Inside a photovolume there is a <strong>head assembly</strong> consisting of a laser, beam splitters and mirror arrays to deflect the beams. There are also electrical components required to interface with a computer.</p>
<p>The data in the drive is stored in trays, which contain crystal wafers derived from a larger crystal boule. These look like very thin disks, and have a large surface area to read and write data to. In most commercial photovolumes, there is a smaller tray called a <strong>cache</strong> that uses higher-performance crystal wafers for temporary storage to increase data retrieval speeds.</p>
<h2 id="storage-information">
  Storage Information
  <a class="anchor" href="#storage-information">#</a>
</h2>
<p>In ternary computing, the smallest kind of data is called a <strong>trit</strong> &ndash; three values that make up a single character. Photovolumes store trits and physical images alongside each other to store useful data for <a href="/computers/">computers</a>.</p>
<p>Scientific ternary units are represented as Metr, Gitr, Tetr and so on. In common use, an &lsquo;ah&rsquo; sound has been appended to most of the units to make them easier to pronounce.</p>
<p>Photovolumes typically have a storage density ranging between 100-200 tetra per square inch. A typical commercial drive might have a storage capacity of 5,000 tetra, or 5 petra.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Unit</th>
<th>Number of Trits</th>
<th>Equivalent in Base-3</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Trit</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>3^0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kitra (Kit)</td>
<td>1,024</td>
<td>3^10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Metra (Metr)</td>
<td>1,048,576</td>
<td>3^20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Gitra (Gitr)</td>
<td>1,073,741,824</td>
<td>3^30</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Tetra (Tetr)</td>
<td>1,099,511,627,776</td>
<td>3^40</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Petra (Petr)</td>
<td>1,125,899,906,842,624</td>
<td>3^50</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Etra (Etr)</td>
<td>1,152,921,504,606,846,976</td>
<td>3^60</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Zetra (Zetr)</td>
<td>1,180,591,620,717,411,303,424</td>
<td>3^70</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Yotra (Yotr)</td>
<td>1,208,925,819,614,629,174,706,176</td>
<td>3^80</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Prosperity-class Aircraft Cruiser</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/prosperity-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/prosperity-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Prosperity-class Aircraft Cruiser Class Prosperity-class Type Aircraft Cruiser Built 2032-42 Home Station N.S. Java Crew 900 Displacement 30,000 tons Length 240 meters Speed 27 knots No. in service 6 The Prosperity-class Aircraft Cruiser is a class of cruiser of the Marine Services of Vekllei. It is a hybrid warship that combines the fire-support and missile defence role of a traditional cruiser with the ability to carry a small complement of VTOL aircraft.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Prosperity-class Aircraft Cruiser</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Prosperity-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Aircraft Cruiser</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2032-42</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-java/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Java <span class="fi fi-java"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>900</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>30,000 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>240 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>27 knots</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>6</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Prosperity-class Aircraft Cruiser</strong> is a class of cruiser of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is a hybrid warship that combines the fire-support and missile defence role of a traditional cruiser with the ability to carry a small complement of VTOL aircraft. Designed primarily for independent operations or as part of smaller task forces, the class is capable of supporting limited air operations while also providing surface warfare capabilities. Its home station is <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/places/ns-java/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Naval Station Java</a> in <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(217, 20, 19); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(217, 20, 19) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/verde/java/"><span class="fi fi-java"></span> Java</a>.</p>
<p>Displacing 30,000 tons and measuring 240 meters in length, the Prosperity-class is powered by the <a href="/nmpr/"><em>Vampire</em></a> marine nuclear power plant, allowing it to operate at a sustained speed of 27 knots. The vessel carries a typical air wing of 12 to 16 aircraft, including VTOL multirole fighters and anti-submarine helijets. These aircraft are launched from a large flat deck at the aft of the ship, enabling up to 4 aircraft on deck at a time.</p>
<p>The primary armament includes the  No. 3 <em>Rackham</em> anti-aircraft missile system, designed for medium-range defence against air targets. The ship also has twin-launchers for No. 5 <em>Spearhead</em> anti-ship missiles, offering surface-to-surface engagement capabilities. Close-in defence is handled by multiple CIWS installations, protecting the ship against incoming missiles and aircraft. Additionally, the Prosperity-class is outfitted with dual 76 mm naval guns for surface action and shore bombardment as an naval invasion support vessel. Anti-submarine capabilities are provided by its air complement.</p>
<p>The Prosperity-class is versatile, and serves a variety of roles with the Vekllei navy. The class of ship is suited for operations where a full-sized carrier (like the <a href="/volcanic-class/"><em>Volcanic</em></a>-class) is not necessary but air support is still required, making it a valuable asset in contested regions and asymmetric operations common in Vekllei&rsquo;s strategic interest. Its combination of defence systems and air complement allow it to act as a deterrent and as a flexible mothership for a variety of naval missions.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Suffrage-class Corvette</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/suffrage-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/suffrage-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Suffrage Class Suffrage-class Type Corvette Built 2031-41 Home Station N.S. Kairi Crew 120 Displacement 2,500 tons Length 100 meters Speed 30 knots No. in service 32 The Suffrage-class corvette is a class of corvette of the Marine Services of Vekllei. The Suffrage-class is a smaller, versatile surface combatant designed for patrol, escort, and coastal defence roles. With a displacement of 2,500 tons and a length of 100 meters, the class is large for a corvette, and has an operational capability closer to a frigate than a coastal patrol vessel.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Suffrage</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Suffrage-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Corvette</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2031-41</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-java/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Kairi <span class="fi fi-kairi"></span></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>120</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>2,500 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>100 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>30 knots</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>32</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Suffrage-class corvette</strong> is a class of corvette of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The Suffrage-class is a smaller, versatile surface combatant designed for patrol, escort, and coastal defence roles. With a displacement of 2,500 tons and a length of 100 meters, the class is large for a corvette, and has an operational capability closer to a frigate than a coastal patrol vessel.</p>
<p>Powered by the <a href="/nmpr/"><em>Vampire</em></a> marine nuclear power plant, the corvette can reach speeds of up to 35 knots, making it fast and agile for its size. Its relatively small crew of 120 operates the ship’s various systems, including weapons, sensors, and communications equipment, and retains a suite of automatic targeting and detection systems to reduce crew workload.</p>
<p>The ship’s armament includes a “Vanguard” dual-purpose 76 mm naval gun for surface and air engagements. In addition, it is equipped with “Harpooner” anti-ship missiles for striking surface targets at medium range and a short-range anti-air missile system for self-defense against aerial threats. For anti-submarine operations, the Suffrage-class carries two lightweight torpedo launchers, making it capable of limited ASW missions.</p>
<p>The Suffrage-class is equipped with advanced radar and sonar systems, providing situational awareness in both open-ocean and coastal environments. Its relatively small size and versatility allow it to perform a range of missions, including escorting larger vessels, conducting patrols, and participating in maritime security operations.</p>
<p>While not as heavily armed or armored as larger warships, the Suffrage-class ocean corvette is a flexible asset suited for environments where larger ships may be less practical. Its role in fleet operations typically centers around providing defense, conducting reconnaissance, and engaging smaller surface threats.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Swordfish-class Air Escort Destroyer</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/swordfish-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/swordfish-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Swordfish-class Air Escort Destroyer Class No. 12 Swordfish-class Type Air Escort Destroyer Built 2042-55 Home Station N.S. Mira Crew 310 Displacement 9,000 tons Length 165 meters Speed 33 knots No. in service 17 The Swordfish-class air escort destroyer is a class of aerial warfare destroyer of the Marine Services of Vekllei. The Swordfish-class is a successor of the Baker-class, incorporating updated technologies and design improvements. The class maintains its focus on air defence, providing escort for fleet carriers and other Vekllei naval formations.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Swordfish-class Air Escort Destroyer</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>No. 12 Swordfish-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Air Escort Destroyer</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2042-55</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-mira/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Mira <span class="fi fi-mira"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>310</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>9,000 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>165 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>33 knots</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>17</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Swordfish-class air escort destroyer</strong> is a class of aerial warfare destroyer of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The Swordfish-class is a successor of the <a href="/baker-class/"><em>Baker</em></a>-class, incorporating updated technologies and design improvements. The class maintains its focus on air defence, providing escort for fleet carriers and other Vekllei naval formations. It is slightly larger than the <em>Baker</em> class, with a displacement of 9,000 tons and a length of 165 meters. Its home station is <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/places/ns-mira/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Naval Station Mira</a>.</p>
<p>The destroyer is powered by the same <a href="/nmpr/"><em>Vampire</em></a> marine nuclear power plant as its predecessor, but improvements to its hydrodynamics allows slightly faster sustained speeds of up to 33 knots. The crew size is slightly reduced to 310, due to increased automation in various ship systems.</p>
<p>The primary armament includes the same No. 3 <em>Rackham</em> air defence system, but larger radar arrays allows for longer-range and more precise targeting of aerial threats. The system is complemented by the No. 6 <em>Shemozzle</em> anti-ship missile launchers. A dual-purpose 76 mm gun, improved from earlier designs, and an upgraded CIWS provide point defence.</p>
<p>The <em>Swordfish</em>-class is also equipped with enhanced sensor and electronic warfare systems under two Automatic Asset Command computers, allowing it to detect and track potential threats at greater distances. These updates were made to counter American improvements to chaff detection in their anti-ship missiles. Like the <em>Baker</em>-class, the <em>Swordfish</em>-class is a core part of Vekllei fleet protection and patrol operations, and serves mostly with the Commonwealth Fleet.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Volcanic-class Fleet Carrier</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/volcanic-class/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/technology/vessels/volcanic-class/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Volcanic-class Fleet Carrier Class Volcanic-class Type Aircraft carrier Built 2045-55 Home Station N.S. Verde Crew 1,600 Displacement 60,000 tons Length 300 meters Speed 28 knots No. in service 4 The Volcanic-class fleet carrier is a class of aircraft carrier of the Marine Services of Vekllei. Their introduction over the middle of the 21st Century represents a significant advancement in Vekllei naval aviation capabilities, designed to project air power over Commonwealth republics and support various strategic roles.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th style="background-color: var(--highlight-background)" colspan="2">Volcanic-class Fleet Carrier</th>
	</tr>


	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Class</th>
		<td>Volcanic-class</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Type</th>
		<td>Aircraft carrier</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Built</th>
		<td>2045-55</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
	<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Home Station</th>
	<td><a style="color: var(--color-marine)" href="/ns-verde/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> N.S. Verde <span class="fi fi-costa-verde"></a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Crew</th>
		<td>1,600</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Displacement</th>
		<td>60,000 tons</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Length</th>
		<td>300 meters</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Speed</th>
		<td>28 knots</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">No. in service</th>
		<td>4</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <strong>Volcanic-class fleet carrier</strong> is a class of aircraft carrier of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. Their introduction over the middle of the 21st Century represents a significant advancement in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> naval aviation capabilities, designed to project air power over Commonwealth <a href="/republics/">republics</a> and support various strategic roles. With a displacement of 60,000 tons, the vessel accommodates a large air wing (or &ldquo;section&rdquo;) typically comprising 40 to 50 aircraft, including VTOL advanced strike fighters.</p>
<p>Constructed with a flat-deck design and equipped with an electromagnetic catapult system, the <em>Volcanic</em>-class allows for rapid launching of aircraft. The carrier’s nuclear propulsion system enables extended deployments without the need for frequent refuelling, allowing the class to patrol Vekllei&rsquo;s territories almost continuously.</p>
<p>Armament features include the No. 3 <em>Rackham</em> air-to-air missile system, as well as a close-in weapon system (CIWS) for point defence, as part of a multilayered threat defence against aerial and missile attacks. The vessel also carries the No. 5 <em>Spearhead</em> anti-ship missile.</p>
<p>The <em>Volcanic</em>-class serves multiple roles, including fleet air defence, strike operations, and amphibious support. Its versatility allows for the coordination of joint operations with other naval and air assets, and forms the cornerstone of Vekllei&rsquo;s regional fleets. The capability of the <em>Volcanic</em> class to project power while maintaining logistical support for air operations underscores its importance in contemporary Vekllei naval doctrine.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
