<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Ministry of Defence</title>
	<link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Ministry of Defence </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Armed Forces</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles Overview # The Armed Forces of the Commonwealth are the military of Vekllei, and a constituent armed component of the Ministry of Defence. They comprise the combined armed services of the country, as well as capabilities for public emergencies, law enforcement and civil defence.
Unlike common practice overseas, Vekllei does not have seperate military branches, and instead administers all aspects of defence as a single armed organisation originating as part of the navy, a term which is still used generally to describe all military services.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> <strong>Armed Forces of the Commonwealth</strong> are the military of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and a constituent armed component of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a>. They comprise the combined armed services of the country, as well as capabilities for public emergencies, law enforcement and civil defence.</p>
<p>Unlike common practice overseas, Vekllei does not have seperate military branches, and instead administers all aspects of defence as a single armed organisation originating as part of the navy, a term which is still used generally to describe all military services. As a union of island communities, the Vekllei Navy is its historic and contemporary primary means of defence, and Vekllei doctrine favours an integrated command. As such, all air and land warfare is conducted as part of the Navy under a unified defence command.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>Because all services operate within the Navy, different roles are organised into different services. For example, the traditional surface navy of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/#maritime-service">Maritime Service</a> does not operate its own seaborne aviation, since all aircraft are part of the Navy&rsquo;s <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/#air-service">Air Service</a>. In this context, &ldquo;Navy&rdquo; is a synonym for &ldquo;Military&rdquo; in Vekllei, and equipment, signage and vehicles are marked as such.</p>
<h2 id="vekllei-armed-services">
  Vekllei Armed Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#vekllei-armed-services">#</a>
</h2>
<p>A Vekllei military service is a component of the overall armed forces, and so they overlap and intersect. Unlike most other militaries, which are divided between different branches and coordinated by a central command, Vekllei military services are effectively interchangeable, and form <em>interarmes services</em> for specific missions. A single <em>interarmes service</em> may even involve regiments from all services simultaneously, which would operate as a single unit under a unified command.</p>
<p>Vekllei is a seagoing country of island communities, and so the Marine Services are the backbone of its strategic forces. They are the oldest military organisations of Vekllei and revered by the country.</p>
<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text"><p><strong>Note</strong></p>
<p>In numbered Vekllei services (e.g. Terrestrial &amp; Air Services, etc.), numerical order is preserved and units are not permanently identified by a particular number. Unit numbers are administrative and assist in formation of interarmes services, so units may change numbers regularly. Instead, unit identity and honours are attached to ceremonial and historical names that remain with the unit.</p>
</span>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="span-classnaviconspan-marine-services">
  <span class="navicon">⚓️</span> Marine Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#span-classnaviconspan-marine-services">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Marine Services consist of the armed forces most commonly associated with seaborne warfare and supply, and include equivalents to the Navy and Coast Guard. It is an administrative rather than conceptual distinction, as many other aspects of oceangoing warfare are folded into the air and territorial services, such as naval aviation and marine infantry.</p>
<details>
<summary>Maritime Service</summary>
<p>The <strong>Maritime Service</strong> (the <strong>Navy</strong> or <em>Navy of the Public</em>) is the traditional naval warfare component of the Vekllei military and consists of its surface ships and submarines. It comprises three fleets and an auxiliary service, that functions similarly to a republican or federal militia.</p>
<details>
<summary>Commonwealth Fleet</summary>
<p>The Commonwealth Fleet (<em>Sovereign/Federal Fleet</em>) of the Vekllei Maritime Service is the largest naval formation in Vekllei and is tasked with defence of the country&rsquo;s central corridor, a triangular area with points in <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(33, 131, 67); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(33, 131, 67) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/verde/"><span class="fi fi-verde"></span> Verde</a> and </p>
<ul>
<li>5 Aircraft Carriers
<ul>
<li>1 Supercarrier (flagship <em>CV Vekllei</em>)</li>
<li>2 Fleet Carriers</li>
<li>2 Helicopter Carriers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>3 Battlecruisers</li>
<li>12 Cruisers
<ul>
<li>2 Scout Cruisers</li>
<li>2 Torpedo Cruisers</li>
<li>6 Missile Cruisers</li>
<li>2 Aircraft Cruisers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>28 Destroyers
<ul>
<li>6 Minelayers/Minesweepers</li>
<li>20 Fleet Air Escort Destroyers</li>
<li>2 Submarine Chaser Destroyers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>32 Corvettes</li>
<li>8 Attack Submarines</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Home Fleet (Auxiliary)</summary>
<p>The Home Fleet (also <em>Auxiliary Fleet</em>) of the Commonwealth Maritime Service is an auxiliary fleet stationed across the 70 island city-states that make up the country. Each Vekllei city-state serves as a home port to a particular frigate. While they serve a ceremonial role, they are active warships that perform littoral maritime security duties and can be federalised into other fleets as necessary. The Home Fleet also consists of vessels with a multi-fleet or multipurpose role, and can be reassigned to other fleets as required.</p>
<ul>
<li>82 Frigates
<ul>
<li>70 <a href="/stories/frigate/">Aurora-Class Republic Warships</a></li>
<li>5 Air Scout Frigates</li>
<li>4 Anti-Submarine Warfare Frigates</li>
<li>3 Guided Missile Frigates</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2 Submarine Rescue Ships</li>
<li>4 Assault Ships</li>
<li>28 Landing Craft Vessels</li>
<li>1 Crane Ship</li>
<li>2 Minelayers</li>
<li>6 Minehunters</li>
<li>4 Naval Yachts</li>
<li>3 Amenities Ship</li>
<li>2 Ammunition Ship</li>
<li>2 Floating Dock</li>
<li>1 Troopship (+ 4 Auxiliary)</li>
<li>6 Naval Yachts</li>
<li>4 Accomodation Ships</li>
<li>2 Dispatch Ships</li>
<li>4 Nuclear Replenishment Ships</li>
<li>2 Replenishment Oilers</li>
<li>4 Gunboats</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Arctic Fleet</summary>
<ul>
<li>1 Fleet Carrier</li>
<li>1 Battlecruiser</li>
<li>6 Cruisers
<ul>
<li>4 Nuclear Icebreaker Cruisers</li>
<li>2 Aircraft Cruisers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>12 Destroyers
<ul>
<li>8 Fleet Air Escort Destroyers</li>
<li>3 Missile Destroyers</li>
<li>1 Arsenal Destroyer</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2 Patrol Boats</li>
<li>3 Attack Submarines</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Antarctic Fleet</summary>
<ul>
<li>1 Fleet Carrier</li>
<li>1 Battlecruiser</li>
<li>6 Cruisers
<ul>
<li>4 Nuclear Icebreaker Cruisers</li>
<li>2 Aircraft Cruisers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>12 Destroyers
<ul>
<li>8 Fleet Air Escort Destroyers</li>
<li>3 Missile Destroyers</li>
<li>1 Arsenal Destroyer</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2 Patrol Boats</li>
<li>3 Attack Submarines</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Missile Fleet</summary>
<ul>
<li>2 Arsenal Ships</li>
<li>6 Ballistic Missile Submarines</li>
</ul>
</details>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Littoral Service</summary>
<p>The <strong>Littoral Service</strong> (the <em>Coast Guard</em> or <em>Navy of the Parliament</em>) is the maritime security component of the Vekllei military. It provides customs, policing and search and rescue services for Vekllei&rsquo;s territorial waters and exclusive economic zones, though it frequently patrols international waters in the Atlantic.</p>
<p>The Littoral Service has 12 commands across the Atlantic, Arctic, Antarctic and Caribbean Oceans, including the entirety of the Vekllei exclusive economic zone and territorial waters.</p>
<p><strong>Customs Cutters</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>6 Frigate Customs Cutters</li>
<li>20 Medium Customs Cutters</li>
<li>20 Fast Response Customs Hydrofoils</li>
<li>2 Air Cutters</li>
<li>12 Coastal Patrol Vessels</li>
<li>8 Search and Rescue Vessels</li>
<li>8 Fast Patrol Boats</li>
<li>16 Hovercraft Cutters</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Utility Vessels</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>4 Seagoing Buoy Tenders</li>
<li>10 Coastal Buoy Tenders</li>
<li>4 Coastal Construction Tenders</li>
<li>5 River Tenders</li>
<li>1 Large Ocean Tugboat</li>
<li>2 Medium Ocean Tugboats</li>
<li>10 Harbour Tugboats</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Icebreakers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>4 Heavy Icebreakers</li>
<li>1 Ice-strengthened Oiler</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Survey &amp; Auxiliary Ships</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>2 Hydrographic Survey Ships</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Coastal Artillery Service</summary>
<p>The Coastal Artillery Service provides coastal fortification and defence for Vekllei republics, including counter-battery fire, raiding, and ship boarding.</p>
</details>
<h3 id="span-classnaviconspan-aeronautical--astronautical-services">
  <span class="navicon">✈️</span> Aeronautical &amp; Astronautical Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#span-classnaviconspan-aeronautical--astronautical-services">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Aeronautical &amp; Space Services include the air supremacy, interception and defence elements, as well as services to supply and equip them. They also consist of the missile and air detection elements of the armed forces.</p>
<details>
<summary>Air Service</summary>
<p>The <strong>Air Service</strong> conducts aerial warfare in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It consists of three commands that specialise in different aspects of air support and supremacy. The Air Service is also a major contributor to other services, since marine and territorial doctrines depend heavily on the air service for their combat capability, combat support, transport, logistics and reconnaissance.</p>
<p>Vekllei has a rapid air-mobile posture across its armed forces, which is facilitated by the relative size and availability of its air service. It is also the only service in which women are a majority of participants in combat, since female pilots contribute just over 52% of its servicemen.</p>
<p><strong>Structure</strong></p>
<p>There are three commands in the Air Service, which in the secular Vekllei tradition have specific and exclusive functions. The Air Combat Command comprises all primary offensive squadrons including fighters, helicopters and scouts. The Air Auxiliary Command comprises miscellaneous aviation including search and rescue, training and replenishment. The Air Transport Command provides transport for both logistics and combat organisations.</p>
<details>
<summary>Air Combat Command</summary>
<p>The <em>Air Combat Command</em> (ACC) provides aircraft and crew for combat air services, including both land and seaborne aviation. The vast majority of these are variants of the <a href="/stories/casemate">No. 8 Casemate</a> fighter jet.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>No. 1 Aerocombat Wing</strong>
<br>
The No. 1 AC Wing comprises the primary interceptor and air superiority squadrons of the Air Service.
<ul>
<li>No. 1-8 Fighter Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 2 Aerocombat Wing</strong>
<ul>
<li>No. 9-16 Fighter Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 3 Aeroweapons Wing</strong>
<br>
The Aeroweapons Wing consists of the attack helicopter and helijets squadrons of the Air Service, which are organised with Aeroscouts and Aerorifles to produce air-mobile platoons.
<ul>
<li>No. 17-20 Aeroweapons Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 4 Aeroscouts Wing</strong>
<br>
The Aeroscouts Wing provides reconnaissance services to the Territorial Service and the interarmes air-mobile platoons.
<ul>
<li>No. 21-24 Aeroscouts Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 5 Aeromarine Wing</strong> <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span>
<br>
The No. 5 Aeromarine Wing provides equipment and crew for the Commonwealth Fleet, and comprises the largest naval aviation force in the Air Service.
<ul>
<li>No. 25-31 Marine Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 6 Aeromarine Wing</strong> <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span>
<ul>
<li>No. 32-33 Marine Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 7 Aeromarine Wing</strong> <span class="hollowtag">Arctic Fleet</span>
<ul>
<li>No. 34-35 Marine Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 8 Aeromarine Wing</strong>  <span class="hollowtag">Antarctic Fleet</span>
<ul>
<li>No. 36-37 Marine Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 9 Aeromarine Helicopters Wing</strong>
<br>
The No. 9 MHW comprises the bulk of maritime rotary-wing and helijet aircraft, and are located across fleets and naval bases as required. Aeromarine squadrons may be subdivided into Aeromarine sections depending on the needs of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/#maritime-service">Maritime Service</a>.
<ul>
<li>No. 38-41 Marine Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 10 Aerordnance Wing</strong>
<br>
The No. 10 Bombing Wing comprises the strategic bombing aircraft in Vekllei.
<ul>
<li>No. 42-45 Bombing Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Air Auxiliary Command</summary>
<p>The <em>Air Auxiliary Command</em> (AAC) includes aircraft types not directly associated with other command roles, and encompasses different kinds of aircraft in a support (auxiliary) role.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>No. 1 Aeroxiliary Wing</strong>
<br>
No. 1 AA Wing provides maritime patrol services to the Air Service as well as the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/#maritime-service">Maritime</a> and <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/#littoral-service">Littoral</a> Services. No. 1 Squadron is assigned to the Commonwealth Fleet.
<ul>
<li>No. 1 Maritime Patrol Squadron <span class="hollowtag">Commonwealth Fleet</span></li>
<li>No. 2 Search &amp; Rescue Squadron</li>
<li>No. 3 Air Firefighting Squadron</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 2 Aeroxiliary Wing</strong>
<ul>
<li>No. 4-6 Maritime Patrol Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 3 Air Training Wing</strong>
<br>
The Air Training Wing has two squadrons in the Virgin and Oslolan republics, and trains pilots for the Air Service.
<ul>
<li>No. 1-2 Air Training Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 4 Air Replenishment Wing</strong>
<ul>
<li>No. 1-2 Air Replenishment Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Air Transport Command</summary>
<p>The <em>Air Transport Command</em> (ATC) supports other services, particularly the Territorial Service, and provides air mobility to Rifles regiments as part of its flexible and rapid-manoeuvre doctrine. When mounted in helicopters and helijets, Rifles regiments are known as Aerorifles, and combine with the crew and equipment of an Aerorifles squadron to form a complete air-mobile platoon.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>No. 1 Aerotransport Wing</strong>
<br>
The No. 1 Transport Wing services the transport aircraft fleet. No. 1 &amp; 2 Squadrons are land-based and 3 &amp; 4 specialise in maritime transport, and include flying boats.
<ul>
<li>No. 1 Aerotransport Squadron (Government)</li>
<li>No. 2-3 Aerotransport Squadron (Strategic Airlift)</li>
<li>No. 4 Aerotransport Squadron (Tactical Airlift)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 2 Aerorifles Wing</strong>
<br>
The Aerorifles are the aircraft and crew component of an interarmes air-mobile platoon, and transport individual infantry regiments.
<ul>
<li>No. 5-8 Aerorifles Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 3 Aerorifles Wing</strong>
<ul>
<li>No. 9-12 Aerorifles Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No. 4 Aerorifles Wing</strong>
<ul>
<li>No. 13-16 Aerorifles Squadrons</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</details>
<p><strong>Equipment</strong></p>
<p>Vekllei aircraft are primarily designed and manufactured domestically, and use mostly nuclear propulsion. Efforts to streamline and simplify inventory in recent years have reduced the overall types of aircraft in service.</p>
<details>
<summary>Air Service Aircraft</summary>
<p><strong>Combat Aircraft</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>210 No. 8 Casemate Atomic Fighters</li>
<li>33 No. 7 Demon Atomic Fighters</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bombers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>22 Strategic Bombers</li>
<li>16 Medium Bombers</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Maritime and Patrol Aircraft</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>16 Long Range Search &amp; Rescue Turboprop Aircraft</li>
<li>4 Search &amp; Rescue Flying Boats</li>
<li>2 Heavy-lift Search &amp; Rescue Aircraft</li>
<li>50 Seagoing Utility Helicopters</li>
<li>4 Ground Effect Combat Aircraft</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tanker Aircraft</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>1 Nuclear Replenishment Aircraft</li>
<li>2 Airborne Fuel Replenishment Aircraft</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Transport Aircraft</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>27 Heavy Transport Aircraft</li>
<li>22 Medium Transport Aircraft</li>
<li>18 VIP Transport</li>
<li>24 Strategic Airlifter</li>
<li>12 Tactical Airlifter</li>
<li>4 Ground Effect Heavy Airlifters</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Helicopters</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>42 Attack Helicopters</li>
<li>52 Scout Helicopters</li>
<li>40 Heavy-lift/Utility</li>
<li>20 Anti-Submarine Warfare/Search and Rescue</li>
<li>10 Transport/Utility</li>
<li>60 Transport/Utility</li>
<li>50 Medium-lift/Utility</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Trainer Aircraft</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>20 Primary Trainer Aircraft</li>
<li>15 Training Helicopters</li>
</ul>
</details>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Air Artillery Service</summary>
<p>The Air Artillery Service provides air defence in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It operates a variety of emplacements and point defences as part of Vekllei concentric air defence doctrine, but its primary force consists of mobile anti-air and flak systems.</p>
<details>
  <summary>Air Artillery Command Structure</summary>
<p>The <em>Air Artillery Command</em> (ATC) consists of</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>No. 1-6 Air Artillery Regiments</strong>
<br>
The No. 1 Air Artillery Regiment</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
  <summary>Air Artillery Service Equipment</summary>
<p><strong>Missile Systems</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>25 No. 8 Javelin (Truck)</li>
<li>25 Truck</li>
<li>15 Trailer</li>
<li>1200 missile platform</li>
<li>12 Tracked Carriers</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Man-Portable &amp; AA Guns</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>120 guns</li>
<li>1000 missiles</li>
<li>1500 missiles</li>
</ul>
</details>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Radar Service</summary>
<details>
<summary>Radar Service Equipment</summary>
<p><strong>Radar Systems</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>5 Aerostat Radar Surveillance Balloons</li>
<li>40 Portable Search Target Acquisition Radar</li>
<li>12 Ground Active Electronically Scanned Array</li>
<li>4 Medium Array</li>
<li>40 Counter-battery Radar</li>
<li>20 Giraffe Array</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Radar Jamming Aircraft</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>8 Radar Jamming Aircraft</li>
</ul>
</details>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Missiles Service</summary>
<p>The <strong>Missiles Service</strong> is the tactical and strategic missile defence organisation of the military. They operate mostly from ground sites across the country, located mostly on isolated islands or in the Arctic. They also operate some rail-mounted launch systems that are stationed deep inside tunnels.</p>
<details>
<summary>Missiles Service Equipment</summary>
<p><strong>Ballistic Missiles</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Estimated 16 No. 3 ICBMs</li>
<li>Estimated 40 No. 6 IRBMs</li>
<li>Estimated 26 No. 6 SRBMs</li>
<li>Estimated 100 No. 2 SLAM Cruise Missiles</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Trucks &amp; Cars</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>80 Multi-Purpose Utility Vehicle</li>
<li>12 Military Truck</li>
</ul>
</details>
</details>
<h3 id="span-classnaviconspan-land-and-army-services">
  <span class="navicon">🗡️</span> Land and Army Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#span-classnaviconspan-land-and-army-services">#</a>
</h3>
<details>
<summary>Territorial Service</summary>
<p>The Vekllei <strong>Territorial Service</strong> is the closest component to a conventional army in the Vekllei armed forces, and comprises the majority of its professional fighting force. All Rifles regiments are trained as marine infantry, and Vekllei does not maintain dedicated marine regiments. All Territorial regiments are a part of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/#commonwealth-guard">Commonwealth Guard</a> and are federalised the same way, but are distinguished by their professional service and expeditionary posture.</p>
<p>In Vekllei, military units are roughly organised as &lsquo;regiments&rsquo; of 1,000 men and &lsquo;sections&rsquo; of 100.</p>
<p><strong>Organisation</strong></p>
<p>Vekllei has a professional combat army of around 45,000 soldiers, 6,000 of which are commandos that suit its expeditionary and interventionist strategic posture.</p>
<p>Including the Guards and Popular Guards, which serve roles as reservists and partisan militias respectively, that number exceeds a million during wartime.</p>
<details>
  <summary>Commonwealth Rifles</summary>
<p>Rifles regiments consist of 1,000 men, and can be assembled into larger divisional units. Regiment numbers are administrative only and so can change, and regiments are identified with inherited names with honours instead. All Rifles servicemen are also part of a Guards regiment as per the Vekllei federal militia system. Rifles are mechanised with armoured cars.</p>
<p>Policy is to have a standing army 35,000 strong, but Rifles regiments are activated as they are combat-ready, and so the 19th and 20th are often deactivated between training.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Rifles Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>1st-20th Rifles Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Aerorifles Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>21st-24th Aerorifles Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Marine Rifles Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>25th-32nd Marine Rifles Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Special Warfare Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>33rd Chemical Regiment</li>
<li>34th Nuclear Regiment</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Armoured Rifles Regiments</strong>
<br>
The Armoured Rifles are mechanised with infantry fighting vehicles and function as shock infantry.
<ul>
<li>35th-36th Armoured Rifles Regiments</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
  <summary>Commonwealth Commandos</summary>
<p>Commandos in Vekllei are highly trained, professional soldiers with an expeditionary character. While often trained for remote and tactical combat, they are also commonly used to lead interarmes services that include regular rifle infantry.</p>
<p>The 1st-3rd commandos include regional special forces sections for polar, equatorial and lunar warfare. The 6th specialises in unconventional and psychological warfare.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Commandos Regiments</strong>
<ul>
<li>1st-3rd Commandos Regiments</li>
<li>4th Airborne Commandos Regiment</li>
<li>5th Marine Commandos Regiment</li>
<li>6th Special Activities Regiment</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
  <summary>Commonwealth Javelins</summary>
<p>Javelin regiments are the Vekllei name for armoured units, and represent the bulk main battle tank force. They are designed to operate with rifles regiments in interarmes formations.</p>
<p><strong>Javelin Regiments</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>1st-2nd Javelin Regiments</li>
<li>3rd Javelin Scouts Regiment</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
  <summary>Commonwealth Guards</summary>
<p>The Commonwealth Guard is the federal militia and primary reserve force of the Territorial Services. It is federalised by default, and contributes its servicemen for the Rifles and other territorial regiments. As such, all Territorial servicemen are part of a Commonwealth Guards regiment, but in regular service are assigned to active units in other services. Only reservists, trainees and officers remained attached to the Guard while it is federalised.</p>
<p>Guards units are numbered in context to their home <a href="/republics/">republic</a>, i.e. <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a> has Guards regiments numbering 1st-12th.</p>
</details>
<details>
  <summary>Commonwealth Popular Guards</summary>
<p>The Popular Guards are the volunteer militia groups found across the country. They reflect the Vekllei concept of the citizen-soldier, and are distinct from regular guards/reservists by their level of training and organisation. They are strictly volunteer, and are raised and organised by gendarmes of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/police-of-the-parliament/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Police of the Parliament</a>. They number perhaps a million if mobilised totally, and would function as a saboteur and partisan force in the event of war.</p>
</details>
<details>
  <summary>Commonwealth Security Service</summary>
<p>The Commonwealth Security Service is the military police of the territorial service, and primarily provides base security, military intelligence and policing for enlisted servicemen.</p>
<p><strong>Security Service Regiments</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>1st Parliamentary Security Regiment</li>
<li>2nd Industrial Security Regiment, <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-lightandwater); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-lightandwater) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/"><span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> Ministry of Light &amp; Water</a></li>
<li>3rd-4th Security Regiments</li>
<li>5th-6th Strategic Security Regiments</li>
<li>7th Security Intelligence Regiment</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Commonwealth Patrol Service</summary>
<p>The Patrol Service is the armed border guard of Vekllei. While all Vekllei borders are found at sea and involve the Littoral Service, the Patrol Service provides onshore security and policing.</p>
<p>Although the service is organised into regiments, their formations are better reflected by their regional sections.</p>
<p><strong>Patrol Service Regiments</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>1st-8th Patrol Regiments</li>
</ul>
</details>
<p><strong>Equipment</strong></p>
<details>
<summary>Territorial Service Equipment</summary>
<h5 id="main-battle-tanks">
  Main Battle Tanks
  <a class="anchor" href="#main-battle-tanks">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>310 No. 4 Sekhmet MBT</li>
<li>21 No. 3 Ordoria MBT</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="infantry-fighting-vehicles">
  Infantry Fighting Vehicles
  <a class="anchor" href="#infantry-fighting-vehicles">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>300 Combat Reconnaissance Vehicles (ASLAV)</li>
<li>1600 Infantry Fighting Vehicles</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="armoured-personnel-carriers">
  Armoured Personnel Carriers
  <a class="anchor" href="#armoured-personnel-carriers">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>3500 Armoured Personnel Carriers (Commandos)</li>
<li>1400 Tracked APCs</li>
<li>800 Amphibious Armoured Vehicles</li>
<li>600 Armoured All-Terrain Carriers</li>
<li>460 Armoured Cars</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="watercraft">
  Watercraft
  <a class="anchor" href="#watercraft">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>30 Amphibious Cargo Vehicles</li>
<li>24 Mechanised Landing Craft</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="trucks--cars">
  Trucks &amp; Cars
  <a class="anchor" href="#trucks--cars">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>3,600 Multi-Purpose Utility Vehicle</li>
<li>3,560 Military Truck</li>
<li>30 High-Mobility Transporters</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="mine-resistant-and-ambush-vehicles">
  Mine-Resistant and Ambush Vehicles
  <a class="anchor" href="#mine-resistant-and-ambush-vehicles">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>240 Protected Combat Support Vehicle</li>
<li>180 Armoured Personnel Support Vehicle</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="engineering-vehicles">
  Engineering Vehicles
  <a class="anchor" href="#engineering-vehicles">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>30 Armoured Combat Engineering Vehicles</li>
<li>80 Combat Recovery Vehicles</li>
<li>20 Vehicle-Launched Bridges</li>
<li>72 Armoured Tractors</li>
<li>15 Amphibious Bridging Vehicles</li>
<li>6 Demining Vehicles</li>
<li>12 Mine Detection Vehicles</li>
<li>20 Bulldozers</li>
<li>8 Backhoe Loaders</li>
</ul>
</details>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Field Artillery Service</summary>
<details>
  <summary>Field Artillery Service Structure</summary>
<h5 id="field-artillery">
  Field Artillery
  <a class="anchor" href="#field-artillery">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>1st-5th Cannons Regiments</li>
</ul>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Artillery Service Equipment</summary>
<h5 id="artillery">
  Artillery
  <a class="anchor" href="#artillery">#</a>
</h5>
<ul>
<li>52 Rocket Artillery</li>
<li>105 Self-Propelled Artillery</li>
<li>120 155mm Towed Howitzer</li>
<li>80 105mm Towed Howitzer</li>
<li>75 Ceremonial Gun-Howitzer</li>
</ul>
</details>
</details>
<details>
<summary>Signals Service</summary>
<details>
<summary>Signals Service Equipment</summary>
<ul>
<li>4 Signals Interceptor Aircraft</li>
<li>2 Intelligence &amp; Control Aircraft</li>
<li>6 Early Warning Aircraft</li>
</ul>
</details>
</details>
<style>
  details div {
  padding: 0;
  }
  .hollowtag {
    line-height: .8rem!important;
    padding: 0.1rem 0.25rem;
    border: 1px solid var(--color-gray);
    list-style: none;
    width: fit-content;
    color: var(--color-gray);
    border-radius: 0.25rem;
  }
  h5 {
    font-size: 1.1rem;
  }
</style><div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The &rsquo;navy&rsquo; as described here is seperate from the Maritime Service, which comprises the naval fleets of Vekllei. It is a broader termp distinct from the maritime and littoral services.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bureau of Supply</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/bureau-of-supply/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/bureau-of-supply/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This bureau is part of the Ministry of Defence The Bureau of Supply is a specialised defence organ that coordinates supply and logistics for the Crown Armed Forces and security services of Vekllei, including its policing and intelligence services. The Bureau of Supply also administrates the network of Crown Ordnance Factories and the production and acquisition of aircraft and vehicles. It is not responsible for strategic decisions about the make and type of supply, only the facilitation and distribution of the purchase.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This bureau is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <em>Bureau of Supply</em> is a specialised defence organ that coordinates supply and logistics for the Crown Armed Forces and security services of Vekllei, including its policing and intelligence services. The Bureau of Supply also administrates the network of Crown Ordnance Factories and the production and acquisition of aircraft and vehicles. It is not responsible for strategic decisions about the make and type of supply, only the facilitation and distribution of the purchase.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bureau of War</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/bureau-of-war/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/bureau-of-war/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This bureau is part of the Ministry of Defence The Armed Forces of Vekllei, arranged under the COSMOKOS ministry, are unusual in that they do not have control directly over troops or equipment. The actual armed forces of Vekllei, known as the Crown Armed Forces, are a sovereign feature of the country and as such are placed under direct supervision of the Palace of Vekllei &ndash; seperate from the Vekllei and Commonwealth governments.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This bureau is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <em>Armed Forces of Vekllei</em>, arranged under the COSMOKOS ministry, are unusual in that they do not have control directly over troops or equipment. The actual armed forces of Vekllei, known as the <a href="/factbook/society/state/palace/military/">Crown Armed Forces</a>, are a sovereign feature of the country and as such are placed under direct supervision of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/palace/">Palace of Vekllei</a> &ndash; seperate from the Vekllei and Commonwealth governments.</p>
<p>The purpose of the Armed Forces of Vekllei, an agency-level body under control of COSMOKOS, is to integrate the Crown Armed Forces with the interior government, and facilitate the employ of Vekllei people in the Armed Forces.</p>
<h2 id="department-of-communications">
  Department of Communications
  <a class="anchor" href="#department-of-communications">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <em>Department of Communications</em> is a bureau-level organisation of the Armed Forces responsible for coordinating public information about military activities. It also produces several newspapers and periodicals for servicemen through subservient publishing houses.</p>
<h2 id="department-of-compulsory-service">
  Department of Compulsory Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#department-of-compulsory-service">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <em>Department of Compulsory Service</em> (DoCS, also CS) oversees the Vekllei Compulsory Service Scheme, a hybrid civilian/military conscription law that requires four years from each Commonwealth citizen between the ages of 18 and 32. Despite reporting to the Armed Forces of COSMOKOS, the DoCS does not facilitate widespread conscription and mobilisation of the civilian population, a role served by the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/bureau-of-war/#department-of-mobilisation">DoM</a>. Instead, it is responsible primarily for supervising the fulfilment of the Compulsory Service Scheme, and administrating the conscription and training of Vekllei citizens, including in civilian and industrial roles.</p>
<h2 id="department-of-expeditionary-affairs">
  Department of Expeditionary Affairs
  <a class="anchor" href="#department-of-expeditionary-affairs">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <em>Department of Expeditionary Affairs</em> (DoEA) coordinates military affairs with states overseas, including members of the Commonwealth. Responsibilities include facilitating military exchange and cooperation with foreign militaries, as well as relations-focussed work with strategic and allied nations.</p>
<h2 id="department-of-mobilisation">
  Department of Mobilisation
  <a class="anchor" href="#department-of-mobilisation">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <em>Department of Mobilisation</em> (DoM) is responsible for recruitment in peacetime, and conscription in the outbreak of war. In the Floral Period, Vekllei defensive doctrine aims to make the country &ldquo;ungovernable,&rdquo; requiring widespread mobilisation and training of the civilian population. Unlike the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/bureau-of-war/#department-of-compulsory-service">DoCS</a>, the DoM is concerned primarily with the combat effectiveness of the mobilised population, and is generally distinguished in its strategic military thinking.</p>
<h2 id="department-of-peacekeeping">
  Department of Peacekeeping
  <a class="anchor" href="#department-of-peacekeeping">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <em>Department of Peacekeeping</em> (DoP) coordinates Vekllei&rsquo;s overseas peacekeeping operations. Vekllei is among the largest contributors of men and equipment towards United Nations Peacekeeping Forces, which are responsible to and administrated by the DoP while deployed. The Department of Peacekeeping also engages with international mechanisms for peace, and contributes personnel as part of foreign aid or disaster relief.</p>
<h2 id="intelligence-liaison-office">
  Intelligence Liaison Office
  <a class="anchor" href="#intelligence-liaison-office">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <em>Intelligence Liaison Office</em> is a specialised office that coordinates military intelligence between Vekllei&rsquo;s security apparatuses, particularly those of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#national-intelligence-directorate">National Intelligence Directorate</a>. Intelligence gathering in Vekllei is performed by a variety of mostly autonomous espionage organs, and the purpose of the Liaison is to authenticate and prepare intelligence for military use. It includes the following branches.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>National Intelligence Branch</strong>: Coordination of intelligence gathered by security apparatuses with Armed Forces.</li>
<li><strong>Civilian Intelligence Branch</strong>: Coordination of intelligence gathered by industrial and civilian sectors (in occupied territories, for example) with Armed Forces and security apparatuses.</li>
<li><strong>Strategic Intelligence Branch</strong>: Coordination of intelligence gathered by the Armed Forces with security apparatuses.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="sovereign-liaison-office">
  Sovereign Liaison Office
  <a class="anchor" href="#sovereign-liaison-office">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <em>Sovereign Liaison Office</em> is a specialised office intended to link the command of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/palace/military/">Crown Armed Forces of Vekllei</a> with COSMOKOS, an interior ministry with no direct control over troops of the Crown. Although it is the <em>de facto</em> office of communication with the Crown forces, in practice communication generally occurs directly with the relevant COSMOKOS department. The purpose of the Sovereign Liaison is mostly as a democracy-advocate, supervising the COSMOKOS departments as an anti-corruption watchdog similar to other democracy-advocates. It also ensures COSMOKOS operations do not affect sovereign operations</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Defence Imagery Establishment</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/die/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/die/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This bureau is part of the Ministry of Defence The Defence Imagery Establishment provides geospatial and topographic intelligence to Vekllei and its intelligence community, including the Armed Forces. It operates military satellites, reconnaissance aircraft and specialised information-gathering apparatus that contribute to a geospatial understanding of territories in Vekllei and abroad.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This bureau is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> <strong>Defence Imagery Establishment</strong> provides geospatial and topographic intelligence to <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> and its intelligence community, including the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/military/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Armed Forces</a>. It operates military satellites, reconnaissance aircraft and specialised information-gathering apparatus that contribute to a geospatial understanding of territories in Vekllei and abroad.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>DSRE</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/dsre/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/dsre/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[DSRE is part of the Ministry of Defence and SIRO The Commonwealth Defence Science Research Establishment (DSRE) is a research organisation of the Ministry of Defence. It is a part of SIRO and is the primary government military research organisation in Vekllei. It is also the largest constituent research establishment of SIRO, and has nearly 25,000 employees across many offices, research complexes, and secure facilities.
The DSRE has extensive connections throughout the Commonwealth defence industry, and regularly collaborates with industry here and abroad.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">DSRE is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a> and <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(0, 155, 113); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(0, 155, 113) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commonwealth/siro/"><span class="fi fi-min-siro fis"></span> SIRO</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-dsre fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Defence Science Research Establishment</strong> (DSRE) is a research organisation of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a>. It is a part of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(0, 155, 113); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(0, 155, 113) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commonwealth/siro/"><span class="fi fi-min-siro fis"></span> SIRO</a> and is the primary government military research organisation in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is also the largest constituent research establishment of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(0, 155, 113); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(0, 155, 113) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commonwealth/siro/"><span class="fi fi-min-siro fis"></span> SIRO</a>, and has nearly 25,000 employees across many offices, research complexes, and secure facilities.</p>
<p>The DSRE has extensive connections throughout the Commonwealth defence industry, and regularly collaborates with industry here and abroad. It is a major contributor to Vekllei sciences and several DSRE inventions have trickled down to the public, including the permanent pleat and instaskin.</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><h2 id="executive-council">
  Executive Council
  <a class="anchor" href="#executive-council">#</a>
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/dsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-dsre fis"></span> DSRE</a>
<ul>
<li>Chief Defence Scientist</li>
<li>Officer for Strategic Policy</li>
<li>Secretary for Ordnance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Secretary for Procurement</strong>, <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/bureau-of-supply/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Bureau of Supply</a></li>
<li><strong>Chairman</strong>, DSRE Industry Board</li>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, Defence Research Intelligence Establishment</li>
<li><strong>Director</strong>, <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(0, 155, 113); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(0, 155, 113) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commonwealth/siro/"><span class="fi fi-min-siro fis"></span> SIRO</a></li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><h2 id="departments">
  Departments
  <a class="anchor" href="#departments">#</a>
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>General Headquarters</strong>
<ul>
<li>Office of Control Authority</li>
<li>Office of Research Culture &amp; Personnel</li>
<li>Office of Research Ethics</li>
<li>Office of Security</li>
<li>Office of Strategic Policy</li>
<li>Office of the Chief Defence Scientist</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Chemical, Viral &amp; Nuclear Defence</strong>
<ul>
<li>Defence Chemical Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Viral Laboratories</li>
<li>Nuclear Weapons Secure Research Complex</li>
<li>Radiological &amp; Nuclear Defence Laboratories</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Combat Operations Analysis</strong>
<ul>
<li>Combat Fatigue Research Centre</li>
<li>Combat Psychology Laboratory</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Defence Propulsion &amp; Energy</strong>
<ul>
<li>Defence Combustion Fuel Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Nuclear Propulsion Laboratories</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Defence Signals</strong>
<ul>
<li>Defence Communications Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Surveillance Laboratories</li>
<li>Electric Defence Laboratories</li>
<li>Electric Sensors Development Facility</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Defence Sustainment</strong>
<ul>
<li>Defence Food &amp; Nutrition Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Personnel Materials Laboratories</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Ordnance</strong>
<ul>
<li>Ballistics Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Weapons Simulation &amp; Training Complex</li>
<li>Missile &amp; Rocketry Laboratories</li>
<li>Ordnance Laboratories</li>
<li>Telemetry &amp; Fire Control Laboratories</li>
<li>Commonwealth Small Arms Testing Range</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Robots &amp; Automatics</strong>
<ul>
<li>Defence Combat Robot Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Procurement &amp; Manufacturing Research Complex</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Department of Vehicle &amp; Machine Research</strong>
<ul>
<li>Defence Aerospace Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Logistics Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Marine Laboratories</li>
<li>Defence Satellite Complex</li>
<li>Defence Territorial Laboratories</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><h2 id="boards--commissions">
  Boards &amp; Commissions
  <a class="anchor" href="#boards--commissions">#</a>
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>DSRE Industry Board</strong>: Partner representatives from industry for public-private research.</li>
<li><strong>Defence Research Intelligence Establishment</strong>: Counter-espionage organisation joined with the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-security); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-security) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/parliaments/security/"><span class="fi fi-min-security fis"></span> Security Parliament</a></li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Police of the Parliament</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/police-of-the-parliament/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/police-of-the-parliament/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Police of the Parliament are part of the Ministry of Defence Read more: The Police of the Parliament The Police of the Parliament (also National Police, or VENOPOR) are the national and paramilitary police of Vekllei, responsible for internal security, riot control, counter-terrorism, disaster response, law enforcement and maritime rights protection. The VENOPOR is made up of a variety of organisations dedicated to specialised and tactical forms of policing unavailable to the Police of the Public.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">The Police of the Parliament are part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a></span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note advice">
  <span class="text">Read more: <em><a href="/stories/police/">The Police of the Parliament</a></em></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <em>Police of the Parliament</em> (also National Police, or VENOPOR) are the national and paramilitary police of Vekllei, responsible for internal security, riot control, counter-terrorism, disaster response, law enforcement and maritime rights protection. The VENOPOR is made up of a variety of organisations dedicated to specialised and tactical forms of policing unavailable to the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/police-of-the-parliament/#police-of-the-public">Police of the Public</a>. As a paramilitary force, the VENOPOR are also trained to support the <a href="/factbook/society/state/palace/military/">Crown Armed Forces</a> in wartime, and coordinate broad mobilisation in the event of a defensive war.</p>
<p>VENOPOR jurisdiction is organised within the individual theatre commands of the Crown Armed Forces. Kala, the Antilles and the Vekllei and Kalina Islands maintain their own VENOPOR police forces, and other Commonwealth members and territories are dependent on Vekllei Islands policing.</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><h3 id="sections">
  Sections
  <a class="anchor" href="#sections">#</a>
</h3>
<p><em>Sections</em> are units directly responsible to VENOPOR command and are generally deployed in conventional policing duties. They consist of special units for different types of policing within the jurisdiction of VENOPOR.</p>
<h4 id="companies-section-of-the-parliament-police">
  Companies Section of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#companies-section-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<blockquote class="note advice">
  <span class="text">Read more: <em><a href="/stories/compor/">Compor, Vekllei&rsquo;s Special Police</a></em></span>
</blockquote>
<p>The <em>Companies Section</em> (Compor) is a paramilitary and riot control unit concerned with maintaining public peace. Compor moves to meet riots, participate in counter-terrorism and counter-espionage operations, and support the Crown Armed Forces in wartime.</p>
<h4 id="rifles-section-of-the-parliament-police">
  Rifles Section of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#rifles-section-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<blockquote class="note advice">
  <span class="text">Read more: <em><a href="/stories/rifles/">The Rifles Section</a></em></span>
</blockquote>
<p>The <em>Rifles Section</em> is a special weapons unit employing specially-trained officers and tactical vehicles for high-risk situations. They are tasked primarily with counter-terrorism, hostage and weapons situations.</p>
<h4 id="animals-section-of-the-parliament-police">
  Animals Section of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#animals-section-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Animals Section</em> employs officers trained in animal-handling and their animal companions, usually dogs and horses. It is the oldest of the National Police sections, as the successor of an animals support unit of the Royal Armed Forces in the 16th Century.</p>
</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><h3 id="guards">
  Guards
  <a class="anchor" href="#guards">#</a>
</h3>
<p><em>Guards</em> are semiautonomous units that operate independently of VENOPOR situational command. They are not independent policing branches, and are generally supplied and trained within existing VENOPOR systems, but serve distinct and specialised policing functions outside of the conventional policing duties of VENOPOR <a href="/#sections">sections</a>.</p>
<h4 id="coast-guard-of-the-parliament-police">
  Coast Guard of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#coast-guard-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<blockquote class="note advice">
  <span class="text">Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-11-14-coastguard/">The Vekllei Coast Guard</a></em></span>
</blockquote>
<p>The <em>Vekllei Coast Guard</em> (also the <em>Navy of the Parliament</em> or the <em>Coast Guard of the Parliament Police</em>) is the maritime naval police of Vekllei responsible for search and rescue and law enforcement in the territorial waters of Vekllei.</p>
<p>As part of the Commonwealth Security Concordat, the Vekllei Coast Guard also provides maritime policing services to members of the Commonwealth. It is among the most well-equipped and militarised coast guards in the world, and assists in rigorous protection of Vekllei&rsquo;s Atlantic claims and oceanic exclusive economic zones.</p>
<h4 id="border-guard-of-the-parliament-police">
  Border Guard of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#border-guard-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Customs of Vekllei</em> (also the <em>Vekllei Customs</em> and the <em>Customs of the Parliament Police</em>) are responsible for customs and excise duties in Vekllei (and, largely, the Commonwealth). It is also the law enforcement agency responsible for the import and export of goods in Vekllei.</p>
<h4 id="mint-guard-of-the-parliament-police">
  Mint Guard of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#mint-guard-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<blockquote class="note advice">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/">Gold Sappers</a></em></span>
</blockquote>
<p>The <em>Mint Guard</em> (also <em>Gold Sappers</em>) are responsible for the security of financial assets in Vekllei, particularly currency and gold reserves minted and held by the Vekllei National Mint. In addition to providing security for Mint sites and infrastructure, the Mint Guard also escorts the transfer of Vekllei currency and gold internationally.</p>
<h4 id="judicial-guard-of-the-parliament-police">
  Judicial Guard of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#judicial-guard-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Judicial Guard</em> are responsible for the policing and security of Interior and Commonwealth courts and prisons. The Judicial Guard supply officers for correctional facilities and bailiffs for courthouses, and are also responsible for prisoner transport. Judicial Guards report directly to the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/crown/courts">Courts of Vekllei</a>.</p>
<h4 id="parliament-guard-of-the-parliament-police">
  Parliament Guard of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#parliament-guard-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Special Guard</em> (also Honour Guard) are a security unit responsible for policing high-value and high-risk targets, particularly the Interior and Commonwealth Parliaments, representatives of the Crown, and sites of particular political or historic importance. They are also responsible for the protection of the Prime Ministers and important persons, as well as foreign dignitaries.</p>
<h4 id="militia-of-the-parliament-police">
  Militia of the Parliament Police
  <a class="anchor" href="#militia-of-the-parliament-police">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The <em>Militia</em> of the Parliament Police are an auxiliary and reserve force of the VENOPOR, and serve a similarly paramilitary function in Vekllei society. Although the miltia report to the Crown Armed Forces as part of the VENOPOR, they similarly serve a primarily policing role in peacetime consisting mostly of crowd control and support of conventional policing outfits. Militia units in Vekllei may consist of volunteers, as per the Army Reserves, or conscripts in Compulsory Service.</p>
</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Police of the Public</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/police-of-the-public/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/police-of-the-public/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Police of the Public are part of the Ministry of Defence ✿ Read more: The Police of the Public The Police of the Public (COSMOPOR) are the local police in Vekllei, consisting mostly of constabulary responsible for local policing. COSMOPOR are retained on a municipal level, and divided between municipalities in neighbourhoods known as commissions. A commission is lead by an Inspector or Qualified Constable.
Municipal (public) vs Commonwealth (parliament) police.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">The Police of the Public are part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Ministry of Defence</a></span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/police/">The Police of the Public</a></em></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <em>Police of the Public</em> (COSMOPOR) are the local police in Vekllei, consisting mostly of constabulary responsible for local policing. COSMOPOR are retained on a municipal level, and divided between municipalities in neighbourhoods known as commissions. A commission is lead by an Inspector or Qualified Constable.</p>
<p><figure>
  <a href="/images/fullres/commonwealth-police.jpg"
     target="_blank"
     rel="noopener noreferrer">

    
    
    
    
    

      
      
      
      

      
      
      

      <img class="rcf-image lazyload show-if-js"
        data-srcset="/images/fullres/commonwealth-police_hue64e7969f0ac0db4878bd796b49b23e3_2016745_680x0_resize_q90_h2_box.webp 1x"
        src="/images/fullres/commonwealth-police.jpg"alt="image of a local and government policewoman standing on break" title="Municipal (public) vs Commonwealth (parliament) police." 
        loading="lazy"
      />

      </a>


  
   <figcaption>Municipal (public) vs Commonwealth (parliament) police.</figcaption>
</figure></p>
<p>Each neighbourhood commission, which might comprise an area of thousands of people, is further subdivided in constabularies, which are the responsibility of a constable. Constables general know each person in their constabulary, and visits each residence regularly to confirm the welfare of their community and hear their grievances.</p>
<p>Constables attend to the security and peacefulness of their jurisdictions, and are often unarmed. Most arrests and warrants are executed by Inspectors or VENOPOR officers rather than constables.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
