<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Studio MillMint on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/docs/MillMint/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Studio MillMint on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://millmint.net/docs/MillMint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/docs/MillMint/Intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/docs/MillMint/Intro/</guid>
      <description>🎊 The Epilogue of the Epoch of Rest #  🌺 Note from the Editor
If you&amp;rsquo;re new to the project, start here. This is a crash course on what this website (and the project at large) is all about.  Under Construction
This page is still under construction, and may be incomplete.  What is this project? #  Vekllei is supposed to be an &amp;lsquo;epoch of rest&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a project that&amp;rsquo;s become very big, with a long storyline and lots of characters, but at its heart this world is about peaceful escapism and whimsical nostalgia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characters</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/docs/MillMint/characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/docs/MillMint/characters/</guid>
      <description>🌺 Note from the Editor
Say hi to the characters of the project! This page is an introduction to the characters of this world. See the Characters section for full articles on each person.  Under Construction
This page is still under construction, and may be incomplete.  Cast of Characters #  Tzipora (Zelda) Desmoisnes #  Main article: Tzipora Desmoisnes
Tzipora is the main character and character utopia of this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/docs/MillMint/vekllei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/docs/MillMint/vekllei/</guid>
      <description>Under Construction
This page is still under construction, and may be incomplete.  Vekllei #  1. Overview #  1.1 Introduction #   Vekllei (also The Kingdom of Vekllei, The Vekllei Commonwealth, Islanda, Iceland) is a sovereign island country situated in the northern Atlantic, between Greenland and the Faroe Islands. It consists of the Vekllei city-state (referred to as the Home Island or Crown Metropole), two autonomous territories, six crown territories and various possessions including over a hundred satellite islands and islets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>