<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cobian on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/cobian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cobian on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/cobian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mittens and Metaphysic — Product Atheism and Vekllei object-form</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.    Pictured above: various fashions worn by Vekllei women, showcasing heavy cold-weather dresses, simple styling, strong geometric shapes and colours, loose fits, and modest hemlines.
  Pictured below: postmodern neomarxism, which I’ve tricked you into reading with anime.
 Previous posts on the Vekllei economy, if you’re new:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlantic Boredom</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   For a brief period of time, Zelda and Cobian took it upon themselves to make something of their youth. Cobian fancied herself a gymnast, and though this ambition arrived too late and left too soon, she was quite good at it for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobian and Zelda &#34;head-over-heels&#34;</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   make love not lore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matchstick Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Another paint-sketch — a painting done fast. I’m trying to learn to a) paint and b) paint on an industrial scale.
She’d missed the fast tram, caught a tiny splinter in her thumb, lost a button and now the match wouldn’t strike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   They showed up at the autopool, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Camp</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Just a paint-sketch.
The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Race for Inefficiency — Vekllei’s advocation of austerity, apathy, and playfulness as economic principles</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   This post is about the economy of Vekllei. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a long one. If you have any questions, just ask.
Overview of the Bureau System #  There are many thousands of companies busy with work in Vekllei. The vast majority of these companies are single-person shops (S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canal Living</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform. And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trials of Cobian</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   According to her friends, Tzipora’s contemporary afflictions were tragic. Her medical problems; her violent childhood; her sensitivity and melancholy — you could feel sorry for her, because a lot of her problems were not her fault. She invoked sympathy.
Tzipora never considered herself particularly tragic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Summers in the Arctic (and Newda architecture)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.    Previous post here.
The Café Resmoiones approaches its hundredth birthday as the girls outside await their fifteenth. The building was once a kindergarten, so they’d been told, but through decades of Vekllei’s irreverent planning it had become a café. It was not a very good café, the food was shit, but the building was nice and it was at the bottom of Lola’s steep residential hill.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
