<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Cobian on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/cobian/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Cobian on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/cobian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Contrails</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-17-jets/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-17-jets/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei has the some of the clearest skies in the world, and they are criss-crossed by distant vapour trails of jets coming and going. They bring the world closer together. It was funny to think that Peking and Tokyo were just a few hours away &amp;ndash; it felt very cosmopolitan; very democratic. It emphasised the smallness of the world.
Tzipora would look at the livery of the planes to figure out where they were going.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Lunch in the Park</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-15-wine/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-15-wine/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Vekllei has several cold-weather wine producing regions in its south, concentrated around the boroughs of Horn and Mopapa. Local staples are hearty reds like cabernet sauvignon and pinot noir, since whites are served with dessert or as apéritifs. Wine in Vekllei is a product of mass consumption, and is often drunk with meals even by teenagers.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,
For the people hear us singing, &amp;ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&amp;rdquo;
  As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &amp;ndash;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Changes to the Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-12-reading/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-12-reading/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This post announced changes made for patrons of Vekllei. Read and discuss the changes made in this post on Patreon here.  Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Hello everyone,
Hobart here, creator of this whole thing. For a couple years now I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained a small Patreon for those interested in supporting my work. Like most Patreons, this has operated monthly.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hall Notes</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-23-friends/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-23-friends/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Cobian was a complicated person. When Tzipora met her, she was burdened by her parents and wracked by small faults that glinted openly at the other girls in the school halls. She was insecure, out of touch, a little childish, and desperate to be liked. Tzipora was a fair bit like her, but carried those traits in different ways.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>On Moneylessness</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-09-moneylessness/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-09-moneylessness/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This essay was published on millmint.net. Read it here.   Pictured: Tzipora and Cobian cycle around the cliffs in the borough of Totoyan, on Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s East Coast. Up ahead lies the Ocean Atlantique Restaurant and Public Gardens, run by the Totoyan Municipality.
 The Vekllei Person What good is more writing about theories and the methodology of country-constructs?</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Autumn Love</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-31-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-31-love/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This image was produced as part of a series of concept art for merchandise.  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Recess on the Roof</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-04-roof/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-04-roof/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Tzipora had smoked since she was thirteen, and so she did for the rest of her life. What started out as a nasty habit in California’s decaying boarding school system eventually became a social medicine in the severe anxiety of her school years in Vekllei. She used her packs strategically, afraid of building a dependence that would dilute nicotine’s effects on her frayed nerves.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Generation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-21-generation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-21-generation/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Children of the children of the bomb — a generation of war-babies born in peacetime. That was how they thought of themselves. Their grandparents and great-grandparents had lived through the war and the occupation, and so they had inherited the burden of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s future as a country of long-sufferers, visionaries, and dispossessed.
Some Marxist continental intellectual had said something a half-century ago about the right way to teach children, and the idea had probably caught the ear of some commissar of the Vekllei interim government, who perhaps passed it along to some bureaucrat rebuilding the government schools.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Something New is on The Horizon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-30-june/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-30-june/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Thanks for a great June. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of different types of posts this month. About 15 in all — that&amp;rsquo;s one every two days! Not bad! I could do with some sleep.
Something very special is approaching in July. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to share it with you all — so are Tzipora and Cobian.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Shabbat Shalom</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  When they met, Tzipora told Baron she was Catholic. He thought that was hilarious — it was one of the few times she saw him laugh. Her name was “Tzipora”, and she gave herself the name “Zelda” — who did she think she was kidding? But that’s just how she was; Tzipora was an intricate person of many backgrounds and instincts.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>How to Read Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  This is an unusual post in that, a) it’s particularly text-heavy and desaturated, and b) much of its material is already available on an existing wiki article on my website.
The above article covers the language conceptually in pretty much all the detail you’d ever want. So, despite the heavy use of labels and text, this picture is particularly concerned with the literal appearance and structure of the Vekllei written language, called Topet.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Gone Hollywood</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  You know you’re near the homeland of the Magma-Electric Commission when you smell it. Somewhere between cracking a rotten egg and standing downwind of a sewerage treatment plant, the volcanic heartlands of Vekllei are the playground of the Magma-Electric Commission, often shortened to just “The Magma” or “Thunderburo”. The smell is caused by Hydrogen Sulphide, a byproduct of the naked volcanic activity Vekllei is known for.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Shrine-Minded Girls</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Shattered fjords make up the north of Vekllei, particularly in boroughs like Santes (lit. Saint) which are well-regarded for their striking cliffs and sloping igneous fingers, which evidence Vekllei’s ongoing volcanism. Offshore, hundreds of islets rise and sink over the centuries.
This is the tiny village of Cult, which sits on the sparse tip of the Grimsy Fjord.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei&#39;s New-Age Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.
 — Lu Xun, 1927
 Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &amp;lsquo;backward elements.&amp;rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>City Rivers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Out in Voya Voya, the gardens light the people, and distill human temperament into momentary, sequential lyrical images. A dead leaf moving by miracle across still water; an overturned bucket collecting dew along its handle; fern leaves half-curled, young and growing. Vekllei is known as a “garden city,” and Voya Voya has the best of them.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Moments in Love</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Lava was a modern walled city. It had long lost its walls, but its florid green belt disguised a complex network of trenches, tunnels and forts that linked emplacements in the surrounding mountains. Together, these systems would ensure Vekllei would never again have to tolerate occupation by a foreign power. Lava was on the outskirts of Vekllei’s great capital city, and much of its cityscape was dispersed, affording residents a slower pace of life.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Robots in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  The Vekllei word for a robot is automasiosn, or ‘automan’. When we talk about Vekllei being a “post-scarcity society,” it is by automen through which it happens. They are found across the entire country in all types of hard and boring work, forever dutiful, forever mindless. It is not that the robot has replaced the human worker, since about 90% of Vekllei people are employed.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>How to Speak Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin  For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, https://millmint.net. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mittens and Metaphysic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin   Pictured above: various fashions worn by Vekllei women, showcasing heavy cold-weather dresses, simple styling, strong geometric shapes and colours, loose fits, and modest hemlines.
  Pictured below: postmodern neomarxism, which I’ve tricked you into reading with anime.
 Previous posts on the Vekllei economy, if you’re new:</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Atlantic Boredom</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin  For a brief period of time, Zelda and Cobian took it upon themselves to make something of their youth. Cobian fancied herself a gymnast, and though this ambition arrived too late and left too soon, she was quite good at it for a while.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Cobian and Zelda &#34;head-over-heels&#34;</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  make love not lore</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Matchstick Girl</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Another paint-sketch — a painting done fast. I’m trying to learn to a) paint and b) paint on an industrial scale.
She’d missed the fast tram, caught a tiny splinter in her thumb, lost a button and now the match wouldn’t strike. It just wasn’t her day.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Road Trip</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  They showed up at the autopool, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Unique among girls There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not realise she is unusual, or does not care.
She has a lot of endearing characteristics that give great character to her mannerisms and physicality.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Base Camp</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Just a paint-sketch.
The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Race for Inefficiency</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Vekllei’s advocation of austerity, apathy, and playfulness as economic principles This post is about the economy of Vekllei. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a long one. If you have any questions, just ask.
Overview of the Bureau System There are many thousands of companies busy with work in Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform. And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables. Out here, you paced life around the station.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Trials of Cobian</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  According to her friends, Tzipora’s contemporary afflictions were tragic. Her medical problems; her violent childhood; her sensitivity and melancholy — you could feel sorry for her, because a lot of her problems were not her fault. She invoked sympathy.
Tzipora never considered herself particularly tragic.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meet Cobian, a concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  If you go back through my posts here, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice Tzipora is basically a cartoon whose only consistent characteristic is her iconography &amp;ndash; her hair fountain, bangs, round head and big smile. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really intentional. I&amp;rsquo;m just an amateur artist who is still learning to draw.
That doesn&amp;rsquo;t work so well in a comic with sequential panels, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on standardising my characters.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>So long 2019, here&#39;s to 2020!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the new Vekllei discord — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Kodak Moment by a Vekllei Geyser</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  In her journal for practicing writing the Vekllei language (appropriately called Vekllei), Tzipora wrote:
 The heavy clouds above were children of early spring, but among the steam vents it seemed like the whole sky was polluted by geysers. Large pools, opalescent with healthy minerals, were heated by the core of the Earth. In a volcanic desert of black sand, the geysers were an oasis, rising from the sulphuric fog like a little eden.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Medicating despair in the pasture of plenty</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   Tzipora is doing well now. She has looked into her heart and made peace with who she is. She has discovered she is a girl who likes free jazz, and milky coffee, and cotton shirts, and trains — to the surprise of no-one who knows her. She knows what things she values in a friend, and what deserves to become family.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>1000 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-10-1000-subscribers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-10-1000-subscribers/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Hey everyone,
Hobart here. You might not know it, but I’m sort of a big fucking deal on the internet. No, don’t touch me. Why am I? Because my subreddit just hit 1,000 subscribers. What’s a subreddit? I’m actually laughing at you; imagine not knowing what reddit is. You ingrate.
Seriously though, this whole renewal of the project through a subreddit (rather than disconnected r/worldbuilding posts) has been an amazing thing.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Emotional Intelligence in the Epoch of Rest</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-25-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-25-love/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   Let’s talk about childhood and utopia. This post comes as we wind down Study Month in r/vekllei. Strap in kids, because this one gets kind of heavy.
  Tzipora and Cobian, pictured here, have very different stories but both have felt something was not quite right about them. That difference, so it would turn out, would blossom into a preference for women as partners, in the unusual desexualised way Vekllei goes about homosexuality in the late 2070s.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Uniform Ideology in the Arctic North</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-17-uniform-ideology/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-17-uniform-ideology/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Hello everyone. In celebration of the approach of exams (at least in the Southern Hemisphere), we turn our gaze north to Vekllei to celebrate Study Week. Every other day we’ll be looking at education in Vekllei, and today we’re looking at uniforms.
Life in Vekllei is filled with uniforms for work and in study, for a various historical and cultural reasons.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Living in Tomorrow, Facing the Past</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-22-tomorrow/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-22-tomorrow/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Welcome again to MoonMonth! It started four days ago and will go until I’ve said all I can say. We’re looking at the space industry in Vekllei. This is just a quick piece I&amp;rsquo;ve done between some larger things.
The Copette Science Basin and Rocket Factory launches sixteen rockets a day. Those rockets are packed with robotic mining equipment and are sent chasing asteroids floating through our solar system.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Mountain Railway</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-04-railway/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-04-railway/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Many dozens of little trains wind their way around mountain peaks in the centre of Vekllei. They stop at upland villages and towns of sometimes only a few dozen people, before consolidating into larger terminuses that connect nearly every village in Vekllei by rail. It is possible, should the timetables align, that you can reach the capital from any part of the country in under 2 hours.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Squish!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-01-squish/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-01-squish/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Sorry for breaking my streak everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m on beta software and it totally shit the bed these last couple days. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing my best to hobble along until full release :)
Tzipora is easily squished. In this picture Moise would be around 16, Cobian 15, and Tzipora about 18.
Moise has lost a lot of weight and has been blessed with a hefty frame befitting his temperament.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>At peace, in dark</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-21-peace/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-21-peace/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Zelda liked to sleep beside someone, which made her feel safe and loved, but she never had many friends and she hadn’t a mother to share a bed with. And, despite her enthusiasm, she was not very easy to sleep beside. She was prone to jerking movements and night terrors, and alternated between pushing her partner to the periphery and then clutching them in comfort.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Carry me! &gt;:(</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora and Cobian. They have not been friends for very long but they like each other a lot. Tzipora weighs nearly 10kg less than her friend, so she gets piggy backs more often.
By me! @melon.kony or r/vekllei on reddit!</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Summer sex-ed</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Porno is available over-the-counter at most book stores. Some industry associations attempt to limit availability to minors but generally it&amp;rsquo;s at the discretion of the shopkeeper. Often, shame and embarassment are more powerful tools than legislation in Vekllei.
Generally it&amp;rsquo;s pretty traditional stuff supported by columns and fiction, although it varies between pornographers.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hot Summers in the Arctic (and Newda architecture)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Previous post here.
The Café Resmoiones approaches its hundredth birthday as the girls outside await their fifteenth. The building was once a kindergarten, so they’d been told, but through decades of Vekllei’s irreverent planning it had become a café. It was not a very good café, the food was shit, but the building was nice and it was at the bottom of Lola’s steep residential hill.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Too Old for Sleepovers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Even for those ageless kids, there’s a time when the charade of childhood comes to a head and begs a certain uncomfortable question: at what point does the whole thing — of immaturity, of carelessness, of sleepovers — start looking like two old women posturing around youth, indulging in a sick genetic perversion?</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>winter love &#43; puffin / feat. Tzipora &amp; Akiko</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-19-puffin-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-19-puffin-love/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  &amp;ldquo;The puffin flies here so early (over the years). The further inland we go, the farther they chase us.&amp;rdquo;
That&amp;rsquo;s the sentiment of the phrase, but in Vekllei &amp;lsquo;The puffin flies here&amp;rsquo; is supplemented with the opening of a saying, &amp;lsquo;all birds flee the sea in Winter,&amp;rsquo; and so there is a reference here that is otherwise lost in translation.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>