<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Vekllei</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Vekllei </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Allia Republic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/allia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/allia/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Allia is part of Vekllei Kalina The Allia Republic is a constituent republic in the Caribbean Sea, and part of the Lesser Antilles island chain that make up the Kalina Commonwealth, which is part of Vekllei. Its closest neighbour, Antam, is just under 50km to its northeast.
Often called the &ldquo;Emerald Isle&rdquo; of the Caribbean, Allia&rsquo;s history and culture is heavily influenced by British settlement of indebted and enslaved Irish and African peoples, whose descendants make up almost all of the 16,000 people who live there today.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Allia is part of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> Kalina</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-ms"></span> <strong>Allia Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> in the Caribbean Sea, and part of the Lesser Antilles island chain that make up the Kalina Commonwealth, which is part of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. Its closest neighbour, Antam, is just under 50km to its northeast.</p>
<p>Often called the &ldquo;Emerald Isle&rdquo; of the Caribbean, Allia&rsquo;s history and culture is heavily influenced by British settlement of indebted and enslaved Irish and African peoples, whose descendants make up almost all of the 16,000 people who live there today. Like all Vekllei <a href="/republics/">republics</a>, the language of government and business is English, but Alliot households speak Irish primarily and many speak Allia Creole, a combination of Irish and indigenous Kalinago languages influenced by neighbouring islands. As such, Allia has the largest population of Irish speakers outside of Ireland. They are mostly Roman Catholic.</p>
<p>Allia was uninhabited during the time of its settling by the British in the 17th Century. It was during this first century that the plantation economy started receiving shipments of slaves from Africa and later Ireland, a practice that continued up until the abolishment of slavery in the early 19th Century. It remained part of the UK in various forms until the independence of the British Atlantic Territories and subsequently became part of Vekllei. Today, its economy is mostly agricultural, but its strong music scene and creative industries are thriving in the capital of Athlone, and contribute to Allia&rsquo;s outsized cultural influence in Vekllei. Its unique history makes it a popular destination for Vekllei tourists, as well as some foreigners.</p>
<p>The island is about 18km long by 10km wide and resembles a pear. It has rugged, volcanic mountains with long pyroclastic slopes that stretch to the water. These mountains are thickly forested with jungle typical of its tropical Caribbean region. The island is actively volcanic and eruptions occur periodically, most recently in the mid-1990s when the Soufrière Hills erupted and destroyed mostly uninhabited areas in the island&rsquo;s southwest.</p>
<p>Most Alliots live in the capital of Athlone, but there are estates and villages that circumnavigate the entire coast. They are connected by a mainline train service, as well as small trams and funiculars. Allia is connected to the rest of Kalina by fast hydrofoils and flying boats.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Caimanas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/caimanas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/caimanas/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the territories series of articles The Republic of Caimanas is a constituent country of Vekllei consisting of three island city-states in the West Caribbean.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/territories/">territories</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Republic of Caimanas</strong> is a constituent country of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> consisting of three island city-states in the West Caribbean.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mira</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/mira/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/mira/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the territories series of articles Overview # The Island Commonwealth of Mira (also Madeira in Portuguese) is an island archipelago situated in the Atlantic, 520km west of Morocco.
Originally a Portuguese overseas territory, Mira became an independent member of the Council of Oceans in 2025 and united with Vekllei as a constituent in 2030. As such, its primary languages are Portuguese and English, and as of the mid-21st Century it has recently concluded federalisation.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/territories/">territories</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <strong>Island Commonwealth of Mira</strong> (also <em>Madeira</em> in Portuguese) is an island archipelago situated in the Atlantic, 520km west of Morocco.</p>
<p>Originally a <a href="/portugal/"><span class="fi fi-pt"></span> Portuguese</a> overseas territory, Mira became an independent member of the <a href="/oceans-council/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Council of Oceans</a> in 2025 and united with <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> as a <a href="/constituents/">constituent</a> in 2030. As such, its primary languages are Portuguese and English, and as of the mid-21st Century it has recently concluded <a href="/federalisation/">federalisation</a>.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/svg/mira.svg" alt="flag of mira"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<h2 id="history">
  History
  <a class="anchor" href="#history">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Mira was originally known as <em>Madeira</em>, and was uninhabited before settlement by the <a href="/portugal/"><span class="fi fi-pt"></span> Portuguese</a> in the 15th Century. For hundreds of years they were governed as part of the Portuguese empire, although over time Miranese culture evolved separately from mainland Portugal.</p>
<p>Portugal was defeated and annexed after it was invaded by neighbouring Iberia in 2014. Most of its colonial empire declared independence, and the former Portuguese Atlantic territories indicated some interest in joining the British-occupied Atlantic after they were embargoed by Iberia for sheltering remnants of the <em>Estado Novo</em> regime.</p>
<p>After <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> established the <a href="/oceans-council/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Council of Oceans</a> in 2025, Madeira (now Mira) petitioned for membership. Shortly thereafter, it began <a href="/federalisation">federalisation</a> and acceded to the Commonwealth in full in 2030, following the Azores.</p>
<h3 id="geography--climate">
  Geography &amp; Climate
  <a class="anchor" href="#geography--climate">#</a>
</h3>
<h3 id="economy">
  Economy
  <a class="anchor" href="#economy">#</a>
</h3>
<h3 id="demographics">
  Demographics
  <a class="anchor" href="#demographics">#</a>
</h3>
<h4 id="ancestry--immigration">
  Ancestry &amp; Immigration
  <a class="anchor" href="#ancestry--immigration">#</a>
</h4>
<h4 id="languages">
  Languages
  <a class="anchor" href="#languages">#</a>
</h4>
<h4 id="religion">
  Religion
  <a class="anchor" href="#religion">#</a>
</h4>
<h3 id="transport">
  Transport
  <a class="anchor" href="#transport">#</a>
</h3>
<h3 id="communications">
  Communications
  <a class="anchor" href="#communications">#</a>
</h3>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Verde</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/verde/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/verde/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the territories series of articles Overview # The Island Commonwealth of Mira (also Madeira in Portuguese) is an island archipelago situated in the Atlantic, 520km west of Morocco. Originally a Portuguese overseas territory, Mira became an independent member of the Council of Oceans in 2025 and united with Commonwealth of Oceans as a Constituent in 2030. As such, its primary languages are Portuguese and English, and as of the mid-21st Century it is still integrating with Commonwealth government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/territories/">territories</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <strong>Island Commonwealth of Mira</strong> (also <em><strong>Madeira</strong></em> in Portuguese) is an island archipelago situated in the Atlantic, 520km west of Morocco. Originally a Portuguese overseas territory, Mira became an independent member of the <a href="/oceans-council/">Council of Oceans</a> in 2025 and united with <a href="/vekllei/">Commonwealth of Oceans</a> as a <a href="/constituents/">Constituent</a> in 2030. As such, its primary languages are Portuguese and English, and as of the mid-21st Century it is still integrating with Commonwealth government.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
