<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Vekllei</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Vekllei </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Caimanas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/caimanas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/caimanas/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the territories series of articles The Republic of Caimanas is a constituent country of Vekllei consisting of three island city-states in the West Caribbean.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/territories/">territories</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Republic of Caimanas</strong> is a constituent country of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> consisting of three island city-states in the West Caribbean.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Helvasia Republic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/helvasia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/helvasia/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Helvasia is part of Vekllei Arctic Helvasia Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Capital Romsa Population 7,400 Languages Northern Sami, English, Norwegian Area 62,045 km2 Vekllei Accession 2026, as part of the Arctic Agreement The Helvasia Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Atlantic Ocean north of the Arctic Circle, nearly 1000km north of Norway. It comprises an archipelago of nine main islands, the largest of which is nearly 40,000 km2 and is home to most of the republic&rsquo;s small population.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Helvasia is part of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> Arctic</div>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/sj.svg);"></span> Helvasia Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/helvasia.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Romsa</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>7,400</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Northern Sami, English, Norwegian</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>62,045 km2</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>2026, as part of the Arctic Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-sj"></span> <strong>Helvasia Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Atlantic Ocean north of the Arctic Circle, nearly 1000km north of Norway. It comprises an archipelago of nine main islands, the largest of which is nearly 40,000 km2 and is home to most of the republic&rsquo;s small population. It is the northernmost Vekllei republic, and holds several records for its latitude, including its capital of Romsa as the northernmost permanent settlement in the world.</p>
<p>According to <a href="/sagas/">sagas</a> in <a style="color: rgb(38, 48, 132)" href="/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, Helvasia was discovered by Scandinavians in the 12th Century, who observed tribespeople living there &ndash; most likely arctic Sami. After the island was rediscovered by Europeans in the 17th Century, whaling stations were established on Bear Island in its south. After quarrels over whaling rights resulted in conflict between Dutch and English settlers, the UK effectively exercised control over Svalbard thereafter, though a small Russian settlement on the main island remained uncontested throughout the 18th Century. In 1836, the archipelago was absorbed into the British Atlantic Territories and later acceded to <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> after the Atomic War.</p>
<p>Because the whale oil industry was largely confined to Bear Island, the indigenous Sami peoples of Helvasia have retained relative independence from foreign powers for over a thousand years. They remain the predominant ethnic and linguistic group on Helvasia, and Northern Sami and English are taught in schools. Sami culture characterises life in Helvasia, and many traditional and animistic practices remain commonplace. Sami culture and language is distinct from both Scandinavian and Algic languages spoken elsewhere in Veklllei.</p>
<p>Life on Helvasia is cold and harsh, and pack ice in its surrounding shallows prohibit access by sea in the winter months to all vessels except nuclear icebreakers. Its climate is Arctic and ranges from around 15 °C in summer to -40 °C in winter. Its extreme latitude means Helvasia experiences midnight sun and polar night for nearly a hundred days in both summer and winter respectively. Polar Bears remain dangerous there and many Helvasians carry rifles outdoors. Outside of company towns and nomads nearly all Helvasians live in the capital of Romsa.</p>
<p>Helvasia has economic zone disputes with Norway and the Soviet Union, and confrontation between the Vekllei Littoral Service and the navies of those countries occur periodically. The country exploits coal, oil and gas reserves on and around the archipelago. Minor industries include domestic tourism, trapping, fishing and municipal goods. The republic also serves as a base for Vekllei polar research and expeditions, and its isolation has encouraged the establishment of initiatives like the Commonwealth Research Bunkers and the International Knowledge Vault.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mira</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/mira/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/mira/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the territories series of articles Overview # The Island Commonwealth of Mira (also Madeira in Portuguese) is an island archipelago situated in the Atlantic, 520km west of Morocco.
Originally a Portuguese overseas territory, Mira became an independent member of the Council of Oceans in 2025 and united with Vekllei as a constituent in 2030. As such, its primary languages are Portuguese and English, and as of the mid-21st Century it has recently concluded federalisation.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/territories/">territories</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <strong>Island Commonwealth of Mira</strong> (also <em>Madeira</em> in Portuguese) is an island archipelago situated in the Atlantic, 520km west of Morocco.</p>
<p>Originally a <a href="/portugal/"><span class="fi fi-pt"></span> Portuguese</a> overseas territory, Mira became an independent member of the <a href="/oceans-council/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Council of Oceans</a> in 2025 and united with <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> as a <a href="/constituents/">constituent</a> in 2030. As such, its primary languages are Portuguese and English, and as of the mid-21st Century it has recently concluded <a href="/federalisation/">federalisation</a>.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/svg/mira.svg" alt="flag of mira"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<h2 id="history">
  History
  <a class="anchor" href="#history">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Mira was originally known as <em>Madeira</em>, and was uninhabited before settlement by the <a href="/portugal/"><span class="fi fi-pt"></span> Portuguese</a> in the 15th Century. For hundreds of years they were governed as part of the Portuguese empire, although over time Miranese culture evolved separately from mainland Portugal.</p>
<p>Portugal was defeated and annexed after it was invaded by neighbouring Iberia in 2014. Most of its colonial empire declared independence, and the former Portuguese Atlantic territories indicated some interest in joining the British-occupied Atlantic after they were embargoed by Iberia for sheltering remnants of the <em>Estado Novo</em> regime.</p>
<p>After <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> established the <a href="/oceans-council/"><span class="fi fi-oceans"></span> Council of Oceans</a> in 2025, Madeira (now Mira) petitioned for membership. Shortly thereafter, it began <a href="/federalisation">federalisation</a> and acceded to the Commonwealth in full in 2030, following the Azores.</p>
<h3 id="geography--climate">
  Geography &amp; Climate
  <a class="anchor" href="#geography--climate">#</a>
</h3>
<h3 id="economy">
  Economy
  <a class="anchor" href="#economy">#</a>
</h3>
<h3 id="demographics">
  Demographics
  <a class="anchor" href="#demographics">#</a>
</h3>
<h4 id="ancestry--immigration">
  Ancestry &amp; Immigration
  <a class="anchor" href="#ancestry--immigration">#</a>
</h4>
<h4 id="languages">
  Languages
  <a class="anchor" href="#languages">#</a>
</h4>
<h4 id="religion">
  Religion
  <a class="anchor" href="#religion">#</a>
</h4>
<h3 id="transport">
  Transport
  <a class="anchor" href="#transport">#</a>
</h3>
<h3 id="communications">
  Communications
  <a class="anchor" href="#communications">#</a>
</h3>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Verde</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/verde/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/vekllei/verde/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the territories series of articles Overview # The Island Commonwealth of Mira (also Madeira in Portuguese) is an island archipelago situated in the Atlantic, 520km west of Morocco. Originally a Portuguese overseas territory, Mira became an independent member of the Council of Oceans in 2025 and united with Commonwealth of Oceans as a Constituent in 2030. As such, its primary languages are Portuguese and English, and as of the mid-21st Century it is still integrating with Commonwealth government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/territories/">territories</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The <strong>Island Commonwealth of Mira</strong> (also <em><strong>Madeira</strong></em> in Portuguese) is an island archipelago situated in the Atlantic, 520km west of Morocco. Originally a Portuguese overseas territory, Mira became an independent member of the <a href="/oceans-council/">Council of Oceans</a> in 2025 and united with <a href="/vekllei/">Commonwealth of Oceans</a> as a <a href="/constituents/">Constituent</a> in 2030. As such, its primary languages are Portuguese and English, and as of the mid-21st Century it is still integrating with Commonwealth government.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
