<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Atlantic Commonwealth</title>
	<link>/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Atlantic Commonwealth </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Costa Verde</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/costa-verde/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/costa-verde/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Costa Verde is part of the Atlantic Commonwealth Verde Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of the Atlantic Commonwealth Capital Green Cape Population 246,820 Area 744.55 km² Languages English, Portuguese, Sinhala Vekllei Accession 1976, as part of the Azores Delegation The Costa Verde Republic (also Verde) is a constituent republic of Vekllei and part of the Atlantic Commonwealth. It is the largest and most populous island of the Azores archipelago, and seats the executive of the regional commonwealth.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Costa Verde is part of the Atlantic Commonwealth</span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/costa-verde.svg);"></span> Verde Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/costa-verde.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of the <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/arctic/"><span class="fi fi-atlantic"></span> Atlantic Commonwealth</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Green Cape</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>246,820</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>744.55 km²</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Portuguese, Sinhala</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1976, as part of the Azores Delegation</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-costa-verde"></span> <strong>Costa Verde Republic</strong> (also <em>Verde</em>) is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> and part of the Atlantic Commonwealth. It is the largest and most populous island of the Azores archipelago, and seats the executive of the regional commonwealth. It is a narrow, verdant island of volcanic origin.</p>
<p>Verde was originally colonised by the Portuguese, who discovered the island in the 15th Century and established a small fishing colony thereafter. Throughout its history, Verde has been vulnerable to earthquakes and tidal waves, and the capital of Green Cape has been rebuilt several times. In the 19th Century, Verde rose to prominence as citrus traders, selling mostly to Southern Europe and the British Empire. Verde, along with the rest of the Azores, voted to secede from Portugal in the 1960s and after its interim government collapsed joined the Atlantic Federation in 1976. It inherited membership in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in 2015.</p>
<p>Verde enjoys a mild climate, and is renowned for its lush vegetation and scattered, lake-filled craters. Its peaks culminate in Vara Mountain at 1,100 meters above sea level. In the postwar period, its beauty and climate has seen many people from others parts of Vekllei move there.</p>
<p>Verde is the headquarters of the anti-Vekllei Azores Independence League, and has been responsible for attacks on police and federal buildings. They enjoy some political support in the Verde parliament but their influence has been waning.</p>
<p>Verde is a major producer of citrus and tea, and also exports significant amounts of pineapples and wine. Agriculture, shipbuilding and sugar refining are the primary components of its economy. It is also home to Atlantic University, the largest university in the Azores archipelago. The republic&rsquo;s settlements are connected by both passenger and freight rail as well as trams.</p>
<details open>
	<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>Holy Christ of the Miracles Church</strong>: the site of an important pilgrimage in the Roman Catholic Church, culminating in an annual procession.</li>
<li><strong>Sete Cidades</strong>: Municipality known for its beautiful volcanic lakes</li>
<li><strong>Furnas Geysers</strong>: Volcanic baths, geysers, and hot springs available for swimming.</li>
<li><strong>Verde Fruit Company</strong>: Oldest and largest pineapple plantation in Vekllei.</li>
<li><strong>Formoso Tea Plantations</strong>: Historic black and orange tea plantation.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
