<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Letter on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letter on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Letter | November 2020</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2020/nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2020/nov/</guid>
      <description>Nov. Update for Patrons -mail  EDITOR  Letters  ❖ This letter was sent out to Patrons in November 2020  Hello my lovelies,
Just a short update on where I’m at as we pass mid-month. I’ve pushed a couple of things back a day or two to finish a very cool/special post. You’ll see it on the reddit soon — it’ll be a really nice painting, and nothing like I’ve ever done before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter | December 2020</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2020/dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2020/dec/</guid>
      <description>Dec. Update for Patrons -mail  EDITOR  Letters  ❖ This letter was sent out to Patrons in December 2020  Hello beloved patrons,
This is your monthly update for the Petticoat Project.
There’s a  new post up on the subreddit and a  new article up on the website — a big one, about Vekllei, although it’s missing a history and culture section. Those are coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter | February 2021</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2021/feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2021/feb/</guid>
      <description>Feb. Update for Patrons -mail  EDITOR  Letters  ❖ This letter was sent out to Patrons in February 2021  Hello beloved Patrons,
It’s been a little while. I’ve called this meeting late because I’ve been working late. Let’s run this through quick, and we can all get back to bed.
 You guys voted! Looks like our next themed ‘week’ (maybe fortnight) is Ocean Week. Great choice, lots of cool concepts coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter | January 2021</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2021/jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2021/jan/</guid>
      <description>Jan. Update for Patrons -mail  EDITOR  Letters  ❖ This letter was sent out to Patrons in January 2021  Hello beloved patrons,
The first chapter of the comic is sketched. You will see it on Monday (about two days from this message). It won&amp;rsquo;t be inked but it&amp;rsquo;ll give you a very good idea of what the final chapter will look like at the end of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter | Zelda&#39;s May</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2021/may/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/newsdesk/patreon/letters/2021/may/</guid>
      <description>Zelda&#39;s May -mail  EDITOR  Letters  ❖ This letter was sent out to Patrons in May 2021  Hello beloved patrons,
It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while since my last direct communiqué. I laid off these for a bit, since I realised you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t need to have your inbox full of blog posts and delay announcements from me. Time better spent drawing I reckon.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had a couple things going on in my personal life, so I&amp;rsquo;ve had to put some of my wilder ambitions on hold for a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
