<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Landscape on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Landscape on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kyala</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-kyala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-kyala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/hydro.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  

&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/&#34;   class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Back to Boroughs
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint green&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;borough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many townsfolk in Ou are employed in operation of the dam, either through the Thunder or Hydroburos. It is also the site of a small Vekllei National University laboratory which examines the dam environment and trains its staff.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/&#34;&gt;The Ou Hydroburo Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;O&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;u&lt;/strong&gt; is a borough in the central Ro Highlands of Vekllei, located southwest of Laisiyo and north of Kyala. It is named after Bakur, an ancient fishing town with history that predates unified settlement in Vekllei. It has the smallest population of any borough in Vekllei, at only 7,500 permanent residents, which fluctuates seasonally. It is most famous for being home to the site of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Deep-Sea Cartography Mission, an initiative of the Ocean Office of the Vekllei Government. This also means Bakur has the highest population of scientific personnel per capita of any borough in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ou&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#history&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Topyas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; pure &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#diphthongs&#34;&gt;Ocean Vowel&lt;/a&gt; meaning &amp;ldquo;spirit&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;personhood&amp;rdquo;, and in its written form is considered a core &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#4-rapotenne&#34;&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/a&gt; rune in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/religion/&#34;&gt;Upen&lt;/a&gt;. Ou is considered the birthplace of demons in Upen mythology, who emerged from the Valley of the Dead to return humans to the spirit world. For this reason, Ou is considered a sacred borough in Vekllei and much of its territory remains untouchable &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#administrative-divisions&#34;&gt;Crown Land&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artefacts recovered from north of the town of Aya in Bakur date to nearly 1000BC, approaching earliest estimates of known settlement in the Vekllei Home Islands. Bakur&amp;rsquo;s first residents were likely nomadic arctic peoples immigrating from nearby Kala (Greenland) looking for hunting grounds in winter. Sagas confirm the town of Bakur was established in the 14th Century AD to support the creation of an arctic naval fort, but the fort was abandoned less than a hundred years later and few residents remained, leaving Bakur mostly abandoned until the early 19th Century, when it was reestablished as a base of operations for Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s colonial whaling fleet. Today it remains a shrinking fishing town, bolstered only by seasonal workers imported by the Ocean Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town is the birthplace of celebrated Vekllei folk songwriter Tohs Viskaismesn (1847-1912).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;significance-in-upen&#34;&gt;Significance in Upen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hydrotown-development&#34;&gt;Hydrotown Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;postwar-reelectrification&#34;&gt;Postwar reelectrification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bakur borough is home to some of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s most spectacular subarctic scenery, dominated lava slopes, ice fields, and fjords. Its position among the Westernmost boroughs in Vekllei makes it a great staging town for Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s expansive fishing fleet, including line and trawling vessels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;valley-of-the-dead&#34;&gt;Valley of the Dead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hydroburo-development&#34;&gt;Hydroburo Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ada-rocketry-base&#34;&gt;Ada Rocketry Base&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;towns&#34;&gt;Towns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ou&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tiamoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;posts&#34;&gt;Posts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/&#34;&gt;Philately Foolery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lo</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-lo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-lo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/women.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  

&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/&#34;   class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Back to Boroughs
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint green&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;borough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Out in Voya Voya, the gardens light the people, and distill turbulent human temperament into momentary, sequential lyrical images. A dead leaf moving by miracle across still water; an overturned bucket collecting dew along its handle; fern leaves half-curled, young and growing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/&#34;&gt;City Rivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he borough of Lo&lt;/strong&gt; is an administrative region in southwest Vekllei, located in the Capital Region south of Bouisgeh and west of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/voya-voya&#34;&gt;Voya Voya&lt;/a&gt;. It covers the entire area of Voya Voya, a city of some 450,000 people in the capital&amp;rsquo;s extended metro area renowned for its parkland and green spaces. Voya Voya makes up part of the capital&amp;rsquo;s satellite belt of boroughs, characterised by green space and mixed-use residential planning. Voya Voya is often referred to as the capital&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;garden borough&amp;rdquo; for its density and quality of parkland and forest reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voya Voya&lt;/strong&gt; is transliterated as &amp;ldquo;Good Good,&amp;rdquo; through in practice is better translated as &amp;ldquo;Good Place,&amp;rdquo; analogous to English towns like &amp;ldquo;Goodwood.&amp;rdquo; It refers to the natural temperate rainforests of its area, much of which are preserved in its parks and in its northern &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#administrative-divisions&#34;&gt;Crown Land&lt;/a&gt;. It is only one of a handful of Vekllei cities to use &lt;em&gt;Topyas&lt;/em&gt; emphasis through repetition, which has more or less been superseded in modern Vekllei by &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#phonetic-reading&#34;&gt;duplicate consonants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s that smell? Smell it. It smells like the freshest thing I&amp;rsquo;ve ever smelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Tzipora Desmoisnes, after visiting Voya Voya for the first time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voya Voya&amp;rsquo;s area originally included several small villages founded in the early Middle Period, which by the 19th Century had developed into satellite suburbs of the industrious capital area. This expansion was encouraged by the Atlantic Junta from the mid-1850s through to the early 1930s, during which Voya Voya tripled in population. By the mid-20th Century, it had become apparent that the sprawling Capital metro area had become overextended, and threatened to link up further with boroughs in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s interior, beyond the glaciers. A &amp;lsquo;green belt&amp;rsquo; programme was announced in 1956, and saw significant portions of Voya Voya and its nearby boroughs preserved as untouchable forests. During this period, Voya Voya was known mostly as a working-class satellite to the wealthier coastal boroughs of the capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Atomic War, the area&amp;rsquo;s permanent rainforest was protected from firestorms by the scorched impact craters in the neighbouring boroughs of Coyenstisn and Lava, and nearby Cusi Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;postwar-development&#34;&gt;Postwar Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Atomic War collapsed the capital area, and dramatically reduced the population of Voya Voya&amp;rsquo;s neighbouring boroughs. Although the borough itself did not receive direct strikes, the subsequent fallout and social collapse saw starvation and emigration from the borough throughout occupation and into independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Floral Period, protections first developed by the Junta for Voya Voya&amp;rsquo;s green belt were extended by the Floral Government, including the establishment of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#administrative-divisions&#34;&gt;Crown Land&lt;/a&gt; in its north and the clearing of rubble and replanting of rainforest throughout its inhabited interior. The architects of early independence reduced the density of the borough dramatically, clearing land for parks that now characterise the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2076, Voya Voya was named Borough of the Year by the Festival Commission, which saw it heavily reported by documentary films and tourism material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voya Voya is flat and low-lying, though its border extends to the dramatic hills of the southern Thanveler Glacier. It is cool and wet, and has large areas of temperate rainforest typical of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s southern coast. Rainforest flora are also found in the city of Voya Voya, where tree ferns grow in alleys and in roundabouts. The city itself is medium-rise, like much of the capital, but checkered into planned areas of habitation and parkland. Aqueducts carrying water from the Hydroburo collectors in Thanveler criss-cross its streets and parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crown-land&#34;&gt;Crown Land&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voya Voya&amp;rsquo;s Crown Land is an area of forbidden rainforest north of the city area, and was officially struck from Floral Government sovereignty in 2025. It remains a densely forested area belonging to the Land Sovereign, and has tremendous influence on both the culture and composition of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cusi-lake&#34;&gt;Cusi Lake&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cusi Lake is a natural body of water to Voya Voya&amp;rsquo;s southwest, which has doubled in size since the construction of the Cusi Hydroelectric Dam in 1965. Its area is split between the boroughs of Voya Voya, Lo, Coyenstisn, and Lava. As a controlled lake, it is popular for watercraft and swimming, though is extremely cold throughout the year due to runoff from distant glaciers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Voya Voya is best known for its parks, it is also highly accessible from the capital, linked by a variety of rail lines including bullet trains to the South Coast, Lonne and Thanveler. It is also the origin of the capital area&amp;rsquo;s aqueduct system, a network of open-air water bridges originating in southern Voya Voya, which were first built in the 19th Century and rebuilt in the 21st. Although tourist infrastructure is sparse, it remains a popular borough for day-trips from coastal hotels, a trip made trivial by the density of the capital&amp;rsquo;s rail network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-water-commission-aqueduct-pumpworks&#34;&gt;The Water Commission Aqueduct Pumpworks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Water Commission (Hydroburo) Pumpworks in Voya Voya supplies pressure for aqueducts in the city and its neighbouring boroughs. It pulls water from both Cusi Lake and open aqueducts from Thanveler, and pushes water through an elevated network of bridges across the area. After its elevation, water is pulled by gravity with pressure from water towers. The aqueduct system provides water for all parkland in Voya Voya. The Pumpworks is a large brick/Newda facility on Cusi Lake, and its pumps are powered by on-site geothermal steam wells, as they have for a century. Small railcars called Microsweeps run along the open-air aqueducts to clear blockages and sediment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;botanical-gardens-of-voya-voya&#34;&gt;Botanical Gardens of Voya Voya&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Voya Voya Botanical Gardens are a complex of green areas covering about 12 city blocks, housing mostly indigenous flora. While the Royal Botanical Gardens in Vekllei Proper feature international gardens sampling every continent on Earth, Voya Voya&amp;rsquo;s Gardens are managed as educational public spaces celebrating local landscapes and rainforest. Its facilities include a fair and parade ground, Newda parks, lakes and ponds, rainforests, and greenhouse infrastructure. The Botanical Gardens are the site of festivals in Voya Voya, and often celebrate live music and theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hydroburo-aqueduct-beautification-scheme&#34;&gt;Hydroburo Aqueduct Beautification Scheme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In celebration of 50 years of independence, in 2065 the Hydroburo embarked on an ambitious public art project to celebrate the South Coast&amp;rsquo;s ancient aqueduct network. Coordinated from Voya Voya, the site of the Aqueduct Pumpworks, Voya Voya&amp;rsquo;s aqueducts were embossed with tiled murals over the course of about ten years, and were finally completed in March 2076. Its contruction employed nearly 1,500 artists and locals in its peak. Voya Voya&amp;rsquo;s aqueducts are widely recognised as some of the most beautiful pieces of civic infrastructure in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;all-smiles-ice-cream-factory&#34;&gt;All-Smiles Ice Cream Factory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-Smiles Ice Cream, the second-most consumed brand in Vekllei, are headquartered in Voya Voya. Its manufactory, A.S. Ice Cream S.p.M., is located in the heart of Voya Voya and is a popular local attraction, since it gives tours and samples to visitors on Sundays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;towns&#34;&gt;Towns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voya Voya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;posts&#34;&gt;Posts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/&#34;&gt;City Rivers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochi</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-stochi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-stochi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/rocket.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  

&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/&#34;   class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Back to Boroughs
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint green&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;borough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Royal Borough of Lita was not far from Copette ( map of Vekllei here), one of the Five Crown Boroughs of Vekllei, but this was Vekllei’s glacial interior and it felt a million miles from anywhere. Its geography was ancient and violent, strikingly barren and brutally volcanic. Why visit Europa? It was alien enough here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/&#34;&gt;A New Year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  

&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/&#34;   class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Back to Boroughs
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint green&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;borough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shattered fjords make up the north of Vekllei, particularly in boroughs like Santes, which are well-regarded for their striking cliffs and sloping igneous fingers, which evidence Vekllei’s ongoing volcanism. Offshore, hundreds of islets rise and sink over the centuries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/&#34;&gt;Shrine-Minded Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he borough of Santes&lt;/strong&gt; is an administrative region in northern Vekllei, located in the Lava Region west of Moma and east of Hoaedesnen. Its area includes several isolated and sparsely-populated towns along Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s northern coast, particularly along the Grimsy and Mus Mus Fjords. The city of Santes is well-served by Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s rail network, but the majority of its coastal and inland towns are somewhat difficult to reach. Because of this, Santes is considered a minor borough and makes up part of the economically-depressed &lt;em&gt;North Senrouive Belt&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Santes&lt;/strong&gt; is the Vekllei word for &amp;ldquo;saint,&amp;rdquo; and dates back to the Christianisation of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Middle Period sometime prior to the 16th Century. Its earliest appearance was traced to the Santesoavis chapel (lit. All Saints) near the city of Santes, built sometime in the 15th Century by Danish settlers, to which the parish and eventual borough owes its name. Outside of Christian contexts, Santes in Vekllei can also refer to noble spirits, the communicative spirits of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/religion/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Upen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know what happens when God meets a spirit? Do you have any idea? It is a place of blessings. It&amp;rsquo;s huge! We &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to find this shrine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/#tzipora-zelda-desmoisnes&#34;&gt;Tzipora Desmoisnes&lt;/a&gt;, convinced of hidden shrines in Santes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s northern coast was settled predominantly by Scandinavian settlers, who were displaced from Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s south in the centuries prior to the 15th Century. For this reason, the cultural and religious segregation of the north coasts produced unusual settlements unique from both southern Vekllei culture and Scandinavia. Settlements in present-day Santes and Moma were heavily christianised, but upon Upen&amp;rsquo;s reformation by King Desimou IV these populations were forcefully integrated into Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s feudal hierarchy and were ethnically displaced by Algic Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, Santes would remain culturally isolated from Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s powerful southern metropole, and remained somewhat politically independent until the late Junta years. By the early 19th Century, a road was established between Montre and the city of Santes, followed by a direct rail line in 1922. By this time, the Junta had consolidated control over all settlements in the Home Islands, and Santes was subsidised heavily by political centres in Montre and Vekllei Proper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;postwar-development&#34;&gt;Postwar Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately after the war, Santes succumbed to a minor famine that killed nearly a tenth of its population. The borough was largely neglected until independence from British occupation in 2015, when the Interim Administration took control of the Home Islands. It was linked to the VNR Coastal Bullet Train Network in 2044.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santes&amp;rsquo;s historical isolation from Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s coastal regions has left many of its fjords undeveloped, which have become minor tourist attractions. Today, the borough is best known for its natural features, and as the origin of &lt;em&gt;Fisk Ferva&lt;/em&gt;, or Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s modern raw fish cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a northern coastal borough, Santes sees wet summers and cold winters. Icebergs routinely wash ashore along its coast throughout the year, pulled south from the arctic by the Vekllei Gulf Stream. The borough itself is marked by cliffs and steep fjords, and most of its large settlements are some 100-200 meters above sea level. It is extremely lush, and features some of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s most visible and saturated coastal temperate rainforest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;coastal-fjords&#34;&gt;Coastal Fjords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santes&amp;rsquo;s glacial fjords appear as dramatic fingers of igneous rock, puncturing its coast with thousands of deep-water inlets. Since the borough is still dominated by aquaculture and minor agriculture, small villages are often found at the base of these inlets. This dramatic landscape and coastal treelessness is described in old Upen sagas, which contribute to the borough&amp;rsquo;s interest among pilgrims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inlet-biosecurity-zone&#34;&gt;Inlet Biosecurity Zone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most inlets in Santes are protected by the Inlet Biosecurity Zone of Santes, a national legal protection that seeks to maintain the populations of open-water fish that live in them. Under these laws, only residents of Santes are permitted to fish among its fjords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;santes-rainforest&#34;&gt;Santes Rainforest&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santes has several crown land rainforested regions, which prohibit sovereign visitation. Since the harsh weather of the coasts has depopulated most of the fjords of trees, these rainforests are mostly found around the city of Santes and further into its interior. The largest of them is the Mus Mus Crown Land, which includes nearly six thousand acres of rainforest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santes is considered a minor borough and is not home to much venrouive/bureau proper activity. Most factories are consolidated in the city of Santes, which mostly produce fish products and metal components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;santes-geo-electric-power-plant&#34;&gt;Santes Geo-electric Power Plant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Santes Geo-electric Power Plant is a facility operated by the Geo-electric Commission of the Thunderburo. Its massive steam bores supply most of the power to Santes and Moma, and the waste water of this process is pumped into the Santes Mineral Lagoons, an open-air mineral spa open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;north-vekllei-tourism-council&#34;&gt;North Vekllei Tourism Council&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The North Vekllei Tourism Council, a direct branch of the Vekllei Tourism Bureau, is headquartered in the city of Santes for its proximity to Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s world-recognised fjords and bullet train rail access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;towns&#34;&gt;Towns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mirah&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gigayeh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frendli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;posts&#34;&gt;Posts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/&#34;&gt;The Vekllei Crown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiyousn</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-tiyousn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-tiyousn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/orange.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  

&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/&#34;   class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Back to Boroughs
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint green&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;borough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Up in Tiyousn, seispri wander freely, attracted by sulphur and silica waste pools discharged by the Magma-Electric Flash Plant nearby. Rich with minerals and warm to the touch, these milky ponds are gathering places for creatures of the spirit world.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-11-spirit/&#34;&gt;Tzipora Meets a Spirit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he borough of Tiyousn&lt;/strong&gt; is an administrative region in the centre of Vekllei, located in the Lava Region between the glaciers of Hofsyoskusl and Vatnayoskusl. It consists of the Ro of Tiyousn, a glacier called Tiyousnayoskusl, the Bosiyo Restricted Site, and a handful of minor settlements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiyousn is situated in a lava valley between Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s urban south and sparse interior, and is famous for its waterfalls caused by glacial runoff. Some 650 waterfalls ranging from 2 to over 60 meters can be found throughout, and is Tiyousn&amp;rsquo;s best known feature to its neighbours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trolls&lt;/strong&gt; are human-sized creatures with rough grey skin and black eyes described by Vekllei sagas. They live in mountains and glaciers, where they hide in caves. If they are caught in daylight, they turn to stone. According to the sagas, the bodies of trolls eventually became the drumlins that litter Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s mossy plains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per the legends of the sagas, the borough of Troll was the site of a troll city, which was destroyed by lava spirits. This fact contributed to its naming upon its incorporation in the early 19th Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I&amp;rsquo;ve met a troll. It was one of the nicest creatures I&amp;rsquo;ve ever met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/#tzipora-zelda-desmoisnes&#34;&gt;Tzipora Desmoisnes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Troll has a signicant cultural history within Vekllei, it is a relatively recent borough. The town of Troll received a trading license in 1823, which is considered its founding as a borough. Little is recorded about its settlement prior to its incorporation, but it is known that nomadic Algic Vekllei had remained in the area for hundreds, if not thousands of years prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although an important cultural site in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/religion&#34;&gt;Upen&lt;/a&gt;, the area around Troll is highly volcanic and spiritually complicated, and its status as isolated, resource-poor land prevented permanent settlement for most of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;postwar-development&#34;&gt;Postwar Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troll has overall shrunk in population since the war, when many of its able-bodied adults moved to the urban coasts in search of employment. Since the late 2050s, the borough has seen a minor revitalisation after the establishment of the Vekllei Highlands Bullet Train, which links it to the larger boroughs on the coast. The economic changes under floral society have also benefited rural boroughs like Troll, since industry is less dependent on proximity to business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2036, a major eruption from the Houismeyvik volcano disrupted air travel in Vekllei and Western Europe for eighteen days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troll is situated in the heart of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s volcanic highlands, surrounded by minor glaciers and meltwater rivers. It is an extraordinarily pretty borough, and is a place of dramatic hues that shift with the landscape. From its main population centre, the town of Troll, the Vatnayoskusl Glacier is visible. Its water is some of the cleanest in the world, and highly prized overseas as a health tonic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;houismey-volcano&#34;&gt;Houismey Volcano&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Houismey Volcano, called Houismeyvik in Vekllei, is a basaltic volcano located to the north-west of an outlet glacier called Vosmaspesteh. It is a subglacial volcano situated underneath the surface, and the intersection of magma and meltwater causes phreatomagmatic explosions that can trigger eruptions. It is one of the most active volcanoes in Vekllei, though the size of its eruptions remain small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;troll-national-park&#34;&gt;Troll National Park&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Troll National Park is one of seventy-two national parks in Vekllei. As a National Park, rather than a Crown Land, it is designed for human visitation and operated by Parks of Vekllei. It is located in the southwest of the borough, and its facilities include boardwalks, rest stops, and hiking trails. It is also the end point of the Vatnayoskusl Track, an extreme hiking trail that crosses the glacier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;troll-lava-fields&#34;&gt;Troll Lava Fields&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Troll Lava Fields are a series of flat extinguished lava flows, which are the site of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s last troll city. They can be found north of Houismeyvik, and are part of the Troll Crown Land and Troll National Park. Although they are well-known within Vekllei, they are considered a site desecrated by the spirits and most visitors to the area are from overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troll is a minor borough that is mostly resource-poor. Its major contribution to the coasts is its abundance of clean fresh water that flows out of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s largest glacier, Vatnayoskusl. Although little of the glacier itself is located in Troll, most of its rivers and outlet glaciers flow through the borough, and so Troll&amp;rsquo;s largest industries are supported by the Hydroburo&amp;rsquo;s vested concerns in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;troll-high-speed-rail-depot&#34;&gt;Troll High-Speed Rail Depot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a midpoint of the Vekllei Highlands Bullet Train, an auxiliary bullet train depot and maintenance yard was established in the town of Troll. As the final developed borough before the expansive Vatnayoskusl Glacier, the maintenance yard is situated well to repair trains damaged by ice and water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vekllei-geological-survey-station&#34;&gt;Vekllei Geological Survey Station&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Volcanoes Bureau and Geological Survey monitor volcanic activity in Vekllei, and have several minor research outposts established outside of and within Troll&amp;rsquo;s glacial territory. The borough&amp;rsquo;s vicinity to the Houismey volcano is of particular interest, and contributes to Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s ongoing research into seismic activity in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;troll-water-treatment-plant&#34;&gt;Troll Water Treatment Plant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troll&amp;rsquo;s location at the base of the Vatnayoskusl Glacier makes it a strategic site for the processing of freshwater runoff, which feeds Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s residential water systems. In 2066, the Troll Water Treatment Plant was established to support ageing plants in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/voya-voya/&#34;&gt;Voya Voya&lt;/a&gt; and Guisimaya. The Troll Water Treatment Plant is operated by the Water Commission of Vekllei (Hydroburo).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;towns&#34;&gt;Towns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vatnayoskusl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troll-Misya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;posts&#34;&gt;Posts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-15-picnic/&#34;&gt;Roadside Picnic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-03-orange/&#34;&gt;VNR Orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Totoyan</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-totoyan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/drafts/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/d-totoyan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/hollywood.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  

&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/&#34;   class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Back to Boroughs
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint green&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about a &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;borough&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is a so-called “flash plant” in Miyatvousi, in the Lava region of Vekllei [&amp;hellip;] the earth here is alive; in the cold, the ponds begin to steam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/&#34;&gt;Gone Hollywood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he borough of Miyatvousi&lt;/strong&gt; is an administrative region in northern Vekllei, located in the Lava Region north of Groisniyah and southwest of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/lita/&#34;&gt;Lita&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DO SOME SHIT ABOUT SUNSTONES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;etymology&#34;&gt;Etymology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miyatvousi&lt;/strong&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#history&#34;&gt;Old Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; combination of the words for &amp;ldquo;mineral&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;vision,&amp;rdquo; which in this case refer to indigenous mythos around still, mirror-like pools common to flower tundras in the area. Its name implies a connection between the physical landscape of the Miyatvousi area and the spirit world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All pools, under the dormant skin of the Earth, lead to other realms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Verse 112, &lt;em&gt;God Saga&lt;/em&gt;, 11th Century&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Miyatvousi has been recognised as a significant cultural site in Upen, the borough housed no major settlements until the formal incorporation of the town of Miyatvousi into the eastern dominion of the Atlantic Junta in the 17th Century. Previously, the land was inhabited by minor agricultural communities, most tending to livestock. Cultural artefacts found in the borough suggest human settlement may date back to the 10th Century, but by the end of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Middle Period the borough was regarded as an empty Spirit Land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Late Period, the town of Miyatvousi remained small and agricultural, and was considered an insignificant settlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;postwar-development&#34;&gt;Postwar Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after independence in the postwar period, Miyatvousi was surveyed by the Electric Company of Vekllei (now Magma-Electric Commission of Vekllei/Thunderburo) for its proximity to exploitable geothermal sites. In 2025, construction began on what is now the sprawling Miyatvousi Magma-Electric Power &amp;amp; Flash Plant, which began operation in 2029 and was expanded with several satellite wells and turbine plants in the the subsequent decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city of Miyatvousi has since become a major so-called &amp;ldquo;Magma Town&amp;rdquo; with a growing population employed directly by the M.E.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town of Poka, in the south of the borough, was the setting of the popular &lt;em&gt;Six Rings&lt;/em&gt; film franchise, and is a minor domestic tourist attraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The borough is now a major contributor of lamb towards Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s food pool, and is home to several agricultural shows throughout its villages and townships each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;geography&#34;&gt;Geography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miyatvousi is sparsely populated and highly volcanic, and the majority of its land-area is characterised by flower-tundras, geysers, steam pools and other geological phenomena. Its largest settlements are in the east of the borough, with its west dominated by the Miyatvouosi-Lavavik Crown Lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miyatvousi&amp;rsquo;s Gismavik Dome is one of the largest dormant volcanoes in Vekllei, and is constantly monitored by the Volcanoes Bureau and Geological Survey for shifts in volcanic activity. The size of its magma pool is of serious concern, since an eruption would be catastrophic the greater Miyatvousi/Groisniyah area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;totoyan-sunstone-crown-lands&#34;&gt;Totoyan Sunstone Crown Lands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large coloured mineral pools are common to the flower-tundras, produced either by underground superheated springs or from runoff from geothermal power activity. The largest of these are popular local attractions, and are traditionally bathed in by locals for health or religious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miyatvousi is linked to the coast via the Vekllei Central Highland Bullet Train, which has contributed to its postwar presence as an arterial link to Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s North Coast. The borough is best known for its production of geothermal power and support facilities which contribute a majority amount of electricity to Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s East Coast Supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;totoyan-sunstone&#34;&gt;Totoyan Sunstone&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;towns&#34;&gt;Towns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miyatvousi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miyatvousi-Vizcette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gismavikette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&#34;posts&#34;&gt;Posts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/&#34;&gt;Gone Hollywood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>