<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>2024</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2024/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2024 </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Military Policeman</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/military-policeman/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/military-policeman/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[She hasn&rsquo;t done anything wrong but it sure FEELS like she has. The territorial service of Vekllei is a federal army, and comprises servicemen from 71 city-states in the Atlantic. Unlike the U.S. National Guard, these regiments are federalised by default. Even professional, volunteer servicemen in the commandos are federalised troops.
Even more confusingly, Vekllei has &ldquo;services&rdquo; in place of seperate branches, descended from the navy. So a territorial serviceman can be a subnational militiaman, federal soldier, and commando infantryman simultaneously, since service is simply &ldquo;enhanced&rdquo; rather than superseded.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/MP.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">She hasn&rsquo;t done anything wrong but it sure FEELS like she has.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The territorial service of Vekllei is a federal army, and comprises servicemen from 71 city-states in the Atlantic. Unlike the U.S. National Guard, these regiments are federalised by default. Even professional, volunteer servicemen in the commandos are federalised troops.</p>
<p>Even more confusingly, Vekllei has &ldquo;services&rdquo; in place of seperate branches, descended from the navy. So a territorial serviceman can be a subnational militiaman, federal soldier, and commando infantryman simultaneously, since service is simply &ldquo;enhanced&rdquo; rather than superseded.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Grub</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/grub/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/grub/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora sleeps in her clothes like 50% of the time, because she reads until she passes out. Tzipora is a voracious reader. She likes sci-fi and fantasy best, as well as detective and adventure stories. She reads them in library paperbacks on loan or in enthusiast magazines that publish short stories.
Her favourite book is not science fiction or fantasy &ndash; it&rsquo;s a novella called Caribbean Holiday, about twins going to a boarding school in Lucia (Vekllei).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/grub.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora sleeps in her clothes like 50% of the time, because she reads until she passes out.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora is a voracious reader. She likes sci-fi and fantasy best, as well as detective and adventure stories. She reads them in library paperbacks on loan or in enthusiast magazines that publish short stories.</p>
<p>Her favourite book is not science fiction or fantasy &ndash; it&rsquo;s a novella called <em>Caribbean Holiday</em>, about twins going to a boarding school in Lucia (Vekllei). It&rsquo;s a kind of comfort reading, cosy and pleasant.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Library Terminal</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/library-terminal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/library-terminal/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora spent six hours reading about the Roman Empire on a library terminal and has just been asked to leave. She&rsquo;s not happy about it. Vekllei uses photo-electric circuits in place of semiconductors and transistors. These are very powerful, and holographic memory has a lot of storage, but the computers themselves are room-sized and consequently consolidated. You can read more about them in the computers article.
Vekllei robots combine centralised computing (sent via radio or cables) with organic wetware for things like navigation and balance.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/library-terminal.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora spent six hours reading about the Roman Empire on a library terminal and has just been asked to leave. She&rsquo;s not happy about it.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Vekllei uses photo-electric circuits in place of semiconductors and transistors. These are very powerful, and holographic memory has a lot of storage, but the computers themselves are room-sized and consequently consolidated. You can read more about them in the <a href="/computers/">computers</a> article.</p>
<p>Vekllei robots combine centralised computing (sent via radio or cables) with organic wetware for things like navigation and balance. Though creepy at first blush, in practice these are &ldquo;chemical steaks&rdquo; with zero cognitive function, simply passing electrical charges.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Notes on Vekllei Robots</strong></p>
<p>The organic wetware of Vekllei robots are situated in an immersion fluid that provides nutrients and prevents decay, and just needs to be swapped out on occasion like an oil change. Vekllei&rsquo;s world also has other biotechnologies like industrial lab meat production, but those are for consumption.</p>
<p>In general, this universe has a superior understanding of brain structure and their function, and so has some means to design new ones that use light-seeing primitive eyes to move. There is not, however, much interest or appetite for actually fashioning a cognisant brain that can think. Especially in Vekllei, the line is drawn pretty clearly and bringing life artificially into the world via consciousness would be considered a crime against nature, and wouldn&rsquo;t suit any preexisting industrial or commercial purpose.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hera Passenger Jet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hera/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hera/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[At eight years old, the Hera is among the newest aircraft in the Commonwealth Airways fleet. The Comen Hera 55 is the world&rsquo;s smallest supersonic passenger aircraft, and the first of its size to include a swing wing. Passengers love its skylights.
You can only fly them with Commonwealth Airways, the flag carrier of Vekllei and a vital link between its 71 island republics.
Design Notes
This jet flies primarily between islands in the Atlantic and the Caribbean, and it really needs low-speed flight manoeuvrability to properly land on runways that aren&rsquo;t as long as those designed for larger, delta-wing international jets.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/hera.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">At eight years old, the Hera is among the newest aircraft in the Commonwealth Airways fleet.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Comen <em>Hera</em> 55 is the world&rsquo;s smallest supersonic passenger aircraft, and the first of its size to include a swing wing. Passengers love its skylights.</p>
<p>You can only fly them with <a style="color: rgb(245, 60, 89)" href="/air/"><span class="fi fi-min-air fis"></span> Commonwealth Airways</a>, the flag carrier of Vekllei and a vital link between its 71 <a href="/republics/">island republics</a>.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Design Notes</strong></p>
<p>This jet flies primarily between islands in the Atlantic and the Caribbean, and it really needs low-speed flight manoeuvrability to properly land on runways that aren&rsquo;t as long as those designed for larger, delta-wing international jets. To allow for both supersonic cruising and low-speed take-offs and landings, this design features a swing wing, and it changes angle mid-flight.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Regret Comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/regret-comic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/regret-comic/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Oh no. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/ohno.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Oh no.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Uniform Hijab</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hijab/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hijab/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Vekllei has large Muslim populations in Mira. Revision of the Vekllei school uniform hijab. It now fastens with a school crest pin.
Mostly for use among the Portuguese muslim community across Mira (Madeira) and the Azores. I&rsquo;m not quite happy with this sketch, and I would like to include more Miran elements in future.
Notes on Headscarves in Vekllei Schools Under the uniform code, only &ldquo;veils&rdquo; are permitted, which encompasses a range of headwear for various groups including Christian and Jewish orthodox communities.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/hijab.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Vekllei has large Muslim populations in <a href="/mira/">Mira</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Revision of the Vekllei school uniform hijab. It now fastens with a school crest pin.</p>
<p>Mostly for use among the Portuguese muslim community across <a style="color: rgb(91, 67, 138)" href="/mira/"><span class="fi fi-mira"></span> Mira</a> (Madeira) and the Azores. I&rsquo;m not quite happy with this sketch, and I would like to include more Miran elements in future.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Notes on Headscarves in Vekllei Schools</strong>
<br>
Under the uniform code, only &ldquo;veils&rdquo; are permitted, which encompasses a range of headwear for various groups including Christian and Jewish orthodox communities. No face coverings are allowed.</p>
<p>Regarding Islamic head coverings, it&rsquo;s not a common issue because Miran muslims do not generally wear a Niqab or similar.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Grocery Robot</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/grocery-robot/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/grocery-robot/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora isn&rsquo;t on speaking terms with the Big Man upstairs, but she loves Maria. Robots are used to subsidise rather than multiply productivity in Vekllei.
This stock bot was built for United Grocers by National Machines to do the busywork of shelf-stocking. Now the grocer girls just sit outside the shop and chat.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/robot.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora isn&rsquo;t on speaking terms with the Big Man upstairs, but she loves Maria.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Robots are used to subsidise rather than multiply productivity in Vekllei.</p>
<p>This stock bot was built for <a style="color: rgb(98, 186, 85)" href="/united-grocers/"><span class="fi fi-min-united-grocers fis"></span> United Grocers</a> by <a style="color: rgb(224, 40, 35)" href="/national-machines/"><span class="fi fi-min-national-machines fis"></span> National Machines</a> to do the busywork of shelf-stocking. Now the grocer girls just sit outside the shop and chat.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Maria</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/maria/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/maria/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora isn&rsquo;t on speaking terms with the Big Man upstairs, but she loves Maria. Tzipora has a weird Catholic theology where she&rsquo;s fallen out with God like a roommate and now only communicates with him through saints.
Her neighbourhood is mostly Jewish, and her friend Cobian is animistic in the Oslolan (Icelandic) tradition. Vekllei is a melting pot.
Ayn is part thai and was raised buddhist, Moise is Greek Orthodox, Lin Zhi is a militant atheist (born in the wrong timeline for reddit).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/maria.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora isn&rsquo;t on speaking terms with the Big Man upstairs, but she loves Maria.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora has a weird Catholic theology where she&rsquo;s fallen out with God like a roommate and now only communicates with him through saints.</p>
<p>Her neighbourhood is mostly Jewish, and her friend Cobian is animistic in the Oslolan (Icelandic) tradition. Vekllei is a melting pot.</p>
<p>Ayn is part thai and was raised buddhist, Moise is Greek Orthodox, Lin Zhi is a militant atheist (born in the wrong timeline for reddit).</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>High-Speed Rail</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/high-speed-rail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/high-speed-rail/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Sketch I won&rsquo;t finish of Oslolan high-speed rail snaking out to the fast routes that cross the island&rsquo;s glaciers. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/hs.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Sketch I won&rsquo;t finish of Oslolan high-speed rail snaking out to the fast routes that cross the island&rsquo;s glaciers.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Casemate</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/casemate/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/casemate/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Let&rsquo;s call it &ldquo;convergent evolution&hellip;&rdquo; The Casemate fighter is the latest atomic fighter in Commonwealth service. It continues the tradition of straightforward fighter aircraft with excellent flight characteristics in the Atlantic.
The ongoing evolution of the nuclear fighter is obvious compared to its predecessor here, which has its reactor mounted beneath the reactor for easy servicing.
Notes on Safety A century of miniaturisation of fission has improved safety in vehicles but it&rsquo;s still not perfect.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/casemate.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Let&rsquo;s call it &ldquo;convergent evolution&hellip;&rdquo;</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Casemate fighter is the latest atomic fighter in Commonwealth service. It continues the tradition of straightforward fighter aircraft with excellent flight characteristics in the Atlantic.</p>
<p>The ongoing evolution of the nuclear fighter is obvious compared to its predecessor <a href="/stories/fighter/">here</a>, which has its reactor mounted beneath the reactor for easy servicing.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Notes on Safety</strong>
<br>
A century of miniaturisation of fission has improved safety in vehicles but it&rsquo;s still not perfect. The aircraft has gyroscopes to auto-scramble the reactor and the reactor system is well-shielded.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, Vekllei&rsquo;s greatest safety measure is that it is a country of islands, and its aircraft are most often flown over water.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei 2024</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/2024/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/2024/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ The first morning of 2064. Ayn is collecting arctic basil for the eggs. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/2024.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The first morning of 2064. Ayn is collecting arctic basil for the eggs.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
