<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020 on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://beta.millmint.net/tags/2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020 on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beta.millmint.net/tags/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Army</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-30-army/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-30-army/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/kmq6u9/the_vekllei_army/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s a thousand years of history in Vekllei’s armed forces&lt;/strong&gt;, though you’ll find very little of it recalled casually today. Almost everything about Vekllei’s prewar society was scorched by the bombs, and the scraps of military infrastructure that survived were appropriated in the subsequent British occupation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since independence, a slate has been wiped clean, and a modern fighting force has replaced the colonial legions and battleships of yesteryear. Since reestablishment, Vekllei’s mettle has been tested in the jungles of Taiwan and the arctic deserts alike, and have proven themselves to be a rugged, versatile army of considerable bravery and fighting strength in spite of poor equipment in the bankruptcy of independence. Attached to British units in Taiwan and sent carelessly into dirty work, the Vekllei Army today has forged new prestige in the blood of its rebirth. Although Vekllei is an island nation, it maintains a large professional and conscripted army and is the third-largest contributor of personnel towards U.N. peacekeeping internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;army-types&#34;&gt;Army Types&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured here is a coalition of soldiers from different branches of the army. Let’s explore some of them now. Please note that this list is not comprehensive, and merely represents a portion of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s most common army branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;armipor&#34;&gt;Armipor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Armipor&lt;/em&gt; (armi denporitsa, or &lt;em&gt;army police&lt;/em&gt;), are a special branch of the secretive cross-bureau Military Intelligence Operations Council, which joins Vekllei’s sprawling espionage networks with its military infrastructure. The Armipor have many duties, including conventional military police-work, but may also engage in intelligence-gathering, counter-terrorism and rural policing work depending on the division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;somitzisma&#34;&gt;Somitzisma&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somitzisma (meaning &lt;em&gt;militia groups&lt;/em&gt;) are formal army units with training somewhere between active reservists and independent militias. Unlike reservists, they are not assigned uniforms and generally receive only periodic training. Their training focuses on a hypothetical home front, specialising in improvised warfare, urban combat and ambushes. They number some 2 million total, and represent one to the largest equipped militia forces in the world. This number would likely rapidly inflate during wartime due to high rates of firearm ownership in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;macka&#34;&gt;Macka&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A “macka” is prewar Vekllei slang for a blunt tool or implement, and at some point during occupation and independence it became attached to Vekllei’s general infantry. Vekllei mackas number some 90,000 serving, and make up the bulk of Vekllei’s professionalised infantry. Mackas are reinforced by nearly a million active reservists, conscripted through Mandatory Service and equipped for defensive fighting. Their equipment varies dramatically, since they are trained for a variety of environments, including Vekllei’s warm southern climates and arctic warfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;carasbine&#34;&gt;Carasbine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Carasbine (commandos, derived from &lt;em&gt;carbine&lt;/em&gt;), are Vekllei’s special forces. Broadly defined as any Vekllei army unit attached to unconventional forms of warfare (since counterterrorism and domestic paramilitary roles are served by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;venopor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), the country’s strategic focus on high-value and covert ops require a flexible fighting force. Although structured within Vekllei’s army hierarchy, their function has considerable latitude among divisions and often intersects with active operations planned and directed by the bureaus of National Intelligence. To this end, Vekllei maintains commandos trained for sabotage, hostage-rescue, special offensive action, combat diving, and manhunts. They often support and work alongside espionage agents of the NI bureaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tzipora&#34;&gt;Tzipora&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora does not have a gun and is not very good at killing the enemy and/or invading foreign nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She does, however, enlist in the Garden Corps for Mandatory Service and spends her military years growing flowers in street garden boxes, severely distracting any foreign invading force with their beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tzipora Christmas Story</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/kkmgdm/a_tzipora_christmas_story/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pachinki is a world of Tzipora’s own creation&lt;/strong&gt;, a dorky retreat from the difficulties she has in Vekllei. Tzipora always loved stories of wild places and adventure, and Pachinki blossomed organically from within her daydreams. Eventually she started writing and drawing it. When she was sad, bored or anxious, she would descend back into Pachinki’s world of ancient magic, edible gems and pirates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chapter she wrote in late November one year resembled her idea of a Christmas story, and so I’ve included a portion here to accompany this picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wrote,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story starts with the tale of a young Pilot Witch, whose job was to guide dead aircraft to safe airports in the shaky peace that followed the Black War. It had to be female witches, since men couldn’t see the dead. She would meet formations of heavy bombers and strike fighters stuffed with corpses out at sea and show them the safe paths to the landing strips, flying low and fast where the Palace Gods couldn’t see them. This was the safe part of the job, since the Palace Gods and Necropirates ambushed out at sea, where they could hide between the archipelagos. Over land, they were mostly safe. It was an important job. Without the witch’s guidance, these planes would navigate the world forever, circling overhead, still packed with bombs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witches would guide the dead airmen down to the ground, where they could finally be relieved of their duty and released with proper burial rights. The planes would be repaired and flown back to the royal palace in Lily. This young witch was glad it was once again peacetime; when the empires warred, they couldn’t keep up with the dead planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, she was told to meet a special transport delegation out at sea. They didn’t explain anything more. She flew out to the coast on her broom and the glint of a wingtip caught her eye. As it approached, her instinct flared with alarm. These were not dead planes — the crew in them were very much alive. She flew out and approached the largest aircraft in the formation, a transport bomber of a type she’d seen several times before. She landed atop the aircraft and made her way inside via a turret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s going on?” The witch asked, irritated at the break in procedure. The captain of the aircraft jumped at the noise, and straightened his shoulders as he addressed her pompously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’re here to guide us, are you? We’re from the Palace, in Lily.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I understand that; I saw your markings. But why’s it any of my business?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What do you mean, witch? We need safe passage, don’t we?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s not my trade; what are you doing this far out? Do you have any idea how dangerous these archipelagos are?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The captain snorted and resettled his cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know what time of year it is, don’t you? All five planets are above us, silly girl.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The other witches won’t like you coming in uninvited, I’ll have you warned.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s nearly the time for the festival. The Queen wants fine gifts for the Princess, and she won’t do with any old hat or dress. We’re part of a military attaché that’s spent the last six months searching the lands for the finest gifts in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Gifts,” the witch said, betraying her surprise. “W-what sort of gifts?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, how about you head below deck and see for yourself. While you’re there, why don’t you pick something out? Provided we understand each other, of course.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, all right. Okay,” the witch said, and hurriedly turned away from the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, the witch was once again atop her broom, though somewhat unevenly under the weight of the largest gem necklace she’d ever seen. She couldn’t believe her luck; it was laden with Soup Gems, and they hadn’t been seen around here in nearly a hundred years. You only found them growing in the stomachs of the Kemi people, and they had been wiped out many eons ago. A gem like this would produce excellent powders, and make her very powerful for a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She resettled her pilot’s hat, and placed both hands on her broomstick. She felt the wind swirl around her as she shot to the front of the formation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The witch depicted here looks awfully like Tzipora, and that’s no coincidence. Tzipora is always somewhere in her own stories. She writes herself in because she likes to imagine herself living among these people, flying on broomsticks and becoming a powerful witch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These types of posts aren’t very regular, but they’re important for my health as an illustrator. Vekllei might be fantastical, but it’s a Cold War consumer society at the end of the day. Pachinki provides me (and Tzipora!) a fun holiday now and then, into a surreal world of planetoids and magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you have any questions. You can read other Pachinki posts (quite old now) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ar8jov/a_gem_girl_shows_off_her_enormous_strength_in/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/ba3mb4/the_littlest_goddess_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/cudjz6/the_teeth_regents/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/b7n1uh/a_mineral_lake_starts_absorbing_grief_in_pachinki/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/de25mz/the_mountain_witches_of_pachinki_and_the/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. That’s all of them, that’s all I’ve ever done. This project’s been going on for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart/MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Heart</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/khl6um/full_heart/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She’d dropped out of school and had the slow accent of a person too foreign to employ&lt;/strong&gt;. She now lived in a country that did not use money. Food was everywhere and you ate until you were satisfied. Around each corner was a new cinema or basement lounge, and water trickled through the streets like all mythic garden cities. It was a paradise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, despite her new wealth, a panic had set in. School hadn’t worked out and she lived parasitically with a person who hadn’t really expected or wanted to take her. Desperate to justify her presence as an immigrant, she started to cook — first from the TV, then out of books. A year into her new life in utopia, she had the makings of a master home cook, serving hot suppers six days a week. On Sundays Baron made a roast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is the sort of place that rewards attention to common things, and Tzipora soon cultivated a chef’s eye for fresh ingredients and learned how to bargain with grocers for the best produce. She would plan her meals carefully and indulged her Colombian childhood, rediscovering the bandeja paisa and flatbreads of her youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was relaying her sadness at being unemployed one day when Baron asked her “why not become a cook?” Somehow the thought had never occurred to her. She began to walk into restaurants and ask for work — but most restaurants in Vekllei are run by families, and have no interest in expanding their kitchen for teenage foreigners. There was a restaurant two stops away on the Lola Main Line she liked especially: The Bull, or “Toro”, was run by a loud Spaniard called Che who’d opened his kitchen into the dining area, so you could see him cook. He was rude — Tzipora’s native fluency picked up more than your average Vekllei person — but more importantly, he was an excellent, classically-trained chef. In any other city in the world, he might have been celebrated, but here he ran his business beneath a print shop in the artist’s quarter of Lola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She asked him for work in the kitchen — any work, and he told her no. She finished her meal and left. The next time, he shouted her out of his restaurant. She continued to look around for work, but a quiet stubbornness deep in her heart had convinced her that el Toro is where she wanted to be. She started waiting until closing, where she would ambush him. Six weeks into her courting, Che told Tzipora that she should be sent to an asylum if she wanted to wash dishes so much — but if she would stop bothering him, he would expect her at 2pm the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was hard work and it was unrewarding work. In her first year she was ostensibly a commis chef in a kitchen of six — but spent more time with her hands in the sink than preparing food. She would occasionally handle ingredients prep too, and had to reach the markets in the early morning to get the best produce or face having a pan thrown at her in the evening. She worked five nights a week from 2pm till the early hours of the morning. Che ran his kitchen like it was in Barcelona. Sometimes she would step out for a cigarette and fall asleep on the stair in the alley, sweat glistening under the streetlamp, cooled by the ocean stir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years into her work at el Toro she would replace the outgoing sous-chef, and her talent as a cook blossomed. It was a peculiar sight, to have someone of Tzipora’s height and appearance shouting at young men, totally secure in her authority. The years of labour had hardened her resolve, and refined her intuition. She wouldn’t be a chef all her life, but she would always be a wonderful cook. In a country of rich foods and hearty wines, that was a precious commodity. More importantly, her persistence in that kitchen earned her place in the country — Vekllei was a land of opportunity, after all. It is one thing to visit paradise, but quite another to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bea and the Mosses</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-08-bea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-08-bea/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/k98fcg/bea_and_the_mosses/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ This character was illustrated as a gift to Bike. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy Birthday!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is Bea&lt;/strong&gt;, an energetic Botanist with the Landscape Bureau of Vekllei. People know her as an eccentric young woman easily persuaded by cottage-fashions, but she takes her work very seriously and spends most of her waking hours documenting the dense temperate rainforests of Vekllei’s coastal lowlands. These are not particularly adventurous expeditions — most of her work is performed along old trails and paths, but Bea finds the sublime amidst the mundane and has contributed enormously to the ecological understanding of local flora in the borough of &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/holsyim&#34;&gt;Holsyim&lt;/a&gt;, where she was born. She specialises in Bryology, the study of mosses and soft green bric-a-brac found abundant on Vekllei’s cool wet forest floors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish her luck on her work, it benefits all people to know and respect the smallest of things around them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crown Land of No King</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/k7dqua/crown_land_of_no_king_veklleis_landscape_of_gods/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It would be misleading to characterise Vekllei as environmentalist in the usual idea of the word&lt;/strong&gt;. Vekllei is no such thing. This is obvious in subtle ways, like Newda’s &lt;em&gt;Dumousiantopet&lt;/em&gt;, or “beautiful and seperate,” which advocates the separation of human and natural design. It is also policy; Vekllei is dependent on its landscape as part of &lt;em&gt;Autosuffisouitopet&lt;/em&gt;, or “self-sustenance,” and to this end sinks forests for hydroelectric dams and topples mountains for novel urban projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unlike most developed countries, Vekllei policy is still informed by an unwavering fear of the natural world. This is a country where belief in demons and fairies and trolls abound; where rivers carry names and biographies; and where Upen’s gentle animism resurrects most material into life. Vekllei is also geologically active, home to some of the world’s largest active volcanoes that grow in the tectonic fissures atop which the country sits. The forests they may sink; but should certain mountains come back to life, entire cities will be consumed in fire and ash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inspires a fear of nature as old as the history of human settlement in the country. Most Vekllei people worship a pantheon of traditional animist gods alongside abrahamic or local faiths. This is a culture in which all things have value, and so the national superego has declined to position human civilisation as unique and consequently exploitative. To this end, Vekllei’s segregationist environmental policy is inversely a symptom of this direct connection with nature, and a cultural fear of the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, this is obvious in the “forbidden regions” of the country. After the war, vast territories of the interior were designated as &lt;em&gt;Kronaismioudelfia&lt;/em&gt;, or “crown land”. These forbid sovereign entry or human exploration in any capacity other than personal curiosity. These are dark pockets of ancient wilderness, where myth and legend abound. If you enter them and become lost, only volunteers will seek you out — for the purposes of the Vekllei government, you have exited the sovereignty of the nation-state. They function in part as natural reservations, but that neglects just how isolated, wild and untouchable these regions are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, this might seem archaic and superstitious, but like most spirituality-as-policy in the country, it serves a foundational component of Vekllei society (and subsequently, the economy). As Vekllei seeks out deindustrialisation via post-scarcity systems, a sincere respect for landscape as living and dangerous becomes essential. Mere appreciation or stewardship in abstract is, by Vekllei metrics, not much different than naked exploitation. Removing human constructions from landscape also necessitates the dismantling of landscape, cartography and tourism conceptually. There are few national parks in the country, but hundreds of &lt;em&gt;Kronaismioudelfia&lt;/em&gt;. Deep within them lurk unmapped, undocumented things — and at their hearts are pure springs, grasslands of eternal life, spirit dwellings and the souls of your ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this image, Tzipora meets her reflection with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/culture/language/#6-upotenne&#34;&gt;Upotenne&lt;/a&gt; sign for peace and friendliness. Reflections of mirror-pools in Vekllei are believed to be places to meet spirits. While your reflection may not be a spirit, your reflection is closer to their world than your own, as a deconstruction of image and physicality. In this sense, Tzipora is hoping her gesture may carry through into the other worlds and convince them of human peacefulness. Such gestures are good manners, considering she is no longer in sovereign human territory and stands in the land of gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to Grips</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-01-grips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-12-01-grips/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/k4pcll/coming_to_grips/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She would spend a long time by the rivulet that ran behind her apartment.&lt;/strong&gt; She would do the housework and hang the wash out, then watch the water trickle past in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She tried to open a jar the other day and started to cry when she couldn’t get it open. She never cried once when she saw those things in America, or got beat to shit, but these days she cried over jam. She didn’t know what was going on. Things were getting worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She caught her reflection in the rivulet’s water. It provoked a nausea. She was so tired. What would stop her from plunging her face into the river until she slipped right in? Would she drown and float away, never to be seen again? Or maybe, in a miracle, she might grow gills and fins and swim away, her life-force put to better use as a fish or turtle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you resolve an ache to confess sadness to someone and the instinct to protect your emotions? It wasn’t in her nature to tell people about her feelings. On some level, she looked down on it; every cell of her body told her to suffer in silence. She wore the same clothes every day. Why did she wear the same clothes every day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a fierce thing to discover within yourself that which you despise the most. She watched the foam gather around a stick wedged in the bank of the rivulet. If she’d been born elsewhere, into power and wealth rather than girlishness and poverty, she would have made an excellent thug. She wondered how much management she needed. Why was it so hard to live?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She tasted the water from the rivulet and it was cold and sweet, and said a prayer to the rivulet for its purity no matter what happened to her. The wash was dry on the line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of The Ground and Into The Light</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-11-28-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-11-28-city/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/k2sf33/out_of_the_ground_and_into_the_light_cities_in/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NO REALTORS EXCEPT THE STATE ■ THE COUNTY THE AGENT OF THE STATE ■ THE ARCHITECT THE AGENT OF THE COUNTY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is clear that in Vekllei democracy is a way of living more than it is a form of government&lt;/strong&gt;. After all, by metrics of representation, the Atlantic nation&amp;rsquo;s electoral system often sputters and fails, undermined by the bundling of the human and natural votes as equal, and the wildly disproportionate borough system. But if democracy is a way of life and not just a ballot in its box, then we can see democracy acted out all around us in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cities are living things; they are made up of people hurrying and talking and building. In cities, we see Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s centralised society/decentralised life contradiction lean towards &amp;ldquo;deurbanisation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;local transparency&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four principles of Vekllei life are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-management and self-interest through Sundress Municipalism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification of property as an independent social organ, like nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abolishment of currency and currency-substitutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Economic feminisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranked in order of their immediacy to the average person, we can see that &lt;em&gt;Sundress Municipalism&lt;/em&gt; is at the core of Vekllei life. What exactly is &lt;em&gt;Sundress Municipalism&lt;/em&gt;? It describes the organisation of Vekllei cities, which are arranged around the following principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local employment, or &amp;ldquo;commutelessness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slumlessness, beautification, and a will to architecture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Property stewardship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open air and clean water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Land usefulness (&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;friendliness&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private ownership of private needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public ownership of public needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These values are oriented around a deeply Vekllei valuation of space, and the accessibility of place and material to ordinary people. They also reveal some peculiarities in their listing &amp;ndash; what constitutes a private and public need, and what constitutes ownership, are deeply spiritual concepts in Vekllei, and their use here relies on uncoded intuition. Let us not forget we are dealing with a state that considers itself to be the human ambassador of the ground on which it sits, and so &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; include the nonhuman in their metrics. This is how, much to the amusement of foreigners, buildings can and often do &amp;ldquo;own themselves&amp;rdquo; in Vekllei. Most ownership is proved by stewardship; the use of space. The person who works the shop and lives above it, owns the shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This image depicts the Vekllei city of Adouisneh, the florid culture capital of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Northwest. It is one of the &amp;ldquo;Five Crowning Cities&amp;rdquo; of Vekllei, measured by population and cultural significance, and was the site of one of the earliest parliaments in the world, centuries before the monarchy would come to power. You can see here the tension between old-world European planning and new-world Sundress Municipalism in the architecture and layout of this city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A cactus bloom is beyond any bloom, I think, manufactured by plants anywhere in the world. And there you have an interesting syllogism, haven’t you? The desperate nature of the armed plant and the exquisite, beautiful efflorescence it produces. Something to think about. There you see, revealed, some processes of nature, the significance of which I don’t gather at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Frank Lloyd Wright, Nov. 1952&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps urbanised modernity is the cactus, and Sundress Municipalism is the blossom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not that Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s feminised Municipalism represents a clean departure from how cities look and feel, but instead constitutes a rethinking of urbanism; it is an ideology of homesteads, decentralisation, clean air, food production, arts and crafts, leisure, and the spirit, if not the literal presence of, &amp;ldquo;disposable income.&amp;rdquo; It is not enough that a factory should be the property of the people who work in it; a factory should become adjacent to the home, a part of it, designed in ways that benefit the good instincts of ordinary people. Vekllei is a celebration of the architect; automatons may now do a lot of the work, but all design is deeply human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the heart of the dream. Vekllei is not a big enough country to gift each person an acre of land to do with as they wish; it is, however, sophisticated enough to decentralise that &amp;ldquo;local acre&amp;rdquo; among the community, cultivating those same values in a modern skyline and allowing the city to flow across the landscape, changing as it responds to the place around it. Ownership is important; stewardship is especially important. By allowing people to own and use land, you give them dignity. Above all, design and architecture are important for the same reason spatiality is important &amp;ndash; they give presence to and emulsify work and leisure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the mid-twentieth century, modernism began to encircle the world and the architectural and urban images once projected as utopian began to fill real space. In the 1960s this reached a saturation point; utopia was, ironically, realised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Karatani Kojin,&lt;/em&gt; Architecture as Metaphor, &lt;em&gt;1983&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This occurred because, upon realising that art must be removed from architecture in order to safeguard it against a looming &amp;ldquo;loss of subject,&amp;rdquo; avant-garde thinkers methodologically reestablished architecture as &amp;lsquo;construction&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; utilitarian efforts towards grand ideas. With art removed, architecture was able to close in on the inherent placelessness of utopia. In Vekllei, this approach is extant (though diminished by their absurd place-metaphysics) through &lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt;, the indigenous design ideology that continues to service architecture through social, rather than artistic, methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;big idea&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt; is an agent for, wrapped up in &lt;em&gt;Sundress Municipalism&lt;/em&gt;, is very straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city should be everywhere and nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Adouisneh, despite its thousand years of history, we can see postwar &lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt; come to life in its integration and decentralisation of the &amp;ldquo;city&amp;rdquo; as a living process, moving people and their concerns closer together. Developed only with the consent of the architect, Vekllei has become an architocracy, serving decentralised, pleasant living through bureau monopolies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, after all, it is the necessity of state authority that is the cactus, and the middle-class free lifestyles of Vekllei people that make up the blossom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Speak Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ju5vmu/how_to_speak_vekllei_and_a_new_website/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters&lt;/strong&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net&#34;&gt;https://millmint.net&lt;/a&gt;. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will briefly discuss some elements shown in this infographic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language&#34;&gt;but a large article on the language has been drafted here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have some interest in constructed language, and some of the more playful aspects of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s evolving utopian communication systems, I encourage you to take a look at it. The website is incomplete, and both the articles on characters and Vekllei itself are very incomplete. Otherwise, a growing archive, essays, and issues of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic&lt;/em&gt; Bulletin are all available. Have a poke around, and let me know if anything breaks! The site has dark mode, if you&amp;rsquo;re a gamer. Just click the moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-language-many-parts&#34;&gt;One Language, Many Parts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To borrow from the article linked above, the Vekllei language has six core systems often referred to as sublanguages. They are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language/#21--spoken-vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoken Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is everyday spoken language. It draws from two glossaries with different meanings and feelings, called &lt;em&gt;Oa&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Loh&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language/#22--topet&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which are logographic characters (occasionally characterised as hieroglyphs). Like other pictographic languages, &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; characters can be broken down into repeating components, called &lt;em&gt;Topotte&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language/#23--rapotenne&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is the traditional logographic language of names. It is much older than Topet, and has more in common with spiritual runes than modern logography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language/#24--potenne&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potenne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, lit. “&lt;em&gt;Hand-Talk&lt;/em&gt;”, is a sign language that incorporates gestures and signing to add meaning to emotion to spoken language, and occasionally in place of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language/#25--upotenne&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upotenne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, lit. “&lt;em&gt;Spirit-Hand-Talk&lt;/em&gt;”, as the recreation of runes in human form, used limitedly in spiritual ritual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language/#26--vekllei-semaphore&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the codification of colour and shape. Traditionally limited to colour, shape and pattern are now also included in &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/em&gt;, in which full sentences can be formed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-this-picture&#34;&gt;In This Picture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see various parts of the Vekllei sublanguages on display, including &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Potenne&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/em&gt;. Before Cobian gets close enough to say hello, Tzipora has already delivered a devastating compliment via a simple three-finger tap to the palm, admiring how she looks. A couple of descriptions of Tzipora written in &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; have been annotated on her left, to demonstrate its use, including a tongue-twister (&amp;ldquo;She always tucks her shirt&amp;rdquo; becomes &amp;ldquo;Louisn Laismoh Loah Liousmineh&amp;rdquo;). You&amp;rsquo;ll notice &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; looks especially hieroglyphic, even by pictographic standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s full Blood Name is spelled out in &lt;em&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/em&gt; below, which is markedly different from &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; in history, characters and grammar. Most formal names in Vekllei employ a seal in place of writing it out in full ornamentation, which has been provided below along with a formal signature. Her signature is entirely pictographic; elements are arranged according to symbolic value, rather than phonological legibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the right, we can see an example of how Semaphore lives up to its name through its presence on flags, reinforcing and communicating information without conventional literacy. Also shown are a handful of basic symbols as they relate to authority, with the landscape of Vekllei superseding all human organs. Their colours matter, and so their meanings are more complex than what is described here &amp;ndash; for example, a small black circle refers to a human being, but an orange one refers to an arctic person (usually Vekllei).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have a breakdown of the word &lt;em&gt;comiya&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language/#222-phonetic-reading&#34;&gt;also looked at here&lt;/a&gt;), which means &amp;ldquo;friend.&amp;rdquo; Tzipora and Cobian are &lt;em&gt;comiya&lt;/em&gt;, and Moise and Cobian are&amp;hellip; sort of &lt;em&gt;comiya&lt;/em&gt;. The introduction here of &lt;em&gt;phonetic complements&lt;/em&gt;, which are duplicate consonant-pairs used to slightly alter the semantic meaning of a word without changing its pronunciation, allows the idea of a &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; to be conceptualised in many different ways, to encompass all sorts of relationships. This one here implies a sort of naïve love (by using characters for late autumn, young woman and a glacial beach, all pronounced /k/.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limpettes are tails that underline vowel-forms called &lt;em&gt;hieyerette&lt;/em&gt; to enhance legibility. Although ornamented &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; has visually distinct consonant-pairings, business &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; does not generally use superscript and so limpettes designate the vowel-form. If you&amp;rsquo;re a bit lost, that&amp;rsquo;s okay. It&amp;rsquo;s in the main article, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make this post too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can imagine then, even with only a handful of examples of language in practice here, how complex Vekllei can become as phonological and semantic meaning compound, combine and seperate in different forms and contexts. The spoken word can be altered by the physical gesture, and the physical gesture can be altered by the written word.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st Century Witch</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/jqgtzx/21st_century_witch/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When the light shifted just right&lt;/strong&gt;, the ceramic tiles and concrete footpaths twinkled like water off the back of a swan. 16th Century witches could build a hut in the woods and forage for herbs; 21st Century witches were susceptible to modernist persuasions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Demotic Meeting Hall was constructed twenty years prior as the main meeting hall of the National Dockworker’s Union. Situated on the coast, and along the recently-built monorail line to Roya, it dominated the coastline like a mythic lighthouse. Where the cathedrals of Europe built spires to God, Vekllei built towers for dockmen. At 112 meters tall, the hall’s colossal window structures were awesome within, and its massive bronze ornament glittered for miles. It was palatial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dockworker’s Union moved west to Montre at some point, so these days it was simply the Roya Demotic Community Hall. It was used for all sorts of things, not least of which domestic tourism. Its lookout provided views across the North-West Fjords. When Tzipora first arrived in Vekllei, the scale and decadence of it appealed to her enormously. It was depicted on her language booklet, and since then she’d developed a minor fascination with the structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She got her chance to visit upon her invitation to a costume party hosted by the Chef’s Concern. Tzipora is a witchy sort of person, and the idea of going as a witch appealed to her. She already had the wardrobe — as Cobian remarked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’ve put on a hat and you’re holding a stick — that’s it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s my costume,” Zelda said. “I’m a witch.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see her here attempting to recreate the sumptuous curve of the Meeting Hall in witch form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vekllei Comic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/jih6t2/major_announcement_a_vekllei_comic/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He not busy being born is busy dying,&amp;rdquo; — that’s off a Bob Dylan bootleg. I’ve just finished my thesis and I’m busy being born again. Sometimes I feel like I’m busy dying. Drawing’s been the way out for a long time now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today I’m starting work full-time on a Vekllei comic called Atomic Modern. The front cover looks like a textbook. The name is not that interesting. That’s okay — apparently my honours in media didn’t do anything for my marketing ability, but this project is about celebrating mundanity and restraint. Tzipora’s got a fag in her mouth but it isn’t lit. I feel like that a lot of the time. It’s a self-contained image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atomic Modern is about Tzipora and Vekllei. It’s about her friends and her memories and all the good and bad parts of her life. It’s about what went down in America and how you can justify living. It’ll have beautiful Vekllei landscapes and characters in muted colour. It will also include passages that act as a guide to Vekllei and society — diagrams, infographics and footnotes. It’s also an escape from everything going on right now — there’s good and bad in all stories, but at the end of the day Vekllei is a utopia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will publish pages here for free&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;I’ll collate them into chapters available exclusively to my patrons&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe some extra stuff too. I’m a good dad to my patrons. I already made a set of postcards and sent them out. Either way, you’ll continue to see stuff here.
This is exciting, isn’t it? This is a new chapter for me as an artist. It’s a vulnerable moment for me, because up until now it’s just sort of been “posting on reddit”. I don’t have a publisher, I’m not trained, I’m just some guy. But this is what I’ve always wanted to do, and I’m trying to get busy being born again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be regular world posts here still. There’s drawings I like to do that just don’t fit into a comic format. I think during weekdays I’ll work on the comic and on weekends I’ll do a painting. We’ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I’ll have a nice big wiki soon with multiple language support. I’ll let you know when it’s done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start this again, with all that off my chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Hobart. I’m busy getting born again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much love,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MelonKony&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;Join the Vekllei Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;Join the Vekllei Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be “petticoat”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All That’s Solid Melts into Zelda</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/jdf5fd/all_thats_solid_melts_into_zelda/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My nerves are like overused sandpaper—all dull; only the eye-catching, bizarre and grotesque can excite me now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tanizaki Junichirō, 1918&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wind had died and it seemed that she would follow it&lt;/strong&gt;. Crazy shadows distorted beneath car headlights. It occurred to her in some way that, as she approached dying, she was living out the ultimate dramatic fantasy of the American misplaced girl, in the same way the townsmen were fulfilling their grotesque constellation of death by murdering women. To them, she was not Zelda, or an agitator, or even a maid from Motel Grande; she was just a girl of girl-form, washed out; beat in; bent before the death-bridge where the creek rolled on below. It was brutal and violent, and also the most tacky thing. It scaled up and down, because it was murdering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hearts of America are like overused sandpaper — all dull. This is how it played out in 2063, ages into the Great American Decline and well before it was put down like a sick dog by Chinese methods. The worn out bodies of the hedonistic coasts were numb to the spectacle of collapse and found themselves displaced and unfeeling, and so the neurotic motions of vampiric culture barons responded. In 2036, long before the Dallas Secession or Zelda’s birthday, the NBC under the Radio Corporation of America broadcast the first televised execution in the United States of child serial killer Wayne Graham. This enticed similar coverage across all major television networks for subsequent executions, which were viewed by millions of Americans. The format culminated in NBC’s The &lt;em&gt;American Justice Show&lt;/em&gt; programme, in which the method and subject of broadcasted executions were made participatory by public poll. It was tremendously successful but was cancelled in 2041, after the botched death of George Kovacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not necrotic; this is neurotic; it is the ultimate sucking up of human desire into the commodity-form, and it was only the beginning. It is not just a poetic coincidence that the cancellation of &lt;em&gt;American Justice&lt;/em&gt; saw the legalisation (or at the very least, decriminalisation) of prostitution in all regions but the Deep South over the next decade (which would contribute to the eventual secession). This is pleasure in its raw form, and the murder of prostituted immigrant-labourers and the eroticisation of the death of Wayne Graham’s teen-age victims was one and the same. The necroticisation would arrive later, as modernity tumoured and pleasure outpaced the sovereignty of the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was Zelda, who was a perfect caricature of the real American in the 21st century — born overseas, poor as shit, and dressed up for dying. And why shouldn’t she die? All the old things were dead. God, kings, outrage, empathy, optimism — it was all thrown in the creek, with the rest of the immigrant-labourers. Why shouldn’t a child and her sensitivity be among them? You could change the channel on television and see pornography and the brutal violence of the Secession adjacent to each other. If you clicked the knob back and forth fast enough, they could become one and the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was the last to arrive and among the first to be lynched, and maybe they would make postcards out of her dead body. She couldn’t even wonder this in her terror; the thought would only occur to her much later. It seemed like the whole Great American Decline, in all its hungry decomposition and hedonism was leading to this single moment — and all that was once solid melts into Zelda.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petrol Heaven — The Rohsm STR-750</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/j9up8s/petrol_heaven_the_rohsm_str750/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rohsm STR series&lt;/strong&gt; is a small racer built for clubs by Rohsm S.p.M., a hundred-year-old company headquartered in the Mediterranean racing culture of Tohs. Its most recent variant, the 750, is available in limited quantities to enthusiast owners and club pools. Like most petrol cars in Vekllei, they are built by hand, so no two 750s drive exactly alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to its neighbouring continents, petrol cars are criminally unsafe in Vekllei, where a preference for speed and lightweight manoeuvrability in European bodies see much of the steel of electric autos traded for light alloys and carbon. They crumple like drink cans in a crash, but prior to their death the driver is having the best driving experience of his life. This reckless pursuit of good driving means locals call them “bastard cars”. Extraordinarily lightweight and tremendously powerful, they cut sharp racing lines and trace corners. Poised and nimble, they make good use of Motorway One, the gentle curved ring road of Vekllei with no speed limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the inconvenience of finding petrol stations and their relative danger, not many people drive petrol cars in Vekllei. Why would you, when it is usually faster and more convenient to take a fast tram or train, or a battery auto from an autopool? The ones that do drive, however, drive hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured is the 25th STR-750, returned home after wins on the circuit in Italy and Spain. Her drivers are pictured above. It also happens to be Tzipora’s favourite car, because it was the first petrol car she ever drove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mittens and Metaphysic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/j8pisi/mittens_and_metaphysic_product_atheism_and/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured above: various fashions worn by Vekllei women, showcasing heavy cold-weather dresses, simple styling, strong geometric shapes and colours, loose fits, and modest hemlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured below: postmodern neomarxism, which I’ve tricked you into reading with anime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previous posts on the Vekllei economy, if you’re new:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hpyyp1/the_race_for_inefficiency_veklleis_advocation_of/&#34;&gt;Sundress Municipalism and how it works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hel2m7/the_vekllei_crown_coins_of_a_moneyless_country/&#34;&gt;Macroeconomics and currency in a country with no money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei’s obvious contradictions are commonly referenced, but not always clear&lt;/strong&gt;. Why are parts of Vekllei epistemology, or the ‘Vekllei way of thinking,’ contradictory? And if these are contradictions, then surely they must fall apart when they’re examined? How is it possible to hold two contradictory ideas at the same time and apply them? Let’s look at Product Atheism, Vekllei’s foundation for necroeconomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atismoprodarte&lt;/em&gt;, lit. “product atheism,” is the process by which Vekllei culture breaks down and rebuilds social preconceptions of objects, including products. Vekllei does not really have &lt;strong&gt;commodities&lt;/strong&gt; in the traditional idea of the word, so it is supplemented here by ‘&lt;strong&gt;product&lt;/strong&gt;,’ which more closely resembles the Vekllei word for commodity-forms: &lt;em&gt;prodart&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;prodatte&lt;/em&gt;. This concept is a part of &lt;em&gt;Upen&lt;/em&gt;, which is found throughout Vekllei culture and its constitution, and coexists agnostically with organised religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Product Atheism” is the term for how Vekllei people think about the objects that make up their lives — clothes, appliances, toys, trinkets and treasures. These things are not quite commodities, because they are not “sold”. Vekllei does not use money, and so it does not produce items of any economic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An object’s economic form, then, is replaced by social form. Among Marxists, they call these social forms &lt;em&gt;fetishistic&lt;/em&gt;, because products are given lives of their own and exist independently of the labour that created them. But this doesn’t work in Vekllei, because&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• &lt;strong&gt;Labour-value is social, not economic&lt;/strong&gt;. Vekllei people are not paid for work and they do not pay money for products. All work is for social reasons; all consumption is for social needs. Any object that is prohibited from the ordinary Vekllei person is merely landscape; it has no form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• &lt;strong&gt;Labour-value is simultaneously suppressed, in imitation of commodity, and celebrated, in imitation of dereification&lt;/strong&gt;. Vekllei shops look like any foreign shops, because they participate in the same fantasy ritual of shopping and allow easy access to products. At the same time, Upen emphasises the importance of local consumption and objects made by hand, and so Vekllei appliances are generally hand-made. This creates a social bond between the producer and consumer, and breaks down commodity-form, but it can’t escape the fetishised valuations encouraged by the consumer-fantasy. So it is neither a social or economic product while being both; resulting in a permanent contradiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Vekllei ‘Product Atheism’ is more or less a rejection of Marxist commodity fetishism, and instead advocates product-worship. This is because objects in Vekllei are regarded as fantasy, and are eroticised by a fantasy market. This is a symptom of the unspoken truth most foreigners are well aware of — Vekllei does not have an economy; &lt;strong&gt;the Vekllei economy is dead; the economy has been reanimated and is zombified&lt;/strong&gt;. No money changes hands, no product has value, and all products are abstracted and exclusively physical simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus Product Atheism has two contradictions; first, that the participatory market economy of Vekllei is both alive and dead, making it both undead and unaliave, and second, that products are both abstracted by Product Atheism and then unabstracted through Product Atheism at the same time, leaving them formless and unconstructed — and, per Upen’s definitions, truly personal and intimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acknowledging this necroeconomic construction destroys it, and so a final truth is revealed. In Vekllei, the exchange of objects is a &lt;strong&gt;social formality&lt;/strong&gt;, like their uniforms and sign-language, and is both entirely superfluous and essential to the functioning of the state. This is not Marxism; this is not even economic; this is Vekllei, and its cultural forms are what determine all constructions of society. Vekllei’s ‘material form’ is actually cultural, and Upen is its culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Vekllei economic forms are not truly economic, it makes sense that Product Atheism does not merely apply to the economy. All products, or objects, are part of its frameworks. The example used in this picture, depicting women’s fashion, is a good example of how Upen brings together an abstract object value and a valueless physical object simultaneously. Clothes in Vekllei have a very powerful social function, enhanced by how colour and shape become forms of communication in themselves as part of Vekllei semaphore. Clothes are both figuratively and literally signifiers of personality and individual expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vekllei written script, called &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt;, most traditional clothing items are each assigned a single character, giving them a transcendental pictographic quality, a feature impossible to replicate in phonetic speech. In this sense, the written description of a dress in Vekllei supersedes its spoken equivalent, privileging pictorial, transcendental imagery over literalism. This poetic form is part of product-worship, and thus part of Product Atheism. This means that, without even touching the sociological tastes and trends of clothing fashion in Vekllei, we can see Product Atheism smashing Western frameworks against their own assumptions, leaving much of Vekllei epistemology, even today, incomprehensible to ideology without &lt;em&gt;Upen&lt;/em&gt; as its framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlantic Boredom</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/j6adwa/atlantic_boredom/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For a brief period of time&lt;/strong&gt;, Zelda and Cobian took it upon themselves to make something of their youth. Cobian fancied herself a gymnast, and though this ambition arrived too late and left too soon, she was quite good at it for a while. Tzipora was better suited on the trampoline, where her stiff leg didn’t give her as much trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They trained for about two hours, and after practice they met up to travel home together. Their gymnasium was in a coastal town called Gigayeh, in the borough of Mirah. Here, sloping lava fields were cast in the sea, buried under fine black sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an hour and a half after practice before the evening train arrived to take them back home to Lola, and so they were left with not much to do. Gigayeh had beautiful empty beaches, littered with icebergs that caught the light like jewels, but Tzipora couldn’t swim and the water was freezing. They could have enjoyed café food in the sun, but Cobian’s regimented home life had left her incapable of eating outside of her designated meals, and Tzipora could only drink so much coffee. Instead, most of these afternoons, they found themselves sitting on the ocean promenade, watching a handful of locals go about their business as they counted the minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the moment, it was stupefyingly boring. They’d spent all day at school with each other and usually couldn’t conjure a word between them. Tzipora would make a remark about a seabird, because she liked them. She had been learning a lot about birds. Sometimes they would share a comic, but they read too fast to fill time. Most of it was spent in the sea air, feeling it grow colder as the day waned, watching the same ocean foam throw itself onto glittering volcanic sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think that’s a horned puffin. That’s special,” Tzipora said out loud. Cobian didn’t even look up. Tzipora squinted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, wait, that’s just a regular one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In time, Tzipora would remember this period of her life fondly, and would visit Gigayeh to recapture that peace. As a teen-ager, however, those afternoons seemed to last forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baron, the Father</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/j23lyw/baron_the_father/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People are not sure what to make of Baron&lt;/strong&gt;. They are not sure what to make of his daughter, Tzipora, either. To that end, they are lucky to have found each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His obscurity is part of a severe disposition, made obvious by his astonishing disinterest in friends and hobbies. When he finishes work, he listens to the radio, prepares supper, and goes to bed. His unrelenting seriousness is mitigated by his general passivity — Baron is a man totally in control, who keeps to himself and does not take issue with what goes on around him. For his seriousness he is not particularly judgemental or opinionated. To call him boring would be a poor characterisation; he simply feels he has done enough and is not looking to complicate the basic equations of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora (Zelda to him) complicates this equation. She’s similar to him in many ways, with her conservative personal disposition and humble lifestyle. She does not make a very good teen-ager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s funny you say that. I was talking to her the other day, and she was talking about how nice it was to have some peace and quiet,” Baron once confided in Ayn. “Of course, she looks very young, so sometimes you have to remind yourself that she’s not a child. She’s not thirteen, she’s nineteen, and very unusual, I think. She’s very smart but she doesn’t let that on much.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora did not really have “phases” — Tzipora was Tzipora, eternal. But she was a much more emotionally attuned person, and her highs were higher and her lowers were lower than anything Baron had felt in decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was not always so unfeeling. Baron’s Ashkenazim parents were pulled straight from the bubbling diaspora of Eastern Europe. They met in the labour zionist movement, but fell out of love with professional organising and immigrated to a struggling Vekllei to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/g4wo2w/the_ou_hydroburo_office/&#34;&gt;work in the national hydroelectricity scheme&lt;/a&gt;, among thousands of immigrants employed by the Thunderburo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was born in 2027 and was not very interested in school as a child. He was rebellious and obstinate, and had only vague ambitions of acquiring a trade certificate in motorcycle repair. His sister, Amelie, died of tuberculosis when he was 11. That was about the end of school ambitions for him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He started conscription early and spent his high school years in an army college. By the time he was 18, he was transferred to military police. It was 2045. He had started dating a middle school sweetheart, Ayn, two weeks before the war in Taiwan broke out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young Baron died in Taiwan, and another figure in his body returned. He was transferred almost immediately to a junior post at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), where he would spend the next decade. While he was stationed abroad, his mother died and his father followed. By this time, Baron was a significant asset for Vekllei’s deep autonomous intelligence work — apolitical, unattached, unsentimental and steady on his feet. He was destined to die in Colombia, employed indefinitely and waiting to be used up. In 2063, he met a fellow Spanish-speaking Jew by name of Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many ways, his identity is as fractured as Tzipora’s, whose Jewish European ancestry was a novel curiosity and not much more. She considered herself a Latina-American until she was Vekllei, and since then she has not been anything more. That was how it went in Vekllei’s grand secular melting pot. Tzipora was still ta bubeleh to him, but by his mid-thirties Baron had lost most of his mother’s Yiddish.
Tzipora is his closest friend and daughter at the same time. She is a wholly energetic and independent agent in his life, and their relationship alternates awkwardly but intuitively between father-daughter and old friends. Ayn wonders if it is not a coincidence that Tzipora looks like Amelie, his sister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two of them champion the redemption of losers; the adrift, empty people of the world, acting on a chance to salvage a life and family. Tzipora expected to die in America; Baron expected nothing at all. But when Christmas comes around, and Ayn visits for supper, Taiwan and America melt into air; and their apartment houses the only Jewish Christmas tree in the neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Bouncy Zelda — an animation diary</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/j0qo4d/little_bouncy_zelda_an_animation_diary/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a week since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted&lt;/strong&gt;. Most of that was spent drawing the same thing over and over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A painting? Please. That&amp;rsquo;s a day&amp;rsquo;s work — maybe two. A five second loop of Tzipora jumping in and shuffling over? A week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to grasp just how much work animation is until you try it. This runs at 12 frames per second (which dickheads will recognise as the anime frame rate). There are maybe 38 unique frames in this tiny animation. It&amp;rsquo;s a title card for my imaginary studio, MillMint, in case I ever make videos in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sketch was fun. It comes alive — your precious characters become real. Then comes the inking. 38 lines traced and polished. Then comes the colouring. Good lord, the colouring. It isn&amp;rsquo;t just labour-intensive &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s mind-numbingly boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This animation has a lot of little imperfections. No, I&amp;rsquo;m not fixing them :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular post tomorrow to make up for a week of empty suffering. Thanks for looking. Let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory and Death in the Flower Tundra</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ivfcj4/memory_and_death_in_the_flower_tundra/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was their first hike after Maya’s funeral&lt;/strong&gt;. She had found adult life completely disappointing, and never moved out of home. In her last summer, she developed a desperate fascination with her receding childhood, and eventually took her own life outside of the classroom she’d studied in as a third-grade student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her death deeply disturbed Tzipora, who was keenly aware of how sentimental people died against metrics of their own imagination. She wondered if the government architects who designed schools and universities considered how those spaces gave life to memories. They were filled with lunchtimes and puppy love and old friends and your parents — and those things folded into brick and concrete and linoleum floors. Fifty years earlier, some architect designed a classroom so valuable that Maya took her own life in the memory of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their Puffling troop had set off for a camp site two hours away. Tzipora and Zo did not walk with them. They followed the flower tundra north, near where Zo and Maya had played as kids. At the base of an old oak, shrouded in a cool mist, Zo buried a pair of plastic earrings and laced school shoes, neither of which had been worn in a long time. Zo started to cry. Tzipora gave her some time to herself. After a while they drank hot tea with their feet in the creek. The mist had closed them in. There was good reason why people travelled to flower-tundras to meet with the dead. The mirror-pools and tombstone drumlins invoked the spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the tea, Zo pulled out her map and they set off again for the camp site, leaving the tree behind forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobian and Zelda &#34;head-over-heels&#34;</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/iu0c58/some_kind_of_gay_sketch_for_my_cool_subreddit/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;make love not lore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matchstick Girl</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/is6pr2/matchstick_girl/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another paint-sketch — a painting done fast. I’m trying to learn to a) paint and b) paint on an industrial scale.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;She’d missed the fast tram&lt;/strong&gt;, caught a tiny splinter in her thumb, lost a button and now the match wouldn’t strike. It just wasn’t her day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were in Callaisn (pronounced ka-lane), a borough of the capital Tzipora regarded as “the worst of them” for its tall buildings and labyrinthian concrete alleys. “Bad people, bad food, bad smells” she said, flashing the tact she was known for. “Let’s go home.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Callaisn was an oddity, built largely by the British during the occupation years in the fashion of London. It was nonetheless a thoroughly Vekllei borough, with its parks and tramways and rivulets, but it had a continental skyline marked by tower blocks and skyscrapers. A lot of boring business was done in Callaisn that Tzipora didn’t care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian frowned as Tzipora rotated a second match between her thumb and finger. She didn’t like this nasty little habit she’d picked up. “You’ll smell like your dad if you keep this up,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Suits me,” said Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/iqaarv/road_trip/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They showed up at the autopool&lt;/strong&gt;, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem. Moise would drive, Tzipora bunked with Cobian in the passenger seat and Alise, Zo and Jerome could cram into the back. It was a squeeze but with the top down and on the coastal highway it couldn’t have mattered less. It was the car of late summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zo had just married Jerome, and they had recently moved in with each other at age 17. Tzipora had no metrics to figure out if that was too young, but Zo was her friend and young newlyweds were lonely people. She was all too ready to volunteer her labour (and that of Cobian and Moise) to drive them down to Koisniya and pick them up a coffee machine she’d ordered six months prior. Tohs S.p.A. was a good company but Tohs himself was a disorganised bastard and he’d rung up to a few times to tell her the order had been delayed. Then she called him back a month later and he said he’d never received the order. So it was that they were on their way now, well after Zo and Jerome had married, to pick up the wedding gift. That was just how things worked in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zo’s friend Alise sat the coffee machine in her lap on the way back, and as the coastal highway reached Vik it skirted an incredible series of cliffs that they stopped to look at. The wind was out and the Atlantic churned beneath. The sun was hot on their skin. The coffee machine was left on the tiny back seat as they got out to have a look and take a picture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/iocwxt/clean_faces_full_hearts_uniforms_in_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society&lt;/strong&gt;. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depicted here are uniforms for education — Tzipora as a puffling of the Puffin Scouts on the left, and the others in mere school uniforms. These uniforms are universal and used across all ages of schooling, from kindergarten to university. Even some teachers wear them — it starts to stretch the conventional imagination about what constitutes a uniform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few observations on this picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, these uniforms are used interchangeably across ages and disciplines. The difference between a red pleat skirt and a navy skirt is trivial; it is merely a difference in the meaning of the clothing, as part of Vekllei semaphore. They are both equally the school-mandated uniform of education, and can be worn interchangeably from one day to the next, in third grade and at university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, there are many small uniquenesses in the uniform of each person, which are accentuated by their surrounding uniformity. Tzipora’s school shirt is pleated along the buttons, acquired off the rack of a department store. One pair of trousers might be a slightly different shade to the pair next to it. These discrepancies are not regarded as malfunctions of the uniform system, since the system is not designed to make each student conform to a single appearance — it is about identity and convenience in a country that spent many decades clawing its way out of abject poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These principles apply across many workplaces and in government, too — where uniforms are not intended to only signify publicly a place of work but instead form social bonds through clothing, which are intimate factors of ordinary life. In Vekllei, clothes are not an expression of personality, but items to communicate and bond with, regulated not by an authority demanding strict conformity but a desire for identity, physicality, infrastructure and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a state of affairs is unimaginable in some countries, especially beyond collectivist or conformist cultures. Individualist intuition suggests that uniforms are actively detrimental to personal expression — but this idea demands a scale of expression far beyond the preference for subtlety and delicateness in Upen. Deviations from uniformity, like earrings, the way hair is worn, wristwatches, makeup and minor irregularities accentuate the value of those things, and make them more important. This aesthetic contrast is at the heart of the wider Upen intuition that you can see in architecture and political priority alike. And, as any Vekllei boy will tell you — seeing a classroom crush out of uniform for the first time is a religious experience, and only afforded by scarcity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is an individualist society, modelled after self-concern and self-love by a salt-of-the-earth and larrikin people of my native Australia. This is not a people compatible with conventional thinking on the regulation of appearance — but, as with many things in Vekllei, both are held true at the same time. They are a free and unrestrained population clothed at work and in school in clothes gifted to them.
As an addendum, although many readers find common ancestry with Japan in this project (not unreasonably, either), Vekllei has more in common in some ways with the distant neighbours of my Australian homeland — countries that haven’t been glamorised in the West through culture export. Thailand, Cambodia and Laos are among them — coincidentally, all three are rare examples of countries where university students wear uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someday, we’ll look at the aesthetics of power and authority-worship, inspired at least in part by the history and culture of these countries, and associate them with cultural forces in Vekllei. If you have any questions, just ask.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ijxvzu/absolute_grotesque/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the morning of the second day, I watched a fly crawl across the cheek of the middle-aged woman, probably an office worker, lying next to me. It moved up her cheekbone to her temple, stopping now and then to rub its front legs as though performing a ritual.
A jagged tear ran down the leg of her dark blue work trousers, but the white calf it revealed was miraculously unscathed. The woman lay still. Probably dead, I assumed. After a while, the fly got on to her eyelid. Suddenly, she reached up and brushed it away, opening the eye. There was still a moist light inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From &lt;em&gt;Insects&lt;/em&gt;, by Seirai Yūichi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By chance, the glass paperweight had survived. When her in-laws’ house had burnt down in Yokohama, the paperweight was among those things that she’d frantically stuffed into an emergency bag, and now it was her only souvenir of life in her girlhood home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From evening on, in the alley, she could hear the strange cries of the neighbourhood girls. Rumour had it that they could make a thousand yen in a single night. Now and then she would find herself holding the forty-sen paperweight she had bought after ten days of indecision when she was these girls’ age, and as she studied the sweet little dog in relief, she would realise with a shock that there was not a single dog left in the whole burnt-out neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From &lt;em&gt;The Silver Fifty-Sen Pieces&lt;/em&gt;, by Kawabata Yasunari&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the 14th of August 2111&lt;/strong&gt;, the Atomic War began in a Chinese submarine in the South Pacific, and ended six hours later. The war marks the single greatest loss of life in human history and would disrupt human life on Earth in previously unimaginable ways — consumer society bottomed out, the world became small, the Earth grew cold, and a new chapter in human history was opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This political map marks the territories of Earth as they stand five years on, in 2116. There are fewer countries in the world today than in any other point in human history, in part because the catastrophic reduction in human population — some 520-600 millions in the first year — has emptied out countries and rendered others uninhabitable. Many of these territories here are disputed and, in some cases, autonomous — for simplicity, they are presented as they are recognised by the U.N.
The map also presents a long-exposure view of the war as it happened, and its remaining fallout currents today. Red dots mark significant nuclear detonations on August 14th. Yellow dots mark surface warfare in some capacity. Red trails mark missile flight, reduced in number here by strict denuclearisation treaties of the decades previous. Yellow trails mark the flight paths of atomic bombers, both supersonic and subsonic. This map does not record failed launches, intercepted missiles or downed aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fighting was arranged along political axes — namely Western (U.S., U.K., West Germany &amp;amp; N.A.T.O. members), Warsaw Pact (U.S.S.R., Cuba, Egypt), East Asian (China &amp;amp; Korea), and non-aligned (Vekllei, France, Brazil). The war experience was unique to each country — Vekllei exchanged warheads and bombs with China but not Warsaw countries, the U.S.S.R. exchanged with both Western and East Asian members, and Brazil fought a catastrophic war against both Soviet and American territories. The immediate aftermath saw a quiet Earth, much of it scorched. Temperatures dropped by 10 degrees centigrade for the first six months, and slowly warmed as debris cleared in the following years. Wide-scale firestorms were tempered by rains that followed the war shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some 274 millions of the dead are accounted for in China, where in 2116 the cities still lie in rot, swollen with corpses; heavy with miasma; concrete dams bleached and cracked; the wood all burned up; the rivers warped and quiet; dead fish along them; a surfaced water main weeping blood; harsh asbestine whistling; railcars in a ditch; sloughing skin; tremors; smoke with no fires; confused wandering; bleeding from the inside; families-as-sand; sand-as-trinitite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exchanges were confused, helter-skelter, and the combatants rattle off like a death snare. The U.S.S.R., the U.S., France, and Vekllei all exchanged death with China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would take more than mere annihilation to extinguish the P.R.C., but the toll was nauseating. Beijing and Shanghai were simply disappeared; there was nothing where there once was. The fistfuls of rebar and concrete amidst glassy, ossified landscape were heaped into direct administration of the U.N. The following year, 40-120 million more Chinese would succumb to the greatest famine in the history of the world. Of course, in the U.N., there was good argument for the nuclear retaliation — China launched first; why should money and food go to the perpetrator of the vastest disaster in human history? One can’t help but wonder if the life of an Oriental coolie wells fewer tears than his equivalent in Paris. There are not enough flowers in the world to pay tribute to the dead of China, who were simply dispensed with in European memory and subsumed in part by the United Nations. The communist party would continue to control the vast interior, divided into two states by ethnography, where 1949 seemed closer than ever. Necrotic politics are legitimised in the land of the dead.
Soon, we saw the consolidation of nation-states into geographic regions with a disregard for ethnography not seen since the colonial years. This was met with violent resistance in some places — in others, locals capitulated to the extraordinary hyperreality of the postwar world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Nations was quickly catapulted into the status of a de facto administrative world government in a last-ditch attempt to ‘freeze time’ as it were, in order to provide the superpowers time to recover from the scope of immediate devastation and prevent humanity from entering a long period of decline. This involved the moving of soldiers on a scale unseen since the World Wars, as U.N. international brigades propped up vulnerable, scorched territories in Central/Western Europe and Asia. The immediate peace of the first days after the war was ruthlessly enforced — and strategic opportunism was threatened to meet indiscriminate violence and U.N.-sanctioned nuclear retaliation. There was some belief that the status quo could carry on. So troops of non-combatant countries were supplied, and in some cases press-ganged, into this global mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battered United States, acknowledging its ‘century of decline’, found itself consolidating control over its urban, though devastated, coasts. The awkward appellation &amp;ldquo;Dallas America&amp;rdquo; was used as a colloquial shorthand for a disputed territory that insisted on referring to itself as the legitimate United States. The name was only superseded by the ridiculous &amp;ldquo;United Nations Heartlands of the United States,&amp;rdquo; the Aid Region of the U.S. interior that had collapsed in the days after the war. This was buffered by the Mojave and Great Lakes Special Administrative Regions, federal territories that contained war industry and nuclear infrastructure that propped up the precarious coasts. Despite efforts to revive agriculture in the scorched U.N. Heartlands U.S., starvation was met with martial law along the coasts the following year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.N. was granted temporary, direct control over several collapsed territories that had either succumbed to nuclear fire or had caved to anarchy in the weeks and months after. In some cases, like the U.N. regions in Hawaii, Jerusalem and the Central Europe International War Government, these behaved as states in themselves, administrated directly by the United Nations Mission for War Recovery. In others, they were merely named as such with the vague promise of future aid. U.N. Cuba and U.N. Taiwan were such examples, in which devastation had been so catastrophic that little remained to govern, and the local population was mostly left to anarchy. In general, there were great inequalities in how the U.N. chose to dedicate resources, largely informed by its largest nation-states and political interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of stories from communities and territories across the world directly impacted by the war — from the atomic bombing of Sydney to the catastrophic reactor meltdowns of Brazil’s south. The war was unprecedented in scale and devastation. This map reveals little of the profoundly human tragedy that was brought about, nor does it invoke the difficult existential artefacts that are still being reckoned with. Perhaps humans are just animals after all — destined to die out the way so many have in this age. Most tragic was not the colossal scale of death, or the collapse and pain that followed, but the upending of domestic society into violence, in which people of consumer society — the middle class — found themselves with not much at all, thrust into a world of chaos and suffering in which all prior epistemologies evaporated. Like the flash of blue light that preceded the roar, it was the stuff in supermarkets and department stores that marked the absolute grotesqueing of life in the new age.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2,000 members! WOW!</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ih3yvf/2000_members_wow/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m Hobart. I’ve been working on this project for a while now. It doesn’t really have a purpose or an end goal — I just want to draw and write about nice things, and I’m learning a lot on the way.
Welcome to everyone new here. I don’t really have anything to sell, I’d just like to thank you for tuning in and checking Vekllei out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve drawn Tzipora here as a sort of Sailor Moon knock-off. Good show that. The Japanese intro is very nostalgic, I’d love to do a little animated short in that style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I post about twice a week. I do a bit of everything — machines, maps, characters, landscapes, architecture, etc. I’m truly a master of none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can come join the Discord if you’d like — it’s just a quiet community to share interests and talk: discord.gg/dCE6vSU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I’ll keep doing what I’m doing and you can keep liking my stuff (please). If you have any questions about the project, or just want to introduce yourselves, here’s a good place to do it!
Thank you kindly to all commenters, readers and friends of the project, whether you’ve been here for years or for six hours — it’s very special to have so many people interested in work that’s so close to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on keeping on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Quiet</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/if77nc/absolute_quiet/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were plumes in the sky, sent from bunkers buried deep in the well of the Earth, killing with switches. Vekllei went to war, and so Tzipora went to war with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The throbbing machinery of another world began turning, and anyone who saw the bomb would hear it. Passing seconds dislocated and caught heartbeats. The plumes were pretty. It was such a shame, those plumes. It was a quiet afternoon in the flower-tundras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an absolute quiet among the grasses, and peace in her heart. She had work to do. She was a warden, after all — and she’d done a good job spotting the missile before the sirens caught up. In truth, any devastation seemed incomprehensible. The flower-tundra would last forever. But that was her job, and she had to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She left her bucket by the freshwater creek, intending to retrieve it a while later. The drinking water tasted better up here. She turned from the plume and followed the moss path out of the flower-tundra. Her village was before her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So ended the old ways and so started the new.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Newda in Rural Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/iavx9l/rural_newda_in_rural_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ed8zwv/life_and_death_in_vekllei_apartment_ideology_or/&#34;&gt;Newda is Vekllei’s national architectural ideology&lt;/a&gt;, applied flexibly in a range of modernist styles developed domestically in her architecture schools. Broadly, Newda buildings emphasise distinction from the surrounding landscape (called &lt;em&gt;Dumousiantopet&lt;/em&gt;, or ‘beautiful and seperate’), natural decay, and honesty in material and construction. Vekllei’s great Parliament House is Newda; as are the little rural homes found in the mountains inland in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora’s house in the village of Montre-Lola (&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.studio/newsroom/blog/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/&#34;&gt;as depicted on the map here&lt;/a&gt;) is built in what Vekllei calls “Azores revivalism”, a Newda style heavily influenced by the stripped deco and streamline moderne buildings of a century prior. It is part of a constant conversation Newda holds with its past, as both a deeply modernist, progressive school and one bound up in the wider aesthetic and cultural traditions of Upen, the spiritualism of Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her house is small, but appears larger due to the layout of the structure. A small sleeping loft sits atop the living, bathing and cooking areas of the home, and opens out into a private rooftop garden. The utilities tower also hides a small staircase leading to the roof, which is also accessible for outdoor recreation. Her home stands amidst the farmland of Montre-Lola, and very near the library and primary school where she works. Her property is marked at its end by a creek that runs into the Dentre River. She has a vegetable garden in her backyard, and shares her paddocks with her neighbours for grazing periodically throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her house was erected in gratitude by her neighbours out of prefab components, and assisted by a “construction line,” — a temporary rail line in which goods are delivered and cranes are supported, minimising the need for lorries. Houses of this type and period are rarely seen in agricultural settings in other countries, but in Vekllei, where Landscape has been abolished, there might as well be no difference between a building suitable for the cosmopolitan, coastal cities and a dwelling for a farmer-girl.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thousand-Year-Old Girl</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/i7tl9c/the_thousandyearold_girl/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The concept of living forever&lt;/strong&gt; jumps out at people uncomfortable with their own existence. There is a contemplative instinct among educated people that — if they could simply will themselves into a state of self-actualisation — death would only be an obstacle to greatness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Tzipora found out quickly, the opposite was true — death and temporality  were wells of meaning against which all great people, beauty, and human constructions were cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora Desmoisnes is what is known as a Gregori Baby, a catch-all term for a unique genetic condition that has seemingly produced a variety of miracle children appropriate for the frothing futurism of the atomic age — boys and girls who, suspended in the purity and good-naturedness of childhood — live forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no single “Gregori Baby” — each is unique, and Tzipora is the 13th to have been recognised overall. The phrase is a shortening of Gregori-Heitzfeld syndrome, a stand-in for medical information that isn’t there. The first, Gregori Hordiyenko, was born in 2024. He was healthy, and died of unrelated causes in his 20s. Tzipora, at 13th, continues to live to this day and is the oldest person on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a disturbing trend among the Gregori children, first heralded as miracles and symptoms of the space age, to deteriorate medically as more are born. The culprit is the malfunctioning of telomeres in their DNA — the source of their longevity — which regularly produce devastating chromosomal disorders, including Trisomy 13 &amp;amp; 18, killing most “ageless children” before their third birthday. Those that survive are often victims of a severe anaphylaxis caused by a hyperactive immune system — rendering many of them permanently sickly. Others find themselves unageing, but continue to grow — reaching as tall as 2.5m before their bodies give out from exhaustion and osteoporosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is Gregori syndrome? What does your average (healthy) Gregori baby look like? Their genetic miracle is linked to the structures of the body that activate at puberty, and so girls vary between 11-16 years of age at onset depending on many factors that affect their development. Boys tend to be a little younger, from 8-14. Between the two, girls tend to be more stable, and all but two of the supercentenarian Gregori children are female.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among girls, they are prepubescent and generally stop ageing on the eve of menarche, or their first period. In Tzipora’s case, her body is estimated to be 13 years and 11 months old. Unlike many Gregori children, Tzipora lives in a wealthy country and has volunteered for extensive research into her genetic makeup, meaning that much of early medical documentation around Gregori-Heitzfeld syndrome was received directly from her case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most obvious is that, at a foundational level, her cells are similar in function to unipotent stem cells, and have been since hormones at the end of thelarche suspended her ageing. This change has occurred somewhere in her DNA — exactly where is unknown — but the end result is that, unlike regular progenitor cells that make up most adult bodies, the building blocks of her body are capable of cell-renewal. Her telomeres, the endcaps of chromosomal DNA in mammals, are undamaged. And so there is an amazing shift in her basic human structure — in which human cell lineage, which usually ends in a mature cell incapable of division, is caught and rearranged. With this considered, it is no wonder that Gregori children suffer from such catastrophic chromosomal instability, and why healthy ageless babies are a rarity. Her body is not exactly a “body of stem cells,” but for their function in a healthy Gregori child, they might as well be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it is that nothing about Tzipora is changing. She suffers from pains in her legs often — called growing pains, although they are not from growing — and her cells continue to replenish, albeit at a rate 1.25 times that of normal people. She is, in essence, “growing” as any other premenarchal girl would, but she is not getting bigger or becoming older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is blessed with an adult life in Vekllei, where the “Child” does not exist as it does in the West, and her individual freedoms are far-ranging. She may smoke, and drink, and has held many different jobs in her life. She holds two doctorates in English and Vekllei Literature. She is obviously sterile — even if she were to somehow “age out” of prepubescence into pubescence and receive the required hormones, she simply lacks the genetic code to reproduce — but raises many children through her active participation in village life and her roles as Montre-Lola’s municipal and school librarian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other countries, with coded roles for children, their problems are much greater. Unable to form adult relationships and often incapable of finding work, many work in entertainment or fall into poverty as they outlive their friends and parents. Socially ostracised and forever young, many are victims of superstition and fear. As the pattern of Gregori children indicates an increase in mortality, even as more are born, their appearance is both a miracle and a tragedy — ageing not through mitosis but through weathering the societies in which they live.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 31st Century</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/i6528h/the_31st_century_vekllei_throughout_our_solar/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-epoch-of-rest&#34;&gt;The Epoch of Rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent a lot of time in the 21st century — but Tzipora is biologically immortal. Where does she go from here? Well, let’s enjoy a small glimpse at that future together, by winding the clock forward one thousand years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 3076, our Solar System is a pleasant place to be. Most of the planets we once gazed at from afar are now habitable and lived on. The Great Epoch of Rest has begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no great interstellar empire, no rise and fall of spacefaring supernations — a Vekllei way of life is now lived out in multicultural, prosperous clusters of people across our Solar System. The ordinary person is afforded incredible freedoms previously reserved for science fiction through the accessibility of personal light spacecraft, translated literally as “boats”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This here is the M-7000 APRICOT, manufactured by the Government Aerospace Factories (GAF) of Vekllei. Many companies are contracted by the GAF, including General Reactor S.A., to whom this boat lends most of its flight control systems and all of its power plant. It is a light, personal boat for women built in 2807, making it relatively unique in both its 28th century design language and its gendered marketing. While the personal boat market was growing rapidly by this time, the vast majority of owners and pilots were men. The APRICOT set out to change that, and Tzipora, the world’s oldest living person with a youthful face, was among the first to demonstrate the accessibility and freedoms of space travel for women and girls in the personal boat market. It was her first boat, and despite its orientation for women it was christened with a male name: BARON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a comfortable and pleasant craft that can be lived in for extended periods of time. Tzipora has done just that, travelling to stars in search of water-planets with Micronesian archipelagos, where she likes to spend most of her time. Its glass roof across the entire accessible cabin, including bubbled cockpit, gives it breathtaking visibility in the depths of space and the most scenic of planets alike. Like almost all spacecraft, it is unarmed, save for the pacifying “jazz” electric canon, named for its firing sound reminiscent of a double bass strum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she tires of being alone, she returns to her hometown of Montre-Lola in Vekllei frequently. Boats are usually parked at off-world stations, preserving the aerospace and quiet of the Solar System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light speed is exceeded through superluminal travel. So-called black boxes require extraordinarily precise programming, since superluminal travel is in all ways but name time travel, and the universe does not tolerate time travel. Coordinates calculated in the universal pyramid system by a pyramid computer ensure that a vessel arrives when it arrives, so to speak. The alternative is going nowhere at all — there is no in-between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Superluminal systems are affected by gravity, so any person looking to exceed the speed of light and subsequently visit other stars must take the highways beyond our home system’s planetary orbit and launch into so-called free-travel from there. There are only a handful of these highways — the solar system is very, very large, and human construction is very, very small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an instinct among many people that human progress would naturally scale exponentially — these were extrapolated from the remarkable progress in the lifetime of Tzipora’s parents and grandparents, who saw canvas aircraft in their childhood advance to the landing of a man on the moon, and again in her own exaggerated lifetime, in which the provinciality of her youth has simultaneously seen an expansion and exploitation of the planets in our native solar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This curve of progress was not to be, however — and it also explains why we had such trouble meeting aliens in the first place. Part of it was simply that there are very few worlds with water that also formed earthlike landmasses nearby — there are many aliens, and Tzipora has seen many herself, but most of them are fish and fish-adjacent. The second is that, if there is civilised life out there, it has most probably encountered the same engineering truths that humanity did, in our great interstellar project of the last thousand years. Namely that, all accounted for, there is no use for wasteful megastructures when a small one will do. People are having less children — on Mars, Mercury and Neptune, the population is actually shrinking. What good is the so-called “ocean liner of the stars,” with a capacity of millions? There are around 12 billion people across the solar system today. Maybe another 8 billion in the Ala system. Maybe a few millions more who have simply given up society for scattered stars in our neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is likely that if any other civilised races exist, they are simply of our scale, or have destroyed themselves completely in the reckless pursuit of expansion. Humanity is lucky not to count themselves among them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The APRICOT is one of many models produced by Vekllei’s Government Aerospace Factories. It is now possible for the ordinary person to explore distant stars for themselves, granting freedoms unimaginable in a previous age. Such is life in the Great Epoch of Rest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/i1fgjd/meet_tzipora_concept_panel_for_a_vekllei_comic/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;unique-among-girls&#34;&gt;Unique among girls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not &lt;em&gt;realise&lt;/em&gt; she is unusual, or does not &lt;em&gt;care&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has a lot of endearing characteristics that give great character to her mannerisms and physicality. She has a small overbite that makes her look a little froggy, and ritually pulls on her shirt and wipes her nose in anxious conversation. She is round-headed and cuts her hair herself. She talks in a low, expressive voice. She has been poorly socialised in childhood, and is afraid of casual conversation with people she does not know. She is keenly socially attuned and feels awkwardness painfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wears the same clothes two or three days in a row. The outfits themselves are variations of the same thing, and her tastes don’t change. Everything hangs off her — she likes baggy, airy clothing, and upsizes to accomodate. She doesn’t like fashionable or voguish people, whom she regards as decadent and offensive. To Tzipora, taste is timeless and bound to the soul. In her case, this fact has held true — she has dressed the same as childhood, and very little else has changed about her in that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is paranoid and conservative, good-natured and austere, with a moral outlook bound by her deepest anxieties and obsessions. She is deeply spiritual and material, fascinated with objects and their history. She has many collections of many things she’s found. She’ll likely die a Catholic, but has a confrontational relationship with God and no longer attends mass, as a declaration of humanism. She does not know if this has pissed Him off, but it’s working out so far. Maybe that’s why He made her a homosexual — to get back at her. He must have a good sense of humour, if that’s the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora may be intense and inward-facing, but she can also be disarmingly charming and self-deprecating. She has a good sense of humour. There are not many girls that can so easily reconcile the contradictions between the peculiar and the healthy, the eccentric and the friendly, and the violent and the domestic. That’s part of her character — an essence of being that radiates decency, good taste and a respect for the spirit of all things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer House in the Azores</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hyt68u/summer_house_in_the_azores/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Azores had been a possession of Vekllei since 2002, when they were leased from Portugal indefinitely. The lease was defunct by the time of Vekllei’s independence from U.K. occupation in 2015, and the new state took formal ownership over the small Atlantic islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Azores was Vekllei’s resort region, often called simply the “holiday isles”. Brief reprieves from the North Atlantic cold were granted to hundreds of thousands domestic tourists each year in resorts and holiday rentals alike. Tzipora spent the summer of 2079 there. Good memories were made in that summer. She did not much like the beach but she liked the ocean. If she could retire, it would be in the Azores.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Camp</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hupcer/base_camp/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a paint-sketch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Krafla high-energy communications tower was visible from all over the region. It provided uninterrupted radio to most of North Lava, and could relay signals through satellites. In another country, it might have been considered a blight on a pristine view — but in Vekllei, there was no such thing as pristine. It was as much a part of the landscape as the trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They started the fire first, figuring they’d have more enthusiasm for the tent when they were warm. Warm sunrays played on the field-grasses around them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora’s ‘Every Day Carry’</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hu6k92/tziporas_every_day_carry/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like a lot of girls of poverty&lt;/strong&gt;, Tzipora was very possessive of her things. No food was ever left on her plate. There was a deep anxiety that whatever wasn’t claimed would be lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was also naturally obsessive and material-oriented, keenly aware of the importance of objects measured by metrics in her own silly head. You can discover a lot about a person from their trinkets and toys — let’s discover a bit about Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Her handbag is manufactured by Spaa S.p.A., a design firm in the capital. They’re a luxury item in the international market but readily available in Vekllei, since few other handbag makers operate on the scale of Spaa. Ayn picked it out shortly after Tzipora’s arrival for its colour, after Tzipora told her she did not own any red things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tzipora has a sweet tooth. Especially for soda, which she calls “fizzy drink”. On her person at any time, she carries a flavoured beverage from one of several brands capable of meeting her discerning tastes. She supplements them with a water bottle, since not even fizzy drink refreshes as well as water after phys-ed or a hot day. She also stocks her arsenal of snacks with good fruit picked off trees that overhang footpaths, as well as devastating salvos of Vekllei’s finest confectionary, including Fruit Tingles and chocolate pearls. Other girls in her class bemoan her childish metabolism as she drinks soda for lunch while they watch the scales.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The nostalgic whimsy of the sweets is tempered by two or three loose cigarettes that float around in her purse at any given time. She’s not a regular smoker, but she’s prone to attacks related to stress, and nothing helps as much as a drag. She carries matches, for not much reason other than that’s what Baron uses, and Tzipora is notoriously sentimental.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tzipora has a rock collection that sits on her bedroom sill, and her recent additions sit at the bottom of her purse. She’s not a rock elitist; quartz from footpaths catches her attention as easily as igneous treasures like palagonite. Her favourite is obsidian.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She carries a small collection of useful books, including a contemporary paperback and a notebook. The paperback is for recess and lunch; the notebook is for language notes and phone numbers. Her Vekllei I.D. papers, which are both a passport and a reference booklet of key information and services, are carried on her at all times. It’s not really necessary in day-to-day life — but who knows when it might be, and Tzipora won’t be the one patting her pockets at the airport gate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, there are a few accessories sitting in the bag. Tzipora made a ring for Cobian in metalworking class, but Cobian is on a school trip to France at the moment and Tzipora is waiting for her return. She has a wristwatch given to her by Baron, which she wears sometimes depending on the occasion. Other items are more precautionary — a scarf for the wind, a handkerchief for sneezing, and a spare pair of socks for when she visits Cobian’s house or if she needs to double up in cold weather. As summer turns to autumn, she also carries gloves and a beanie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With everything in its place, her handbag is her anchor in the world outside her small second-floor apartment. The decommodification of society has only intensified the social value of objects, and they remain as important as ever in the life of the ordinary Vekllei person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Race for Inefficiency</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hpyyp1/the_race_for_inefficiency_veklleis_advocation_of/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;veklleis-advocation-of-austerity-apathy-and-playfulness-as-economic-principles&#34;&gt;Vekllei’s advocation of austerity, apathy, and playfulness as economic principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is about the economy of Vekllei. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a long one. If you have any questions, just ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;overview-of-the-bureau-system&#34;&gt;Overview of the Bureau System&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are many thousands of companies busy with work in Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;. The vast majority of these companies are single-person shops (S.p.A., or &lt;em&gt;senrouiva pettetie anaproiouya&lt;/em&gt;). Also common are wobbly shops, or co-operative businesses (S.q.A., or &lt;em&gt;senrouiva qualitie anaproiouya&lt;/em&gt;). The largest of the non-bureau companies are village factories (S.p.M., or &lt;em&gt;senrouiva persimonaya manufacturie&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bureau-level world is full of company mastheads that emphasise modernity, dynamism and progress. Vekllei’s “private businesses”, however, tend to be local in taste. The vast majority of S.p.A. and S.q.A. businesses bear the family names of their founders — Desmesyo S.p.A., Risyiouisnesn Home Machines S.q.A., etc. Their legal denominations are almost always affixed to the end of their nameplates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their &lt;em&gt;senrouiva&lt;/em&gt; designation marks them as non-bureau businesses. A &lt;em&gt;bureau&lt;/em&gt;, as a reminder, is simply the top-level organisation of a trade union that organises business in the country. In practice, it means that a company is responsible to the political organs of the country. Although independent from the government, bureau business is inextricably entwined in government concern and runs parallel to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Senrouvia&lt;/em&gt; businesses are also part of the bureau structure, but are in practice not managed directly by them. They are usually united in local concern by so-called &lt;em&gt;petty bureaus&lt;/em&gt;; small cooperative organs that safeguard local interest and business. These petty bureaus are often at odds with the bureau organs proper, and so even though they are part of the same structure, they are fundamentally political opposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is sort of business goes on in a bureau proper?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two common categories of so-called “bureau firms”. You have state industries (S.A., or &lt;em&gt;societie indastrie&lt;/em&gt;), which deal with manufacturing and exploitation of resources that require direct management by a public organ. You’ll already be familiar with several — General Reactor S.A., Comen Aeroyards S.A., Farmer’s Syndicate S.A. to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also have state requisites (A.r., or &lt;em&gt;requoisesiasn amourisocietie&lt;/em&gt;), which refer to the vast government-operated organs made up six categories primarily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilities (A.r.Un.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transport (A.r.R.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education (A.r.E.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local healthcare (A.r.F.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Construction (A.r.Lo.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation (A.r.M.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes — education is not organised as a government department, but a bureau business. Other state responsibilities are folded directly into government departments — war, intelligence, healthcare, police, fire, and the mint are all managed directly by the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;argument&#34;&gt;Argument&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the legal division of enterprise laid out, let us examine again the four precepts of the Vekllei economic ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-management and self-interest through Sundress Municipalism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification of property as an independent social organ, like nature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abolishment of currency and currency-substitutes. Participatory employment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Economic feminisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These four principles reveal a great deal about the character of the country, and stand largely at face value. There is an interest in chasing the promises of modernity while deconstructing its metaphysical constructions, through the abolishment of exchange-value, property and the overhaul of gender-economics. There are anarchist gestures in each principle, yet it is obvious that the product of these values complexify the conventional anarchist imagination. This is part of a series of contradictions — between free and planned markets, between internationalism and provinciality, between man and woman, between freedom and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;austerity&#34;&gt;Austerity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bureau system is plagued by inefficiencies, arising from logistic systems premised on warehousing, poor Coasean bargaining between petty bureaus and proper bureaus, a political emphasis on macroeconomic outcomes, a decoupling of aggregate demand and national economic output, cultural intolerance for Pareto inefficiencies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luxury goods often vary in both supply and access, and economies are often severely localised to the point of provincialism, meaning that Vekllei has failed to transition reliably to a modern consumer society. The inhabitants of the Montre borough most often eat seafood because speciality meats, especially authentic red meat, are scarce. The opposite is true in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/yana&#34;&gt;Yana&lt;/a&gt;. Clothes are repaired and regifted, appliances are available only from regional outlets usually located in the same city as the factory, and culture and diet are fiercely regional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is, in part, a result of unflinching national austerity and the sublimation of artificial markets prompted by Vekllei’s gold-based auxiliary currency, which necessitates meeting debt obligations for its strength internationally. There is a belief in Vekllei that the wealth of the country allowed the abolition of the currency — in fact, the opposite is true. The abolition of currency allows a permanent wealth that compensates for the inefficiencies of the bureau system. The bureau firms do not pay their workers — on paper, there are no expenses for anything beyond raw commodity exchange. This is how Vekllei’s largest companies — and, per the bureau system, its government — remain solvent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Austerity&lt;/em&gt; is a cultural force, too — the scarcity of luxury goods inflates their social value, where comforts and necessities are largely abundant in automation. It creates an unimportant hardship that keeps Vekllei people forward-facing, lean, and ambitious. To acquire Picco S.p.A.’s iconic lounge chairs, you have to travel to their outlet in Horn, hundreds of kilometres from the capital area. There is no motivation for a craftsman to meet demand — there is no petty consumption, either. To own a Picco chair means you have understood its cultural value, utility and craftsmanship, and have made the effort to find and transport one to your home. Inconvenience, and by extension, austerity, is celebrated as a “trial of ownership.” Objects are very important in Vekllei, and craftsmanship is highly valued, and so people like to surround themselves with hand-made, sublime things wrought not just by the labour of the artisan, but their own effort to acquire it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Petty &lt;em&gt;austerity&lt;/em&gt; instills a national sentiment that tells the ordinary Vekllei person they are hardier than the ordinary American or European, even if the wealth of the ordinary Vekllei person is much greater than that of the ordinary American or European.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;apathy&#34;&gt;Apathy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite a vast, loosely organised private market in the &lt;em&gt;senrouiva&lt;/em&gt; categorisation, Vekllei does not reward entrepreneurial ambition. Ambitious people are funnelled into positions of power in bureau firms and political office, but the founding of S.p.As and S.q.As is rarely motivated by a desire for influence or power. Indeed, artisanal S.p.As are often incapable of the sort of economies of scale needed for expansion. Vekllei instead relies on a sort of economic &lt;em&gt;apathy&lt;/em&gt;, in which aggregate demand and productivity are spurned for immediate interest and pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ensures that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;luxury products remain creative, personal works per Upen’s insistence on the symbiosis of labour and product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the private senrouiva market is not capable of threatening the provincialism of Sundress Municipalism, which might make a commodity universally accessible and threaten to introduce generic consumer society into Vekllei life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the private senrouiva market under petty bureau organisation does not threaten the organised de facto monopolies of the bureau companies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Vekllei has replaced the commodity with the object, then it is through economic apathy that they have ensured objects will never again become commodities. Just as the ordinary Vekllei person is apolitical, so too are they apathetic towards change in their purchasing habits, favouring small, inconvenient and personal brands over those exploiting aggregate demand. In a sense, this also contributed to the popular Vekllei term &lt;em&gt;product atheism&lt;/em&gt;, in which the metaphysics of products are dismantled and rearranged into social forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, the &lt;em&gt;apathy&lt;/em&gt; is found on both ends — within the &lt;em&gt;senrouiva&lt;/em&gt; business owner, who is provided little upward mobility to satisfy ambition beyond local and regional expansion, and within the consumer, who recognises products only within cultural and social dimensions. Neither is conducive to a functioning, fair market on an interregional scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;play&#34;&gt;Play&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Play&lt;/em&gt; is the foundational motivation of most work in Vekllei. There are existential motivators, too — a desire to wield power, or professional legacy — but in many professions it is &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt; by which a Vekllei person justifies labour. It is also why work is fiercely protected by petty bureaus and other labour organisations — work is their connection to wider society, and that connection is held sacred in Upen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is through work as &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt; that Vekllei is able to justify the employment of children. Financial motivations for work have all but disappeared — in its place, the workplace has to convince people to work. There are few state protections for businesses unable to maintain a workforce, either — it is one of the most common reasons for the shuttering of a company. The boss must convince his workers to stay, and so a total inversion of power has occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In place of money, there is prestige, and in prestige there is myth. Few people have genuine interest in Fordism. Many more are attracted to the hand-crafted furniture of Picco S.p.A., and becoming recognised as a builder of great things. In a sense, a person “acts out” the role of a craftsman, in the same way a person “acts out” the role of a police officer, or “acts out” life as a pilot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this system, the childish spirit of recreation, duty and “the adult world” is acted out by millions of Vekllei people each day. Seeds planted by a child play-acting as a farmer continue to grow, and so too does the Vekllei economy feed its population through the intersection of fantasy and labour. At this point it is obvious that &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt; is not fantasy at all, but in fact a motivation for labour as genuine as profit. Where it falls short, in hard, disempowering jobs, it is automated and conscripted through the mandatory service system. As it is often described:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The &lt;em&gt;Bureau System&lt;/em&gt; is labour-intensive where wanted, alleviated by industrial machinery where preferred, and automated where necessary.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its wake are states of &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt;, and through play comes a decent framework for living, obvious in the basic satisfaction of the Vekllei people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hmz7af/police_in_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or &lt;em&gt;venopor&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or &lt;em&gt;cosmopor&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A young &lt;em&gt;venopor&lt;/em&gt; officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike &lt;em&gt;cosmopor&lt;/em&gt;, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance. They are special units of special purpose, and supplement the deficiencies of local policing through their training and tactical deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are police insofar as they protect and respond to their community, including through special tactics situations, but are paramilitary in their wider function as a defence force for critical infrastructure. This is reflected in their history, traced cleanly back past independence and the Atomic War to the royal guards and junta federal police of old society, which continue to be reflected in their uniforms and several other ceremonial artefacts, like swords and knee boots. &lt;em&gt;Venopor&lt;/em&gt; is a complex organisation with many different purposes. There are street patrols, pictured here, but there are also intelligence units associated with HO/NI and by extension the military, as well as tactical response teams, bomb squads, search and rescue and most other specialised emergency units outside of the capabilities of any given local police station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is contrast to the &lt;em&gt;cosmopor&lt;/em&gt;, a more conventional police outfit. A &lt;em&gt;cosmopor&lt;/em&gt; officer stands on the right, in standard summer uniform. He carries a radio, revolver and rubber baton for the worst of his duties, and is embedded deep into his local community. &lt;em&gt;Cosmopor&lt;/em&gt; officers traditionally visit and introduce themselves to each house in their beat, and spend far more of their time mediating, counselling and organising than they do making arrests. The autonomy of most Vekllei communities largely spurns petty legal proceedings, and so the &lt;em&gt;cosmopor&lt;/em&gt; are a critical aspect of sundress municipalism, resolving disputes personally and taking custody of a person only when it’s needed. Most crime in Vekllei tends to be emotionally motivated — so it is in this domain that &lt;em&gt;cosmopor&lt;/em&gt; navigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the &lt;em&gt;cosmopor&lt;/em&gt; especially powerful figures in a Vekllei village or township, but their duties are closely watched. While the Vekllei village may be autonomous, all officers in Vekllei are responsible to a division of &lt;em&gt;venopor&lt;/em&gt; called “officer welfare,” or picosec, which operates autonomously to seek out incompetent or misbehaving police officers, no matter their jurisdiction or status. Where most business in Vekllei has very little in the way of professional behaviour or “work culture”, policing in Vekllei is held to high standards, and they are severely bound by traditions that have become codified as the country has grown. This is a time and place where the children of police often inherit the jobs of their parents, and the constables of a village often have roots that go back centuries. This often makes &lt;em&gt;cosmopor&lt;/em&gt; very respected figures, and their successors and recruits are expected to work for that respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a country that has done away with money as a measure of success, professional legacy is profoundly important in Vekllei. In this inversion of priority, teachers, doctors, pilots, constables and librarians are celebrated. This is not founded in a general egalitarianism, but in fact the precise opposite — a celebration of success and influence, touching the lives of those around them. The glamour, and paycheque, has largely been stripped away. Only the work remains, and so that work has become more important than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is This Project?</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hiow8c/what_is_this_project/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Vekllei?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi, I’m Hobart and I write and draw Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; at Studio MillMint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty complex project. Not just complex insofar as there’s a lot to read about it, but that it uses concepts and terminology you might not be familiar with if this is your first time around utopian fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Vekllei is a utopia — what does this mean? It’s latin for “no place,” and I use that literally. Vekllei, in a literal sense, cannot exist. Not because I think it could never have existed, or that some part of it is completely unreasonable, or it breaks the laws of physics — but because it exists in a certain place and time that is just isn’t replicable. It’s all built from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is a very good place to live, &lt;strong&gt;but it is not perfect&lt;/strong&gt;. Utopia does not mean “perfect place”. Utopia is a form of social dreaming, much like worldbuilding, linked to the values and priorities of its author. In utopian studies, “utopia” is usually broken down further:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eutopia&lt;/strong&gt; — “good place”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dystopia&lt;/strong&gt; — “bad place”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that both form a part of the “utopia” — this is appropriate, since Vekllei is grounded in a social realism that acknowledges the good and bad parts of life. Indeed, they are inseparable — you cannot have the light without the dark. Obviously, in my eyes, Vekllei is very much a eutopia.
You can read more about Vekllei (the country) by clicking here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three parts to my “social dreaming”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landscape&lt;/strong&gt; — the world and country of Vekllei. When you think of “utopia,” this is it — shining modernist cities against striking landscapes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Character&lt;/strong&gt; — not all social dreaming takes place in spaces. Some of it is built around experiences, objects and relationships. Tzipora is a “character utopia” in the sense that she represents a utopian life experience, full of stories good and bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt; — Vekllei is a representation of the problems of my life, as a form of escapism. A lot of my posts here reflect dissatisfactions and displacements in my own life — consumer society, commodification of childhood, wage labour, postmodernism, etc. I’m very much a part of this utopian dialectic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s run through some of the common queries and misunderstandings about Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are you?
&lt;em&gt;A Tasmanian illustrator.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re not Japanese?
&lt;em&gt;お前はもう死んでいる&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is Vekllei a utopia?
&lt;em&gt;It makes me feel better about my life and the world. It’s escapism; it’s a dream.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a bit cringe to grandstand your political beliefs, doncha think?
&lt;em&gt;Vekllei is a personal utopia. That’s what I’m selling. At least you’re getting good opinions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where’s the tension if it’s perfect?
&lt;em&gt;Vekllei is very cynical and tragic in places. Utopia is just a reflection of the author, good and bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a novel? A story? A comic?
&lt;em&gt;I’m working on a comic right now. I’m pretty much working on Vekllei full-time so I’m hoping to announce it soon. I’ve got a lot of different Vekllei projects going.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is Vekllei?
&lt;em&gt;Iceland.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does Vekllei look Japanese?
&lt;em&gt;Vekllei is like a country of Scandinavians speaking French with an Aussie accent in Shōwa era Japan/Maoist China/Taiwan etc. Vekllei looks however I imagine utopia looks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does that make sense?
&lt;em&gt;Why can’t it just be cool?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your alt-history thought out?
&lt;em&gt;Vekllei’s history is whatever I need it to be. I’m always trying to be realistic, but it’s all worked backwards from the setting. I’m not really “worldbuilding” in a typical sense. Very little of it is published, most of it is retrieved on request. Just ask if you have questions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Vekllei communist?
&lt;em&gt;No.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Vekllei calls itself “petticoat socialist”.
&lt;em&gt;Vekllei is set in a culture of Marxist revivalism in the 50s and 60s. A lot of Vekllei’s lexicon is set in that context. Vekllei is a decentralised democracy that doesn’t use money. It’s a sort of participatory economy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why the &amp;ldquo;petticoat&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;em&gt;Vekllei is a female country. Womanhood is decommodified. It&amp;rsquo;s maternal, social and friendly where socialist rhetoric is masculine, technocratic and progressive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is Zelda?
&lt;em&gt;Zelda is another name for Tzipora. She has two names specifically to confuse you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the “bulletin”?
&lt;em&gt;I publish the Atlantic Bulletin once a month via email. It’s got the month’s posts in it as well as facts and tidbits from Vekllei. DM me an email if you want to join.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Map of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/h8tskh/a_map_of_vekllei_100_boroughs_100_hearts/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Map Key&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red&lt;/strong&gt;: Magjet trains, 750km/h&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yellow&lt;/strong&gt;: Bullet trains, 300-400km/h&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orange&lt;/strong&gt;: Regional trains, &amp;lt;150km/h&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brown&lt;/strong&gt;: Local trains, including limited express, &amp;lt;100km/h&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blue&lt;/strong&gt;: National highway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dashed&lt;/strong&gt;: Ferry line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green&lt;/strong&gt;: tarmacadamed airport&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The largest division of any portion of Vekllei land is the borough&lt;/strong&gt;; a region of varying size and population with common culture, food dependency and economic interest. Anything larger than that is simply Vekllei — they are “one city”, after all, and consider themselves a city-state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been exactly 100 boroughs since 2015. Each is named after the largest city in its region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The smallest borough is &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/bakur&#34;&gt;Bakur&lt;/a&gt;, in Afouismeh, with a population of 7,500 people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The largest is Vekllei proper, in the Capital Region, of 2.4 millions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This transit map illustrates all 100 boroughs, Vekllei’s five tallest mountains, its permafrost glaciers and Tzipora’s home in Montre-Lola. Her five largest boroughs — namely Vekllei, Lonne, Adouisneh, Montre and Copette, are highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in this simple transit map we can see several truths about the country, like its population bias on the West Coast and the emptiness of the Lava volcanic region. You might recognise a few names there, like Lola in the West (Tzipora’s home with Baron) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/yana&#34;&gt;Yana&lt;/a&gt; in Vekllei’s Ro Highlands (Ayn’s birthplace).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trains are clean, reliable, fast, efficient and safe. They are incorporated under &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/cr65zu/the_people_of_veklleis_railway_plus_dog/&#34;&gt;Vekllei Rail&lt;/a&gt;, owned by the Transport Group Bureau. Using this map, designed for domestic tourists and foreigners, the adequacy of Vekllei’s rail transport is easy to plan around — you can eat breakfast in a cafe in the seaside town of Mumen, and hike before midday on the glacial slopes of Askayoisn. Since there are no tickets or costs, there are no excuses for not visiting relatives in the country, now that transport is now a trivial inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each borough is represented in Vekllei’s parliament by an elected representative. These representatives wield extraordinarily disproportionate power — the representative for Callaisn, for example, represents hundreds of times more people than the representative for Tanger, but both have the same vote. This is because boroughs are not just representative of their populations, but also their environments, industry and other social organs otherwise unable to vote. It is important to keep in mind that Upen (and consequently, policy) recognises the landscape itself as the sovereign organ of the country, and so in this sense it has its own interests and projections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, representatives act in an advisory, nonpartisan role in government, voting rarely in an auxiliary role to the professionalised, elected legislature. Vekllei has a strictly constitutional parliament, and the economy largely prohibits interference. In this sense, the parliament is both partially undemocratic in its inefficiency and apolitical in its orientation as a sort of civil service bureau, managing state affairs and reacting to pressures and the long-term aims outlined in the 2015 constitution. In the Vekllei mindset, the “government” is more or less another bureau, no different or particularly more interesting than the Transport Group Bureau. The trains, at least, have a tangible impact on their daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How appropriate, then, that this transit map produced in the summer months of 2076 combines both monuments of society. It also offers a glimpse of a larger, documented country not necessarily revealed in piecemeal story posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Crown</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hel2m7/the_vekllei_crown_coins_of_a_moneyless_country/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency&lt;/strong&gt;. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country. At no point do coins or paper currency change hands in the day-to-day affairs of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, Vekllei is usually described as “moneyless” — yet it does in fact have a currency. The Vekllei Kroner, or “Crown,” is hundreds of years old, and Vekllei still operates a mint for currency. At any time, a Vekllei person can write to the National Mint and order a set of coins, like the ones pictured above. So what is going on here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Kroner has not been used since 2022, after the last village in Stochi returned coinage to the Mint, it continues to exist to this day as a gold-backed currency in the International Market, through which Vekllei trades with other countries. The physical coins, produced mostly as a novelty in the tradition of &lt;em&gt;mayaesdiou&lt;/em&gt; (medallions, or small metal pieces commonly collected and given in Vekllei), are a physical coinage of the International Market. The coins also operate as a form of bullion, or wealth reserve, since each coin is worth exactly its face value in gold. Since the International Market is completely closed and independent of the domestic economy, its value is controlled directly by the so-called Government Bank. It is one of the few gold-backed currencies in a developed nation today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further complicate things, there are actually two different Kroner in Vekllei. There is the &lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Kroner&lt;/strong&gt;, which represents the International Market, but there is also a seperate &lt;strong&gt;Government/State Kroner&lt;/strong&gt;, which is not minted and used only as an investment mechanism, backed by government &amp;ldquo;white bonds&amp;rdquo; which are usually measures of labour-hours or refined materials. It is, in a sense, a fiat currency alongside a gold-backed currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They exist independently because they are used for two seperate purposes. The Vekllei Kroner is used a wealth reserve and bullion, and also represents the collective wealth of the Vekllei people. Each citizen, in theory, is entitled to an equal share of the Government Bank, although it can only be withdrawn as currency in specific circumstances. Vekllei also holds substantial amounts of foreign currency in the Government Bank and Vekllei Kroner, which is used to invest and stabilise holdings and capital in foreign countries. The Government Kroner, on the other hand, is used as an investment mechanism abroad, usually in support of infrastructure. It is also used to acquire foreign currencies through investment in foreign capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having two currencies, neither the &amp;ldquo;Vekllei Crown&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Government Crown&amp;rdquo; are used in the domestic economy in Vekllei, which is autonomous and not subject to a central bank. So it is that Vekllei’s currency is both little more than a novelty and essential to the function of the country in a world still ruled by money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the coinage depicted above — 8 coins are minted in Vekllei today.&lt;/strong&gt; They were designed in 2015, in the year of independence. They represent eight core values in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “small crowns,” worth 1VK and 10VK respectively, represent fraternity and liberty, two founding elements of the Vekllei constitution. The 50VK coin is plated in silver and has a small ruby inset. Rubies are used to represent energy, in this case, the vitality of the spirits, which dominate Upen and the Vekllei landscape. The 100, 200, 500 and 1,000VK coins represent different landscapes of the country. As a volcanic island nation, the ocean (100) and landscape (200) coins are fairly straightforward. The humanity coin (500) represents the Vekllei people and ancestry — note how humans are placed alongside other natural forces. The flower coin (1,000VK) represents the flowers of the country, which are important spiritually and have formed part of the Vekllei identity. Vekllei has the most flowers per capita in the world. The final, larger 10,000VK coin represents the previous seven together, as a total sum of Vekllei landscape and identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer Tzipora’s question — a bottle of fizzy drink cost about 2VK in the waning days of coinage in the early 2020s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Village Map of Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/hhjytf/village_map_of_montrelola/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The village of Montre-Lola&lt;/strong&gt; is home to about 400 people in its entirety, a stone’s throw from the Aisyo borough. Each morning, however, the population swells as 300 children from tiny villages in both Aisyo and Montre take a fast tram to the Montre-Lola Area School No. 2, a district school raising all ages of local youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many Vekllei villages, Montre-Lola’s history is complex and has origin stories in both viking-inuit settlement as well as less sentimental government programmes that flourished after the atomic war. By historical accounts, Montre-Lola has been inhabited since at least 1500CE. By contemporaneous records, however, it was established as a village in land reform during the 1960s and revitalised by the building of the area school in 2057.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Montre-Lola features many civic objects common to Vekllei villages — a nondenominational place of worship (in this case, a historical Catholic church), a constabulary, a doctor, an auto/tractor pool, a general store, a station platform, and a village hall. A map of the village centre is dominated by the Area School, built in an Edunewda style, which features many new facilities that distinguish it from smaller, 20th-century schools. It’s a good place to grow up; where farmland and earnest modernity collide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Montre-Lola is most relevant as the residence of Tzipora Desmoisnes, the world’s oldest person and one of the first people to be diagnosed with Gregori-Heitzfeld Syndrome. She works as a librarian in both the Montre-Lola Area School and the Montre-Lola Library &amp;amp; Archives, spending most of her 12-hour workday in either of these institutions. She commutes via fast trams, which arrive automatically at the two platforms in Montre-Lola every half-hour and continue out into the surrounding farms. This means that, if she sets her watch right, she can step outside her front door and arrive at the school library in under ten minutes. This journey is marked in red on the map above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dominated by farmland, Montre-Lola is communal and more traditionally ‘anarchist’ in flavour than Vekllei’s urban boroughs, which are obscured by convenience. As charming as it is suffocating, the community is very close-knit and made up of all sorts — smart educated young men and women sent from Montre to teach, as well as farming families that have resided here for centuries. Life moves slower and people know each other. When the school hosts its cross-country race each year, nearly every person in the village is out to watch it. After all, it takes a village to raise a child.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Most Beautiful Woman</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/h1480l/a_most_beautiful_woman/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn&lt;/strong&gt;, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture. Tzipora was not quite sure how to describe it. Her beauty was very alive in the way she inhabited a space, as she walked into the hotel lounge to meet them. Maybe it was grace — maybe it was a little girl-crush — she didn’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Baron greeted her and they exchanged cheek kisses, it appeared to Tzipora that Ayn and Baron were old friends, and she was further assured in her respect for him — that Baron could know such beautiful women seemed natural! Baron was capable of anything in Tzipora’s eyes, a figure of ultimate power — it only made sense that he knew this woman!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, both Ayn and Baron were mortal, and Tzipora got to know them well during the helter-skelter weeks following her arrival in Vekllei. Baron might have rescued her, but it was Ayn who introduced her to Vekllei, as AB/NI called Baron into office for the first time in a decade. It was Ayn who took her clothes shopping and wrestled with Zelda’s obsessive-compulsive fabric requirements. It was Ayn who taught Tzipora her first Vekllei sentence. And in the end, it was Ayn who convinced Baron that he had to take responsibility for Tzipora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only years later that Tzipora began to realise that Ayn and Baron were, in a sense, married to each other through their work. They worked closely (he as recent head of operations at AB/NI, she as a research analyst in American economics) and their friendship went back decades. She was his “work wife,” which was the closest Baron could ever get to that particular institution, and so her proximity and love towards Tzipora made her a mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was a vision of everything Tzipora wanted for herself — to be capable and respected; beautiful and unassuming; intelligent and productive. And once more, it was Ayn, in the end, who convinced Tzipora that she could these things for herself, regardless of her genetic disability. “Go out there,” is what she said, “and trust in yourself.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oa-Class Battlecruiser</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gx7l0c/the_oaclass_battlecruiser/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei’s defensive military posture has&lt;/strong&gt;, in doctrine and arms development, limited its ability to meaningfully project power outside of the Atlantic. As an island nation with a large and multifaceted naval armada, the Oa-Class Battlecruiser is the heart of her armed forces, as the flagship of her fleets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where U.S. doctrine places carriers offensively in the structure of its ship-groups, the Vekllei Navy is considerably more Soviet in its employ of carriers as primarily defensive air-bases to exercise sovereignty over her far-flung territories and island possessions. Oa-class Battlecruisers are notable as hybrid carrier-battleships, and feature a diagonal jetway with capacity for carrier-type naval jets (almost indistinguishable in the illustration above) and a variety of VTOL aircraft, which are common by the 2050s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First built in the 2050s by the sprawling National Naval Arsenal (located on Vekllei’s Far East coast, close to the foundries that pour her iron), 12 Oa-Class Battlecruisers are in service in the 2070s. They carry heavy fission reactors built by bureau monopoly General Reactor, supplemented by a gas-turbine generator, as is standard on all Vekllei-built nuclear vessels. Her unusual serpentine funnel is characteristic of Vekllei’s navy, and is a distinguishing feature of their naval design language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her hulking superstructure and massive 15-inch fore guns recall the capital battleships of yesteryear, but she is a thoroughly modern battlecruiser with contemporary armament and electrics for combat and fleet administration. Named after Vekllei’s National flower, these Battlecruisers are the third-largest vessels in the navy and are multifunctional by design, often operated as strategic and operational platforms to support Vekllei’s large defensive armadas that patrol the North Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is armed with two triple-barrelled 15-inch shore guns that can be loaded with a variety of shells including nuclear payloads, silos for guided missiles, and specialised guns and missile platforms for anti-ship, submarine and satellite warfare. Her powerful communications array and sensors are positioned 80 meters above the surface for the benefit of radar and subsurface monitoring. She can also support up to 12 standard carrier jets at one time, or 16 individual helijets/VTOL craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has larger battlecruisers (the so-called super-battlecruisers match her height and are nearly twice her length) and much larger carriers, but the displacement of the vessel was never a priority. Vekllei’s naval architecture prioritises mobility and capability in their capital ships, and so the Oa-class vessels represent many intersecting vertices of Vekllei’s naval doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canal Living</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gva5mi/canal_living/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad. Nothing was trucked. Fish was traded fresh in markets or turned into emulsifiers and fertiliser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canals were worked heavily, and few fishing vessels were incorporated. The vast majority of Vekllei’s fishing fleet was owned by the people that worked them, trading with the Sea Office. From a &lt;em&gt;quaisiosn&lt;/em&gt; or “canal park” you might see a dozen vessels in an hour. Some were run-down prewar things limping out to the shallow coasts, while others were nuclear-powered salmon trawlers designed for the storms of the Atlantic. On the northern coast, the bigger boats were reinforced as ice-breakers. Fish was one of the few meats in the Vekllei diet that wasn’t grown in an industrial laboratory, a fact reflected in the scale of its infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canals are good for a city, and are good for the heart. Tzipora would take long walks in the morning along the Wellington Canal to where it met Touismah, then follow it to where it circled back into Lola. She would figure out what she was doing with her life as the boats departed for the day’s catch. She never much liked salmon, but she liked the boats. They were an island country, and their futures and pasts met in the sea — where it churned and swelled in their dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fission Cloud at Vekllei&#39;s 50th Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gu0nwj/fission_cloud_at_veklleis_50th_anniversary/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In an unprecedented event,&lt;/strong&gt; during Vekllei’s 50th Sea Festival since Independence in 2065, an 8 kiloton fission bomb was sunk to a depth of 150 meters and detonated at midday. It was an incredible sight on a day so clear you could see the gentle curve of the earth where it met the horizon. A flash of light and a spray dome surged outwards into the quiet Atlantic, which was broken apart by plumes that formed a column of water that climbed high into the sky. The lateral plumes, the “mushroom”, reached far across the horizon, forming thick clouds that would begin to rain into the sea.  From the coast, fifteen kilometres away, a warm light bathed observers and was followed a moment later by a bang that deeply shook you and those around you. In this instance it seemed that the whole universe was their domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plume would rise nearly 1,500 metres into the sky before falling away. It stayed that way for a while. Almost nobody moved for a long time after — people stood on cars and tables. You could only recognise the scale and the feeling of the fission bomb by seeing it in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed incomprehensible, in the face of such a device, that wars could still be fought at all. What use is a battleship in the face of a cloud like that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora and Elise, covering the detonation for Lola 7th School’s student newspaper, found themselves not quite sure what to say. Elise wrote, captioning Tziproa’s photograph, “The Independence bomb filled our sky with our sea for a half-hour on Sunday, and with it rose the thoughts of every person in attendance, who considered the awesome power now shouldered by each of us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was indeed some sense that they had contributed to the bomb, and that they had more at their disposal. Few would fly the planes to deliver them, and fewer still had the brains to develop them, but participating in a nuclear century contributed to, in some effect, a nuclear horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rain in the Arctic Circle</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gqy57h/hot_rain_in_the_arctic_circle/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tzipora had been ejected&lt;/strong&gt; from the operations room once the guys arrived. She knew what was going down, anyway. No specifics. But you didn’t bring in uniformed soldiers for regular business. National Intelligence liked to work with their own people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five days prior, Baron hailed an EB/NI company car and it pulled up beside him. The electric passenger window slid down. Baron nodded at the passenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everything’s in here. There’s more if you need it. I’d appreciate a call, I’m in my office all next week, okay?” He passed over a white postage envelope. “Take care.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The British man opened the letter and read it twice as the car approached the Vekllei World Jetport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JULES WYNN IS YOUR 3RD MAN. “JEREMY” APPEARS IN ARCHIVES 2046 — ALMOST CERTAINLY WYNN. NEARLY 20 YEARS. NOTES TO USSR THRU CYPHER CLERK (UNKNOWN). RECALLED TO MOSCOW — GREAT SUSPICION OF HIM FROM CONTROLLER DOWSETT-CLARK (OXFORD). THIS IS GOOD INFO FROM PARIS ASSET. WYNN WILL DIE IN RUSSIA. GET HIM AND ANOTHER RING SURFACES. CIA KNOWS WHERE BUT NOT WHO. DO US BOTH A FAVOUR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora went for a walk to clear her head. She had a lot going on in her life — though she was sure it seemed small compared to whatever was going on in the operations room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It began to rain an hour into the walk. She’d left her umbrella with the rest of her things in Baron&amp;rsquo;s office. That was okay. She didn’t mind the shower, anyway — it was mid-summer, and the rain was warm. What a novelty that was, at 60 degrees north. This was weather from the sunny Azores, pulled north by the wind currents over the Atlantic. Within minutes her skirt was heavy and her camisole was showing at the shoulders. She blinked heavy streams of water out of her eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She passed the soldiers on their way out as she returned to AB/NI reception. A friendly receptionist had cloaked her in a towel by the time Baron had found her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Did you have a good meeting?” She asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sure,” and characteristically, he considered that a satisfactory answer. He pulled the towel off her head. “You’re completely soaked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It doesn’t matter. Are you with those guys? About that other guy?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Watch it,” he said. “Keep that talk past security. But I’m going to fly out tomorrow. I’ll be back in the evening.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No cooking for me, then. Where are you going? Or can’t you say?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“England.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh,” Tzipora said, forming a gun with her fingers. “Like James Bond.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her life was a nexus of various global ambitions, it seemed — imagined only through the dreamy lens of a teen-ager too small for the world’s problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gndpwo/the_last_train_out_of_ada/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform.&lt;/strong&gt; And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables. Out here, you paced life around the station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was not much to say about this, between the two of them. Tzipora looked at Cobian and pulled a froggy smile that tried to express that it was nobody’s fault. Sure — it was Tzipora who had misplaced her purse, and it was also true that it was Tzipora who’d stopped by the orchard to steal a peach, but as to how they’d missed the train? It was simply impossible to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’re a complete idiot,” Cobian said matter-of-factly, and Tzipora wilted. They watched 416 trundle into the sunset. A picturesque vision of rural utopia — if only they were a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gkuij7/winter_uniforms_in_vekllei/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months&lt;/strong&gt;. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, by late October, the the earth is hard with cold and the days are short. The world may be warmer, but Vekllei’s polar latitude is unchanged, and in the depths of winter the sun only rises for an hour a day. These are Vekllei’s “moon months”, and they announce some of the most important spiritual festivals in Upen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although school hours are reduced in winter, life carries on and Vekllei fashion becomes traditionally utilitarian. Tzipora has poor circulation and cold hands even in the warm months, and by November she’s traded the skirt and gi for traditional &lt;em&gt;rouisha&lt;/em&gt; trousers and a cloak. &lt;em&gt;Rouisha&lt;/em&gt;, like a lot of traditional clothing, have origins in agriculture and are characterised by a loose, baggy fit and insulated lining. Cobian is wearing a heavy wool sack-type dress, which is worn like an apron over other clothing. Winter brings forth “petticoat society” literally. Note the leather &lt;em&gt;plate&lt;/em&gt; on her shoulder, to which her &lt;em&gt;christmas aiguillette&lt;/em&gt; is attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, Winter’s revival of traditional clothing and customs further evidences its practice as the most traditional season of the year. Although the warm calendar flourishes with the futurist sympathies of a modernist Vekllei, not even the atomic age has been able to dispense with its hard-worked pragmatism developed in a millennia of bitter cold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031 Apartment Diagram</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gjpcha/2031_apartment_diagram/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baron had inherited the apartment&lt;/strong&gt; from his uncle, who passed in the year following his parents. It was in a mixed residential-industrial neighbourhood, adjacent to a canvas factory. Out back was a rivulet, which roared in the long rainstorms of early April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each January, the Colour Bureau of the Architecture Assembly announces the year’s colours, and tradition in mainstream architecture and interior design is to incorporate the announced palettes, which usually contain a hundred or so colours. His uncle’s apartment had been built and furnished in 2031, and so it had a #2031 Colour Profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways, it was a very conventional apartment in the Vekllei tradition. It had a sauna and bath in the wetroom, a bidet, a sunken living room and a bread oven. In others, it was more peculiar. The apartment was bizarrely allocated across three levels. You alighted the entrance light well into a sunken living space, then climbed back up into the kitchen. The main living room and master bedroom were another step above the kitchen. Adjacent to the main living area was a closet and study, which overlooked the entrance from a half-meter mezzanine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was in this study that Tzipora set up shop when she arrived in March 2063. Baron had been reluctant to take her even provisionally, not least because it would mean searching for a new apartment in his busy return period after being abroad for ten years. Tzipora, however, had lived in a dormitory for much of her life and had settled in the alcove once she acquired a dresser screen. She refused outright the master bedroom, which sparked a sleepy agoraphobia. By the time Baron had made other accomodations, Tzipora had entrenched herself in the neighbourhood and had developed a severe sentimentality about the apartment and its rivulet, and so that was where he lived for the rest of his life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, Tzipora had a strange kinship with the apartment. Baron sealed himself off in the master bedroom each night, but she never left the main living space. It was warm in there, especially in the flickering light of the enormous oven and fireplace, and when she moved the screen aside in the morning her little corner became part of the living area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had a lot of good memories of that apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Tzipo-stcards</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gide8n/announcing_tzipostcards/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone. &lt;strong&gt;Just a little update&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How many cards will the set contain?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m aiming for about six cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think about $20 over your pledge lifetime would cover print and shipping, though I’ll let you know if that goes up or down. I’m hoping to cover shipping, so you’ll just need to supply an address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I haven’t yet pledged enough?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a Patron who hasn’t yet pledged the $20 or whatever it is to cover print and shipping, just contact me and I’ll make… alternative arrangements for you. Don’t worry — if you want the cards, you won’t miss out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who would even want these?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who like cute 6x4” illustrations on nice card stock will like them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a good time to plug my Patreon if you’ve got some government stimulus bux floating around — &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt;. It produces enormous pressure for me to create new work and art, so if you’re a fan of what I do it’s a good way to position yourself as an investor and get on my ass about posting more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of posts, there’s one coming tomorrow or the day after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks always, and best wishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiery Peaks</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gel3e9/fiery_peaks/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After three days in Ada, Tzipora set off towards Mt Miya. She made good time, and after three hours had happened upon the shoulders of the bright Volouisnesnkull Glacier. It was about here that she heard a morbid industrial siren, echoing up the valleys from far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first she thought it might have come from Ada, since Boya Chemical had a large plant there, but as she lay out her things for lunch she heard the distinct whine of a turbojet. It grew louder, and deeper, until a National Fire VTOL tanker roared across the sky, swirling powdered snow on nearby peaks as it arced across the glacier. It was close enough to catch the sun ablaze in the reflection of its glass nosecone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She later learned that lava streams had opened up not far from where she’d hiked, and had been making their way towards a geothermal power plant nestled in the highlands. In the evening, on her way back, she saw a long line of fire supertankers and pumpers spraying water in beautiful arcs, where it caught hisses from bright streams of melted rock. It was a common enough sight in Vekllei — hoses were the only defence you could reasonably make against the the fracturing earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, it was not often you saw jets flying so low. It was funny to her that even the barren glaciers were tamed in this age.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chemical Feast</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ge1gmw/the_chemical_feast/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;East of Montre, West of Tjornes, waits a rare sight among Vekllei’s hard igneous slopes&lt;/strong&gt; — a crown of gentle sedimentary cliffs packed with ruddy sandstone, which melt glacially into the sea chasing blue-sky bergs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was, at the time, making her way on foot from Montre-Lola to Ada, which was a coastal town in the North-East known for its luxurious health spas. Tzipora was not much interested in health, but she was interested in walking, and she made a pilgrimage along the coast every few years to make sense of the world. She was going whichaway and destined for nowhere in particular. Tzipora was very much Baron’s daughter, in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had stopped to see the Red Cliffs forty kilometres out from Tjornes when she saw a cruiser of the constabulary parked unusually by the shore. The constabulary were not local police — they were a national outfit tasked with policing government and “bureau business”. You found them at power plants, outside universities, guarding the prime minister and providing bodies for HO/NI (Home Office at National Intelligence) when they needed doors kicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora was not the sort of girl to be intimidated by a badge, and she wandered innocently to the shore where she found the cruiser empty. She looked across a beach of black sand and saw some sort of operation playing out — there was a gun boat not too far from the shore, and a police hydrofoil beached on the sand. She counted maybe a dozen officers. She wondered if they’d arrest her if she walked down to see what was happening. She climbed onto the hood of the cruiser to get a better look. Perhaps it was immigrants — or smugglers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It only took another moment to spot the smashed crates broken across the rocks before she knew what was going on. She was witnessing the dying days of the countercultural decade, and its chemical fuel was now smashed open before her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2070s were a wild time for the so-called “pink years” in Vekllei, and for the first time in Tzipora’s memory she started seeing “pleasure drugs” on the streets. There had always been plenty of sin carrying on in Vekllei, even in her early days — hallucinogenics, alcohol, and synthesised highs were legal and easy. But you didn’t see much of the exotic stuff, which grew in a better climate. Hash, coke, H — it was all underground stuff for personal use. These drugs were listed among many others in the class-A import prohibition orders, which made them hard to find and illegal to import. These were “pleasure drugs” — the Vekllei phrase for overseas narcotics that didn’t have a place in Upen or a preexisting cultural history. Comparatively, they were just ‘for pleasure’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H for heroin was a big news item for a long time, and with it you had one the largest moral panics in modern Vekllei cultural memory. Crackdowns came soon after. Tzipora found it difficult to describe the feeling of the time. It was a new generation — one she didn’t belong to, despite her appearance — and she didn’t have much sympathy for hedonists. They might tell her different, but she never thought the pink years were about much more than feeling good all of the time. She wondered if she was growing old and grumpy inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wondered how the crates had got there. Had the coast guard sunk another smugger? You heard about the navy firing shots in the news sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruined with seawater and picked over by constables, the chemical feast of Vekllei’s pink years died with the times. Tzipora wouldn’t miss it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She stepped off the hood and set off back towards the road, where a warm inn and hot food awaited her.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trials of Cobian</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/gbknfu/the_trials_of_cobian/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/newsdesk/bulletin/2020/1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;According to her friends&lt;/strong&gt;, Tzipora’s contemporary afflictions were tragic.  Her medical problems; her violent childhood; her sensitivity and melancholy — you could feel sorry for her, because a lot of her problems were not her fault. She invoked sympathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora never considered herself particularly tragic. It seemed straightforward, if difficult; she continued to live — and so she lived. Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s sympathy was instead reserved for her first and closest friend: Cobian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian was not well-liked at school, and it did not take long for Tzipora to find out why. She had a childish edge for a sixteen-year-old, and bitterly hated losing. She was not good at school or sports, was not particularly charming, and came across as desperately lonely. She was a quiet misandrist, which would have been fine if she could play the part of a self-assured social matriarch, but her mother’s despotic conservatism struck out that possibility early on. Such is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because her world was predicated on being liked and living a normal life, her psyche prohibited self-reflection. That was the great difference between Cobian and Tzipora. They may both have been young and neurotic, but Tzipora’s relentless self-interrogation left great space for personal growth. Cobian was instead trapped in a domestic play-fantasy, in which she could live out a mythical high-school life, and shattering that illusion would collapse her whole reason for being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora recalled visiting Cobian’s home for the first time. Cobian’s mother asked Tzipora to remove her shoes and socks and wash her feet before going to play inside. By the time Tzipora found Cobian in her room, the girl had already changed and handed over her uniform to be laundered. Tzipora, in her tomboyish indigence, had never encountered such a brutally hygienic regime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian was a different girl at home. Her anxiety and neurosis washed out a little, and her confidence was propped up by the routines her mother had set out for her since she was a child. There was a friendly, curious girl buried under a decade of loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora wondered what Cobian thought about lying in bed at night, and why the girl worried so much about things that didn’t matter. And it was precisely in the smallness of those things and the tremendous anxiety Cobian owed toward them that made Tzipora want to hug her. To be so worked up over something so pathetic was startlingly moving. The idea that the girl had deluded herself into a corner of hopelessness seemed sad — and the fact that no one would reasonably care about such a feeble, meaningless, self-inflicted state of affairs made it tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Tzipora’s friendship and the world it opened up for her, some of Cobian’s edges were sanded down. Some of it was a late maturity — some of it was Tzipora’s dismantling of the scaffolding the girl’s mother had shoved in there. With that effort, and obvious love, Cobian’s reason for being changed too. One day, in Tzipora’s presence, it didn’t seem so important to be liked by everybody anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/g6pemk/life_in_montrelola/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tomorrow&lt;/strong&gt;: 2020 Complete Guide to Vekllei&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the ro, the Vekllei flower-tundra home to spirits and people alike, green slopes and igneous monument make an ample crucible for myth and magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out here, there was a very keen sense of place and purpose. “Landscape” was neither revered nor ignored, since it did not exist here altogether. Every hill, rock and tree was taken at face value in its full honesty, with commodity dead and modernism suppressed. The place supported human life, and human life supported place. It was intuitive symbiosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora’s house was built by the hands of her friends with wood from the forest nearby and concrete from Adouisneh. They built her a fireplace big enough to keep her loft warm and the bread hot. She was a small girl and had to split her wood with a pedal saw, which she fed wood from her journeys for kindling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She cycled to the village a kilometre down the road each morning, where she worked in the district library. People from villages nested in the hills and valleys made the commute here, to see films and borrow books. It was funny to her that the scope of the books were so worldly and comprehensive, and that the lives here were so small and pleasant. Living like this, the whole world seemed like a distant curiosity, far removed from their concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/eqi5tr/the_girl_and_the_sublime/&#34;&gt;Much like the inversion of the sublime&lt;/a&gt;, Tzipora found an inversion of priority in Montre-Lola too. Time and space seemed to collapse in on themselves here, and all abstractions and petty knowledge was squashed. All that existed was the immediate relationship between herself and her surrounds — the old path and tractor, the flowers and drumlins — each heartbeat after the next, life and death adjacent, the future and past as quiet as the present. In places like this you could live a thousand years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentle Enthusiasm</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-23-enthusiasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-23-enthusiasm/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/g65op7/gentle_enthusiasm/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tzipora stood astride the bicycle luggage rack, and looked at her best friend Moise. She smiled at him, and looked to the town before them, and squinted at the clouds rising over the Atlantic horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a warm late summer and there was salt in the air. Pebbles made better swimmers than Tzipora, but from up here she could admire the coast and fill her heart with the breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked at the road ahead, and thought about what they’d eat for tea. It was all good from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had a thought that she would remember this moment for the rest of her life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ou Hydroburo Office</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/g4wo2w/the_ou_hydroburo_office/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost any other &lt;em&gt;venrouive&lt;/em&gt; national bureau is more glamorous than Vekllei’s &lt;strong&gt;Hydroburo&lt;/strong&gt;, but that fact does not detract from the organ’s critical function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the sophisticated age of robotics demands the incredible yield of nuclear fission, a significant minority of Vekllei’s electricity is produced by hydroelectric dams, which are jointly operated by the Thunderburo and Hydroburo. Hydroelectricity appeals to the common Vekllei person strategically and culturally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, where the nature of fission demands operational stability and exceptionally well-trained personnel that might be vulnerable to nuclear strikes, estimates by the War Department suggest the country’s hydroelectric dams would survive a nuclear strike, and would be operational shortly after a war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, hydroelectric dams appeal to the Upen intuition. Vekllei’s principle of &lt;em&gt;dumousiantopet&lt;/em&gt; (beautiful and seperate) is epitomised by the concept of a dam, which modifies its environment to benefit its local community, but also transforms a landscape with a permanence associated with natural phenomena. It is a tremendous structure, monumental in size and quiet in operation. Its analogue modernity and gentle nature appeal to Vekllei’s deindustrial spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depicted here is the Ou Hydroburo Office, located outside of &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/ou/&#34;&gt;Ou&lt;/a&gt; in the Vekllei West Ro Highlands and serviced by a special express train that arrives in the morning and departs at the end of the day. Many townsfolk in Ou are employed in operation of the dam, either through the Thunder or Hydroburos. It is also the site of a small Vekllei National University laboratory which examines the dam environment and trains its staff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is early Newda in style, built soon after the Atomic War, and is remarkable for its striking water tower and pump house. These pumps draw water from the reservoir into pipes tunnelled into the surrounding mountains, at which point gravity carries it all the way to &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/ou/&#34;&gt;Ou&lt;/a&gt;, Yana, and Vekllei proper’s own reservoirs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AB/NI’s Spectres of Violence</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/g4b7mh/abnis_spectres_of_violence/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Americas Bureau at National Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; (AB/NI), a semiautonomous organ of the covert operations council of the War Department, is recognised as the busiest of the continental bureaus. There is a lot to be busy with — the Dallas Secession, the Brazilian invasion of Bolivia, the Dallas nuclear lend-lease, and the reliability of Venezuelan oil production are all of some concern to Vekllei, and so AB/NI proactively has fingers in those pies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AB/NI foreign operations are provocative and direct, often guiding or outright employing shadow contractors, criminals, mercenary groups and political action groups. This is in the spirit of Vekllei’s concentric security concerns, which are benefited by the destabilisation of major powers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequently implicated and rarely rarely held accountable, AB/NI soaks up hard men returning from the previous decade of vicious fighting in Asia and puts them to work in coat and tie as servants of the Vekllei intelligence community. These include superficially respectable, decent men like Baron Desmoisnes, but also many of those whose violent tendencies and undiagnosed psychological problems are kept isolated from domestic life by their disposal in the regional bureuas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora first met &lt;strong&gt;Wihle “Willy” Tesmehsnoisen&lt;/strong&gt; in Baron’s orbit shortly after her arrival in Vekllei in 2063. She immediately liked him. His filthy ragged hair and stache were at odds with his business attire, and his short, sharp movements carried a threat of violence. His incongruity radiated freakish charm and power — the sort of person Tzipora liked. He thought Tzipora was the funniest thing he’d ever seen, and not just for her good sense of humour. To him, her diagnosis wasn’t worth much more than a good laugh. “You haven’t changed a bit,” he’d say every time he saw her. She liked that. He also faked an American accent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He worked as an operative at AB/NI, and she only saw him occasionally. As far as she could tell, he was not particularly close with Baron — Baron was not particularly close with anyone but her and maybe Ayn — but she thought Wihle respected him. They’d both been boys in the Asian war, and he’d clearly had a place in Baron’s history, no doubt in shadowy work to which Tzipora was not privy. When Tzipora performed in the school play as Witch #2, Wihle was in the audience with Baron and Ayn, clapping and stomping his feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Where he’s from?” She asked Baron.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He said he’s from California, but that’s a lie. I don’t know where he comes from.” Like most of their conversations in his office, he was looking at his work and did not look up to answer her questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“California,” she said, and something about it — the spirit, if not the truth — made sense. She asked, “what does he do at work?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Shit all,” Baron said, and that was the end of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2072, Wihle was killed in an altercation with his wife. The unsolved disappearances of several Americans went with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willy’s loud anarchism was contrasted by &lt;strong&gt;Jiro Kondō’s&lt;/strong&gt; obsequious professionalism. Here, lo, was another AB/NI contradiction — a man dressed like a gangster with the disposition of a well-paid civil servant. Jiro had started out as a merchant navy sailor on old diesel ships in the Sino Crisis, and after the war had found work with Vekllei’s Japanese Embassy as a double agent. Soon he’d been granted citizenship and recognised as a capable regional advisor for OB/NI (Oriental Bureau at National Intelligence) and met Baron through Vekllei’s work monitoring U.S.-Japan relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although many Vekllei staff in the provincial HO/NI (Home Office at National Intelligence) dismissed him as an unremarkable “import” from the East — a pretentious Japanese bureaucrat — Jiro was a fascinating character. Generally, men who’d actually seen action were unremarkable and gentle like Baron, or easy-going and irreverent like Wihle, but Jiro was neither. He was a very intense, focused man who volunteered almost any information about himself freely, though he was not a conversationalist. Baron shrugged decades of his life away in the most innocent of questions, but a simple “did you ever kill somebody?” elicited a frank, disarming admission from Jiro:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes… In 2056. A Korean… He was monitoring a man of interest to me… and the man in question was in a very delicate situation. I shot the Korean in his apartment. This was in Osaka.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was not a warm man, but he remembered every occasion of her life and delivered small gifts. Tzipora loved gifts, the the care of the gesture in a decommodifiied society, and so she reciprocated the gesture to him several times a year. So it was that Jiro’s birthday gifts consisted only of the scarves knitted by the daughter of his boss. He never married,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were others at AB/NI whom Tzipora liked, not least of which the fabulous and loving Ayn, but few typified the eccentricity and violence associated with the regional bureaus more than Wihle and Jiro. It was a glimpse of the “real” world. Away from her Vekllei language lessons, and the superficiality of her classmates, were the spectres of real danger, mental illness and genuine intrigue. That connection, as tenuous and unjustifiable as it was, was very important to her.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghosts of Taiwan in the Yana Lakehouse</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-05-lakehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-05-lakehouse/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/g4b7mh/abnis_spectres_of_violence/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By 2047, Vekllei had a lot of broken men&lt;/strong&gt;. Tens of thousands had alighted troop ships at the end of the War of Taiwan, only to find that pieces of their lives had unravelled overseas. Hardy, bronze-skinned boys were left with their ghosts, and those ghosts introduced them to drinking, and brawling, and suicide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the Birmingham Convention and the second round of the Commonwealth War Trials, a young and recently defeated Vekllei nation was chained to a conflict that was beginning to fester in East Asia. They didn’t want to be there, but that’s what happens when you lose a war. So they became &amp;ldquo;Whites&amp;rdquo; — as opposed to &amp;ldquo;reds&amp;rdquo;, or communists, they supposed. But it was also apparent that they were anglos in an oriental war. They fought begrudgingly alongside the Taiwanese, American GIs, Brits, and some Australians. At one point there were more white foreigners in the Datong district in Taipei than Chinese — that’s modern war, Baron supposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was not a friend of any People’s Republic, but the Kuomintang wankers were off the rails. The high schools had closed down and they’d taken the boys and put them in uniform. They sent those boys south from their provisional headquarters in Wulai, down as far as Yuchi where they rounded up the smartest-looking people and shot them. In the Five Days Terror, Taipei glowed in the light of a hundred thousand books turned to ash in bonfires. They were spotting Mao on street corners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind any KMT officer there was a Joint Intelligence Bureau slug, and behind the slug was some CIA motherfucker. Vekllei soldiers, who were ostensibly nonaligned but were in no position to argue, took orders from these clowns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The People’s Republic had control over a decent part of Kaohsiung and the whites were terrified of rumours of Red Chinese in the mountains on the West Coast. The communists did not have the benefit of a century of support from the Americans, and most of the boys they killed were ill-equipped and skinny. At night you could hear the distant booms of gunfire in the sea between the ROC and Xiamen. At this time Atomic shit was still restricted to naval warfare. Occasionally an old diesel ship would go up, and you’d see it from the shore. Those fireballs looked like they touched satellites overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baron had a clinical, empty side to him in which he stored a lot of his pain. He had done unspeakable things, and had merely forgotten them or parcelled them away so that they could not be coherently retrieved. That sort of conscience lands you with spooks; for the rest of the boys coming home from Taiwan, their lives had ended with the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem of dead vets and criminal heroes became such that the War Bureau, equipped with new research on shell-shock, established a series of hospitals across the country that isolated and gave time for these boys to come to terms with what they did and what they saw. They were sanatoriums, in a sense — you took a train into the highlands, and you came back when you were ready. A lot of boys found it difficult to be around people who didn’t understand them. At the hospitals, called &lt;em&gt;ouismaindesdenyo&lt;/em&gt; or “Care Homes”, they could be around those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baron would visit people occasionally at the &lt;em&gt;Yana&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;ouismaindesdenya.&lt;/em&gt; Tzipora would go with him. She thought it was because her being there made him feel less like a patient. She did not know if the people he visited were comrades, friends or if he was simply fulfilling a duty as an ex-officer. He never made it clear to her. She spent time on the lake shore painting and thinking. At dusk the sky would glow, and she would think about what the hell it was she was doing with her life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways, she was a patient at &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/yana&#34;&gt;Yana&lt;/a&gt; too — after all, like these men, she’d done and seen terrible things. She’d seen the other side of life’s coin, in a way. When she underwent &lt;em&gt;sumoirnesdenen&lt;/em&gt; (ego death) years later, she thought it felt similar to that moderated, clinical idea of trauma — like she had crossed a rubicon, and had been exposed to some secret about violence and death, and that every part of her life was now framed in relation to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She never claimed to be like the boys at Yana, because she wasn’t. But she knew what it was like to enter domesticity and never feel at home in it. She was lucky; she had Baron. She wondered about those boys who married before they left. She wondered where those brides were now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week, they would travel downstream from the highlands and leave Yana behind. There the memories would stay, until their return the following season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montre, City of Learning</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-03-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-03-learning/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ftlx4v/montre_city_of_learning/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Montre Prefecture of the Vekllei city-state is among the most learned urban landscapes in the world. In the days of the monarchy, it had been an unremarkable city, home to the empire’s submarine fleet. It was obliterated by bombs in the war, and the &amp;ldquo;new Montre&amp;rdquo; that has blossomed in its place is nourished by its ashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the most prolific creatures in Vekllei’s academic elite, including prestigious folk like physicist Thomas Weihennet and Chief Engineer of General Reactor Maya Ou, almost all of them were educated in Montre. It is home to Vekllei National University, and also to the more bohemian Montre School of Economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn’t the ivy or sandstone that makes Montre remarkable, however. Montre’s status at the forefront of learning is found amidst the dozens of small unorthodox, nonconformist, radical and avant-garde schools that have proliferated in Petticoat Society. Any chump can wiggle his way into Vekllei National University — but only twelve students a year can study under renowned architect Urian Reddennen, who teaches “Sick Newda” architectural ideology to talented young architects as young as fourteen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora herself has a brief encounter with the &lt;em&gt;uoismendainda&lt;/em&gt;, or “underground schools”. While working anonymously as central mailer of &lt;em&gt;Kid Comix&lt;/em&gt;, an underground APA (amateur press association, a sort of decentralised magazine created and possessed only by contributors), she made contact with Sgt. Salt, AKA cartoonist Darren Heidoismen. It was only years later that he discovered that editor “Squick” was Tzipora Desmoisnes — none other than Vekllei’s first Gregori Baby. After meeting her in Montre-Lola, her quiet provincial lifestyle in stark contrast with his fame as a comics author, she agreed to work for him at his studio in Montre, mostly as a colourist for serialised strips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her apprenticeship only lasted six months, and she wouldn’t return to comics after her stint in the biz, but she kept in close contact with both Heidoismen and her own roots in the underground comix scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in these schools, taught by auteurs against curriculums of fancy, that much of Vekllei’s cultural fabric is woven today. It is not particularly sentimental — in fact, it is ruthlessly modern, facing deindustrialisation as the liberation of artist and worker alike. Uoismendainda are the spirit of Vekllei’s postwar resurgence, and their concentration in Montre makes the prefecture a clear choice for youth looking for answers in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego Death and Upen&#39;s Spiritual Rebirth</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-01-ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-04-01-ego/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/fsz8lq/ego_death_and_upens_spiritual_rebirth/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Beach was a small part of herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another stroke on the Hell Screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She washed ashore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two dollars were in the sand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hound had come here to rest&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damp cotton touched green water&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She thought of what she was doing here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of what the night invoked&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hot sand met a rising wind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happened again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She realised&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was not a single dog left to fight&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the whitecap constellations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sumoirnesdenen&lt;/em&gt; or “facing self abolishment” is better described as ego death. It has a long history in Upen, Vekllei’s nondenominational animism, which employs hallucinogenic drugs in service of spiritual revitalisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of sumoirnesdenen is not to better prepare a mind for a sincere spiritual pursuit, but to propel the psyche into an objective, disassociated space to clarify the pressures and deceptions in life. It is in a sense a psychological and spiritual rebirth, if performed with an experienced guide in a controlled environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora Desmoisnes, Vekllei’s first Gregori Baby, engaged in sumoirnesdenen in 2076 at the age of 29 against her father’s advice. She had concerns about having a “bad trip” because of lingering psychological concerns, but decided to proceed after years of depression. She engaged in the trip with the help of an Upen minister, as is standard practice in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice is celebrated in two parts — first, a period of ego-death under influence of mushrooms (although synthetic drugs are often used today, especially in urban areas), and second comes a sober reassessment of priority (called &lt;em&gt;maloidenen&lt;/em&gt; or self-worship) that aims to rebuild the person positively while the memory of the open soul is still vivid. This is done largely through scripture and controlled socialising, and is celebrated, much like a birthday, as a milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Tzipora’s sumoirnesdenen experience was positive and provided important clarity in a very lonely time of her life, she soon after began recalling dreams from her early months in Vekllei for the first time in a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were nasty-feeling images, encumbered with insecurities and a dark paranoia. Never a strong swimmer, she found herself washed up on beaches, meeting dead acquaintances, and grimacing as her waterlogged nightshirt chafed her shoulders. It began to disturb sleep. She wondered if sumoirnesdenen had exposed a clearer subconscious filled with a sinister, more accurate, depiction of her past and future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had, however, provided a clear frame of mind to understand herself in the context of the universe. The dreams began to fade. Her ego quickly reasserted her place in the world — indeed, it had never really disappeared. It provided her with a glimpse at the other side of the coin, and it put her heart at peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back after a break. I&amp;rsquo;m relearning how to write worldbuilding posts. I hope you enjoyed, there&amp;rsquo;s more on the way  &amp;ndash; Hobart.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Ro Highlands</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-03-11-highlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-03-11-highlands/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/fgskau/the_great_ro_highlands/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I pick up some larger projects, my posts here will slow down a little bit. That&amp;rsquo;s okay &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m still easy to track down and get in touch with, and you guys will still see the best stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I post a lot of sketches to &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;the Vekllei Discord&lt;/a&gt;, which is something between a fan club and a social club for the project. Check the #utopia channel for little artworks like this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re paying me money to make posts, that&amp;rsquo;s where you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few projects on the go at the moment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website is still be developed, complete with a comprehensive wiki of all the latest canon. I stopped working on it for a while as I approached the limits of my HTML ability, but I&amp;rsquo;ve enlisted someone smarter to help me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The comic is making tentative progress but I hope to release some pages here eventually. It&amp;rsquo;s a long-term project that needs to be started right &amp;ndash; in the meantime, I can prepare as well as I can for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Vekllei card game is well under way. 150/180 cards are sorted, and then it&amp;rsquo;s all a matter of doing the art for them. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be pretty great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple other things, like animation experiments, storyboards for a trailer, and so on are also burning in the background. I just hate to see so much time go between posts on this place :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, feel free to hang out here and keep on keeping on. I&amp;rsquo;m on the upward trend out of a serious creative slump that&amp;rsquo;s lasted the last three months, and it feels good to be working again. Let me know if you&amp;rsquo;ve got any questions about&amp;hellip; anything, or this picture specifically!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Cobian, a concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/f4teoq/tzipora_the_princess_of_the_earth/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go back through my posts here, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice Tzipora is basically a cartoon whose only consistent characteristic is her iconography &amp;ndash; her hair fountain, bangs, round head and big smile. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really intentional. I&amp;rsquo;m just an amateur artist who is still learning to draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t work so well in a comic with sequential panels, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on standardising my characters. This is a concept panel for Cobian, Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s longtime friend (and occasional girlfriend). She&amp;rsquo;s an awkward, sympathetic sort of person, and often left out in my posts. She certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t deserve such treatment &amp;ndash; she&amp;rsquo;s one of the most interesting, complex people in the Vekllei cast and I hope to treat her with respect in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This panel is the first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on pages for the comic, but it&amp;rsquo;s slow going. I post pages as they come to my patrons (more or less!) but it&amp;rsquo;ll be a while before any chapters come together. That&amp;rsquo;s okay. I work better that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora, the Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/f4teoq/tzipora_the_princess_of_the_earth/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Editor’s note — it’s getting close to 4 a.m. and I’m not sure I can even remember why I wrote this post. Everything is a fog. Expect revisions and possibly major changes in the morning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictured above is Tzipora Desmoisnes, the Princess of the Earth and one of the most interesting persons of the last century. She has made good use of her 126 years on Earth (and counting), and a few samples have been chosen for your viewing pleasure. Conveniently, captions have been attached to briefly describe a few choice (but not comprehensive) depictions of her life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Years Old / 2049&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An infant Tzipora arrives in a country she would remember as her homeland. Knowing the tumultuousness of her childhood from here on, it is sobering seeing the round baby&amp;rsquo;s face staring back, red-faced and full-cheeked. Her mother, Mette Sumoisnesn from Vekllei, is a bohemian political scholar and radical looking to start fresh in South America after several life events leave her dissatisfied with life in Vekllei. With her savings secured, they move into a wealthy neighbourhood called Modelia, in Bogota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 Years Old / 2052&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At five, Tzipora speaks Spanish natively and only a handful of Vekllei phrases like many immigrant children. A naturally lithe and timid girl, she won’t make friends at school until her second year. In many ways, she is already becoming a picture of opposites from her mother; where Mette is a postmodern lady of wide social interest, Tzipora is conservatively inward-facing. She has, however, already inherited Mette’s disarming honesty and decisive mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7 Years Old /2054&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Mette kept irregular hours and a laissez faire attitude towards parenting, Tzipora is already fairly independent for her age. Although hardly the only child to maintain a household in Bogotá, she is certainly unique in her social class. Mette’s Vekllei-sourced wealth goes a long way in Colombia, but her bohemian lifestyle and liberal social instincts lend to a world of contradictions and colourful schisms that leave Tzipora caught between worlds — that of the poor, artistic, and revolutionary as well as the wealthy, polite and domestic. Even at this age, Tzipora already showcases several of these contrasts in her malleable personality, which are as charming as they are awkward. Although her relationship with Mette is untraditional for a single mother and daughter, it is affectionate and Tzipora is happy in Modelia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 Years Old / 2057&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2057. President Cifuentes has been dead for six months, the communists are in power in Bogotá, and Mette has depleted ten years of Colombian wages to shelter Tzipora in a Catholic boarding school in the U.S. to keep her safe from an imminent American invasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She now wears the uniform of St Mary&amp;rsquo;s Catholic College in Sacramento, California. She&amp;rsquo;s cut her hair in keeping with the American fashions and has lost some weight as she diets for what the other girls in her dorm call a “Coca Cola body”. On Tzipora’s small, girlish frame, her thinness looks pitiful and achingly neglected, not attractive. She is an Inuk-Scandinavian girl with Jewish European ancestry who knows only the language and culture of a wealthy Latina. Compounded with her little eccentricities and timidity, she does not fit in well at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 Years Old / 2061&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot can happen in four years. There was an atomic bomb in Cairo, and the Federal Government has lost control of the so-called Dallas States. Mette has stopped responding to letters and Tzipora’s out of money. She makes plans to move in with her male mathematics teacher, who predated on her near-idiotic numeracy weaknesses to foster an illicit relationship, but abandons that idea when she discovers he has been grooming multiple other girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She takes the California Zephyr to Utah instead of San Francisco on advice of a trusted priest, and quickly finds herself indigent and starving. Clothed by a charity in filthy artefacts of the previous decade, she lives in a women’s shelter that has too little to go around. There’s not even work as a strikebreaker anymore, since sporadic fighting in Southwest Utah has moved or shuttered all business that isn’t literally burrowed into the surrounding desert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 Years Old / 2063&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She’s aware by now, and has been since her school days, that she has some sort of nutritional deficiency or hormone imbalance impeding her puberty. As a good Catholic girl of the faith, she does not understand anything about puberty, but it doesn’t take a doctor to figure out she looks half the age of the teen-agers in the shelter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has miraculously managed to find work as a maid at a nearby motel, and has money for little luxuries that now mean the world to her. Clean underwear, some sneakers that are good for day work, and a steady stream of penny dreadfuls from the local bookshop, operated by the mysterious “Baron”. She lives in a so-called “Women’s House” that starts attracting attention as the turbulent political climate in the Dallas States continues to destabilise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 Years Old / 2065&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora celebrates her eighteenth birthday as a student at Lola 6th School in Vekllei. She is overwhelmed with affection for the country and her new father, Baron, but is struggling to reconcile her natural inadequacies as a new immigrant with her expectations of success in a country that offers her so much. Life is busy, and is full of new things that send her reeling with excitement — friends, music, and good food are just a few. At once younger and older than her years, Tzipora’s independence and stubborn affection make raising her easy for first-time dad Baron, who never intended to have children, let alone start with a teen-ager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32 Years Old / 2079&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffering from a severe bout of seasonal depression and a deep sense of listlessness after graduating from university, Tzipora’s long-neglected existential epistemology breaks open all at once. Now a librarian in the Lola central library, she watches Baron get older and wonders about ending her life once he passes. She drowns her panic in her work, working days at a time cataloguing stock at the library while also editing the underground ‘zine &lt;em&gt;Kid Comix&lt;/em&gt;. The sardonic nihilism of the underground Comix community is her only comfort as she considers her future and the place in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;86 Years Old / 2133&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Tzipora always evolved slowly, by 86 Tzipora’s turbulent youth is well behind her. Her little insecurities and aching sense of inferiority have blossomed into a gentle sense of humour and easygoing disposition common in old ladies. Does Tzipora qualify as one? By the numbers, certainly. But ask anyone in Montre-Lola, the village she’s lived in since moving there over fifty years earlier, and they’ll tell you that she retains a teen-age vitality and curiosity in her that should have been dissipated long ago. Physically, she is, of course, unchanging — and her spastic tics are as present as ever. Montre-Lola may change, and Tzipora may watch generations cycle through, but she is apparently timeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;126 Years Old / 2173&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much older, and a little wiser, Tzipora has had decades to reconcile her extended stay on Earth with the seeming immortality of the Vekllei cultural landscape. She still lives in Montre-Lola as a maternal root of the community, and resides in the little house built for her by the town over eighty years ago. For Tzipora, her sense of time has slowed to a crawl. A creature of routine, life around her goes on despite it all — the atomic war, the rebuilding, the stresses of a post-war world. A lot of her life is boring. She doesn’t mind. She finds great pleasure in the mundane, and her body is young and healthy. There are always reasons to live, and not just for the people in her life — after all, novels continue to be written and her plants need to be watered. Absorbed in her pleasant little life, it barely occurs to her that next year she will become the oldest living human being in history.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salad Time</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-02-11-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-02-11-salad/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/f1rlww/salad_time/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite appearances, most of the population of Vekllei are Scandinavian, not Asian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zhu is the first time in a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn an ethnically Chinese person. She was graciously lent to me to draw by u/boodyclap in an art trade. &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/pm6cuMH&#34;&gt;You can see his end of the deal here&lt;/a&gt;, complete with Tzipora balancing a baseball bat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Zhu&amp;rsquo;s homeland she suffers a meat-heavy diet, and Vekllei is the first time she&amp;rsquo;s seen a salad this big. You can see iconic Vekllei icebergs washing ashore on a beach of black sand behind them. I&amp;rsquo;ll let u/boodyclap share any extra tidbits below :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow Zhu&amp;rsquo;s adventures at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/the_jeggy/&#34;&gt;@the_jeggy&lt;/a&gt; on insta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like worldbuilding, trains or friendship please come &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;join us at the Vekllei Discord&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More posts soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Timeline</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-02-05-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-02-05-timeline/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/eysikg/the_vekllei_timeline/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is it. The dates are laid out. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a document that tracks the story thus far. Longtime followers might be surprised by where certain events land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will be pinned and serve as a stopgap until I can complete something more professional on my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/files/Vekllei%20Timeline.pdf&#34;&gt;CLICK HERE for a timeline of the events so far, and how they line up in this story.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Updated: &lt;strong&gt;13/7/2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your convenience, I&amp;rsquo;ve embedded links to the relevant posts in each year to help you keep track of the spiralling canon. Please note that this is not a complete or comprehensive catalogue of events, since for the sake of storytelling (and spoilers) I&amp;rsquo;ve deliberately excluded the bulk of events around the world in the document above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will be updated with the most current version of the timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face to Face with Immortality</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ew9gb3/face_to_face_with_immortality/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tzipora had never been taller than anyone in Vekllei at a meagre 5’2, but she was taller than Shizuku Kobayashi. Like Tzipora, Shizuku had not physically aged a day since she was a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was summer, and six days after Tzipora had arrived in Japan as a Gregori ambassador from Vekllei. Although she would not be the oldest victim of Gregori-Heitzfeld syndrome until Quentin Cook’s (USA) infamous murder-suicide ten years later, she was one of the so-called &amp;ldquo;First Thirteen&amp;rdquo; publicised patients, and so was somewhat known to the international community. By the time of their meeting in 2071, there had been an estimated 250 Gregori baby births, and around 130 living across the world. Kobayashi was the 122nd ageless child, and Japan’s first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora met Kobayashi in the Ozake Ryokan outside Kamigōri, Kobayashi’s birthplace and home. It was not far from Aioi. Tzipora was 24 at the time, and Shizuku was 18, and still in school. Poor Zelda was so nervous about meeting another Gregori baby that she became overwhelmed by Japanese manners. So it was that Shizuku’s first introduction to Tzipora was via a clonk on the head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shizuku was sweet and even-tempered, and they talked for nearly five hours before she was retrieved by her mother in the late evening. She spoke okay English, because she’d dropped out of school for a year to pursue acting with an American film company based in Yokohama that operated through the NGHQ. Acting was a common profession for Gregori babies — it seemed that the miracle children of the world were quickly relegated to freaks of entertainment. Tzipora did not have the stomach for it, but she knew of several others around the world who made good money playing children in film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora excitedly relayed the awkwardness of life in Vekllei as an unageing child, from her problems at university to her dreams of the future. She had no metric for how it might differ in Japanese society, because in many ways she was still fourteen — the problems of a young teen-age girl seemed universal, even then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No one takes you seriously at first,” Tzipora said, but she acknowledged that once people got to know her she’d had no problem being treated with respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I suppose,” replied Shizuku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora could not help but notice that Shizuku looked different from her Japanese peers. It was only later that she would learn that Shizuku’s father was a GI from Okinawa, shamefully rendering her eternally “&lt;em&gt;hafu&lt;/em&gt;” despite the miracle of her existence. She could sympathise, in her own privileged way — Tzipora, too, was a girl of many ethnicities and cultures. But even with her television understanding of the land of the rising sun, Tzipora grasped that things might be more difficult here, where old-world memory collided with new-world growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora quieted her obnoxious enthusiasm and asked Shizuku what pictures she was in. Shizuku said she wasn’t in pictures, just television, and Tzipora wouldn’t have seen them anyway. Tzipora asked what she wanted to do. She said she didn’t know. As for Tzipora?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to work in a library,” Tzipora said. “I love stories, and I like the idea of being in charge of the books.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I love stories too,” Shizuku said. “I’d like to write them, really. But we’ll have to see. It’s difficult…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She trailed off, perhaps lost in her foreign vocabulary. She didn’t have to finish the point. It &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; difficult: it was difficult to make money, it was difficult to find love, and it was difficult to picture a future where the only constant was yourself. It was no wonder that Gregori children, whose personalities were often developed by the projections of those around them, ended up killing themselves when the uselessness and meaninglessness of their existence revealed itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Shizuku’s mother received money from the estranged father, and Shizuku herself had made good money through acting, a fugue settled on Tzipora in the days after their meeting. Previously she had not considered herself a “Gregori baby;” she had considered herself merely “Tzipora”. In Vekllei, that was an identity she could afford. But despite Shizuku’s outward satisfaction with her present state of affairs, Tzipora couldn’t help but feel ill thinking about the anxious, isolating existence that almost certainly awaited any girl whose childhood stretched into the decades. All at once it seemed very unfair in its quiet cruelty — the hafu girl who would never grow up to be a beautiful actress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although she’d kept in contact with Shizuku Kobayashi, Tzipora would not visit another Gregori baby for many decades.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girls of the Last Carriage</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/eu7a4h/the_girls_of_the_last_carriage/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’d accidentally starched her &lt;em&gt;gi&lt;/em&gt; quarter-pleat in the wash. She held it self-consciously against her side as she watched the clouds navigate the sharp mountains that formed Montre’s deepest valleys. Even out here, where human presence was gentle and subservient to the land, Vekllei National Railways had tracks that serviced the smallest villages. Today it was high summer, and the slopes were green and free of ice. They waited in the shade of the regional limited express carriage for train 802, which would take them home to Montre-Lola and complete a two hour ritual all Montre-Lolan university students made for their studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;802 was the second of an 800-series trainset that had been manufactured since 2003. These trains came from old society, long before Tzipora or her father had ever been born, back when VK Rail had been the Montre Regional Transport Company. It was crazy to think that the 802 had been around since before the bombs had fallen, and had survived the chaos of the atomic aftermath. It was funny how human creations became guides through history, linking young women like Tzipora to the solemn echoes of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was something sobering about that idea, she thought. She was thinking about this as she waited in the carriage, as a younger girl fidgeted in boredom and another whistled away in sleep. The sun was hot on the platform outside and the rising air distorted the bright yellow glint that signalled 802’s approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite a week between posts, I’ve been a busy little bee. I made a Tintin-style Tzipora today, &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/VJSR4mn&#34;&gt;please click here to see her&lt;/a&gt;. I also drew Tzipora causing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/hAkBZ1i&#34;&gt;ruckus in a Ryokan here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also encourage you all to come &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;join the Vekllei Discord&lt;/a&gt;, where I do a lot of sketching and a lot of nice worldbuilding discussion goes on. In the coming days I have a few projects I’d like to share, including a new animated studio title for this project!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These last few posts have been heavy on the melancholy and light on the worldbuilding. That’s all about to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girl and the Sublime</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-19-sublime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-19-sublime/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/eqi5tr/the_girl_and_the_sublime/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Tzipora moved to study English and Vekllei literature at the university of Montre in 2075, she had to walk from the little home where she lived to Montre-Lola’s old concrete platform, which facilitated a single electric railcar each way, each day. If she was feeling lively, she could make it to the platform in a half hour. On the days where she dreaded sighting her plimsolls in the shoebox, it might take forty-five minutes. She made this trip six days a week for five years, because that was the price of acquiring two degrees at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the walk had been a welcome canvas of boredom. If the weather was good, it could even invoke the sublime. A row of gnarled old pines, planted by dead men, formed rank beside the dirt road. In the spring, the flower-tundras flashed colour through the waving pine needles as the breeze rolled through, which cooled her dreadful perspiration. She felt a very strong kinship with the Earth then, and she steadied the pace of her breaths, and she tasted sweet pine and warm soil in the air. She looked doll-like in her cape and dark leather shoes against the bright sunlight. After a long winter, her skin was not gently porcelain, but instead a waxen and tallowed complexion coloured only by the vigour of the honest walk and the spirit of the good earth around her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, she passed the same gnarled pines, and the same buried fallout shelter by Silverwater Creek, and the same abandoned machine shed that slumped closer to the fenceline with each passing season. It collapsed one day in March, baring its rusted mechanical organs briefly before it was buried in winter snow. She would look at the old tractor and wonder what part it had played in the lives of the stewards of these old fields. She thought about the factory where it might have been made and was struck with sadness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After five years of walking in this timeless landscape, she no longer resented its obtrusion on her journey to school. She had memorised everything there was to memorise along her path. She recognised lichen on the old stair rail like moles on the face of a friend, and could recite the make and count of the wine bottles in the bed of the creek. It occurred to her, in some small way, that it was only after the beauty of the path had evaporated that she was able to truly visit it. It was the eternal conflict of landscape, she supposed; it was only now, in her utter boredom and total blindness to landscape, that she had finally removed herself from the vista and allowed herself to see place as it was for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had intuitively discovered for herself a central tenant of Upen, where the sublime had been usurped by the much quieter, and much richer, mundane. The sublime screams like colour through pine leaves; the mundane is the dew that gathers silently on the spokes of the tractor ruin. The sublime is in the perfume of country air; the mundane is in the carcass of a beetle nestled in the moss; the sublime is the self-conscious rouge on her lips; the mundane a dirty scuff on her sock ankle; the sublime the whisper of the wind, betrayed by a new bud beneath a branch; the prism of her light blue eyes by the moistness around her nostrils in the cool weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, it was never a matter of birth and decay, or light and dark; it was never about a schism to begin with. It was a fundamental kinship with a transcendental memory of place, and the hidden spirituality of the unimportant, and the sweetness of the unbeautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unconscious recognition became conscious knowledge, and it obliterated her world. The entire axis of cosmology tripped. The world pivoted. Beauty and pleasure were rediscovered in an instant. She looked around her, and she had discovered the mundane. She was no longer standing amidst landscape, but mere place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her heart swelled with pleasure. Her blood sounded in her ears. Through five years of emotional labour and millions of footfalls, she had discovered the mundane in the sublime, if only here. Her eyes and heart had a sudden clarity; she was filled with love not just for the smallest of things, but in fact the smallest things exclusively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the feeling she had in that moment was by its nature irreproducible, she would do her best to recognise the mundane everywhere. She sincerely fell in love with &lt;em&gt;Newda&lt;/em&gt; shortly after. The small and honest voice of the simple and inconsequential and imperfect called to her wherever she went, and from then on she was always at peace in place; for she was always surrounded by patina, and change, and the most delicate hinge of life that animated the inanimate in her renewed understanding of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traditional Dress in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/en6pig/a_foreigners_guide_to_female_traditional_dress_in/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tzipora, illustrated here, is happy because her traditional dress makes her feel stylish and her cape is soft and warm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is an ancient culture with many inherited and vestigial artefacts. Nowhere is this more apparent than in her national dress, particularly that for women, where old and new collide as they do all across Vekllei. Pre-war, post-war and future are present here. Let’s run through some of the elements, which can be found throughout her society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fountain hairpieces.&lt;/strong&gt; These are the centrepieces of Vekllei ceremonial hairstyles, and are aided by sticks traditionally or more commonly gels today. These are only for women, and are arranged at the top of the head. Hats are not worn with traditional dress, and the Fountain hairpieces date back to the 12th century, in initial Danish settlement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temple hairpieces.&lt;/strong&gt; These hairpieces are fastened symmetrically at the side of the head, and accompany the fountain. Traditionally an exclusively male style, it was incorporated into women’s culture in postwar liberalisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uroastopet (birth flower) hairpieces.&lt;/strong&gt; Flowers are central component of Vekllei animistic iconography, and their employ with people is analogous to Zodiac or astrological traditions. A birth flower is usually attached as a hairpiece in ceremony to distinguish the girl against the stars, acknowledging the chance in her birth not dependent on blood or heritage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Floral collar pins.&lt;/strong&gt; These are recent items that first appeared in the last half-century, in response to the urbanisation of Vekllei life. Where traditionally flowers would be attached to the collar, here they are replaced by enamel and metal pins that are also worn with business and school shirts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regional Flower Plate.&lt;/strong&gt; This unusual item displays a special floral arrangement, called a &lt;em&gt;ro poisnesn&lt;/em&gt; (flower-tundra blood arrangement) which can be genuine or artificial. It displays a curated collection of flowers from the girl’s village or region, usually selected from a local flower-tundra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camisole Pinafore.&lt;/strong&gt; These pinafores first appeared as detachable suspenders in the 19th century and have become an indispensable component of styles and uniforms since. Like most elements of Vekllei ceremonial dress, its origins are in agriculture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refined Women’s Tie.&lt;/strong&gt; A woman’s tie is carefully folded to respect the integrity of its sacred source; the shape and cascading petals of the &lt;em&gt;Oa&lt;/em&gt; flower, which is the national Vekllei symbol. Men have a similar item that fastens to the neck of a tie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School/workplace armband.&lt;/strong&gt; Armbands are universal in Vekllei. Instead of a symptom of authoritarian workplace culture, they are instead seen as markers in the country of public face. They are found in most professions and schools and have even seen ironic popularity in progressive fashion scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dien agricultural shirt.&lt;/strong&gt; These loose, baggy cotton shirts rolled at the elbow are a uniquely Vekllei style of dress, and appeared just prior to the time of the Camisole pinafore. Originally a male item, it is mostly worn by women today in professional and casual settings alike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uroaten floral belt.&lt;/strong&gt; These belts are mural testaments to the lineage of a girl, usually displaying the birth flowers of her female relatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bell Sash.&lt;/strong&gt; The bell sash jingles as she moves and it sounds nice. The girls pick the bells themselves, and different sounds have different meanings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oanan lace apron.&lt;/strong&gt; These aprons are rarely worn, because they are extremely delicate, but they are precious cultural items often handed down through generations. Girls are often married in them. In postwar life, they are iconic for how the woman has been liberated from work — where even her aprons are stripped of utility and transformed into beautiful decorations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Honey half-cape.&lt;/strong&gt; Vekllei is very cold, and half-capes or full-capes are often worn. You’ll find them in school uniforms and throughout professional workplaces in the country. They are interchangeable with other long coats, but are beloved for their versatility, warmth and softness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gi quarter-pleat.&lt;/strong&gt; These are very sacred items, and are designed specifically for the girl at her menarche. They usually incorporate their birth flower, birth festival and other iconography into their patterns. Girls wear them to school. Boys also have &lt;em&gt;gi&lt;/em&gt;, but they are much smaller and not nearly as intricate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory Sash.&lt;/strong&gt; A glory sash is affixed to the &lt;em&gt;uroaten&lt;/em&gt; and proclaims the beauty of the girl’s family through religious iconography and runes, called &lt;em&gt;upotenne&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thousand-pleat skirt.&lt;/strong&gt; Traditionally skirts without pleats are worn, but postwar manufacturing has gifted young women with many types of skirt and pleat less varieties have been largely substituted for decorated or “thousand-pleat” versions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sun petticoat.&lt;/strong&gt; These are petticoats that hang below the hem, and often accompany the &lt;em&gt;oanan&lt;/em&gt; lace apron as a set. Like the &lt;em&gt;oanan&lt;/em&gt;, these are very delicate and are usually only worn on special occasions. Pure white, they dirty easily below the hem and are mostly decorative, although they do have utility in supporting the weight of the girl’s skirt with pleat and sash attached.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mido socks.&lt;/strong&gt; A longer cotton sock is folded three times to make a cuff, which offers versatility in a climate that changes without warning. At the hem’s current fashion, a &lt;em&gt;mido&lt;/em&gt; sock can instantly become a stocking of sorts, depending on the make and taste of the girl. They are worn throughout the country, including in business environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misc. felt/leather shoes.&lt;/strong&gt; There are several types of traditional Vekllei shoe, from old boots and sandals to modern makes of foreign design, like penny loafers. The choice is the girl’s, for it is by far the most impermanent style of the outfit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional dress is worn on holidays, to church, in festivals and in ceremony at school and work. To many Vekllei people, it epitomises womanhood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hobart and Tzipora are off to Japan</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/elsgfb/hobart_and_tzipora_are_off_to_japan/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora here is wearing a simplified form of Vekllei’s national dress, which plays fast and loose with lace and showcases some of Vekllei’s more decadent iconography. Long &lt;em&gt;gi&lt;/em&gt; (decorative quarter-pleats you’ve seen around) accompany &lt;em&gt;sun petticoats&lt;/em&gt;, or Vekllei lace aprons. Flowers take the place of astrology or the Zodiac in Vekllei, and so they often accompany spiritual runes (in upotenne, or religious script) about the girl. Other aspects are just as unique, but not nearly as noticeable. The loose style of shirt, folded at the elbow, is a deliberate imitation of Vekllei agricultural fashion, and three-fold socks and soft felt or leather shoes are worn by women of many ages and professions. Much like her ecology, Vekllei is also culturally atomised, and in her isolation has developed subtle variations of what might otherwise be dismissed as plain clothing items. Every part of her outfit has heritage and symbolism, often barely detectable to a foreigner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 hours from now I’m off to Japan again. The last time I was in Japan (August 2019) left me inspired and enthusiastic. While I was there I started work on this subreddit. What a good time it’s been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.2k subscribers later, and I’m off again. It’s been a hectic week. I’m still unpacking into my new house. The house is quite nice. I’m hoping to return to my roots somewhat, featuring different folks around Vekllei in a rougher concept style. Hopefully, I’ll find the time to stick to the semidaily illustration routine, instead of the 4-5 days I’ve been operating on for the last month or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to invite anyone interested to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/gpatU6H&#34;&gt;Vekllei Discord&lt;/a&gt;, which has blossomed into really great little community full of art and fashion and photography and all sorts of things. It’s much better than the r/worldbuilding Discord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to do a drawing a day while I’m over there; the one time a year I acknowledge without caveats the Japanese influence on this worldbuilding project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valleys of the Wind</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-04-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-04-wind/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ejiime/valleys_of_the_wind/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The summer had rolled into the valley, and so the air smelled of hot grass from the fields. It was quiet at the station, where a single train clacked each way in the afternoon. The only sound was the wind, which caught the heads of dry grass and roared up the slopes of the mountain ranges around her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seemed an exaggeration to even call it a station, since the bare concrete slab had been laid fifty years ago and left to crumble. The installation of a station sign had been the first work on it in decades. The whole world seemed to have forgotten this place. Every day she would catch the train both ways to university, and watch Vekllei’s ancient slopes groan by as the train cars rounded the waists of the valleys. There was no hurry out here. There were no thoughts of the future. In Vekllei’s warm agrestic towns, pastoral spiritualism took many forms; and for her, no site would stir the heart like the old concrete station outside of Montre-Lola.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So long 2019, here&#39;s to 2020!</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ei5xr7/so_long_2019_heres_to_2020/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;new Vekllei discord&lt;/a&gt; — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts. Speaking of which, this one is a substitute — the one I’m working on ended up being a bit too sad for an exciting new year, so I’ll put the sad stuff off until Jan 2nd in favour of something happier tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Moise sits alone and feels like a cow-handed chucklehead, let’s wind up the year with some awards I’ll hand out to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner Up: Favourite Post of 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/auz580/the_forgotten_generation/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Forgotten Generation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old photographs have a certain tragedy to them. Especially considering the hardships of the past. I like the maoist elements of the uniforms and the vague sense of loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner Up: Worst Post of 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/e6iykk/wallabies_of_the_arctic_veklleis_pademelon_and/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wallabies of the Arctic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pademelons are cute, and were fun to draw. Somehow I managed to make Tzipora, whom I’ve been drawing since I was 15, incredibly ugly and awkward to look at. The expression I was trying to draw is fine in theory; the shape and colour of the face is wrong. You’ve got to wonder what I was thinking, posting it without alterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite Post of 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/c05k16/absolute_grotesque/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Absolute Grotesque&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As anyone who does creative work knows, you don’t usually anticipate your favourite work. This one was made in about four hours (it was the quickest landscape I ever did).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t always like the dark stuff, but this one just turned out well. The lore doesn’t waste any words, and it says exactly what I wanted to say about the subject. It’s clear and simple and I like reading back through it. The art is much better than more recent attempts at similar subjects, and there’s a brevity to the art and lore that I usually fuck up. I’ve made many posts now trying to recreate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Worst Post of 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/dj5di0/uniform_ideology_in_the_arctic_north/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uniform Ideology in the Arctic North&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to trust me when I say the women’s uniform is extraordinarily beautiful. Despite its capes and gold, it can be stripped of ornamentation and reduced to a white shirt and red skirt, recalling images of Taiwan in the White Terror or postwar Vietnam. It has a fundamental simplicity and adaptability that’s quite important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to trust me about all that, because it does not carry through in this post at all. It’s not that there’s one particular element that makes a post shitty; it’s just the total half-arsed effort throughout. Uniform ideology is such an untapped concept, and I wasted it here. The girls look strange. The only good thing about this post is that it introduced me to several nice fellow worldbuilders that I would go on to collaborate with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is your best and worst? I know my choices might be a bit surprising. If you comment that the worst is &amp;ldquo;every post&amp;rdquo;, I’ll ban you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, cheers to all of you here and at my Patreon. I’ve had a slow month for drawing, and I’ve got to find a place to live by this weekend, but we’ve got good things ahead. I’m back in Japan on the 9th, so expect some vitality there. I love drawing on the trains there. I was inspired to make this subreddit after my last visit in August, actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to get back to making posts every other day — it’s the best feeling in the world to put stuff up here, but sometimes life just gets in the way. January is a time of rebirth, and Tzipora is eternal — there will be lots of Vekllei to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s to 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Moise did, in fact, get his slow dance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>