<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>sketch on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/sketch/</link>
	<description>Recent content in sketch on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/sketch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>The Crown and the Gi</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-08-06-crown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-08-06-crown/</guid>
	  <description>The Crown # The crown depicted here is not the actual crown of the Vekllei Sovereign,1 but in fact the national hat of Vekllei and is part of traditional dress. This &amp;lsquo;crown,&amp;rsquo; so-called, is a felt or velvet hat with two peaks and a tall, narrow brim stitched with traditional patterns in gold thread. Historically, the crown was a work hat made of leather and wool, but today it is designed primarily for fashion and comfort, and is most commonly seen at ceremonies, schools and some professions like the Public Police.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Fruit Tingles</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-27-tingles/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-27-tingles/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This image is a website-exclusive sketch produced as a masthead for the November Patreon update. The typeface in this image is a preview version &amp;ldquo;Nay Aug&amp;rdquo; by Alex Tomlinson, who you can follow here. Fruit Tingles (Fodsa Spas) are a chalky sweet popular in Vekllei. They fizz in your mouth and come in several flavours. They&amp;rsquo;re as popular today as they were a hundred and fifty years ago when they were first produced by Montre Confectionary in 1936.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Autumn Love</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-31-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-31-love/</guid>
	  <description> ❖ This image was produced as part of a series of concept art for merchandise. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Studio Zelda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-26-millmint/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-26-millmint/</guid>
	  <description> ❖ This image is a website-exclusive sketch produced as a masthead for the september Patreon update. The typeface in this image is a preview version &amp;ldquo;Nay Aug&amp;rdquo; by Alex Tomlinson, who you can follow here. </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>