<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tzipora on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/tzipora/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tzipora on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/tzipora/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Transmission Towers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-23-transmission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-23-transmission/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/tl3ktc/transmission_towers/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tzipora finished most school days at two in the afternoon. Her routine looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catch the tram home. Walk if the weather is &amp;lsquo;interesting&amp;rsquo; (dramatic). Unlock the apartment and exchange her shoes for sandals. Bring in the bedding airing in the backyard and say hello to the stripy stray cat. Put away her books and rinse her lunchbox. Set the meat out to defrost and boil and refrigerate the water. Blow her nose. Eat an apple with a glass of milk. Listen to the news on the radio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on what she was making for dinner, she would usually head back out sometime around three thirty and find somewhere to read in her neighbourhood. From all places in Seispri you could see its beautiful circular high-voltage transmission towers, which carried power from the 2nd Magma-Electric Cogeneration Plant to their homes, supplying them with heat and light. The neighbourhood had been bombed in the war and there were still ruins out here. You could find old paths that were abandoned, overrun with mosses and bushes. These were good places to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora spent most evenings alone until Baron got home. She loved Cobian, but they were quite different people and Tzipora spent a lot of time in her own head. That was probably the origin of a lot of her neuroses; she processed things slowly and inwardly; a cascading reaction of memories and identity splitting and colliding. You could hear the transmission towers hum with electricity. She felt that if her skull wasn&amp;rsquo;t so thick you could hear her brain humming, full of thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contrails</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-17-jets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-17-jets/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/tgctec/contrails/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has the some of the clearest skies in the world, and they are criss-crossed by distant vapour trails of jets coming and going. They bring the world closer together. It was funny to think that Peking and Tokyo were just a few hours away &amp;ndash; it felt very cosmopolitan; very democratic. It emphasised the smallness of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora would look at the livery of the planes to figure out where they were going. Red and white was Vekllei Overseas Airways &amp;ndash; which meant anywhere, really. With quiet nuclear engines, they could fly for thirty years before deciding where they wanted to go. Blue and white was the Vekllei Air Service, which flew domestic routes between Commonwealth destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t really matter what colour they were &amp;ndash; on their lonely island in the Atlantic, anywhere else seemed far away. Peking was Paris, as far as she was concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Between Stations</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-16-liminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-16-liminal/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/tfjxvv/inbetween_stations/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out on the branch lines there are in-between stations. Sometimes they emerge out of history as relics of dead and dying towns overlooked by the timetable. Others are a quirk of the rail company machine &amp;ndash; workshops and line junctions where people switch trains. As you get further and further out of the city, and the trains get older and older, these in-between stations become more common. Between Yana and Kotaismoyeh there is an irregular line serviced by steam trains that are over a hundred years old. &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/rail/&#34;&gt;Vekllei National Rail&lt;/a&gt; thinks in centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, perversely, a cultural incentive in Vekllei to prioritise experiences over efficiency or productivity. In Vekllei, the company is responsible for not just a material product but an emotional service to its employees and customers, which makes up part of the bizarre social theatre of the Vekllei economy. Vekllei National Rail has the means to rework its rural timetables, modernise its rolling stock and build faster lines. These features are a straightforward economic benefit and a convenience to the people who travel with them. But that is, as the Vekllei colloquialism goes, &amp;ldquo;thinking like an American.&amp;rdquo; Companies in Vekllei, year after year, become more inefficient, apathetic, and playful. Not simply because they are badly managed or poor, but because they have a human emotional interest in cultivating the &amp;ldquo;new way of living&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the Floral Period way of living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this system, steam trains continue to run not just because they are objects of history and sentimental to their ridership, but because they are old, easily physically conceptualised, and slow. So too are under-utilised routes serviced. It is not that Vekllei National Rail is unaware of their inefficiencies &amp;ndash; Vekllei National Rail is in fact asserting its cultural priorities on you, and expects you to weather those inconveniences. If that sounds sinister, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; every aspect of Vekllei society is like this, and contributes to the richness of their lives. In one sense, it is manipulative and managing, but the opposite is also true &amp;ndash; to scrap old rolling stock, rebuild lines and close stations would also coerce people into new journeys and places. You only need to look at the alternative mindset in America, where wealth and accessible consumerism has, by the late 21st Century, stripped out most of what makes life worth living. Their lives are more convenient and empty than ever, which has contributed to a cultural slump that in part spurred the collapse of Ford and the Dallas Secession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora sits at an in-between station and she understands this. This is what makes Vekllei National Rail so smart, she thinks. There is a direct, tragic parallel between the collapse of the Ford Motor Company and why she is waiting forty five minutes for the steam train to the village of Vos. Vekllei people don&amp;rsquo;t realise it because they are immersed in their own intricate ways of thinking, and they will never understand living in the shrill, hedonistic fantasy of the middle class. Being so wealthy and so empty that you&amp;rsquo;re sitting in a motel room trying to figure out if you want to&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whatchoo thinking about, Zelda?&amp;rdquo; Moise asks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nothing,&amp;rdquo; she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This sucks. How much longer?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I dunno.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunch in the Park</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-15-wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-15-wine/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/tevxfs/lunch_in_the_park/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has several cold-weather wine producing regions in its south, concentrated around the boroughs of Horn and Mopapa. Local staples are hearty reds like cabernet sauvignon and pinot noir, since whites are served with dessert or as apéritifs. Wine in Vekllei is a product of mass consumption, and is often drunk with meals even by teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora liked the drowsy, warming feeling of it. She liked it so much that she kept clear of it except on occasions. Sometimes that occasion is a birthday or a sad night in. Sometimes that occasion is 3pm in the Ivo St Park with her friends. There was plenty to go around.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicking the Habit, Pt. 1 of 12</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-14-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-14-habit/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/te1rew/kicking_the_habit_pt_1_of_12/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tzipora doesn&amp;rsquo;t smoke anymore. She prefers Camel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</guid>
      <description>


  
  


&lt;a  href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/ta8bwp/all_chapels_for_all_women/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  Archived from the original article here
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,&lt;br&gt;
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray&lt;br&gt;
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,&lt;br&gt;
For the people hear us singing, &amp;ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &amp;ndash;&lt;br&gt;
For they are women&amp;rsquo;s children and we mother them again.&lt;br&gt;
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &amp;ndash;&lt;br&gt;
Hearts starve as well as bodies: Give us Bread, but give us Roses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei people have a right to organise in their work. This principle is expressed in the structure of the economy, in which cooperative enterprises form company ballots that go on to inform commercial and industrial practice. Collections of individual trade unions may form bureaus, massive monopolies of organised workplaces cooperating and competing under the bizarre structure of the Vekllei moneyless economy. These are expressions of a mobilised democratic workforce which sustain the country in their self-interest, and are a defining characteristic of the Floral Period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation also exists outside the workplace. Their negotiations occur with the municipal and state authorities, and are a common means by which groups of people express their grievances and strengthen each other. The most well-known of these are Vekllei’s Chapel system — the unionisation of local women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapels are localised by community. Tzipora was at first very sceptical of the Chapels, which had offered her membership upon her arrival in Vekllei. You have to understand, Tzipora was in a crisis of inferiority at this time, and considered the ingratitude of the ungovernable female organisers to be naïve and entitled. She was convinced otherwise by Ayn, who was a moderate and carefully-spoken person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You want to integrate in Vekllei, don’t you?” She asked Tzipora. “This is what integration looks like; the Chapels are an expression of our democracy. A means of support and celebration; to have people know and care for you. There is no political commitment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora found Chapel meetings to be friendly and informal, characterised by shared meals and conversations of joys and grievances. Local Chapel № 23 was a social club of individuals made strong by their trust in each other. Tzipora sat silently at the end of the Chapel hall, an old concrete building with a flat roof built after the war. It had the appearance of a midcentury church. She ate her bread and sausage with her fingers and listened to the women talk amongst themselves. Children ran around, playing chasings. It was not like any place she’d been before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well-wishes to all this International Women’s Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>