<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>update on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in update on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Something New is on The Horizon</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-30-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-30-june/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Thanks for a great June. We&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of different types of posts this month. About 15 in all — that&amp;rsquo;s one every two days! Not bad! I could do with some sleep.
Something very special is approaching in July. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to share it with you all — so are Tzipora and Cobian. A new chapter in Vekllei is fast approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vekllei Comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Hi everyone,
&amp;ldquo;He not busy being born is busy dying,&amp;rdquo; — that’s off a Bob Dylan bootleg. I’ve just finished my thesis and I’m busy being born again. Sometimes I feel like I’m busy dying. Drawing’s been the way out for a long time now.
As of today I’m starting work full-time on a Vekllei comic called Atomic Modern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2,000 members! WOW!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Hello,
I’m Hobart. I’ve been working on this project for a while now. It doesn’t really have a purpose or an end goal — I just want to draw and write about nice things, and I’m learning a lot on the way. Welcome to everyone new here. I don’t really have anything to sell, I’d just like to thank you for tuning in and checking Vekllei out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Tzipo-stcards</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hello everyone. Just a little update.
As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.
How many cards will the set contain?
 I’m aiming for about six cards.
 How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hobart and Tzipora are off to Japan</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora here is wearing a simplified form of Vekllei’s national dress, which plays fast and loose with lace and showcases some of Vekllei’s more decadent iconography. Long gi (decorative quarter-pleats you’ve seen around) accompany sun petticoats, or Vekllei lace aprons. Flowers take the place of astrology or the Zodiac in Vekllei, and so they often accompany spiritual runes (in upotenne, or religious script) about the girl.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
