<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Arctic Commonwealth</title>
	<link>/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Arctic Commonwealth </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Helvasia</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/helvasia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/helvasia/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Helvasia is part of the Arctic Commonwealth Helvasia Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of the Arctic Commonwealth Capital Romsa Population 32,400 Area 62,045 km² Languages Northern Sami, English, Norwegian Vekllei Accession 2026, as part of the Arctic Agreement The Helvasia Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the Atlantic Ocean north of the Arctic Circle, nearly 1000km north of Norway. It comprises an archipelago of nine main islands, the largest of which is nearly 40,000 km² and is home to most of the republic&rsquo;s small population.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Helvasia is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/"><span class="fi fi-arctic"></span> Arctic Commonwealth</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/sj.svg);"></span> Helvasia Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/helvasia.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of the <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/arctic/"><span class="fi fi-arctic"></span> Arctic Commonwealth</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Romsa</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>32,400</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>62,045 km²</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Northern Sami, English, Norwegian</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>2026, as part of the Arctic Agreement</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-sj"></span> <strong>Helvasia Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the Atlantic Ocean north of the Arctic Circle, nearly 1000km north of Norway. It comprises an archipelago of nine main islands, the largest of which is nearly 40,000 km² and is home to most of the republic&rsquo;s small population. It is the northernmost Vekllei republic, and holds several records for its latitude, including its capital of Romsa as the northernmost permanent settlement in the world.</p>
<p>According to <a href="/sagas/">sagas</a> in <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, Helvasia was discovered by Scandinavians in the 12th Century, who observed tribespeople living there &ndash; most likely arctic Sami. After the island was rediscovered by Europeans in the 17th Century, whaling stations were established on Bear Island in its south. After quarrels over whaling rights resulted in conflict between Dutch and English settlers, the UK effectively exercised control over Svalbard thereafter, though a small Russian settlement on the main island remained uncontested throughout the 18th Century. In 1836, the archipelago was absorbed into the British Atlantic Territories and later acceded to <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> after the Atomic War.</p>
<p>Because the whale oil industry was largely confined to Bear Island, the indigenous Sami peoples of Helvasia have retained relative independence from foreign powers for over a thousand years. They remain the predominant ethnic and linguistic group on Helvasia, and Northern Sami and English are taught in schools. Sami culture characterises life in Helvasia, and many traditional and animistic practices remain commonplace. Sami culture and language is distinct from both Scandinavian and Algic languages spoken elsewhere in Veklllei.</p>
<p>Life on Helvasia is cold and harsh, and pack ice in its surrounding shallows prohibit access by sea in the winter months to all vessels except nuclear icebreakers. Its climate is Arctic and ranges from around 15 °C in summer to -40 °C in winter. Its extreme latitude means Helvasia experiences midnight sun and polar night for nearly a hundred days in both summer and winter respectively. Polar Bears remain dangerous there and many Helvasians carry rifles outdoors. Outside of company towns and nomads nearly all Helvasians live in the capital of Romsa.</p>
<p>Helvasia has economic zone disputes with Norway and the Soviet Union, and confrontation between the Vekllei Littoral Service and the navies of those countries occur periodically. The country exploits coal, oil and gas reserves on and around the archipelago. Minor industries include domestic tourism, trapping, fishing and municipal goods. The republic also serves as a base for Vekllei polar research and expeditions, and its isolation has encouraged the establishment of initiatives like the Commonwealth Research Bunkers and the International Knowledge Vault.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Kala</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/kala/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/kala/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Kala is part of Arctic Commonwealth Kala Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of the Kalina Commonwealth Capital Kanek Population 482,448 Area 2,166,086 km² Languages Kalan, Aleutian Algic, English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Kala Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei, located 320km west of Oslola. It is the world&rsquo;s largest island, and makes up the majority landmass and population centre of the Arctic Commonwealth.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Kala is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/"><span class="fi fi-arctic"></span> Arctic Commonwealth</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/kala.svg);"></span> Kala Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/kala.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of the <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina Commonwealth</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Kanek</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>482,448</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>2,166,086 km²</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Kalan, Aleutian Algic, English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-kala"></span> <strong>Kala Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, located 320km west of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>. It is the world&rsquo;s largest island, and makes up the majority landmass and population centre of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/arctic/"><span class="fi fi-arctic"></span> Arctic Commonwealth</a>. It is known for its rugged, mostly arctic terrain and interior glaciers that forms the second-largest ice sheet in the world. Kala plays a major part in the history of Vekllei Inuits (often called Algics) and the population today remains majority Algic.</p>
<p>Two thirds of Kala is above the arctic circle, and its climate is moderated only by the Gulf Stream across its populated southwest coast. The interior forms a permanent low-pressure system that circles cold air above the country, where permanent ice sheets form and feed peripheral glaciers. Dramatic weather changes are a part of Kalan life, and seasons experience both polar night and midnight sun during the solstices. Exposed terrain is mostly covered by low-lying tundra vegetation and a few species of Atlantic Pine. Polar bears, Arctic Oxen and Reindeer can all be found there.</p>
<p>Settlement in Kala dates back thousands of years, but its extensive history is poorly recorded compared to the Oslolan kingdoms. The island was home to the first permanent settlements of Vekllei Inuits, who inhabited the coastline and islands around the capital of Kanek at least 3,000 years ago. Unlike <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, Kala was not historically united under a single kingdom, and its harsh terrain prevented extensive trade between coasts. Local languages and culture on the east and west coasts are referred to in common as Kalan, but are seperate from each other, and have distinct identities.</p>
<p>Kala&rsquo;s massive, though isolated, internal area is unique across Vekllei, and the country is home to many government installations. The public service remains the largest employer in the country, and most Kalans live in a few major metropolitan areas on the southwest coast. Due to the interior permafrost, the island has been slow to develop rail infrastructure common across other Vekllei republics. Life under its arctic climate has been improved by the limitless supply of fusion power provided by a reactor completed in 2026. As a consequence, streets and rails are able to be heated in winter and kept free of deep snow. Kanek is home to several major Vekllei companies, including <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(224, 40, 35); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(224, 40, 35) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/national-machines/"><span class="fi fi-min-national-machines fis"></span> National Machines</a> and <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(243, 3, 89); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(243, 3, 89) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/common-gemstone/"><span class="fi fi-min-gemstone fis"></span> Common Gemstone</a>. Major deposits of oil, coal, precious metals and uranium are mined there.</p>
<details open>
<summary>Points of Interest</summary>
<ul>
<li><strong>National Machinery Complex</strong>: The headquarters and primary fabrication and research plant of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(224, 40, 35); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(224, 40, 35) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/national-machines/"><span class="fi fi-min-national-machines fis"></span> National Machines</a>, the third-largest robotics manufacturer in the world.</li>
<li><strong>Mesters Vig Aeromanufacturie</strong>: <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(247, 85, 85); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(247, 85, 85) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/state/gaf/"><span class="fi fi-min-gaf fis"></span> Government Aircraft Factories</a> complex and major air base serving the northern command of the air service.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth Arctic Division</strong>: <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a> specialist research complex and base of arctic circle expeditions.</li>
<li><strong>Jewel Street</strong>: Headquarters campus of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(243, 3, 89); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(243, 3, 89) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/common-gemstone/"><span class="fi fi-min-gemstone fis"></span> Common Gemstone</a>, Vekllei&rsquo;s largest synthetic gemstone manufacturer. Located in the heart of Kanek and known for its dramatic stained-glass architecture.</li>
<li><strong>Seqi Olivine Mine</strong>: Peridot mine in continuous operation for over three hunded years.</li>
<li><strong>Kala National Park</strong>: The world&rsquo;s largest national park, comprising much of the island&rsquo;s glacial interior.</li>
<li><strong>Commonwealth National Vault</strong>: Preservation vault of Vekllei government, libraries, technology and seeds, designed to survive a total nuclear war.</li>
<li><strong>Alavia</strong>: Historic site containing the oldest evidence of Inuit settlement in northern Kala, adjacent to a small village of the same name.</li>
</ul>
</details>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
