<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>catia</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/catia/</link>
	<description>Recent content in catia </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/catia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Uniform Hijab</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hijab/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hijab/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Vekllei has large Muslim populations in Mira. Revision of the Vekllei school uniform hijab. It now fastens with a school crest pin.
Mostly for use among the Portuguese muslim community across Mira (Madeira) and the Azores. I&rsquo;m not quite happy with this sketch, and I would like to include more Miran elements in future.
Notes on Headscarves in Vekllei Schools Under the uniform code, only &ldquo;veils&rdquo; are permitted, which encompasses a range of headwear for various groups including Christian and Jewish orthodox communities.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/hijab.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">Vekllei has large Muslim populations in <a href="/mira/">Mira</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Revision of the Vekllei school uniform hijab. It now fastens with a school crest pin.</p>
<p>Mostly for use among the Portuguese muslim community across <a style="color: rgb(91, 67, 138)" href="/mira/"><span class="fi fi-mira"></span> Mira</a> (Madeira) and the Azores. I&rsquo;m not quite happy with this sketch, and I would like to include more Miran elements in future.</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Notes on Headscarves in Vekllei Schools</strong>
<br>
Under the uniform code, only &ldquo;veils&rdquo; are permitted, which encompasses a range of headwear for various groups including Christian and Jewish orthodox communities. No face coverings are allowed.</p>
<p>Regarding Islamic head coverings, it&rsquo;s not a common issue because Miran muslims do not generally wear a Niqab or similar.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Grocer Girls</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/grocer-girls/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/grocer-girls/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Miranese islanders Isuri and Catia return. As they approached adulthood, compulsory service loomed large in their futures like a great wall. The thing about compulsory service (or &lsquo;corsosva,&rsquo; as it was called) was that it could be dice toss, which was a hell of a thing for something that took four years of your life. You applied for jobs you might like to do, but if they were full or you didn&rsquo;t make the cut, you could find yourself on the other side of the country doing clerical work or working construction in the Arctic.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/united-grocers.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">The Miranese islanders <a href="/stories/isuri/">Isuri and Catia</a> return.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>As they approached adulthood, <a href="/corsosva/">compulsory service</a> loomed large in their futures like a great wall. The thing about compulsory service (or &lsquo;corsosva,&rsquo; as it was called) was that it could be dice toss, which was a hell of a thing for something that took four years of your life. You applied for jobs you might like to do, but if they were full or you didn&rsquo;t make the cut, you could find yourself on the other side of the country doing clerical work or working construction in the Arctic.</p>
<p>No, thank you. There was a scheme that allowed teenagers too young to start corsosva to accumulate credit towards it, which would deduct from the total length of service. You still had to work, but at least you had security in choosing where you were.</p>
<p>For Isuri and Catia, they picked up casual work after school at their local <a href="/united-grocers/">United Grocers</a>. Vekllei might be a society of miracles, but their groceries look the same as anywhere, and the work was easy and boring. Their neighbourhood was small and they knew everyone who came through.</p>
<p>Their jobs were unadventurous, but the store was owned by a neighbour of Isuri and they goofed off a lot or sat outside in the sun when it was quiet. The stock robot did most of the work, so they were really just around to keep an eye on things, and often read magazines or played chess to pass the time.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mira Uniform</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/isuri/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/isuri/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[From left: Catia, Isuri. This drawing depicts girls wearing school uniforms on the Vekllei republic of Mira (real-life Madeira), a former Portuguese territory that now has a large population of immigrants from Ceylon.
Isuri (right) was born on Mira to Sinhalese parents and Catia (left) is also Miranese. Catia is part of a community of Portuguese muslims who originally settled on the island in the 1960s after persecution in Lisbon.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/isuri.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">From left: Catia, Isuri.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>This drawing depicts girls wearing school uniforms on the <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> republic of  <a href="/mira/"><span class="fi fi-mira"></span> Mira</a> (real-life Madeira), a former Portuguese territory that now has a large population of immigrants from <a href="/ceylon/"><span class="fi fi-lk"></span> Ceylon</a>.</p>
<p>Isuri (right) was born on Mira to Sinhalese parents and Catia (left) is also Miranese. Catia is part of a community of <a href="/portugal/"><span class="fi fi-pt"></span> Portuguese</a> muslims who originally settled on the island in the 1960s after persecution in Lisbon. Since 2030, all Miranese people are now citizens of the united island republics called Vekllei.</p>
<p>The uniform is in the <a href="/education/">Commonwealth tradition</a>, consisting of simple universal elements accentuated by cultural accessories. In this case, features of Miranese traditional dress like red striped wool skirts and throws or capes are included. A hat is also part of uniform, called the Miranese Carapuça.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
