<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0">
  <channel>
	<title>Moise</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/moise/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Moise </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<image>
		<url>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</url>
		<title>Moise</title>
		<link>https://millmint.net/stories/</link>
	</image>
	<webfeeds:cover image="https://millmint.net/images/missile.jpg" />
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/moise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Waiting for a Movie</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/movie/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/movie/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/movie.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/movie.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint story&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ This image was part of an art trade with my friend JM. Thank you JM. This picture features his red-head character, Isabeau. See his drawing of Tzipora and Isabeau down below.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Vekllei people do not own a television, so they go to movie theatres. Even though personal appliances are abundant in the U.S. and Europe, they are in constant shortage for almost all classes of Vekllei people, and so the social tradition of the cinema is alive and well. Most people visit a few times a week for films and the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like television, the programming depends on the time of day. After school finishes at 2pm, the movies are playing stuff for kids. After the work-day finishes at 4pm, they play normal films and television programmes. 6pm is the news &amp;ndash; Tzipora always tried to catch the news &amp;ndash; usually followed by a documentary. And afterwards came the feature films, which ran late into the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora, Moise and Isabeau are finishing pre-movie drinks in the ruins of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/lola/&#34;&gt;Lola&lt;/a&gt;, surrounded by night-shadows and stars. Ruins are common all over Vekllei, but no kids gave much thought to them. To them, the war was already history. This time of year, the moon has been up for hours. A science fiction movie Tzipora has been wanting to see again plays at the &lt;em&gt;Royal&lt;/em&gt; tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was legal to drink as a 16-year-old in Vekllei, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t mean it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a hassle. Just as they do overseas, most Vekllei teenagers drink together in the private corners of public places, away from parents and the local nuisances, the lights of Copetpek glowing beneath them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;JM&amp;#39;s Submission&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/fanart/jm-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Café Diplomacy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/vista/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/vista/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/vista.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/vista.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instafilm #445&lt;/strong&gt;. Marked &amp;ldquo;2064&amp;rdquo;. Month of the Mosses. You remembered that because it was about the same time war broke out in the Congo again. Everyone at the table had opinions about that war, but not much to do with it. Everyone asked Coretti what she thought about the war. She hated that, she hated being singled out for it. Coretti had been two years old when she left the Congo. But Vekllei people are far away from the world and curious and so they asked stupid questions sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora didn&amp;rsquo;t like the news so she stopped reading it. Sometimes she got people asking her about America &amp;ndash; what do you think about what they say&amp;rsquo;s going on in Dallas? Is it real or is some of it made up to sell papers? Here&amp;rsquo;s an idea &amp;ndash; how about you shut your mouth and stop asking me so many fucking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left to right: Moise, Coretti, Lin Zhi, Cobian, Tzipora. 2064.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>In-Between Stations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/liminal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/liminal/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/liminal.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/liminal.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out on the branch lines&lt;/strong&gt; there are in-between stations. Sometimes they emerge out of history as relics of dead and dying towns overlooked by the timetable. Others are a quirk of the rail company machine &amp;ndash; workshops and line junctions where people switch trains. As you get further and further out of the city, and the trains get older and older, these in-between stations become more common. Between Yana and Kotaismoyeh there is an irregular line serviced by steam trains that are over a hundred years old. &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/rail/&#34;&gt;Vekllei National Rail&lt;/a&gt; thinks in centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is, perversely, a cultural incentive in Vekllei to prioritise experiences over efficiency or productivity. In Vekllei, the company is responsible for not just a material product but an emotional service to its employees and customers, which makes up part of the bizarre social theatre of the Vekllei economy. Vekllei National Rail has the means to rework its rural timetables, modernise its rolling stock and build faster lines. These features are a straightforward economic benefit and a convenience to the people who travel with them. But that is, as the Vekllei colloquialism goes, &amp;ldquo;thinking like an American.&amp;rdquo; Companies in Vekllei, year after year, become more inefficient, apathetic, and playful. Not simply because they are badly managed or poor, but because they have a human emotional interest in cultivating the &amp;ldquo;new way of living&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the Floral Period way of living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this system, steam trains continue to run not just because they are objects of history and sentimental to their ridership, but because they are old, easily physically conceptualised, and slow. So too are under-utilised routes serviced. It is not that Vekllei National Rail is unaware of their inefficiencies &amp;ndash; Vekllei National Rail is in fact asserting its cultural priorities on you, and expects you to weather those inconveniences. If that sounds sinister, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; every aspect of Vekllei society is like this, and contributes to the richness of their lives. In one sense, it is manipulative and managing, but the opposite is also true &amp;ndash; to scrap old rolling stock, rebuild lines and close stations would also coerce people into new journeys and places. You only need to look at the alternative mindset in America, where wealth and accessible consumerism has, by the late 21st Century, stripped out most of what makes life worth living. Their lives are more convenient and empty than ever, which has contributed to a cultural slump that in part spurred the collapse of Ford and the Dallas Secession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora sits at an in-between station and she understands this. This is what makes Vekllei National Rail so smart, she thinks. There is a direct, tragic parallel between the collapse of the Ford Motor Company and why she is waiting forty five minutes for the steam train to the village of Vos. Vekllei people don&amp;rsquo;t realise it because they are immersed in their own intricate ways of thinking, and they will never understand living in the shrill, hedonistic fantasy of the middle class. Being so wealthy and so empty that you&amp;rsquo;re sitting in a motel room trying to figure out if you want to&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whatchoo thinking about, Zelda?&amp;rdquo; Moise asks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nothing,&amp;rdquo; she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This sucks. How much longer?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I dunno.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meta Moments</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/meta/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/meta/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/valin.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/valin.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ &lt;strong&gt;This image&lt;/strong&gt; was a gift to my friend Bez. Thank you Bez.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll join an &amp;ldquo;art trade&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; to change things up and break the repetition of working in one universe with one set of characters. Bez is a friend of mine and a talented artist, and so for Christmas we decided to produce secret works involving characters and places we don&amp;rsquo;t usually draw. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing more exciting as an artist than seeing through new eyes &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s the magic of having someone illustrate your people and places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My piece, finished today three days after Christmas, depicts the Vekllei crew encountering Valin and her aphis, a sort of canine-feline hybrid creature. The setting is based on photographs I took of where I grew up, amidst temperate rainforest on my property. Bez&amp;rsquo;s contribution is below. I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;


 
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.millmint.net/images/fanart/bez-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint caption&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;I love the composition of it, it&amp;rsquo;s very optimistic. Very cute.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the attention to detail on Tzipora and the golden wattle on the right. Vekllei has wattle as canon &amp;ndash; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense, but who cares? It&amp;rsquo;s too lovely to exclude from utopia. Bez also shared a preliminary sketch with me, seen below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;


 
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.millmint.net/images/fanart/bez-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint caption&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Bonus Tzipora with a bird. Bez likes birds.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Bez &amp;ndash; let&amp;rsquo;s do it again sometime!&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>30 Minutes to Midnight</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/party/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/party/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/cosme.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/cosme.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;Moise’s father worked for Cosme Car, and a big company like that throws a big party each year to celebrate the passing of the summer solstice. It was a good excuse to dress up and drink. This time of year, the sun never sets on the north of Vekllei. It gently touches the horizon and begins to rise again. Tzipora caught a train up the coast with Moise and his dad and they arrived before seven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big Cosme party was thrown at its headquarters and manufacturing plant in Bohs each year. At the centre of the facility was Auto Tower, which rose 50 floors above the ground and housed workers at the plant. General wisdom was the higher you climbed, the better the party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise had dressed up as Zeus, but Tzipora didn’t know much about the Greek myths and thought he was Caesar. Moise, for his part, thought Tzipora had decided to accompany him as Helios, god of the sun. She didn’t know who or what a Helios was, but didn’t want to disappoint him so she pretended. She had actually been aiming for the indigenous warrior spirit Acovo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willy the spy was there, on the lawns away from the music. He wasn’t a good guy — he was an officer with AB/NI, and exemplified the fraying edge of Vekllei’s wide-cast intelligence net. He was creepy. Tzipora, in her upside-down view of things, liked him well enough and struck up a conversation with him. Willy liked that about her; he liked the comedy of this schoolgirl chatting with this monster about their old war stories. Moise had never met him before, and the guy put him on edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You’ve gotten so tall,” Willy said. Same joke every time he saw her — Tzipora wasn’t getting any taller anytime soon. She shook her head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing here? Who invites a guy like you? Did you get reassigned as a bodyguard?” Tzipora asked. He snorted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m actually headed north for a couple days. Thought I’d stop in and have a beer. Feels like a long time since I seen you — hey, why don’t you tell your old man to give me a call? I’m rotating out in a few weeks and wouldn’t mind the work. He’s hard to reach now, Director Desmoisnes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He doesn’t like you much, you know that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, I know that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a good party. They lay about on the lawn drinking and talking like pantheon gods. The sun was low in the sky, and Auto Tower was glittering thirty minutes to midnight.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Generation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/new-generation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/new-generation/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/generation.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/generation.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children of the children of the bomb —&lt;/strong&gt; a generation of war-babies born in peacetime. That was how they thought of themselves. Their grandparents and great-grandparents had lived through the war and the occupation, and so they had inherited the burden of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s future as a country of long-sufferers, visionaries, and dispossessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Marxist continental intellectual had said something a half-century ago about the right way to teach children, and the idea had probably caught the ear of some commissar of the Vekllei interim government, who perhaps passed it along to some bureaucrat rebuilding the government schools. As a result, Vekllei children only go to school three or four days a week. There, they spend only a few hours a day in classrooms. There is, after all, no real workforce for which they are being primed. &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/#play&#34;&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s labour economy is a play-fantasy&lt;/a&gt;, and so they mostly learn how to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not designed to &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; children — Vekllei schools have hierarchies, punishments and are mandatory &amp;mdash; instead, the primary goal of education is self-discovery and self-respect. It is precisely these qualities that benefit most the modern Vekllei economy, which is heavily automated and competes internationally through the product of its participatory creative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no grading system in Vekllei — all classes are passed or failed. The value of compulsory education through government schools, then, is the socialisation of boys and girls with others boys and girls, and the availability of equipment and facilities to participate in extracurricular activities. This is the real body of Vekllei school life — its clubs, societies, and individual associations. Many professional photographers in this country discovered an affection for photography before they turned 15 years old, through exposure to it in school. These resources, and the need to socialise children with others, are the reasons the Vekllei government continues to universalise government schooling, even alongside home-schooling or independent/religious education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depicted here are the good-natured youth of the new generation in school uniform — &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/&#34;&gt;a topic we&amp;rsquo;ve visited before&lt;/a&gt;. All students in Vekllei wear the same uniform, including at university. The uniforms themselves are not designed specifically to regulate appearance — and to this end, schools do not have dress codes regarding hair or cultural/religious accessories including jewellery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discard any assumptions about the meaning behind the colour or style of their clothes — all variations depicted here can be worn by whomever, no matter their age, school or association. In fact, school uniforms are not provided directly by schools — they are found at department stores, on the rack alongside suits and dresses. Because of this fact, specific styles of shirt, trousers, socks and shoes vary between students — and are acceptable as long as they meet the basic requirements of the uniform. This intersection of control and anarchy can be found widely throughout broader Vekllei society, and is an interesting example of how the basic principles of the &amp;ldquo;Vekllei way of life&amp;rdquo; are reflected in the microscopic mundanities of life and foundations of national culture simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Gone Hollywood</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hollywood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hollywood/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/hollywood.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/hollywood.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You know you’re near the homeland of the Magma-Electric Commission when you smell it.&lt;/strong&gt; Somewhere between cracking a rotten egg and standing downwind of a sewerage treatment plant, the volcanic heartlands of Vekllei are the playground of the Magma-Electric Commission, often shortened to just “The Magma” or “Thunderburo”. The smell is caused by Hydrogen Sulphide, a byproduct of the naked volcanic activity Vekllei is known for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sulphur is everywhere in Vekllei — even in the cities, the drinking water smells of it. It even overpowers the perfume of a ro, the Vekllei flower-tundras. In the places where the smell is most intense, you usually find a geothermal power plant nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Vekllei, The Magma pumps water deep into the belly of the Earth, so deep that the temperature and pressure cause the water to go supercritical, at which point it’s neither a liquid or a gas. Supercritical water carries much more energy than water or steam, and produces much more electricity — so much so that residences in Vekllei are powered entirely by geothermal (Magma-Electric Commission) and hydroelectric (Hydro-Electric Commission) facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a so-called “flash plant” in Miyatvousi, in the Lava region of Vekllei. Lava is full of plants like these. A rail line runs near its injection well, where fresh glacial runoff is transformed into clean, limitless electricity through the miracle of its landscape and human ingenuity. The water is recycled, but excess waste water is dumped into the surrounding ro, forming foggy pools of light blue water. The earth here is alive; in the cold, the ponds begin to steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise had complicated ambitions of becoming a filmmaker. As with all student filmmakers, he drafted his friends to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His girlfriend, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/locjnz/turning_things_around/&#34;&gt;Coretti&lt;/a&gt;, operated the compact 8mm camera. Tzipora was the production assistant, doing makeup and foley and whatever he asked of her. Cobian was going to be a star — that’s what he said to her, anyway, and he paired her up with a mate of his in what would be an epic short film about lost love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Tzipora who suggested Miyatvousi, since she’d developed a good catalogue of scenic locations in her quest to find natural shrines. There was a place where the rail line crossed a small mineral lake, near the flash plant’s turbine halls. If worked out just right, you could have a shot that’d make the whole film. It was a hell of a journey — a bullet train in the morning to &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/landscape/boroughs/krafla/&#34;&gt;Krafla&lt;/a&gt;, where they got breakfast, and a two-hour local train far out from the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it unfolds, you never realise how good a moment is. It was maybe the second or third-best day of Tzipora’s life. She didn’t know Coretti all that well, and it was the first time they’d talked about things other than Moise. They were on a great adventure, and they all knew it. They laughed when Moise coughed out his coffee all over himself and pretended to be interested when Tzipora talked at length about how geothermal power plants work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the gig had been sort of a joke for Cobian — she was humouring the friend of her girlfriend — but as the film progressed, she realised how talented and passionate her friends were. They were deeply odd and talented people, and they believed in what they were doing — Cobian had never had friends like that before. On the train back to Lola, as the city lights of the capital loomed, Cobian turned to Tzipora and told her that she loved her for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambitious, arrogant, naive, laughing, well-fed, tired, and in love. Looking back, Tzipora thought the candid footage of themselves made better cinema than anything in a theatre. Lights, camera — action.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Turning Things Around</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/around/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/around/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/around.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/around.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His hand was hurting bad, but no one asked him about it the day after&lt;/strong&gt;. Moise always had a temper, and now he had a reputation. He got no words of sympathy from the other seniors of Lola 8th School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering his bluntness and irritability, it was funny that he could only make good friends with women. His father was a bastard and his mother was in Greece, so his sister took their place. His closest friend was Tzipora, the boyish miracle child who helped him lose weight. His love was Coretti, his high school sweetheart and, a little further along, his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti was the daughter of Congolese scientists, but was born and raised in the Soviet Union. She had a typical brief for Afro-Russians — her father had worked with the Congo Water Company, and later was brought over for the Soviet Ministry of Agriculture and Food. She spent her early years in the relative wealth of the Basmanny District.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrangement collapsed quickly after the coup in Congo and the death of Party Secretary Shchusev. The office her father worked for disappeared, and the family emigrated to Vekllei when she was six. Vekllei was full of displaced people with displaced heritage. After all, Moise was himself the son of wealthy Greek folk, his mother a fascist in the shadow party there. The way their identities intersected brought about difficult dimensions to their character — often empowering, occasionally suffocating, and sometimes resurrecting ghosts from their past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise was graduating this year with Coretti, and had already landed a gig running cameras for Dovo Studios, a big deal for someone his age. His real passion was filmmaking — the creation of dreams. That was on hold, after last night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some shithead assistant-to-an-assistant was mouthing off about him to the C.A., telling him he had an attitude. Moise didn’t know what this guy’s problem was, and he kept picking at him all night. Moise didn’t take shit, and got up in his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked at his right hand, which was swollen so fat he couldn’t tuck his fingers in. It’d be right in a couple days, maybe a week. But he was off the set for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti hated his fighting. Tzipora, ever the contrarian by way of instinct, admired him for it. It was like those cartoons with the angels and devils on your shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I hate it when you fight,” says Coretti, in a white gown and halo. “You’re a better man than that, I know it in your heart.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Is that right?” Tzipora says, with horns and a tail. “Seems to me he’s proved exactly who he’s better than.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’d lost his job and got in trouble again, but as Moise lit a cig and sat back, the whole afternoon ahead of him, he felt pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” he said, and took a drag. “Serves me right.”&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>How to Speak Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/language/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/language.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/language.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/news/bulletin/2020/7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters&lt;/strong&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net&#34;&gt;https://millmint.net&lt;/a&gt;. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will briefly discuss some elements shown in this infographic, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/vekllei/language&#34;&gt;but a large article on the language has been drafted here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have some interest in constructed language, and some of the more playful aspects of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s evolving utopian communication systems, I encourage you to take a look at it. The website is incomplete, and both the articles on characters and Vekllei itself are very incomplete. Otherwise, a growing archive, essays, and issues of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic&lt;/em&gt; Bulletin are all available. Have a poke around, and let me know if anything breaks! The site has dark mode, if you&amp;rsquo;re a gamer. Just click the moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-language-many-parts&#34;&gt;
  One Language, Many Parts
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#one-language-many-parts&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To borrow from the article linked above, the Vekllei language has six core systems often referred to as sublanguages. They are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/culture/language/#21--spoken-vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoken Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is everyday spoken language. It draws from two glossaries with different meanings and feelings, called &lt;em&gt;Oa&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Loh&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/culture/language/#22--topet&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which are logographic characters (occasionally characterised as hieroglyphs). Like other pictographic languages, &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; characters can be broken down into repeating components, called &lt;em&gt;Topotte&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/culture/language/#23--rapotenne&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is the traditional logographic language of names. It is much older than Topet, and has more in common with spiritual runes than modern logography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/culture/language/#24--potenne&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potenne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, lit. “&lt;em&gt;Hand-Talk&lt;/em&gt;”, is a sign language that incorporates gestures and signing to add meaning to emotion to spoken language, and occasionally in place of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/culture/language/#25--upotenne&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upotenne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, lit. “&lt;em&gt;Spirit-Hand-Talk&lt;/em&gt;”, as the recreation of runes in human form, used limitedly in spiritual ritual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/culture/language/#26--vekllei-semaphore&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the codification of colour and shape. Traditionally limited to colour, shape and pattern are now also included in &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/em&gt;, in which full sentences can be formed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-this-picture&#34;&gt;
  In This Picture
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#in-this-picture&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see various parts of the Vekllei sublanguages on display, including &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Potenne&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/em&gt;. Before Cobian gets close enough to say hello, Tzipora has already delivered a devastating compliment via a simple three-finger tap to the palm, admiring how she looks. A couple of descriptions of Tzipora written in &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; have been annotated on her left, to demonstrate its use, including a tongue-twister (&amp;ldquo;She always tucks her shirt&amp;rdquo; becomes &amp;ldquo;Louisn Laismoh Loah Liousmineh&amp;rdquo;). You&amp;rsquo;ll notice &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; looks especially hieroglyphic, even by pictographic standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s full Blood Name is spelled out in &lt;em&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/em&gt; below, which is markedly different from &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; in history, characters and grammar. Most formal names in Vekllei employ a seal in place of writing it out in full ornamentation, which has been provided below along with a formal signature. Her signature is entirely pictographic; elements are arranged according to symbolic value, rather than phonological legibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the right, we can see an example of how Semaphore lives up to its name through its presence on flags, reinforcing and communicating information without conventional literacy. Also shown are a handful of basic symbols as they relate to authority, with the landscape of Vekllei superseding all human organs. Their colours matter, and so their meanings are more complex than what is described here &amp;ndash; for example, a small black circle refers to a human being, but an orange one refers to an arctic person (usually Vekllei).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have a breakdown of the word &lt;em&gt;comiya&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net//utopia/culture/language/#222-phonetic-reading&#34;&gt;also looked at here&lt;/a&gt;), which means &amp;ldquo;friend.&amp;rdquo; Tzipora and Cobian are &lt;em&gt;comiya&lt;/em&gt;, and Moise and Cobian are&amp;hellip; sort of &lt;em&gt;comiya&lt;/em&gt;. The introduction here of &lt;em&gt;phonetic complements&lt;/em&gt;, which are duplicate consonant-pairs used to slightly alter the semantic meaning of a word without changing its pronunciation, allows the idea of a &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; to be conceptualised in many different ways, to encompass all sorts of relationships. This one here implies a sort of naïve love (by using characters for late autumn, young woman and a glacial beach, all pronounced /k/.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limpettes are tails that underline vowel-forms called &lt;em&gt;hieyerette&lt;/em&gt; to enhance legibility. Although ornamented &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; has visually distinct consonant-pairings, business &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; does not generally use superscript and so limpettes designate the vowel-form. If you&amp;rsquo;re a bit lost, that&amp;rsquo;s okay. It&amp;rsquo;s in the main article, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make this post too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can imagine then, even with only a handful of examples of language in practice here, how complex Vekllei can become as phonological and semantic meaning compound, combine and seperate in different forms and contexts. The spoken word can be altered by the physical gesture, and the physical gesture can be altered by the written word.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Road Trip</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/road-trip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/road-trip/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/roadtrip.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/roadtrip.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint story&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/news/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They showed up at the autopool&lt;/strong&gt;, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem. Moise would drive, Tzipora bunked with Cobian in the passenger seat and Alise, Zo and Jerome could cram into the back. It was a squeeze but with the top down and on the coastal highway it couldn’t have mattered less. It was the car of late summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zo had just married Jerome, and they had recently moved in with each other at age 17. Tzipora had no metrics to figure out if that was too young, but Zo was her friend and young newlyweds were lonely people. She was all too ready to volunteer her labour (and that of Cobian and Moise) to drive them down to Koisniya and pick them up a coffee machine she’d ordered six months prior. Tohs S.p.A. was a good company but Tohs himself was a disorganised bastard and he’d rung up to a few times to tell her the order had been delayed. Then she called him back a month later and he said he’d never received the order. So it was that they were on their way now, well after Zo and Jerome had married, to pick up the wedding gift. That was just how things worked in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zo’s friend Alise sat the coffee machine in her lap on the way back, and as the coastal highway reached Vik it skirted an incredible series of cliffs that they stopped to look at. The wind was out and the Atlantic churned beneath. The sun was hot on their skin. The coffee machine was left on the tiny back seat as they got out to have a look and take a picture.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/uniforms/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/uniform.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/uniform.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint story&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; was featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/news/bulletin/2020/5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Atlantic Bulletin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society&lt;/strong&gt;. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depicted here are uniforms for education — Tzipora as a puffling of the Puffin Scouts on the left, and the others in mere school uniforms. These uniforms are universal and used across all ages of schooling, from kindergarten to university. Even some teachers wear them — it starts to stretch the conventional imagination about what constitutes a uniform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few observations on this picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, these uniforms are used interchangeably across ages and disciplines. The difference between a red pleat skirt and a navy skirt is trivial; it is merely a difference in the meaning of the clothing, as part of Vekllei semaphore. They are both equally the school-mandated uniform of education, and can be worn interchangeably from one day to the next, in third grade and at university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, there are many small uniquenesses in the uniform of each person, which are accentuated by their surrounding uniformity. Tzipora’s school shirt is pleated along the buttons, acquired off the rack of a department store. One pair of trousers might be a slightly different shade to the pair next to it. These discrepancies are not regarded as malfunctions of the uniform system, since the system is not designed to make each student conform to a single appearance — it is about identity and convenience in a country that spent many decades clawing its way out of abject poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These principles apply across many workplaces and in government, too — where uniforms are not intended to only signify publicly a place of work but instead form social bonds through clothing, which are intimate factors of ordinary life. In Vekllei, clothes are not an expression of personality, but items to communicate and bond with, regulated not by an authority demanding strict conformity but a desire for identity, physicality, infrastructure and convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a state of affairs is unimaginable in some countries, especially beyond collectivist or conformist cultures. Individualist intuition suggests that uniforms are actively detrimental to personal expression — but this idea demands a scale of expression far beyond the preference for subtlety and delicateness in Upen. Deviations from uniformity, like earrings, the way hair is worn, wristwatches, makeup and minor irregularities accentuate the value of those things, and make them more important. This aesthetic contrast is at the heart of the wider Upen intuition that you can see in architecture and political priority alike. And, as any Vekllei boy will tell you — seeing a classroom crush out of uniform for the first time is a religious experience, and only afforded by scarcity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is an individualist society, modelled after self-concern and self-love by a salt-of-the-earth and larrikin people of my native Australia. This is not a people compatible with conventional thinking on the regulation of appearance — but, as with many things in Vekllei, both are held true at the same time. They are a free and unrestrained population clothed at work and in school in clothes gifted to them.
As an addendum, although many readers find common ancestry with Japan in this project (not unreasonably, either), Vekllei has more in common in some ways with the distant neighbours of my Australian homeland — countries that haven’t been glamorised in the West through culture export. Thailand, Cambodia and Laos are among them — coincidentally, all three are rare examples of countries where university students wear uniforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someday, we’ll look at the aesthetics of power and authority-worship, inspired at least in part by the history and culture of these countries, and associate them with cultural forces in Vekllei. If you have any questions, just ask.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Gentle Enthusiasm</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/enthusiasm/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/enthusiasm/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/enthusiasm.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/enthusiasm.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;Tzipora stood astride the bicycle luggage rack, and looked at her best friend Moise. She smiled at him, and looked to the town before them, and squinted at the clouds rising over the Atlantic horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a warm late summer and there was salt in the air. Pebbles made better swimmers than Tzipora, but from up here she could admire the coast and fill her heart with the breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked at the road ahead, and thought about what they’d eat for tea. It was all good from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had a thought that she would remember this moment for the rest of her life.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>So long 2019, here&#39;s to 2020!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/dance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/dance/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/dance.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/dance.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;new Vekllei discord&lt;/a&gt; — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts. Speaking of which, this one is a substitute — the one I’m working on ended up being a bit too sad for an exciting new year, so I’ll put the sad stuff off until Jan 2nd in favour of something happier tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Moise sits alone and feels like a cow-handed chucklehead, let’s wind up the year with some awards I’ll hand out to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner Up: Favourite Post of 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/auz580/the_forgotten_generation/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Forgotten Generation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old photographs have a certain tragedy to them. Especially considering the hardships of the past. I like the maoist elements of the uniforms and the vague sense of loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Runner Up: Worst Post of 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/e6iykk/wallabies_of_the_arctic_veklleis_pademelon_and/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wallabies of the Arctic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pademelons are cute, and were fun to draw. Somehow I managed to make Tzipora, whom I’ve been drawing since I was 15, incredibly ugly and awkward to look at. The expression I was trying to draw is fine in theory; the shape and colour of the face is wrong. You’ve got to wonder what I was thinking, posting it without alterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favourite Post of 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/c05k16/absolute_grotesque/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Absolute Grotesque&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As anyone who does creative work knows, you don’t usually anticipate your favourite work. This one was made in about four hours (it was the quickest landscape I ever did).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t always like the dark stuff, but this one just turned out well. The lore doesn’t waste any words, and it says exactly what I wanted to say about the subject. It’s clear and simple and I like reading back through it. The art is much better than more recent attempts at similar subjects, and there’s a brevity to the art and lore that I usually fuck up. I’ve made many posts now trying to recreate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Worst Post of 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/dj5di0/uniform_ideology_in_the_arctic_north/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Uniform Ideology in the Arctic North&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to trust me when I say the women’s uniform is extraordinarily beautiful. Despite its capes and gold, it can be stripped of ornamentation and reduced to a white shirt and red skirt, recalling images of Taiwan in the White Terror or postwar Vietnam. It has a fundamental simplicity and adaptability that’s quite important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to trust me about all that, because it does not carry through in this post at all. It’s not that there’s one particular element that makes a post shitty; it’s just the total half-arsed effort throughout. Uniform ideology is such an untapped concept, and I wasted it here. The girls look strange. The only good thing about this post is that it introduced me to several nice fellow worldbuilders that I would go on to collaborate with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is your best and worst? I know my choices might be a bit surprising. If you comment that the worst is &amp;ldquo;every post&amp;rdquo;, I’ll ban you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, cheers to all of you here and at my Patreon. I’ve had a slow month for drawing, and I’ve got to find a place to live by this weekend, but we’ve got good things ahead. I’m back in Japan on the 9th, so expect some vitality there. I love drawing on the trains there. I was inspired to make this subreddit after my last visit in August, actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to get back to making posts every other day — it’s the best feeling in the world to put stuff up here, but sometimes life just gets in the way. January is a time of rebirth, and Tzipora is eternal — there will be lots of Vekllei to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s to 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. Moise did, in fact, get his slow dance.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>1000 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/1000/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/1000/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/1000.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/1000.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;Hey everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart here. You might not know it, but I’m sort of a big fucking deal on the internet. No, don’t touch me. Why am I? Because my subreddit just hit 1,000 subscribers. What’s a subreddit? I’m actually laughing at you; imagine not knowing what reddit is. &lt;em&gt;You ingrate&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously though, this whole renewal of the project through a subreddit (rather than disconnected r/worldbuilding posts) has been an amazing thing. It gives me more wriggle room in what I can talk about, and — even better — allows me introduce you to my characters, who are very precious to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your State of the Subreddit bulletin follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’ll turn your attention to the badges on this post, I’ve scribbled up a few community awards for fun. They’re both 500 coins, the cheapest I can make it. They can’t give you premium. Reddit is garbage and they don’t really deserve your money, but some of the regulars here are pretty wonderful and if they ask a really good question or something you can reward them in a way you never could in Vekllei — with money. I made them so I can hand them out, really. You can choose from &amp;lsquo;Medal of Valour&amp;rsquo; for long-time service or &amp;lsquo;Great Question&amp;rsquo; for, uh, you can probably guess. Let me know what you think. Do I need more types?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For my new friends, of which there are many of you, it might take a while to settle into Vekllei’s world and characters. For example, Tzipora, pictured here abusing a friend, also goes by Zelda. If you get confused, you can check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/czi423/a_brief_introduction_to_vekllei/&#34;&gt;this meta intro to the project&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/vekllei/comments/czi423/a_brief_introduction_to_vekllei/&#34;&gt;this brief summary of Vekllei as a country&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve got a few different projects going, in addition to the regular posts. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/melonkony&#34;&gt;I’ve made a Twitch&lt;/a&gt;, since it’s literally a single button on my iPad to stream me working. This isn’t the start of some illustrious streaming career, just something that was easy to do. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;I also have a Patreon&lt;/a&gt;, if you’d like to send a few dollars my way for the posts or food or whatever else. On the horizon is the graphic novel (no two ways about it, it’s a long-term project but it’s coming), and a few special experiments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for hanging around. I’m very lucky to have a community that responds to my work. So many of you have reached out personally and interrogated my posts and it’s very flattering to attract that sort of interest. I’ll keep on keeping on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hobart Phillips&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MelonKony&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The King</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/king/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/king/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/king.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/king.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;The King and Tzipora do not get along. Zelda met him through Moise, when King managed the Domepent School’s cricket team. Moise was a pretty good wicket keeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;King had offended Zelda with an off-hand comment on her youthful appearance, and she’d retorted with a remark about his weak blood circulation. Moise, caught between his new boss and his angry Zelda, navigated these stormy waters by ignoring the dispute entirely and separating them on the walk home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Moise would turn out to be a decent athlete, and she would spend more time around King, she never would come to like him. He was pompous without pomp. For his part, he regarded her as small and cranky. It was not an entirely unreasonable assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Mafioso and His Witch</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/mafioso/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/mafioso/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/mafioso.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/mafioso.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;Hello, everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s been six days. I&amp;rsquo;d like to have been here sooner, but I had the good fortune to leave my Apple Pencil in a hotel room in Sydney. Although delighted with my welcome and surprising expense (~$150AUD, or roughly 43 bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves), I&amp;rsquo;ve consequently fallen behind with my off-daily illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I carry the ANZAC spirit deep within me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve made use of my time. I have a document, many thousands of words long, detailing a special kind of script. &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/lL3T32R&#34;&gt;The writing is excellent.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a hint &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s not for a film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for sticking with me. I&amp;rsquo;m back. In the meantime, please enjoy this illustration and story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Moise arrived at the Desmoisnes&amp;rsquo; to pick up Tzipora for the halloween festivities, he was greeted at the door by Baron, who looked tired and held a powder mirror in one hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, hello, Moise,&amp;rdquo; Baron said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How&amp;rsquo;s things?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Good, good. Say, Moise, could you tell Zelda she looks nice when you see her?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Moise could ask, Zelda&amp;rsquo;s voice rang out from behind her father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tell him I&amp;rsquo;ll be a moment! Just a moment!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; like most Zeldaic exclamations, there was panic in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, he stepped inside her room to see her. She was dressed as a witch, and wore a cardboard hat fashioned in black linen on her head. Most immediately, however, he noticed she was wearing eye-liner and rouge. He&amp;rsquo;d never seen her wear make-up before, because she looked too young to wear it. She was a teen-ager whose appearance made such feminine gestures a costume rather than daily practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You look really nice,&amp;rdquo; Moise said. &amp;ldquo;Have you done yer face?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; she beamed, &amp;ldquo;you noticed! It&amp;rsquo;s not done poorly is it? I&amp;rsquo;ve got no practice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nah, it looks great.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wasn&amp;rsquo;t lying. She&amp;rsquo;d gone a bit heavy since her lashes were so dark already, but she looked years older for it. Zelda wilted under any timid flattery and smiled genuinely at him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe I should wear it sometimes. It&amp;rsquo;s not too much trouble.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baron called from the living room: &amp;ldquo;It took &lt;em&gt;two hours&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All right!&amp;rdquo; she yelled, and after a moments of pause, followed with a kinder shout. &amp;ldquo;Thanks for helping me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The festival went until the early hours of the morning. Cold city air washed over them in waves as they passed through warm clouds of woodsmoke from fires set out for hallow&amp;rsquo;s eve. He was dressed in pinstripes as a Mafia don. He told her he had Mafia blood in him. Zelda asked if he was getting Greece confused with Italy, to which he took great offence. She started laughing as his fake moustache danced about on his upper lip when he corrected her, which made him more annoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nice night out, in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Squish!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/squish/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/squish/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/squish.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/squish.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;Sorry for breaking my streak everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m on beta software and it totally shit the bed these last couple days. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing my best to hobble along until full release :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is easily squished. In this picture Moise would be around 16, Cobian 15, and Tzipora about 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise has lost a lot of weight and has been blessed with a hefty frame befitting his temperament. Tzipora &amp;rsquo;s tastes in clothes are specific and mostly unchanging, except for a brief phase a few years after her arrival where she started poaching neckties for her own use. Cobian is conscious of and struggles with the fact that she is not particularly photogenic.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Introducing Moise</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/moise/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/moise/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/introducingmoise.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/introducingmoise.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;Moise was a fat kid who went to another school. Zelda only knew him from the tram, where he carried a criminal stigma because of his rumoured gang affiliations. He was a second-generation Vekllei boy of immigrant Greek heritage. There were a few ethnic gangs in his area, and most immigrant boys that didn’t do well in school quickly found other causes to fight for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zelda quickly antagonised the boy by offering him to her own bullies. She would point out his weight and he’d point out her clumsy Vekllei language skills and apparent lack of intelligence commonly attributed to foreigners, and so the arms race began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bullying did not come naturally to either of them, since they were on the receiving end most of the time and were not particularly manipulative. She would tell Moise he stunk, he would say she was skeletal and unattractive, and they’d seethe about each other that evening. She would make fun of him for eating a chocolate on the tram, and he stole a hairclip and wouldn’t give it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day she was walking behind him after alighting the tram and had set to whacking him with her bookbag, demanding the return of her red pencil. She kept pushing him. In a fit of anger he slammed her against a garage door repeatedly, where her head bounced against the corrugated steel and nearly knocked her out. He left her incapacitated on the pavement, and fled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He buzzed her apartment the following evening after school, seeking to apologise. She weighed her own crimes against his attack, using unique Zelda metrics that gauged physical and emotional violence somewhat improportionately. She accepted his apology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus began the kind of awkward and unconventional friendship that Zelda seemed to attract. With entrepreneurial zeal she rarely displayed, she struck a deal with Moise — he would teach her to fight, and she would help him lose weight. He did not have much experience talking to girls, which was both revealing and endearing, but it helped that Zelda was socially maladjusted and not particularly girlish. On weekends he would take her to the nearest park, they’d lay out a blanket, remove their shoes, and he’d show her how to use a bigger opponent’s weight against them. During the week, she’d meet him at the tram station and they’d go for long walks until he was red and puffing. Zelda liked making food, which seemed to be the one thing she was good at, and soon after began preparing his school lunches, which she’d pass surreptitiously on the morning tram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although they grew close, they both recognised her condition would make any romantic relationship inappropriate and so they remained each other’s quiet soulmates as he went on to film school and married. Moise’s wife, an incredibly patient woman of enormous spiritual strength, would soon learn to tolerate Zelda’s presence at their life occasions. Although Zelda would often think about what might have been if she’d only been normal, they remained close for the rest of his life and she would remain a close family member and guardian of his children for decades after his passing.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Summer sex-ed</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sex-ed/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sex-ed/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/sex-ed.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/sex-ed.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;Porno is available over-the-counter at most book stores. Some industry associations attempt to limit availability to minors but generally it&amp;rsquo;s at the discretion of the shopkeeper. Often, shame and embarassment are more powerful tools than legislation in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally it&amp;rsquo;s pretty traditional stuff supported by columns and fiction, although it varies between pornographers. It&amp;rsquo;s quite common for well-known Vekllei models to end up in nude shoots either before or after their fame. Nudity is a little more common in Vekllei than it is in the U.S. (at beaches and so on), and that relaxes the moralising of smut somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, the generation previous to Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s (about 20 years prior, so around the early 2050s) were very sex-positive and deviant. Certain cultural iconography from this time is still used in porno &amp;ndash; heavy makeup, curled hair, bare thighs &amp;ndash; but this has prompted a conservatism among Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s generation towards the &amp;ldquo;vanity&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;superficiality&amp;rdquo; of their parents&amp;rsquo; sexual liberation and bare skin. Today it is much more common to have skirts below the knee than above it, and pornography is starting to shift to accommodate the fetishistic and fantasy as opposed to outright explicit desire common in the previous decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;foreign porno, however, is highly prized as a sort of racialised sexual unorthodoxy (especially of Asian or Black men and women, neither of whom are particularly large racial demographics in Vekllei). It&amp;rsquo;s rare to find and not commonly traded. There are very few bureaus that import pornography, and export is far more common.&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>summer nerds reading comix</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/princes-of-the-earth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/princes-of-the-earth/</guid>
	  <media src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/nerds.jpg"/> 
	  <description>
		  <image src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/nerds.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;p&gt;nerds&lt;/p&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
