<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Moise on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/moise/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Moise on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/moise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Waiting for a Movie</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/movie/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/movie/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This image was part of an art trade with my friend JM. Thank you JM. This picture features his red-head character, Isabeau. See his drawing of Tzipora and Isabeau down below. Most Vekllei people do not own a television, so they go to movie theatres. Even though personal appliances are abundant in the U.S. and Europe, they are in constant shortage for almost all classes of Vekllei people, and so the social tradition of the cinema is alive and well.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Café Diplomacy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/vista/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/vista/</guid>
	  <description>Instafilm #445. Marked &amp;ldquo;2064&amp;rdquo;. Month of the Mosses. You remembered that because it was about the same time war broke out in the Congo again. Everyone at the table had opinions about that war, but not much to do with it. Everyone asked Coretti what she thought about the war. She hated that, she hated being singled out for it. Coretti had been two years old when she left the Congo.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>In-Between Stations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/liminal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/liminal/</guid>
	  <description>Out on the branch lines there are in-between stations. Sometimes they emerge out of history as relics of dead and dying towns overlooked by the timetable. Others are a quirk of the rail company machine &amp;ndash; workshops and line junctions where people switch trains. As you get further and further out of the city, and the trains get older and older, these in-between stations become more common. Between Yana and Kotaismoyeh there is an irregular line serviced by steam trains that are over a hundred years old.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Meta Moments</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/meta/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/meta/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This image was a gift to my friend Bez. Thank you Bez. Occasionally I&amp;rsquo;ll join an &amp;ldquo;art trade&amp;rdquo; to change things up and break the repetition of working in one universe with one set of characters. Bez is a friend of mine and a talented artist, and so for Christmas we decided to produce secret works involving characters and places we don&amp;rsquo;t usually draw. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing more exciting as an artist than seeing through new eyes &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s the magic of having someone illustrate your people and places.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>30 Minutes to Midnight</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/party/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/party/</guid>
	  <description>Moise’s father worked for Cosme Car, and a big company like that throws a big party each year to celebrate the passing of the summer solstice. It was a good excuse to dress up and drink. This time of year, the sun never sets on the north of Vekllei. It gently touches the horizon and begins to rise again. Tzipora caught a train up the coast with Moise and his dad and they arrived before seven.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Generation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/new-generation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/new-generation/</guid>
	  <description>Children of the children of the bomb — a generation of war-babies born in peacetime. That was how they thought of themselves. Their grandparents and great-grandparents had lived through the war and the occupation, and so they had inherited the burden of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s future as a country of long-sufferers, visionaries, and dispossessed.
Some Marxist continental intellectual had said something a half-century ago about the right way to teach children, and the idea had probably caught the ear of some commissar of the Vekllei interim government, who perhaps passed it along to some bureaucrat rebuilding the government schools.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Gone Hollywood</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hollywood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hollywood/</guid>
	  <description>You know you’re near the homeland of the Magma-Electric Commission when you smell it. Somewhere between cracking a rotten egg and standing downwind of a sewerage treatment plant, the volcanic heartlands of Vekllei are the playground of the Magma-Electric Commission, often shortened to just “The Magma” or “Thunderburo”. The smell is caused by Hydrogen Sulphide, a byproduct of the naked volcanic activity Vekllei is known for.
Sulphur is everywhere in Vekllei — even in the cities, the drinking water smells of it.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Turning Things Around</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/around/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/around/</guid>
	  <description>His hand was hurting bad, but no one asked him about it the day after. Moise always had a temper, and now he had a reputation. He got no words of sympathy from the other seniors of Lola 8th School.
Considering his bluntness and irritability, it was funny that he could only make good friends with women. His father was a bastard and his mother was in Greece, so his sister took their place.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>How to Speak Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/language/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, https://millmint.net. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.
This post will briefly discuss some elements shown in this infographic, but a large article on the language has been drafted here.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Road Trip</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/road-trip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/road-trip/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin They showed up at the autopool, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem. Moise would drive, Tzipora bunked with Cobian in the passenger seat and Alise, Zo and Jerome could cram into the back.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/uniforms/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.
Depicted here are uniforms for education — Tzipora as a puffling of the Puffin Scouts on the left, and the others in mere school uniforms.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Gentle Enthusiasm</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/enthusiasm/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/enthusiasm/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora stood astride the bicycle luggage rack, and looked at her best friend Moise. She smiled at him, and looked to the town before them, and squinted at the clouds rising over the Atlantic horizon.
It was a warm late summer and there was salt in the air. Pebbles made better swimmers than Tzipora, but from up here she could admire the coast and fill her heart with the breeze.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>So long 2019, here&#39;s to 2020!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/dance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/dance/</guid>
	  <description>Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the new Vekllei discord — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts. Speaking of which, this one is a substitute — the one I’m working on ended up being a bit too sad for an exciting new year, so I’ll put the sad stuff off until Jan 2nd in favour of something happier tomorrow.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>1000 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/1000/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/1000/</guid>
	  <description>Hey everyone,
Hobart here. You might not know it, but I’m sort of a big fucking deal on the internet. No, don’t touch me. Why am I? Because my subreddit just hit 1,000 subscribers. What’s a subreddit? I’m actually laughing at you; imagine not knowing what reddit is. You ingrate.
Seriously though, this whole renewal of the project through a subreddit (rather than disconnected r/worldbuilding posts) has been an amazing thing.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The King</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/king/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/king/</guid>
	  <description>The King and Tzipora do not get along. Zelda met him through Moise, when King managed the Domepent School’s cricket team. Moise was a pretty good wicket keeper.
King had offended Zelda with an off-hand comment on her youthful appearance, and she’d retorted with a remark about his weak blood circulation. Moise, caught between his new boss and his angry Zelda, navigated these stormy waters by ignoring the dispute entirely and separating them on the walk home.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Mafioso and His Witch</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/mafioso/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/mafioso/</guid>
	  <description>Hello, everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s been six days. I&amp;rsquo;d like to have been here sooner, but I had the good fortune to leave my Apple Pencil in a hotel room in Sydney. Although delighted with my welcome and surprising expense (~$150AUD, or roughly 43 bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves), I&amp;rsquo;ve consequently fallen behind with my off-daily illustrations.
However, I carry the ANZAC spirit deep within me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve made use of my time.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Squish!</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/squish/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/squish/</guid>
	  <description>Sorry for breaking my streak everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m on beta software and it totally shit the bed these last couple days. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing my best to hobble along until full release :)
Tzipora is easily squished. In this picture Moise would be around 16, Cobian 15, and Tzipora about 18.
Moise has lost a lot of weight and has been blessed with a hefty frame befitting his temperament. Tzipora &amp;rsquo;s tastes in clothes are specific and mostly unchanging, except for a brief phase a few years after her arrival where she started poaching neckties for her own use.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Introducing Moise</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/moise/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/moise/</guid>
	  <description>Moise was a fat kid who went to another school. Zelda only knew him from the tram, where he carried a criminal stigma because of his rumoured gang affiliations. He was a second-generation Vekllei boy of immigrant Greek heritage. There were a few ethnic gangs in his area, and most immigrant boys that didn’t do well in school quickly found other causes to fight for.
Zelda quickly antagonised the boy by offering him to her own bullies.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Summer sex-ed</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sex-ed/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sex-ed/</guid>
	  <description>Porno is available over-the-counter at most book stores. Some industry associations attempt to limit availability to minors but generally it&amp;rsquo;s at the discretion of the shopkeeper. Often, shame and embarassment are more powerful tools than legislation in Vekllei.
Generally it&amp;rsquo;s pretty traditional stuff supported by columns and fiction, although it varies between pornographers. It&amp;rsquo;s quite common for well-known Vekllei models to end up in nude shoots either before or after their fame.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>summer nerds reading comix</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/princes-of-the-earth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/princes-of-the-earth/</guid>
	  <description>nerds</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>