<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>landscape on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/landscape/</link>
	<description>Recent content in landscape on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/landscape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>A Vekllei Spaceship</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-30-spaceship/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-30-spaceship/</guid>
	  <description>A New Frontier #  The stars are close to Vekllei.
The common availability of space travel is the most wonderful achievement of Vekllei aerospace. It lights the furthest corners of the imagination in the postwar Vekllei spirit of play and dreams. The democratisation of space travel is in fact the democratisation of space itself, and so essential to the realisation of the Vekllei dream — as on Earth, so in the stars.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Municipal</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-08-municipal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-05-08-municipal/</guid>
	  <description>The base unit of Vekllei society are municipalities, called municipolis in their language. They occupy a uniquely intimate presence in Vekllei life as an unusual body of public affairs. Unlike other state bodies in Vekllei, which function similar to their overseas counterparts, local municipalities supersede their conventional definition as mere &amp;lsquo;local governments&amp;rsquo; and are considerably more essential to the wellbeing of Vekllei communities.
In Vekllei, the word municipolis refers to</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Towers in the Park</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-04-24-towers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-04-24-towers/</guid>
	  <description>Merce was one of seven sisters but she didn’t know it. Like many Vekllei people in young adulthood, her parents were born overseas, and so her Spanish heritage was somewhat obscured.
Growing up in postwar Vekllei, you develop an unusual esprit de corps which supersedes almost everything about you — a civic mission to establish a place in the world regardless of your prior circumstance or heritage. This well-intentioned internationalism cut both ways; you were not much judged about where you came from, but you also did not talk much about where you came from.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>In-Between Stations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-16-liminal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-16-liminal/</guid>
	  <description>Out on the branch lines there are in-between stations. Sometimes they emerge out of history as relics of dead and dying towns overlooked by the timetable. Others are a quirk of the rail company machine &amp;ndash; workshops and line junctions where people switch trains. As you get further and further out of the city, and the trains get older and older, these in-between stations become more common. Between Yana and Kotaismoyeh there is an irregular line serviced by steam trains that are over a hundred years old.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>School Lunch</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-13-school-lunch/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-13-school-lunch/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Read more: A Vekllei Breakfast  In Vekllei schools, they take an hour and a half for lunch most days. Food is a complicated subject here, as a ubiquitous demonstration of the Vekllei cultural tradition and its relative scarcity compared to consumer societies.
Food unable to be grown for the house is usually obtained from grocers. Those grocers put in orders for produce from agricultural companies or their representatives — usually ‘petty’ (informal) bureaus.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</guid>
	  <description>As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,
For the people hear us singing, &amp;ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&amp;rdquo;
  As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &amp;ndash;
For they are women&amp;rsquo;s children and we mother them again.
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &amp;ndash;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Rivers of the Atlantic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-01-rivers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-02-01-rivers/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This character was illustrated as a gift to my friend Qweezi. Happy Birthday!  In Vekllei, you met all sorts of people. All nations passed through the Home Islands, some to visit, others to live. Tzipora met a great many of them in her time at school.
Sydney came from Kosava, an anarchist island commune in the Lesser Antilles we know as St Kitts and Nevis. Kosava is an independent member-state of the Kalina Islands, which describes a series of autonomous islands in the Caribbean.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Policing Anarchy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-11-police/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-11-police/</guid>
	  <description>Police in the Epoch of Rest #  Vekllei is a place divided between public and private spaces. The public markets are very public — centralised, controlled, documented and secure. The private markets are very private — anarchic, wide-ranging, interpersonal and unseen. Police in Vekllei work in both of these spaces, maintaining the peace and navigating their unique criminal topography.
Vekllei has three police forces, one for each of its features as a country.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>On Moneylessness</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-09-moneylessness/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-12-09-moneylessness/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This essay was published on millmint.net. Read it here.   Pictured: Tzipora and Cobian cycle around the cliffs in the borough of Totoyan, on Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s East Coast. Up ahead lies the Ocean Atlantique Restaurant and Public Gardens, run by the Totoyan Municipality.
 The Vekllei Person #  What good is more writing about theories and the methodology of country-constructs? More importantly — how is it authentically convincing to the person who has lived their entire lives immersed in their own ways of living?</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Socialism, Backwards</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-20-socialism/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-20-socialism/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora had become interested in the blossoms of Vekllei society around the same time she became aware of them. That’s actually what they were called, in the pidgin of Vekllei ideology — the tenets of petticoat-style socialism were called blossoms.
Vekllei maintains it is not ideological; it is in fact very ideological — you are looking at a state that is afraid of its skeleton. In the dawning weeks after Vekllei’s catastrophic war, the British occupiers (British Recovery Expedition to Vekllei, or BREVEK) released into the streets some 16,000 activists who were rotting away in political prisons.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Coast Guard</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-14-coastguard/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-14-coastguard/</guid>
	  <description>The Vekllei Coast Guard (officially the Navy of the Parliament and distinct from the Navy of the Sovereign, i.e. the “Royal Navy”), is part of the country’s broad paramilitary commission and functions both as a civilian maritime police and military naval fleet depending on the mission.
Most often, its duties are conventional — search and rescue, law enforcement, and maritime patrols across Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s territorial waters and exclusive economic zone. Its civilian parliamentary charter, however, is complicated by its participation in grey-zone operations and presence in international waters, largely as part of Vekllei’s ongoing fight to maintain sovereignty over the Atlantic Ocean and North Sea fish stocks.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Garden City</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-23-garden/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-23-garden/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei is growing; it was an age of wonder. But it was still old enough to smell like wood smoke on cold days, when a thick mist travelled down from the highlands, filling and overflowing the valleys between glaciers, gentle and cool, leaving dew upon you. This is Vekllei; city of water and light.
Wet weather was Tzipora’s favourite because it made Vekllei feel like home. She recognised the smells better than she did the city.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The World’s Last Great Utopia</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-07-map/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-10-07-map/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei is the last great utopia of the world, defying attempts to predict the curve of progress and standing alone in its radical embrace of moneylessness and the goodness of people. This is what it looks like; here are its streets; its cities and villages.
A map lays a framework to conceptualise what the lives of these people might look like. You can seperate nature from the city, and places from the paths.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>ForeignFoto</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-27-foreignfoto/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-09-27-foreignfoto/</guid>
	  <description>Even as Vekllei people suffer, in the postwar troubles and demographic crises of their fledgling utopia, the media apparatuses of Vekllei have become highly skilled at documenting and confronting suffering here and around the world.
Vekllei people are, by any metric, exquisite documentarians. Fifty years ago, all news reporting was subject to censor by the insecure Atlantic Junta. Today, Vekllei has cultivated timely, comprehensive and impactful journalism among its disparate news organisations and film units.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Generation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-21-generation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-21-generation/</guid>
	  <description>Children of the children of the bomb — a generation of war-babies born in peacetime. That was how they thought of themselves. Their grandparents and great-grandparents had lived through the war and the occupation, and so they had inherited the burden of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s future as a country of long-sufferers, visionaries, and dispossessed.
Some Marxist continental intellectual had said something a half-century ago about the right way to teach children, and the idea had probably caught the ear of some commissar of the Vekllei interim government, who perhaps passed it along to some bureaucrat rebuilding the government schools.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>June 21st, 2111</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-12-atomic-war/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-12-atomic-war/</guid>
	  <description>000
CDCDCD DW001 VK
HEAR THIS — THIS IS CIVIL DEFENCE — THIS IS NOT AN EXERCISE. THIS COUNTRY IS UNDER NUCLEAR ATTACK. STAY TUNED TO THIS WAVELENGTH AT 444 KHZ.
IN FIVE MINUTES OR LESS NUCLEAR WEAPONS WILL STRIKE THIS COUNTRY AND INFLICT …MOST CATASTROPHIC DAMAGE UNSEEN SINCE 2005…
YOU ARE IN DANGER AND MUST ACT IMMEDIATELY TO SURVIVE. IT IS TOO LATE TO LEAVE. YOU MUST STAY IN YOUR OWN HOME.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Anxiety, Utopia</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-07-27-anxiety/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-07-27-anxiety/</guid>
	  <description>In the voices we hear, isn&amp;rsquo;t there an echo of now silent ones?
 — Walter Benjamin, On the Concept of History, 1942
Tzipora remembered living in the twilight of the dying world, and how quiet it seemed in Vekllei in those years. It had an effect on the air; on the grass. Tzipora was very good at admiring the mundane, and the spaces it inhabited.
Landscape is all around us, all of the time.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Looking Good and Feeling Good</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-07-21-fashion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-07-21-fashion/</guid>
	  <description>For most of her life, Tzipora dressed how she was told to dress. When she was a child, her clothes were provided. When she started school, the school clothed her. After school, heading west on the trains and picking up work as she found it, she wore whatever she could afford.
Up until her first steps inside the Cozetti Department Store in Vekllei, clothing was for gazing, not for being gazed at.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Quality of Life Surveillance Commission</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-29-qlc/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-29-qlc/</guid>
	  <description>The Quality of Life Surveillance Commission (Q.L.C.) is part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Fair Work Authority, and is one of the most important economic regulators in Vekllei today. In a country without money, you can think of it as the payroll of every Vekllei person — the body responsible for the welfare of Vekllei people.
Although Vekllei does not use money domestically, the country is bound by the Floral Constitution, the Dignity in Employment Act 2016,and the Fair Work Act 2022 to provide regular, measurable increases in the standard of living for Vekllei people.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Compor, Vekllei&#39;s Special Police</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-23-compor/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-23-compor/</guid>
	  <description>Where Tzipora lived in Lola, most people remained of the working class well into the utopian period. Despite their equitable access to the fruits of the country, their housing was poorer and their problems generational. Alcoholism was very common; many of them were veterans of the War in Taiwan. Others were in great pain from their early work in the postwar years, their bodies broken by the demons of manual labour.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Spiritful</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-19-spiritful/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-19-spiritful/</guid>
	  <description>There was not much different about one spirit than another. Foreigners mistook Upen, the animism of Vekllei, for environmentalism — that was not the case at all. Landscapes changed, and so did the things that lived in them.
Of course, humans are sentimental creatures, and they become attached to native things. It is important to seperate human desire — the protection of native plants and animals — and the interests of spirits, since they are not the same.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Heavy Mist</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-11-mist/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-11-mist/</guid>
	  <description>The sky was heavy with grey and water, and it bled into the air. Vekllei’s moon months were here, and with it came the end of Vekllei’s bright summer season. In came the days of coats, mist and darkness.
Tzipora here wears rouisha, loose-fitting felt pants that have been worn in Vekllei for a thousand years. They’re often worn under a skirt, but can be worn alone as trousers if you like.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Air Atomic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-04-air-atomic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-04-air-atomic/</guid>
	  <description>The Royal Vekllei Air Force runs nuclear these days. Just fifty years ago, that would have been unthinkable. Times change.
The Ramoin-Dupont Aircraft Company, with help from the research subsidiary of the absurdly-named “Government Aircraft Factories,” spent about two decades trying to get a reactor to fly. It was easy enough to build a plane around a fission reactor — the problem was keeping the pilot alive. Ramoin-Dupont figured out that, for every megawatt of power, you required about 8 tonnes of rubber and lead shielding — an intolerable figure for a fighter or light aircraft of any kind.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>VNR Orange</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-03-orange/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-03-orange/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei takes a lot from its land. That fact is the bedrock of the Vekllei way of life, in fact — land stewardship and dependency. In this sense, they owe a great debt to the physical landscape of the country, a concept usually translated as the ‘Landscape Sovereign’ in English. The human royals may be long dead, but Vekllei’s flowering petticoat society retains a monarch — the literal physical presence of the land.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Station Logic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei is full of stations in the middle of nowhere; platforms for people in no hurry, alighting to places never thought of before. It is in these stations that old government infrastructure projects take on a greater meaning, and cultivate an absurd sort of spirituality that touches the lives of the people who discover them. Is there anything gentler than a concrete platform in the middle of a flower-tundra, weathered and warmed by the sun?</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>How to Read Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/</guid>
	  <description>This is an unusual post in that, a) it’s particularly text-heavy and desaturated, and b) much of its material is already available on an existing wiki article on my website.
The above article covers the language conceptually in pretty much all the detail you’d ever want. So, despite the heavy use of labels and text, this picture is particularly concerned with the literal appearance and structure of the Vekllei written language, called Topet.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Gone Hollywood</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/</guid>
	  <description>You know you’re near the homeland of the Magma-Electric Commission when you smell it. Somewhere between cracking a rotten egg and standing downwind of a sewerage treatment plant, the volcanic heartlands of Vekllei are the playground of the Magma-Electric Commission, often shortened to just “The Magma” or “Thunderburo”. The smell is caused by Hydrogen Sulphide, a byproduct of the naked volcanic activity Vekllei is known for.
Sulphur is everywhere in Vekllei — even in the cities, the drinking water smells of it.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Vekllei Breakfast</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-09-breakfast/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-09-breakfast/</guid>
	  <description>Postwar Vekllei has a problem. In the old days, many hundreds of years ago, Vekllei’s long, dark winters forced subsistence farmers to preserve their dishes for six or seven months of the year. This changed under the Junta, which opened trade with the Scandinavian powers, and Vekllei soon saw its growing population dependent on fresh imports of oats and grain from Europe. These Atlantic people, whose diets were previously gamey and nomadic, were now a rough storm away from famine.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Shrine-Minded Girls</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/</guid>
	  <description>Shattered fjords make up the north of Vekllei, particularly in boroughs like Santes (lit. Saint) which are well-regarded for their striking cliffs and sloping igneous fingers, which evidence Vekllei’s ongoing volcanism. Offshore, hundreds of islets rise and sink over the centuries.
This is the tiny village of Cult, which sits on the sparse tip of the Grimsy Fjord. It has a local train, but is otherwise only serviced by the Santes regional express — a mere single step up on Vekllei’s train hierarchy.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The People of Vekllei National Rail</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-25-rail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-25-rail/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei National Rail, or VNR, is one of those organisations caught somewhere between a faceless government enterprise and a family member.
Almost every Vekllei person rides a train each day, and that train is operated by VNR, which has a monopoly on rail travel and operation. Very few people know exactly what ‘VNR’ is. Is it a government department? A state-owned company? Or is it a “bureau” — the Vekllei word for a collection of companies?</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Gold Sappers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/</guid>
	  <description>The Venopor (Fedecenoayan porits, lit. Police of the Parliament) are Vekllei’s special police branch. They occupy a function somewhere between special policing and the paramilitary, linking Vekllei’s treasured infrastructure with its civilian police (“Cosmopor”), armed forces, and shadowy intelligence networks. Though they fulfil police functions today, their history is with the Royal Guards and Federal Police of yesteryear, which in turn has produced unusual units like the Gold Sappers, which are unique in modern policing.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei&#39;s New-Age Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</guid>
	  <description>A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.
 — Lu Xun, 1927
 Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &amp;lsquo;backward elements.&amp;rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.
 — Ding Ling on the long-marcher woman soldiers, 1942</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Killing a Sea Serpent</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-17-serpent/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-17-serpent/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Ocean Month in March 2021  In Eyri, the bones of an ancient beast warp and groan in the sun, red skin glinting in the whitecap churn of the shallows, oxidising, broken, ripped open by the sea. Everyone in the North of Vekllei knows about it. Mysteries abound. Even in our atomic century, the humans of Vekllei are enamoured with and terrified by the ocean.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei’s Sprawling Commonwealth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-10-commonwealth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-10-commonwealth/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Ocean Month in March 2021  Welcome again to Ocean Month. If you have questions, just ask.
When we say “Vekllei,” we most often think of the Home Island, the city-state to which the country owes its name. In practice, however, the state of Vekllei is portioned between many far-flung corners of the Atlantic Ocean. From tropical jungles and dry wine-making country to mossy woodlands and arctic deserts, “Vekllei” as a singular concept is obfuscated by its diversity of land and people, and better represents a coalition of disparate Atlantic states than a single, centralised city-state.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Marine Railway</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-06-marine/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-06-marine/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Ocean Month in March 2021  ❖ Note from the Editor Although vessels described here are written with female pronouns as per Western convention, Vekllei traditionally uses male pronouns for navy vessels.  Nuclear Heavy Battlecruiser V.V. Lava is the first of the Lava-class cruisers, the largest of Vekllei’s surface warships. Vekllei doctrine does not typically float cruisers with fleets, and so the Lava often operates independently, outfitted for a variety of roles.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Post is for People</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  Caught amidst sunrays in early Autumn, things are good. You could call almost anyone on the telephone these days. And if you wanted to see someone, why travel? A videophone was just as good. But just as the photograph failed to displace the painter, neither did the telephone or videophone succeed in killing the hand-written letter. There was something thoughtful about it.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Philately Foolery</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  We’re going to do a deep dive on stamps today.
You can tell a domestic Vekllei stamp from its international counterpart quite easily:
 Domestic stamps have a coloured square, called a chromacode, used for sorting mail automatically within the country by a special machine called a kinosemimatia. Domestic stamps do not show a price in Vekllei Kroner, and generally do not use the Vekllei hieroglyph to announce its origin.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Stamp Manufacturie</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  The Stamp Manufacturie of the Royal Mail Press, located on 5th Avenue, churns millions of stamps a year out of its massive drum presses. Stamps are used on mail instead of postcodes, and as payment for the international and courier work the Royal Mail does abroad. Since Vekllei does not use money domestically, Vekllei people do not pay for postage and stamps are used in the automatic sorting system to determine the destination for any Vekllei territory, including its arctic, peripheral and antarctic possessions.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Racing the Post Office to the Station</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  It was the hottest day of June so far, in that time of year where the sun never set on Vekllei. It was the first week of sleepless nights; the windows thrown open, air sticky and pungent with the smells of the rainforests, tossing and turning in the heat.
A stab of panic shot through her as she woke, bleary-eyed and senseless, to the quiet bedside clock.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Fairie</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  The M.S. Fairie Model 54-2 “Mail Hopper” is a strange aircraft. The basic design has remained unchanged for over a hundred years, imported from the United States way back during the massive scrapping of junk warplanes after the Second World War. Even back during the Junta years the country had little respect for foreign intellectual property, and by 1949 had started rolling out Imitation Catalinas, which were among the first indigenous aircraft in the country.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Postmistress of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  Here we have arranged the highest-ranking and lowest-ranking members of the Royal Vekllei Mail (Mail A.r.). On the left is an Office Postgirl, a precursory position tasked with distributing letters in the sprawling bureau complexes abundant in the centralised postwar period. This particular employee is Aleja Hernández, who has decided she’d rather deliver mail than spend another year studying for high school exit exams.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Men and Women of the Royal Mail in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  There are not many postal services older than the Royal Vekllei Mail. It is so old that in the Vekllei language its title is simply ‘Mail’ — the ‘Royal’ and ‘Vekllei’ are implied by the use of its hieroglyph. Founded in 1422 as part of the military communications system between government and mercantile government holdings, it has survived various restructurings — and several wars — to remain a critical communications and cultural institution today.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Robots in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</guid>
	  <description>The Vekllei word for a robot is automasiosn, or ‘automan’. When we talk about Vekllei being a “post-scarcity society,” it is by automen through which it happens. They are found across the entire country in all types of hard and boring work, forever dutiful, forever mindless. It is not that the robot has replaced the human worker, since about 90% of Vekllei people are employed. Instead, the automan takes its place in the necessary evils of industrial society, fulfilling the wildest fantasies of utopian industrialists; the factory is no longer just the place of the machine, it is in fact a machine itself.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</guid>
	  <description>The New Year in Vekllei rings out during its months of darkness and cold. This calendar runs the regular affairs of the country, like it does the modern world. To Vekllei people, however, it is plain that New Years occurs not in darkness but instead in the summer solstice in June, the way it has for thousands of years in the dramatic cycles of light and dark in the country. In this sense, the end of December resonates among businesses and little else, much like the financial year elsewhere.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Army</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-30-army/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-30-army/</guid>
	  <description>There’s a thousand years of history in Vekllei’s armed forces, though you’ll find very little of it recalled casually today. Almost everything about Vekllei’s prewar society was scorched by the bombs, and the scraps of military infrastructure that survived were appropriated in the subsequent British occupation.
Since independence, a slate has been wiped clean, and a modern fighting force has replaced the colonial legions and battleships of yesteryear. Since reestablishment, Vekllei’s mettle has been tested in the jungles of Taiwan and the arctic deserts alike, and have proven themselves to be a rugged, versatile army of considerable bravery and fighting strength in spite of poor equipment in the bankruptcy of independence.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bea and the Mosses</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-08-bea/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-08-bea/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This character was illustrated as a gift to Bike. Happy Birthday!  This is Bea, an energetic Botanist with the Landscape Bureau of Vekllei. People know her as an eccentric young woman easily persuaded by cottage-fashions, but she takes her work very seriously and spends most of her waking hours documenting the dense temperate rainforests of Vekllei’s coastal lowlands. These are not particularly adventurous expeditions — most of her work is performed along old trails and paths, but Bea finds the sublime amidst the mundane and has contributed enormously to the ecological understanding of local flora in the borough of Holsyim, where she was born.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Crown Land of No King</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/</guid>
	  <description>It would be misleading to characterise Vekllei as environmentalist in the usual idea of the word. Vekllei is no such thing. This is obvious in subtle ways, like Newda’s Dumousiantopet, or “beautiful and seperate,” which advocates the separation of human and natural design. It is also policy; Vekllei is dependent on its landscape as part of Autosuffisouitopet, or “self-sustenance,” and to this end sinks forests for hydroelectric dams and topples mountains for novel urban projects.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Coming to Grips</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-01-grips/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-01-grips/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin  She would spend a long time by the rivulet that ran behind her apartment. She would do the housework and hang the wash out, then watch the water trickle past in the sun.
She tried to open a jar the other day and started to cry when she couldn’t get it open. She never cried once when she saw those things in America, or got beat to shit, but these days she cried over jam.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Out of The Ground and Into The Light</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-28-city/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-28-city/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin   NO REALTORS EXCEPT THE STATE ■ THE COUNTY THE AGENT OF THE STATE ■ THE ARCHITECT THE AGENT OF THE COUNTY
 It is clear that in Vekllei democracy is a way of living more than it is a form of government. After all, by metrics of representation, the Atlantic nation&amp;rsquo;s electoral system often sputters and fails, undermined by the bundling of the human and natural votes as equal, and the wildly disproportionate borough system.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>How to Speak Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin  For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, https://millmint.net. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.
This post will briefly discuss some elements shown in this infographic, but a large article on the language has been drafted here.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>21st Century Witch</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin  When the light shifted just right, the ceramic tiles and concrete footpaths twinkled like water off the back of a swan. 16th Century witches could build a hut in the woods and forage for herbs; 21st Century witches were susceptible to modernist persuasions.
The Demotic Meeting Hall was constructed twenty years prior as the main meeting hall of the National Dockworker’s Union.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Petrol Heaven — The Rohsm STR-750</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The Rohsm STR series is a small racer built for clubs by Rohsm S.p.M., a hundred-year-old company headquartered in the Mediterranean racing culture of Tohs. Its most recent variant, the 750, is available in limited quantities to enthusiast owners and club pools. Like most petrol cars in Vekllei, they are built by hand, so no two 750s drive exactly alike.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mittens and Metaphysic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin   Pictured above: various fashions worn by Vekllei women, showcasing heavy cold-weather dresses, simple styling, strong geometric shapes and colours, loose fits, and modest hemlines.
  Pictured below: postmodern neomarxism, which I’ve tricked you into reading with anime.
 Previous posts on the Vekllei economy, if you’re new:
 Sundress Municipalism and how it works Macroeconomics and currency in a country with no money  Vekllei’s obvious contradictions are commonly referenced, but not always clear.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.
Depicted here are uniforms for education — Tzipora as a puffling of the Puffin Scouts on the left, and the others in mere school uniforms.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin   On the morning of the second day, I watched a fly crawl across the cheek of the middle-aged woman, probably an office worker, lying next to me. It moved up her cheekbone to her temple, stopping now and then to rub its front legs as though performing a ritual. A jagged tear ran down the leg of her dark blue work trousers, but the white calf it revealed was miraculously unscathed.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rural Newda in Rural Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Newda is Vekllei’s national architectural ideology, applied flexibly in a range of modernist styles developed domestically in her architecture schools. Broadly, Newda buildings emphasise distinction from the surrounding landscape (called Dumousiantopet, or ‘beautiful and seperate’), natural decay, and honesty in material and construction. Vekllei’s great Parliament House is Newda; as are the little rural homes found in the mountains inland in Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Thousand-Year-Old Girl</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The concept of living forever jumps out at people uncomfortable with their own existence. There is a contemplative instinct among educated people that — if they could simply will themselves into a state of self-actualisation — death would only be an obstacle to greatness.
As Tzipora found out quickly, the opposite was true — death and temporality were wells of meaning against which all great people, beauty, and human constructions were cast.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The 31st Century</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The Epoch of Rest #  We’ve spent a lot of time in the 21st century — but Tzipora is biologically immortal. Where does she go from here? Well, let’s enjoy a small glimpse at that future together, by winding the clock forward one thousand years.
By 3076, our Solar System is a pleasant place to be. Most of the planets we once gazed at from afar are now habitable and lived on.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Summer House in the Azores</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The Azores had been a possession of Vekllei since 2002, when they were leased from Portugal indefinitely. The lease was defunct by the time of Vekllei’s independence from U.K. occupation in 2015, and the new state took formal ownership over the small Atlantic islands.
The Azores was Vekllei’s resort region, often called simply the “holiday isles”. Brief reprieves from the North Atlantic cold were granted to hundreds of thousands domestic tourists each year in resorts and holiday rentals alike.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Race for Inefficiency</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Vekllei’s advocation of austerity, apathy, and playfulness as economic principles #  This post is about the economy of Vekllei. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a long one. If you have any questions, just ask.
Overview of the Bureau System #  There are many thousands of companies busy with work in Vekllei. The vast majority of these companies are single-person shops (S.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.
 Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or venopor) Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or cosmopor)  A young venopor officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike cosmopor, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Map of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Map Key
 Red: Magjet trains, 750km/h
Yellow: Bullet trains, 300-400km/h
Orange: Regional trains, &amp;lt;150km/h
Brown: Local trains, including limited express, &amp;lt;100km/h
Blue: National highway
Dashed: Ferry line
Green: tarmacadamed airport
 The largest division of any portion of Vekllei land is the borough; a region of varying size and population with common culture, food dependency and economic interest.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Crown</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country. At no point do coins or paper currency change hands in the day-to-day affairs of the country.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Village Map of Montre-Lola</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The village of Montre-Lola is home to about 400 people in its entirety, a stone’s throw from the Aisyo borough. Each morning, however, the population swells as 300 children from tiny villages in both Aisyo and Montre take a fast tram to the Montre-Lola Area School No. 2, a district school raising all ages of local youth.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Oa-Class Battlecruiser</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Vekllei’s defensive military posture has, in doctrine and arms development, limited its ability to meaningfully project power outside of the Atlantic. As an island nation with a large and multifaceted naval armada, the Oa-Class Battlecruiser is the heart of her armed forces, as the flagship of her fleets.
Where U.S. doctrine places carriers offensively in the structure of its ship-groups, the Vekllei Navy is considerably more Soviet in its employ of carriers as primarily defensive air-bases to exercise sovereignty over her far-flung territories and island possessions.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Canal Living</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad. Nothing was trucked. Fish was traded fresh in markets or turned into emulsifiers and fertiliser.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Fission Cloud at Vekllei&#39;s 50th Anniversary</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  In an unprecedented event, during Vekllei’s 50th Sea Festival since Independence in 2065, an 8 kiloton fission bomb was sunk to a depth of 150 meters and detonated at midday. It was an incredible sight on a day so clear you could see the gentle curve of the earth where it met the horizon. A flash of light and a spray dome surged outwards into the quiet Atlantic, which was broken apart by plumes that formed a column of water that climbed high into the sky.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.
Still, by late October, the the earth is hard with cold and the days are short.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>2031 Apartment Diagram</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Baron had inherited the apartment from his uncle, who passed in the year following his parents. It was in a mixed residential-industrial neighbourhood, adjacent to a canvas factory. Out back was a rivulet, which roared in the long rainstorms of early April.
 Each January, the Colour Bureau of the Architecture Assembly announces the year’s colours, and tradition in mainstream architecture and interior design is to incorporate the announced palettes, which usually contain a hundred or so colours.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Fiery Peaks</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  After three days in Ada, Tzipora set off towards Mt Miya. She made good time, and after three hours had happened upon the shoulders of the bright Volouisnesnkull Glacier. It was about here that she heard a morbid industrial siren, echoing up the valleys from far away.
At first she thought it might have come from Ada, since Boya Chemical had a large plant there, but as she lay out her things for lunch she heard the distinct whine of a turbojet.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Chemical Feast</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  East of Montre, West of Tjornes, waits a rare sight among Vekllei’s hard igneous slopes — a crown of gentle sedimentary cliffs packed with ruddy sandstone, which melt glacially into the sea chasing blue-sky bergs.
Tzipora was, at the time, making her way on foot from Montre-Lola to Ada, which was a coastal town in the North-East known for its luxurious health spas.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Life in Montre-Lola</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</guid>
	  <description>Tomorrow: 2020 Complete Guide to Vekllei
Today:
 Up in the ro, the Vekllei flower-tundra home to spirits and people alike, green slopes and igneous monument make an ample crucible for myth and magic.
 Out here, there was a very keen sense of place and purpose. “Landscape” was neither revered nor ignored, since it did not exist here altogether. Every hill, rock and tree was taken at face value in its full honesty, with commodity dead and modernism suppressed.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Gentle Enthusiasm</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-23-enthusiasm/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-23-enthusiasm/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora stood astride the bicycle luggage rack, and looked at her best friend Moise. She smiled at him, and looked to the town before them, and squinted at the clouds rising over the Atlantic horizon.
It was a warm late summer and there was salt in the air. Pebbles made better swimmers than Tzipora, but from up here she could admire the coast and fill her heart with the breeze.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Ou Hydroburo Office</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/</guid>
	  <description>Almost any other venrouive national bureau is more glamorous than Vekllei’s Hydroburo, but that fact does not detract from the organ’s critical function.
Although the sophisticated age of robotics demands the incredible yield of nuclear fission, a significant minority of Vekllei’s electricity is produced by hydroelectric dams, which are jointly operated by the Thunderburo and Hydroburo. Hydroelectricity appeals to the common Vekllei person strategically and culturally.
First, where the nature of fission demands operational stability and exceptionally well-trained personnel that might be vulnerable to nuclear strikes, estimates by the War Department suggest the country’s hydroelectric dams would survive a nuclear strike, and would be operational shortly after a war.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>AB/NI’s Spectres of Violence</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/</guid>
	  <description>The Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), a semiautonomous organ of the covert operations council of the War Department, is recognised as the busiest of the continental bureaus. There is a lot to be busy with — the Dallas Secession, the Brazilian invasion of Bolivia, the Dallas nuclear lend-lease, and the reliability of Venezuelan oil production are all of some concern to Vekllei, and so AB/NI proactively has fingers in those pies.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ghosts of Taiwan in the Yana Lakehouse</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-05-lakehouse/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-05-lakehouse/</guid>
	  <description>By 2047, Vekllei had a lot of broken men. Tens of thousands had alighted troop ships at the end of the War of Taiwan, only to find that pieces of their lives had unravelled overseas. Hardy, bronze-skinned boys were left with their ghosts, and those ghosts introduced them to drinking, and brawling, and suicide.
 As part of the Birmingham Convention and the second round of the Commonwealth War Trials, a young and recently defeated Vekllei nation was chained to a conflict that was beginning to fester in East Asia.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Montre, City of Learning</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-03-learning/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-03-learning/</guid>
	  <description>The Montre Prefecture of the Vekllei city-state is among the most learned urban landscapes in the world. In the days of the monarchy, it had been an unremarkable city, home to the empire’s submarine fleet. It was obliterated by bombs in the war, and the &amp;ldquo;new Montre&amp;rdquo; that has blossomed in its place is nourished by its ashes.
Among the most prolific creatures in Vekllei’s academic elite, including prestigious folk like physicist Thomas Weihennet and Chief Engineer of General Reactor Maya Ou, almost all of them were educated in Montre.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ego Death and Upen&#39;s Spiritual Rebirth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-01-ego/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-01-ego/</guid>
	  <description>The Beach was a small part of herself.
Another stroke on the Hell Screen
She washed ashore
Two dollars were in the sand
A hound had come here to rest
Damp cotton touched green water
She thought of what she was doing here
Of what the night invoked
Hot sand met a rising wind
It happened again
She realised
There was not a single dog left to fight
Among the whitecap constellations</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Great Ro Highlands</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-11-highlands/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-11-highlands/</guid>
	  <description>As I pick up some larger projects, my posts here will slow down a little bit. That&amp;rsquo;s okay &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m still easy to track down and get in touch with, and you guys will still see the best stuff.
I post a lot of sketches to the Vekllei Discord, which is something between a fan club and a social club for the project. Check the #utopia channel for little artworks like this one.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Girl and the Sublime</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-19-sublime/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-19-sublime/</guid>
	  <description>When Tzipora moved to study English and Vekllei literature at the university of Montre in 2075, she had to walk from the little home where she lived to Montre-Lola’s old concrete platform, which facilitated a single electric railcar each way, each day. If she was feeling lively, she could make it to the platform in a half hour. On the days where she dreaded sighting her plimsolls in the shoebox, it might take forty-five minutes.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Traditional Dress in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora, illustrated here, is happy because her traditional dress makes her feel stylish and her cape is soft and warm.
Vekllei is an ancient culture with many inherited and vestigial artefacts. Nowhere is this more apparent than in her national dress, particularly that for women, where old and new collide as they do all across Vekllei. Pre-war, post-war and future are present here. Let’s run through some of the elements, which can be found throughout her society.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Valleys of the Wind</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-04-wind/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-04-wind/</guid>
	  <description>The summer had rolled into the valley, and so the air smelled of hot grass from the fields. It was quiet at the station, where a single train clacked each way in the afternoon. The only sound was the wind, which caught the heads of dry grass and roared up the slopes of the mountain ranges around her.
It seemed an exaggeration to even call it a station, since the bare concrete slab had been laid fifty years ago and left to crumble.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Kodak Moment by a Vekllei Geyser</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</guid>
	  <description>In her journal for practicing writing the Vekllei language (appropriately called Vekllei), Tzipora wrote:
 The heavy clouds above were children of early spring, but among the steam vents it seemed like the whole sky was polluted by geysers. Large pools, opalescent with healthy minerals, were heated by the core of the Earth. In a volcanic desert of black sand, the geysers were an oasis, rising from the sulphuric fog like a little eden.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Life and Death in Vekllei Apartment Ideology</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/</guid>
	  <description>To substitute for my shocking (and deeply shameful) absence over the last two weeks, please accept a longer-form post concerning domestic Apartment Ideology in Vekllei, which they call Newda and is known internationally as The Vekllei Newda School. Pictured is the apartment of our very own Zelda. While the building itself deserves a feature, for now we’ll discuss Newda as a theory and her life in this building. If you get bogged down and pissed off at the jargon, skip to the “practice” section.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A “Horizon Wing” Atomic Passenger Jet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/</guid>
	  <description>Click here for a view inside the wing.
Although the CN-1 Horizon Wing passenger jet was not a “flying wing,” that didn’t stop Comen Aeroyards, the manufacturer, from celebrating it as such. Much like similar large-wing aircraft from McDonnell and de Havilland, the CN-1’s large vertical stabilisers and obvious centre fuselage precluded it from qualifying as an authentic “flying wing,” which were already common in many air forces at this time.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Inside VOA’s “Flying Wing” Atomic Passenger Jet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-09-wing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-09-wing/</guid>
	  <description>In this limited cross-section of a CN-1 “Horizon” Wing, the scale of the aircraft is immediately impressed upon the reader. It is nearly four times as wide as the older wide-body passenger jets of yesteryear, and twice as wide as most American and European supersonic jets. It is no coincidence that the “flying wing” concept was only made possible by the development of supersonic jetport infrastructure, with their wide and long runways, at the turn of the century.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Wallabies of the Arctic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-06-wallabies/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-06-wallabies/</guid>
	  <description>8 days without posts feels like a century. Tomorrow, SkyMonth returns, and we’ll see what it’s like flying VAS. The day after tomorrow we’ll see an update for a few things — particularly a massive (and awesome) overhaul of the Vekllei site + wiki. Yeah, if you’re wondering where I’ve been, I’ve ditched Wordpress and have been learning HTML, which is like scraping the exposed brain against unpolished concrete. And after that there will be a lot more posts to follow to make up for the silence</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ocean-liners of the Sky — Vacuum Dirigibles in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-24-dirigible/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-24-dirigible/</guid>
	  <description>Sorry it took so long, mateys. I&amp;rsquo;ve been laying the first pages of the comic down and it&amp;rsquo;s like crack for me. Not much sleep and totally fell behind on SkyMonth. But, as any longtime members know, our Months are r/vekllei usually last a little longer than they should past their expiry date. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to come!
 The Angel and Memory of the People of Vekllei is the largest and most recent of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s airships.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Air Stewards in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-19-stewards/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-19-stewards/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  Although Vekllei’s flag-carrying airline might appear just one of many in the small island country, don’t be fooled — all civilian aviation operates under a venrouive bureau excitingly titled the Vekllei Air Service (Skyburo), which operates several distinct ‘airlines’ but wholly controls all of them. In Vekllei economic lexicon, a bureau is the largest trade union of an industry, made up of many hundreds of others, and is partially beholden to the direction of government.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ten corpses in the snow</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/</guid>
	  <description>&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve just pulled a body from an air force jet here that looks like General MacMillan, and we really need to know right now if it&amp;rsquo;s him.”
The partially buried remains of a U.S. Air Force passenger aircraft are the only blemish on the horizon of central Greenland’s frigid snowscape. It is the site of one of the greatest political scandals in American history. The ancient landscape was violently disturbed in late December of 2068, when a Grumman Atomcat slammed into the ground, killing all 10 people on board.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Jetport Guide shuffles Americans onto the airport maglevs</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-07-tourist/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-07-tourist/</guid>
	  <description>It is very difficult to obtain papers for tourism in Vekllei as an American, despite the fact that the Arctic island nation is positioned obstinately between the Americas and Europe. It’s not made difficult for any discernible political reason, either — relations with the U.S. are as good as they could be for a country like Vekllei. Nonetheless, tourism is regarded as a risk rather than an opportunity, and most Americans who visit for pleasure are wealthy enough to put up the sums of cash required to enter on the national carriers that exclusively operate in Vekllei’s airspace.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Vekllei Timetable</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-06-timetable/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-06-timetable/</guid>
	  <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s wind down Study Month with a look into the Vekllei curriculum. A few days ago I wrote about how Vekllei schools operate on fundamentally different assumptions about what it means to be ‘a child’. Let’s take a look at how that pans out in practice.
Most students study about 3-5 days a week, depending on the taste of the student and the work timetable of their parents. These days might occur sequentially or be scattered throughout the week, but most common is a Monday-Wednesday table table of four hours a day.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>High-stakes air racing</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-02-racing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-02-racing/</guid>
	  <description>Each year, a race is held amongst the most remarkable geological monuments of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s interior. Steep mountains forged in the restlessness of the European and American tectonic plates become deadly checkpoints in the world&amp;rsquo;s most high-stakes aeroplane race in the Western Hemisphere.
Low-speed, high-maneuverability jets (manufactured by the likes of General Reactor, V.K. Heavy Industries, and Kaleidoscope Aerospace) roar through narrow valleys in time trials that last only a few minutes.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Schools in a Society Without Children</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-01-schools/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-01-schools/</guid>
	  <description>Let’s talk about childhood and utopia. This post comes as we wind down Study Month in r/vekllei. Strap in kids, because this one gets kind of heavy.
 When you get into the idea of it, “The Child” is a particularly unfortunate projection. It’s not something most would agree with, but that’s how it’s worked out in the late 2070s. In fact, critical foundations of how foreigners view the world are not culturally neutral subjects as they might assume, timeless and naturally occurring, but are in fact symptoms of ideology.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Emotional Intelligence in the Epoch of Rest</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-25-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-25-love/</guid>
	  <description>Let’s talk about childhood and utopia. This post comes as we wind down Study Month in r/vekllei. Strap in kids, because this one gets kind of heavy.
  Tzipora and Cobian, pictured here, have very different stories but both have felt something was not quite right about them. That difference, so it would turn out, would blossom into a preference for women as partners, in the unusual desexualised way Vekllei goes about homosexuality in the late 2070s.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Boyhood Fashion in Vekllei&#39;s School Halls</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-24-school-fashion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-24-school-fashion/</guid>
	  <description>This is a follow-up to this post, as part of Vekllei’s “Study Week,” where we’re touring education and youth in the utopia of Vekllei.
Compared to their girls, who are adorned with many layers of clothing and dazzling patterns, the schoolboys of Vekllei are unadorned. Lace and quarter-pleats give way to bolder forms and masculine colours.
As much of Vekllei’s uniform ideology straddles complex (and often precipitous) schisms of modern and traditional clothing items, boys have received considerably more progressive attention than their sisters.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Uniform Ideology in the Arctic North</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-17-uniform-ideology/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-17-uniform-ideology/</guid>
	  <description>Hello everyone. In celebration of the approach of exams (at least in the Southern Hemisphere), we turn our gaze north to Vekllei to celebrate Study Week. Every other day we’ll be looking at education in Vekllei, and today we’re looking at uniforms.
Life in Vekllei is filled with uniforms for work and in study, for a various historical and cultural reasons. In the late 21st century, in a society where work is social, they help distinguish and professionalise employment, which grants important psychological and social benefits.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tattoos of Violence on Quiet Men</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-14-tattoos/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-14-tattoos/</guid>
	  <description>Where tattoos had once been an indication of class and work, they were now uncommon. Both class and work had been abolished. Tattoos were almost never seen in the prism of ordinary Vekllei life, but in less savoury occupations they were found where utopian concessions collide with violence and memory.
Baron rolled up his sleeves and laid them out for her. You could accuse him of many things — he was a reticent bloke — but he was never dishonest with Tzipora.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Showdown</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-11-showdown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-11-showdown/</guid>
	  <description>It is not uncommon for gangs to form in Vekllei, especially among immigrant communities otherwise marginalised by a complex logographic language and rigid belief system.
In fact, in a country of plenty, there is not much to otherwise identify with. Class is irrelevant in utopia, and the basic ideas of manhood and womanhood are being destroyed in hand with the abolishment of industry. Racial identifiers certainly exist — the population is descended almost entirely from Scandinavian settlers (with notably fair hair) and those of mixed Inuit-Scandinavian ancestry, whom carry Caucasian features but have dark, often black, hair.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The State of the Moon in 2078</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-28-moon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-28-moon/</guid>
	  <description>Welcome again to MoonMonth! It started a week ago and will go until I’ve said all I can say. We’re looking at how Vekllei conquered the moon today.
Vekllei unequivocally won the space race. Not because it had the first man in space — the Soviets succeeded in that. Nor were they the first to the moon — the Americans had been there for nearly a century. But Vekllei was the first to establish permanent habitation of the Moon’s southern pole, and its claims of territory were reluctantly accepted in the early 2070s after nearly a decade of heated diplomacy.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Puffin Scouts</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-27-puffins/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-27-puffins/</guid>
	  <description>MoonMonth will return tomorrow. As an interlude&amp;hellip;
 In Winter 2064, the changes made to the constitution of the Boy Scouts of America (BSA) would be felt around the scouting world. By this point it was pretty clear that the globe had entered a “helter skelter” decline towards tragedy. The emerging fission technologies were too slow and expensive to mass produce, and the fossil fuels that lighted homes around the world were starting to run dry.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Living in Tomorrow, Facing the Past</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-22-tomorrow/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-22-tomorrow/</guid>
	  <description>Welcome again to MoonMonth! It started four days ago and will go until I’ve said all I can say. We’re looking at the space industry in Vekllei. This is just a quick piece I&amp;rsquo;ve done between some larger things.
The Copette Science Basin and Rocket Factory launches sixteen rockets a day. Those rockets are packed with robotic mining equipment and are sent chasing asteroids floating through our solar system. The robots return sometime in the following year with an asteroid rich with metals in tow, where they are incinerated upon entry and many tonnes of metals are plunged into empty drop zones in the Atlantic.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A space tourist contemplates her first moonwalk</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-21-moonwalk/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-21-moonwalk/</guid>
	  <description>Welcome to MoonMonth, which started two days ago and will go until I’ve said all I can say. These posts are going to work a little differently — we’re going to follow Tzipora through her adventures in Moon City and beyond, and learn about the moon in this world along the way. Strap in!
 Vekllei has put a great deal of effort into developing infrastructure for tourism across the lunar surface of the Vekllei Moon Zone.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Holiday on the Moon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-19-moon-holiday/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-19-moon-holiday/</guid>
	  <description>Caption: “So — Mr Spaceman… How long have you held a job at Vekllei National Astrospace? 37 years?”
 Like most Vekllei people, Tzipora has visited the moon. From Ground Control on Earth in the district of Huay, Vekllei operates many moonbases, domes, research facilities and tourist opportunities in the moon’s southern hemisphere within a large complex called Moidonnet — Moon City. It sits a hundred kilometres south of Mt Io (called Malapert Mountain in the West) in the Vekllei Moon Zone.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Expo’74 Experimental Molten-Salt Peace Reactor</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-15-reactor/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-15-reactor/</guid>
	  <description>Only had time for a quick painting tonight. Bigger things soon, after I get some things out of the way&amp;hellip;
 Expo’74 was the 2074 World’s Fair, hosted in Vekllei for the first time in nearly a century. The country had made tremendous progress in recovery from the First Atomic War, and set to work nearly a decade in advance of the Expo to create a palatial fairgrounds between the districts of the Capital and Ro.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Face of War in the 21st Century</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-08-war/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-08-war/</guid>
	  <description>This is a story about Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s consumption and disposal of soldiers through her foreign fighting force. You can read more about the Vekllei army in these old posts here and here.
The Vekllei de ra Couismenan Desnepotet, or the Vekllei Foreign Army, is an exclusively foreign fighting force employed by the National War Bureau. It accepts any person between the ages of 18 and 35. After five years or being wounded, the soldier is granted Vekllei citizenship, making the Foreign Army one of the only guaranteed ways to secure citizenship in the country.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tesmosnen, the Festival of Fasting</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-07-festival/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-07-festival/</guid>
	  <description>In the quaint ocean country of Vekllei, during their years of fecundity and fun, the calendar is divided into twelve festivals of various celebration and purpose. They include the Festival of the Sea in October, which celebrates Vekllei’s vast fishing navy and concludes with the detonation of a nuclear weapon off Vekllei’s coast, to the Festival of the Moon in January, which is quiet and acknowledged only through personal ceremony and decorations.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Most Complex Machine, the Autokinotheodolite</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-06-machine/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-06-machine/</guid>
	  <description>Hey everyone, I drew this a little while back after getting back from Woomera, South Australia. Woomera&amp;rsquo;s a closed government town that tests missiles. Not my finest illustration, but it is what it is.
Deep in the mountains around Montre, above a tangle of submerged forts and ballistic missile silos, there sits a Vekllei Rocketry Corps test facility called the Strawberry Site. From the peaks of the surrounding mountains, should you evade the helicopter patrols and dog teams, you can witness the next thirty years of missile technology unfolding before you.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Mountain Railway</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-04-railway/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-04-railway/</guid>
	  <description>Many dozens of little trains wind their way around mountain peaks in the centre of Vekllei. They stop at upland villages and towns of sometimes only a few dozen people, before consolidating into larger terminuses that connect nearly every village in Vekllei by rail. It is possible, should the timetables align, that you can reach the capital from any part of the country in under 2 hours.
This sprawling rail network is ubiquitous with the Vekllei landscape, where images of simple agricultural life coincide with a train or tram.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Valley of Faith and Sorrow</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-02-valley/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-02-valley/</guid>
	  <description>On her days off from her place of work in the village library, Zelda would descend the slope of the village into a great basin of creeks and flower-tundra. In the summer, when it was warm enough to sit in the sun, you could sit at one end of the valley and admire the wind rushing to meet you as it whipped through fields of flowers. For a few moments you could admire yourself for what you were — a small being in a landscape as old as the Earth.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Noble Helijet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-28-helijet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-28-helijet/</guid>
	  <description>Fourteen girls from the 23rd Chapel Explorer’s Club and two of their supervisors have been airlifted to safety after heavy rains overran the banks of the Rumoisen rivulet. The girls, aged between 10 and 16, found themselves stranded on the southern face of Mt Resner for three nights after the single bridge to the area’s trails was washed away in Thursday’s storm.
Clear skies Saturday allowed air rescue services from Montre to reinforce the tiny Rumoisen Village fire brigade, and by Sunday morning a mammoth rescue operation involving two 45th Brigade helijets and several rescue teams brought Rumoisen’s girls home to safety.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sweat and Ink in the Vekllei News Agency</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-27-vna/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-27-vna/</guid>
	  <description>Tanny was twenty-five and as colourful as her flaming red hair implied. She was a once-in-a-generation editor, the kind of person who absorbed grammar rules on magical wavelengths beyond mortal comprehension and proceeded to violently enforce them. This was compounded by the Vekllei language, with its sublanguages and logography, leading to daily shouting matches in The Atlantic’s newsroom over sentence structure and colour as language. Although only a copy editor, there was no doubt in anyone’s mind that she would be head honcho one day.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Neighbourhood Cruiser</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-22-cruiser/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-22-cruiser/</guid>
	  <description>The foundations of a Vekllei neighbourhood, repeated so often to foreigners and children, is the community — a group of people larger than a family but small enough to have valuable social bonds through work and shared spaces. In a society without currency, value is almost entirely derived from your immediate surrounds.
Municipal police, as distinct from Venrouiva police, appear in many different roles in Vekllei communities. There are officers as we’d understand them, but there are also many employees of the municipal police that deal exclusively with social work, mental health and substance dependency.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Supermarkets in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-19-supermarket/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-19-supermarket/</guid>
	  <description>In Vekllei, the economy is a social organ that lingers awkwardly between cultural and political interests. On one hand, the country is regressing (both politically and culturally) towards deindustrialised, decommodified life. On the other, it is irreversibly equipped with the benefits of automation and robotics, rendering large swathes of the labour-force obsolete. Work is now, for most purposes, a creative organ that facilitates society, culture and technology. This has led to a society not unlike most planned economies, in which employment is both essential and unnecessary, leading to vast wastage and consumption at scales a market would see as horrifically inefficient but in Vekllei is understood as an enormous social benefit.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Cherry Car</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-17-cherry/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-17-cherry/</guid>
	  <description>A road trip around Vekllei in the summer is an experience that makes life worth living. In some ways, it is a spiritual detox than reinvigorates a person with the intimate, elusive premise of the Vekllei spiritual enlightenment. In others, it is a way of returning to the earth, and understanding the human place in the principles of Upen.
No matter your intention, be it holiday or rediscovery, the very best of Vekllei is on display.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</guid>
	  <description>I’m starting a series looking at the lives and machines of domestic Vekllei life.
Vekllei National Railways, or ‘VK Rail’ was the bastard of six major pre-war rail companies that were extinguished along with the society that housed them. Today there are three rail companies in Vekllei, but all of them operate under direct supervision of a Vekllei Industry Bureau (making it Venrouiva, in other words) and are only broken up for reasons of logistics.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>