<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>landscape on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/categories/landscape/</link>
    <description>Recent content in landscape on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/landscape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>City / Forest Living</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-20-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-20-landscape/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   In Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s vast interior, there are large areas of uninhabited land designated as off-limits terra nullius. This is kronaismioudelfia, or &amp;ldquo;crown land,&amp;rdquo; named for the Upen&amp;rsquo;s perception of all living creatures as god-kings rather than Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s historical monarchy.
It is very important to make a distinction between the modern nation-state and Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s preconception of itself.
This is a forced pacifism hoisted upon themselves, a disciplined fear integral to the deeper psychospiritual intuition within Upen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Speak Vekllei, and A New Website</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, https://millmint.net. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.
This post will briefly discuss some elements shown in this infographic, but a large article on the language has been drafted here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of The Ground and Into The Light</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-23-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-23-city/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here    A NEW WAY FOR MAN BY WAY OF FAIR USE OF THE MACHINE AND SOCIAL COORDINATION ■ LAND DISTRIBUTED BY THE STATE TO BE HELD ONLY BY USE AND IMPROVEMENTS ■ NO REALTORS EXCEPT THE STATE ■ THE COUNTY THE AGENT OF THE STATE ■ THE ARCHITECT THE AGENT OF THE COUNTY
 Decentralisation and integration are the foundations of Sundress Municipalism, as core to life experience in the country as moneylessness or petticoatism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st Century Witch</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   When the light shifted just right, the ceramic tiles and concrete footpaths twinkled like water off the back of a swan. 16th Century witches could build a hut in the woods and forage for herbs; 21st Century witches were susceptible to modernist persuasions.
The Demotic Meeting Hall was constructed twenty years prior as the main meeting hall of the National Dockworker’s Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petrol Heaven — The Rohsm STR-750</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   The Rohsm STR series is a small racer built for clubs by Rohsm S.p.M., a hundred-year-old company headquartered in the Mediterranean racing culture of Tohs. Its most recent variant, the 750, is available in limited quantities to enthusiast owners and club pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mittens and Metaphysic — Product Atheism and Vekllei object-form</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.    Pictured above: various fashions worn by Vekllei women, showcasing heavy cold-weather dresses, simple styling, strong geometric shapes and colours, loose fits, and modest hemlines.
  Pictured below: postmodern neomarxism, which I’ve tricked you into reading with anime.
 Previous posts on the Vekllei economy, if you’re new:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.    On the morning of the second day, I watched a fly crawl across the cheek of the middle-aged woman, probably an office worker, lying next to me. It moved up her cheekbone to her temple, stopping now and then to rub its front legs as though performing a ritual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Newda in Rural Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.    Newda is Vekllei’s national architectural ideology, applied flexibly in a range of modernist styles developed domestically in her architecture schools. Broadly, Newda buildings emphasise distinction from the surrounding landscape (called Dumousiantopet, or ‘beautiful and seperate’), natural decay, and honesty in material and construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thousand-Year-Old Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   The concept of living forever jumps out at people uncomfortable with their own existence. There is a contemplative instinct among educated people that — if they could simply will themselves into a state of self-actualisation — death would only be an obstacle to greatness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 31st Century — Vekllei throughout our Solar System</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   The Epoch of Rest #  We’ve spent a lot of time in the 21st century — but Tzipora is biologically immortal. Where does she go from here? Well, let’s enjoy a small glimpse at that future together, by winding the clock forward one thousand years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer House in the Azores</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   The Azores had been a possession of Vekllei since 2002, when they were leased from Portugal indefinitely. The lease was defunct by the time of Vekllei’s independence from U.K. occupation in 2015, and the new state took formal ownership over the small Atlantic islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Race for Inefficiency — Vekllei’s advocation of austerity, apathy, and playfulness as economic principles</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   This post is about the economy of Vekllei. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a long one. If you have any questions, just ask.
Overview of the Bureau System #  There are many thousands of companies busy with work in Vekllei. The vast majority of these companies are single-person shops (S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.
 Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or venopor) Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or cosmopor)  A young venopor officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike cosmopor, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Map of Vekllei — 100 Boroughs; 100 Hearts</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Map Key
 Red: Magjet trains, 750km/h
Yellow: Bullet trains, 300-400km/h
Orange: Regional trains, &amp;lt;150km/h
Brown: Local trains, including limited express, &amp;lt;100km/h
Blue: National highway
Dashed: Ferry line
Green: tarmacadamed airport
 The largest division of any portion of Vekllei land is the borough; a region of varying size and population with common culture, food dependency and economic interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Crown — coins of a moneyless country</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Village Map of Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   The village of Montre-Lola is home to about 400 people in its entirety, a stone’s throw from the Aisyo borough. Each morning, however, the population swells as 300 children from tiny villages in both Aisyo and Montre take a fast tram to the Montre-Lola Area School No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oa-Class Battlecruiser</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Vekllei’s defensive military posture has, in doctrine and arms development, limited its ability to meaningfully project power outside of the Atlantic. As an island nation with a large and multifaceted naval armada, the Oa-Class Battlecruiser is the heart of her armed forces, as the flagship of her fleets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canal Living</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fission Cloud at Vekllei&#39;s 50th Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   In an unprecedented event, during Vekllei’s 50th Sea Festival since Independence in 2065, an 8 kiloton fission bomb was sunk to a depth of 150 meters and detonated at midday. It was an incredible sight on a day so clear you could see the gentle curve of the earth where it met the horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031 Apartment Diagram</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Baron had inherited the apartment from his uncle, who passed in the year following his parents. It was in a mixed residential-industrial neighbourhood, adjacent to a canvas factory. Out back was a rivulet, which roared in the long rainstorms of early April.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiery Peaks</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   After three days in Ada, Tzipora set off towards Mt Miya. She made good time, and after three hours had happened upon the shoulders of the bright Volouisnesnkull Glacier. It was about here that she heard a morbid industrial siren, echoing up the valleys from far away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chemical Feast</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   East of Montre, West of Tjornes, waits a rare sight among Vekllei’s hard igneous slopes — a crown of gentle sedimentary cliffs packed with ruddy sandstone, which melt glacially into the sea chasing blue-sky bergs.
Tzipora was, at the time, making her way on foot from Montre-Lola to Ada, which was a coastal town in the North-East known for its luxurious health spas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tomorrow: 2020 Complete Guide to Vekllei
Today:
 Up in the ro, the Vekllei flower-tundra home to spirits and people alike, green slopes and igneous monument make an ample crucible for myth and magic.
 Out here, there was a very keen sense of place and purpose. “Landscape” was neither revered nor ignored, since it did not exist here altogether. Every hill, rock and tree was taken at face value in its full honesty, with commodity dead and modernism suppressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</guid>
      <description>Station Dogs #  I’m starting a series looking at the lives and machines of domestic Vekllei life.
Vekllei National Railways, or ‘VK Rail’ was the bastard of six major pre-war rail companies that were extinguished along with the society that housed them. Today there are three rail companies in Vekllei, but all of them operate under direct supervision of a Vekllei Industry Bureau ( making it Venrouiva, in other words) and are only broken up for reasons of logistics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
