<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Volcanic Commonwealth</title>
	<link>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Volcanic Commonwealth </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Aismious</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/aismious/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/aismious/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Aismious is part of the Volcanic Commonwealth Aismious Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of the Volcanic Commonwealth Capital Thor&#39;s Harbour Population 64,337 Area 1,393 km² Languages Aismious, English Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Aismious Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the North Atlantic Ocean. It comprises a group of 17 inhabited islands between Oslola and the Shetland Islands of the United Kingdom, as well as numerous islets and reefs.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Aismious is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic Commonwealth</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/fo.svg);"></span> Aismious Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/aismious.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of the <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic Commonwealth</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Thor&#39;s Harbour</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>64,337</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>1,393 km²</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Aismious, English</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-fo"></span> <strong>Aismious Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the North Atlantic Ocean. It comprises a group of 17 inhabited islands between <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a> and the Shetland Islands of the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(200, 16, 47); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(200, 16, 47) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/uk/"><span class="fi fi-gb"></span> United Kingdom</a>, as well as numerous islets and reefs. The people there are mostly of Celtic-Scandinavian stock descended from Irish settlers and Norsemen. The republic is known for its conspicuous and perpendicular cliffs and flat summits, and its gothic medieval cathedral in the village of Magnus.</p>
<p>About a third of the population live in the capital and largest city, Thor&rsquo;s Harbour. The remainder live in small communities scattered across the islands, which are characterised by fjords, river valleys and dramatic volcanic terrain. The climate is mild, though rain and fog is common. Treeless, mossy and without indigenous land mammals or reptiles, the Aismious Islands have a stark, volcanic appearance similar to <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>.</p>
<p>The economy remains dependent on cod fishing and raising livestock, though undersea oil drilling has recently begun and attracted investment in the capital. The islanders have a strong tradition of oral storytelling and history, which have carried stories for over a thousand years. Islanders speak Aismious, a language similar to Scandi-Oslolan with Celtic elements.</p>
<p>The islands are serviced by hydrofoils and an water airport in the capital, as well as trams between the larger settlements.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Demon</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/demon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/demon/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Demon is part of the Volcanic Commonwealth Demon Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Capital Aran Population 13,947 Area 377 km² Languages English, Latin, Irish Vekllei Accession 1840, gifted to the British Atlantic Territories The Republic of Demon is an island republic in the North Atlantic, and part of the country of Vekllei. It was discovered by Irish settlers in the 13th Century, where they settled at the base of the Birianvik, or Mt Birian Volcano.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Demon is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic Commonwealth</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/demon.svg);"></span> Demon Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/demon.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Aran</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>13,947</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>377 km²</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>English, Latin, Irish</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1840, gifted to the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-demon"></span> <strong>Republic of Demon</strong> is an island republic in the North Atlantic, and part of the country of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It was discovered by Irish settlers in the 13th Century, where they settled at the base of the Birianvik, or Mt Birian Volcano. Its capital, Aran, exists on this site and is home to about 14,000 people today.</p>
<p>Desolate, windy and cold, Demon is isolated by 500km of water from Kala, its closest neighbour. Its economy is dominated by fishing, community agriculture, the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Armed Forces</a> and tourism. Demon has few trees but a little tundra, and is home to arctic foxes, seabirds and all manner of North Atlantic sea life.</p>
<p>After Irish settlers established Aran in the 13th Century, a monastery was built by monks on the slope of Birianvik, making it the oldest in Vekllei. It continues to operate today on the site of the original monastery, which was destroyed by an eruption in the 18th Century. The town of Aran was abandoned twice in the 15th and 18th centuries, but the monastery has operated continuously since its founding. This heritage, collections of relics and strong religiosity among its citizens are part of the culture of Demon, and contribute to its flag which features a Black Madonna.</p>
<p>Demon can be accessed by hydrofoil or ship at Port Aran in its capital and only major settlement, and there is a combined civilian and military aerodrome on the southern region with a couple regional flights each day. A single tramline connects Aran with the farms and villages in the south.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Oslola</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Oslola is part of the Volcanic Commonwealth Oslola Republic Constituent Republic of Vekllei Part of the Volcanic Commonwealth Capital Oslola Population 8,331,426 Area 103,125 km² Languages Oslolan Algic, English, Oslolan Islandi Vekllei Accession 1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories The Oslola Republic is a constituent republic of Vekllei in the North Atlantic Ocean. It is the most populous Vekllei republic, and is historically its centre of industry, education and administration.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Oslola is part of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic Commonwealth</a></span>
</blockquote>

<table class="infobox" style="float: right; border-radius: .25rem; padding: .25rem;">
	<tr>
		<th colspan="2"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(/svg/flags/4x3/oslola.svg);"></span> Oslola Republic</th>
	</tr>

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2"><a href="/republics/">Constituent Republic</a> of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/flags/oslola.svg">
		</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<a src="/svg/maps/locator/oslola.png">
	<tr>
		<td colspan="2">
			<img src="/svg/maps/locator/oslola.png">
		</td>
	</tr>
	</a>
	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="background-color: var(--highlight-background); text-align: center" colspan="2">Part of the <a style="color: var(--color-blue)" href="/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic Commonwealth</a></td>
	</tr>
	

	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Capital</th>
		<td>Oslola</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Population</th>
		<td>8,331,426</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Area</th>
		<td>103,125 km²</td>
	</tr>
	

	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Languages</th>
		<td>Oslolan Algic, English, Oslolan Islandi</td>
	</tr>
	

	
	<tr>
		<td style="font-weight: 500; width: 50%;">Vekllei Accession</th>
		<td>1836, as part of the British Atlantic Territories</td>
	</tr>
	
</table>
<p>The <span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> <strong>Oslola Republic</strong> is a <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> in the North Atlantic Ocean. It is the most populous Vekllei republic, and is historically its centre of industry, education and administration. The large island sits atop the border of the European and North American tectonic plates and is famous for its volcanic activity and striking landscapes characterised by flower tundras, glaciers, hot geysers and and temperate rainforests.</p>
<p>Oslola has been continuously inhabited for over 4,000 years by Algic Inuits, who are a distinct ethnic and linguistic group from other Arctic Inuits. Archaeological evidence suggests Irish settlers established fishing communities on the south coast in 1200BC, and Scandinavians arrived a hundred years later. Since that time, Algic and Scandinavian/Irish populations (commonly &ldquo;Scandis&rdquo;) have participated in united and seperate kingdoms. Oslola is the site of the world&rsquo;s oldest democracy, which has varied in structure and power through succeeding kingdoms and councils. Oslola was a major centre of power in the British Atlantic Territories and the First Commonwealth that followed it, and in the postwar Fourth Commonwealth retains an important though diminished role.</p>
<p>Oslola has historically been a major entrepôt for trans-Atlantic traffic, and a trade metropole for Vekllei. It enjoys a maritime subarctic climate, with strong warm currents anchored by the Oslola Low Pole warming the southern coast. Summer typically average between 12-25 °C, and about 0-10°C in winter. The high latitude of the republic means it features midnight sun for a couple of weeks in summer. Forests of birch and eucalyptus dominate mossy, cold-weather rainforests that populate the south coast. In the glacial interior and north tundras, scrub and flowers cover mostly treeless valleys and dramatic terrain.</p>
<p>Oslola is densely populated, and the metropolitan region in the south-east comprises one continuous city broken up by mountains and crown lands. The main city, also called Oslola, has a varied character of narrow medium-height streets, railways, canals and street vegetation. It is home to many Vekllei institutions, including Vekllei National University, as well as international organisations like the new UN building and the International Federation of Journalists.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
