<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>society on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/society/</link>
	<description>Recent content in society on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Armed Forces of the Atlantic Crown</title>
	  <link></link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid></guid>
	  <description></description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Bureaus</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/bureaus/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/bureaus/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the industry series of articles Bureaus in Vekllei are industrial syndicates of companies that represent substantial or monopoly power over an industrial market. Their existence is recognised by Vekllei economic policy as a means of furnishing a reasonable standard of living for Vekllei people outside of the anarchy of the private markets. As a result, bureaus are concerned primarily with the public good and industrial policy.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Parliament</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/</guid>
	  <description> ߷ Part of the state series of articles The Commonwealth Parliament is the supranational governing body of the Vekllei Commonwealth and its member-states. Secretariats of the Commonwealth Parliament ⚒️Commonwealth Construction Secretariat (coming soon) 🏵Commonwealth Culture Secretariat (coming soon) 🎓Commonwealth Education Secretariat (coming soon) ⚕️Commonwealth Health Secretariat (coming soon) ⛓️Commonwealth Labour Secretariat (coming soon) 🏹Commonwealth Security Secretariat </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Computers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/technology/computers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/technology/computers/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei computing, but most of these technologies are available world-over Computers are used to subsidise rather than multiply productivity in Vekllei. This does not mean that they do not make commerce or industry more efficient, or open new means of communication between people &amp;ndash; only that they are understood foremost as a social benefit that enables the more idealistic features of the Floral Period and its functional moneylessness.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Consosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/consosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/consosva/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the state series of articles Consosva (a portmanteau of consivismiosn sovis, lit. &amp;ldquo;contributory service&amp;rdquo;) refers to a collection of laws that require adult citizens in Vekllei to be employed. The legal obligation is fairly straightforward and is easily avoided, and in practice acts as a form of moral pressure from the state.
Consosva is a legal obligation to register an occupation with your municipality, which forwards its ledger to the Vekllei government.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Corsosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/corsosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/corsosva/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the state series of articles Corsosva (a portmanteau of corsivis sovis, lit. &amp;ldquo;compulsory service&amp;rdquo;) is the period of civic conscription that applies to all Vekllei citizens. It requires four years of service, served between the ages of 18-32. Although administered by the Department of Compulsory Service of the Ministry of Defence, most citizens perform civilian or industrial work during Corsosva, and only a minority enter the armed forces as conscripts.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Crown Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/</guid>
	  <description> Crown Assets are a kind of state-owned enterprise subordinated to the Vekllei Sovereign, known as the Atlantic Crown or simply Crown. Crown SOEs are owned equally by all full Commonwealth member-states. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Crown Parliament</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/crown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/crown/</guid>
	  <description> ߷ Part of the state series of articles The Commonwealth Parliament is the supranational governing body of the Vekllei Commonwealth and its member-states. Secretariats of the Commonwealth Parliament ⚖️Courts of the Crown (coming soon) 💼Fair Work Authority (coming soon) 🗳️Vekllei Democracy Commissariat (coming soon) </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Documents</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/documents/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/documents/</guid>
	  <description>⚠️ This list is evolving, and will be expanded in future. The Vekllei Document System is an internal circular provided by the Government of Vekllei to direct policy. They do not represent policy in depth &amp;ndash; rather, documents are issued discretely to relevant ministries and outline the direction or spirit of policy. Historically, they announce major events and actions. Documents 📄Document No. 1: Communiqué on the Establishment of the 4th Commonwealth 📄Document No.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Education</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/education/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/education/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei society. Education emerged as a foundational right for Vekllei people in the constitution of the 4th Commonwealth, in the spirit of postwar democratisation and the rising of all people. Education in Vekllei is a good example of the &amp;lsquo;system working backwards,&amp;rsquo; the popular phrase to describe the Floral Period moving in two different directions at once. Is it modern, supplied and robust in the Western tradition &amp;ndash; children wear uniforms, are divided into school years and learning is arranged and taught in subjects.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Education</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/education/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/education/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a secretariat of the Vekllei Commonwealth Parliament Commonwealth Education Secretariat # CHICOM The Commonwealth Education Secretariat (SOLSEC) is the commonwealth body responsible for all state education across the Commonwealth, including compulsory primary, vocational and tertiary schooling. Alongside the COSMOCOM Accreditation Directorate, CHICOM certifies teachers and the Commonwealth curriculum, and publishes textbooks and learning materials via the Children&amp;rsquo;s and Tertiary Press.
The stated mission of CHICOM is the democratisation and celebration of knowledge and the development of technical skills.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Espionage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/espionage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/espionage/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei. Espionage is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Finance</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei Even if they do not use money, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests. Overview # The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &amp;ldquo;functionally moneyless,&amp;rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Government</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/</guid>
	  <description>The Vekllei Government is the supranational parliamentary government of the Vekllei Islands and the members, dependent states and territories of the Vekllei Commonwealth. It is distinct from the Palace of Vekllei, the monarch and sovereign of the Vekllei Commonwealth. The Government of Vekllei 🌸Crown Parliament ⚖️Courts of the Crown (coming soon) 💼Fair Work Authority (coming soon) 🗳️Vekllei Democracy Commissariat (coming soon) 🌸Commonwealth Parliament ⚒️Commonwealth Construction Secretariat (coming soon) 🏵Commonwealth Culture Secretariat (coming soon) 🎓Commonwealth Education Secretariat (coming soon) ⚕️Commonwealth Health Secretariat (coming soon) ⛓️Commonwealth Labour Secretariat (coming soon) 🏹Commonwealth Security Secretariat 🌸Interior Parliament 🪙Ministry of Commerce 🚧Ministry of the Commons (coming soon) 🌐Ministry of the Commonwealth ⚔️Ministry of Defence 🌍Ministry of Foreign Affairs (coming soon) ⚙️Ministry of Industry (coming soon) 🌋Ministry of Landscape (coming soon) 🔌Ministry of Light &amp;amp; Water ⛏️Ministry of Syndicates &amp;amp; Chapels (coming soon) 🚃Ministry of Transport (coming soon) Overview # ߷ This article is about the Vekllei state Vekllei is positioned uniquely between the anarchy and control.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Housing</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/housing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/housing/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the state series of articles Housing in Vekllei is socialised in the Georgist tradition. It is a recognition that all wealth lies in land, the resources beneath it, and the people that work it. In this sense, housing in Vekllei is just as radical and striking as its moneylessness. All real estate in Vekllei is negotiated, purchased and leased at a municipal level. This system depends heavily on stewardship as a factor of ownership.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/</guid>
	  <description> This article is about businesses and industrial practice in Vekllei. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Interim Prosperity Government</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interim/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interim/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the state series of articles The Interim Vekllei Government (also the Interim Parliament and Interim Prosperity Government) was a temporary puppet state of the United Kindgom, established in 2015 as a means to Vekllei independence after twenty years of British occupation in the country. It consisted of approved leaders in the arts and industry, who developed proposals for a new democratic Vekllei state.
Included was a majority female council, many of whom were socialists opposed to communist unrest in British-occupied Vekllei and were seen as a strategic alternative to a hostile communist government upon British withdrawal.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Interior Parliament</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/</guid>
	  <description> ߷ Part of the state series of articles The Vekllei Interior Parliaments are national political chambers of members of the Commonwealth. The ministries below belong to the Vekllei Islands Parliament, but most other full members of the Commonwealth maintain identical government structure. Ministries of the Interior Parliament 🪙Ministry of Commerce 🚧Ministry of the Commons (coming soon) 🌐Ministry of the Commonwealth ⚔️Ministry of Defence 🌍Ministry of Foreign Affairs (coming soon) ⚙️Ministry of Industry (coming soon) 🌋Ministry of Landscape (coming soon) 🔌Ministry of Light &amp;amp; Water ⛏️Ministry of Syndicates &amp;amp; Chapels (coming soon) 🚃Ministry of Transport (coming soon) </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Language</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/language/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei The language of Vekllei is an important part of the project. Utopianism cascades through every part of society, and rethinking communication is a foundational part of that instinct. In this article, we look at what makes Vekllei as a language special, and give insight into how these Atlantic people communicate with each other. Overview # Vekllei language, abbreviated to just Vekllei, has six core sublanguages that are used commonly today.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mail</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/mail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/mail/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei society The Royal Mail of Vekllei is perhaps the country&amp;rsquo;s most visible organisation overseas. For many foreigners, Royal Mail aircraft may be the closest they ever come to seeing for themselves the mysterious Atlantic country. For Vekllei residents, the ancient organisation is a living relic of the country&amp;rsquo;s ancient history, and an ongoing testament to the longevity of their people. Overview # The Royal Mail of Vekllei, referred to as the Mail or Mail A.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Metaphysics</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/metaphysics/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/metaphysics/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei This article draws on many concepts broadly, with meandering interest in the same way you might hold a conversation. The purpose of this article is to introduce an alternate perspective on Vekllei thinking, and provoke the buried understanding that these people understand the world in fundamentally different ways. What is history for you is not history for Vekllei, and what land means to you is not what land means in Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Commerce</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commerce/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commerce/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a ministry of the Vekllei Interior Parliament Overview # COSMOSOL The Vekllei Ministry of Commerce (COSMOSOL) regulates and initiates trade in the country. Despite the functional moneylessness of the Commonwealth, COSMOSOL remains among the busiest ministries of the Interior Government, since all economic policy, international trade and entitled renumeration (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for withdrawing from the Labour Bank) occurs through its subordinate commissions. Common responsibilities of COSMOSOL include:</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Defence</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/defence/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/defence/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a ministry of the Vekllei Interior Parliament Overview # COSMOKOS The Ministry of Defence (COSMOKOS) represents the Sovereign Armed Forces of the Vekllei Commonwealth in the Interior Government, which are consolidated under the Commonwealth Military Command. COSMOKOS does not exercise command authority over the armed forces of Vekllei, and serves instead as the ministerial liaison between the Commonwealth Military Command and the Interior Government. Common responsibilities of COSMOKOS include:</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Light &amp; Water</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/light-and-water/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/light-and-water/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a ministry of the Vekllei Interior Parliament Overview # COSMOLA The Ministry of Light &amp;amp; Water (COSMOLA) is responsible for the government monopoly on water and energy in Vekllei. Through its statutory corporations (SCs) and public utilities, the ministry is responsible for the vast majority of energy production in the Vekllei Islands and contributes significantly to energy research through its network of laboratories. Increasingly, COSMOLA investment has indicated an interest in energy and water conservation.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of the Commonwealth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commonwealth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interior/commonwealth/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a ministry of the Vekllei Interior Parliament Overview # COSMOCOM The Ministry of the Commonwealth (COSMOCOM) is the organ through which the Interior Parliament communicates and cooperates with the Commonwealth Parliament and its secretariats. Its primary responsibility is cooperation between member states and standardisation, and publishes reports and manuals towards this goal. It is also the primary ministry through which the subordinates of the Commonwealth influence the Interior Parliament.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Municipalities</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/municipalities/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/municipalities/</guid>
	  <description>✿ Read more: The Good, The Municipal Municipalities are the bedrock of sundress municipalism, and a physical feature of everyday Vekllei life. A municipality refers to both a local council and its services, including libraries, schools, and policemen. Municipalities in Vekllei are the predominant form of local government, and vary dramatically in scale, power and resources. They usually refer to council municipalities, which are bodies of elected industrial and political leaders of a community.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>OPSEC</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about a secretariat of the Vekllei Commonwealth Parliament Overview # OPSEC The Commonwealth Security Secretariat (OPSEC) is the mother organisation of the internal and external security organs of the Vekllei government. Its constitutional mission includes intelligence gathering, espionage, special policing, and state security. It is headed by the Secretary of Security, and reports directly to the Commonwealth Parliament.
Commonwealth Military Command # The Commonwealth Military Command (CMC) is the unifying command organisation for the Crown Armed Forces, responsible ultimately for facilitating Commonwealth control of the armed forces.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/</guid>
	  <description> This page is an archive for content posted to the dormant Vekllei Patreon. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rail</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/state/rail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/state/rail/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei society This article discusses one of the most important and visible organisations in everyday Vekllei life: Vekllei National Rail. Vekllei is criss-crossed by hundreds of different rail lines of various gauges, grades, and purposes. In fact, it runs many lines at a total loss, often under capacity. To understand these inefficiencies is to understand why the National Rail exists, and to some extent, how Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s state assets and powerful bureaus shape life in the country today.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Religion</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/religion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/religion/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei Upen is the nondenominational animistic spiritualism of Vekllei. It is both an organised religious belief system and a decentralised local animism, localised regionally across the Home Islands and beyond. As a basis for Vekllei metaphysics and general belief systems, Upen is a central part of Vekllei cultural identity and informs most parts of life at all levels in the country. Overview # Upen is the animistic, nondenominational dominant and historical religion of Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sagas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/sagas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/sagas/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the culture series of articles Sagas are a kind of historic prose narrative that recorded the oral history of early Vekllei. They are distinguished by their use of Topyas, a predecessor to modern Topet. They are recognised for their realism and poetry, and provide a valuable historical record of the 1st Commonwealth and practices of Old Upen.
Sagas were consolidated into historical and thematic eras in the 14th Century during the Period of Rest, which is typically how they are arranged today.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>State</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/</guid>
	  <description> ✿ Main article: The Government of Vekllei The start and end of the supranational Vekllei state is difficult to illustrate, since society in the 4th Commonwealth is dominated by several overlapping institutions with competing sovereignty. These articles are mostly concerned with features of the commonwealth nation-state, including the government and aspects of its laws and institutions. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>State Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/state/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/state/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei Large segments of the Vekllei economy are dominated by industries of the state, as both direct ministerial privileges and state-owned enterprises. In total, they form the basis of the basic Vekllei standard of living, holding back catastrophe through reliable overproduction where gaps in the participatory economy might threaten serious shortages. Overview # There is no real distinction in Vekllei between state assets, state-owned enterprises (SOE) and government-owned corporations (GOC), and the terms are used interchangeably.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Technology</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/technology/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/technology/</guid>
	  <description> This article is about unique technology in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s world. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Army Construction House</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/ach/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/ach/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the industrial series of articles The Army Construction House (ACH) is the largest construction company in the Commonwealth by gross revenue and number of employees, most of whom are conscripts in the compulsory service scheme. It is a part of the Armed Forces of Vekllei, and subsequently reports directly to the palace. In practice, it consists of dozens of smaller companies that are administered by the Ministry of Defence in its local member-state.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Universal Cotton</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/bureaus/universal-cotton/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/bureaus/universal-cotton/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the industry series of articles Universal Cotton is a bureau based in the Vekllei Islands. It is the largest clothing manufacturer in the Commonwealth, specialising in shirts, trousers, skirts, dresses, and underwear. It supplies most department stores in the Vekllei Islands as part of the Commons Comfort Scheme of the Vekllei government, and has a significant presence throughout the Commonwealth.
The flag of Universal Cotton. It trades overseas under the Universal Cotton Company brand.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>