<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>society</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/society/</link>
	<description>Recent content in society </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Bureaus</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the industry series of articles Bureaus in Vekllei are industrial syndicates of companies that represent substantial or monopoly power over an industrial market. Their existence is recognised by Vekllei economic policy as a means of furnishing a reasonable standard of living for Vekllei people outside of the anarchy of the private markets. As a result, bureaus are concerned primarily with the public good and industrial policy.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/industry/">industry</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Bureaus</strong> in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> are industrial syndicates of companies that represent substantial or monopoly power over an industrial market. Their existence is recognised by Vekllei economic policy as a means of furnishing a reasonable standard of living for Vekllei people outside of the anarchy of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#domestic-markets">private markets</a>. As a result, bureaus are concerned primarily with the public good and industrial policy.</p>
<p>Bureaus typically consist of a general council, which organise votes from workers in subsidiary companies into <em>company ballots</em>, which are used to establish standards and self-regulate industry. Bureau membership also allows interaction with the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">Vekllei International Market</a>, and provide a means for foreign investment and export. Companies within bureaus still compete against each other.</p>
<p>The largest bureaus include <em>Electra</em> and <a href="/universal-cotton/"><em>Universal Cotton</em></a>. Electra represents a collection of state-owned electricity generation companies, and Universal Cotton consists of over a hundred individual clothing manufacturers. Although state monopolies may form a bureau in part or as a whole, bureau membership does not necessarily imply state ownership.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Consosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/consosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/consosva/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Consosva (a portmanteau of consivismiosn sovis, lit. &ldquo;contributory service&rdquo;) refers to a collection of laws that require adult citizens in Vekllei to be employed. The legal obligation is fairly straightforward and is easily avoided, and in practice acts as a form of moral pressure from the state.
Consosva is a legal obligation to register an occupation with your municipality, which forwards its ledger to the Vekllei government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Consosva</strong> (a portmanteau of <em>consivismiosn sovis</em>, lit. &ldquo;<em>contributory service</em>&rdquo;) refers to a collection of laws that require adult citizens in Vekllei to be employed. The legal obligation is fairly straightforward and is easily avoided, and in practice acts as a form of moral pressure from the state.</p>
<p>Consosva is a legal obligation to register an occupation with your municipality, which forwards its ledger to the Vekllei government. This is to encourage productivity and discourage &ldquo;social parasitism,&rdquo; as a requirement to contribute to the wealth of society. Failure to do so is considered a crime and is usually penalised with community service.</p>
<p>Consosva has many recognised exemptions, including full-time study, participating in <a href="/corsosva/">Compulsory Service</a>, acting as the primary caregiver of children, and poor health.</p>
<p>Consosva applies to Vekllei citizens or permanent residents aged between 22 and 50.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Corsosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/corsosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/corsosva/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Corsosva (a portmanteau of corsivis sovis, lit. &ldquo;compulsory service&rdquo;) is the period of civic conscription that applies to all Vekllei citizens. It requires four years of service, served between the ages of 18-32. Although administered by the Department of Compulsory Service of the Ministry of Defence, most citizens perform civilian or industrial work during Corsosva, and only a minority enter the armed forces as conscripts.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Corsosva</strong> (a portmanteau of <em>corsivis sovis</em>, lit. &ldquo;<em>compulsory service</em>&rdquo;) is the period of civic conscription that applies to all Vekllei citizens. It requires four years of service, served between the ages of 18-32. Although administered by the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/defence/#department-of-compulsory-service">Department of Compulsory Service</a> of the <a href="/cosmokos/">Ministry of Defence</a>, most citizens perform civilian or industrial work during Corsosva, and only a minority enter the armed forces as conscripts.</p>
<p>Individuals entering Corsosva elect their preferences for service, which are then weighted based on experience and ability. The most common forms of Corsosva are in construction, education and healthcare.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Crown Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Crown Assets are a kind of state-owned enterprise subordinated to the Vekllei Sovereign, known as the Atlantic Crown or simply Crown. Crown SOEs are owned equally by all full Commonwealth member-states. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Crown Assets are a kind of state-owned enterprise subordinated to the Vekllei Sovereign, known as the <em>Atlantic Crown</em> or simply <em>Crown</em>. Crown SOEs are owned equally by all full Commonwealth member-states.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Documents</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/documents/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/documents/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[⚠️ This list is evolving, and will be expanded in future. The Vekllei Document System is an internal circular provided by the Government of Vekllei to direct policy. They do not represent policy in depth &ndash; rather, documents are issued discretely to relevant ministries and outline the direction or spirit of policy. Historically, they announce major events and actions. Documents 📄Document No. 1: Communiqué on the Establishment of the 4th Commonwealth 📄Document No.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><span class="smallicon" style="font-size: 14px;">⚠️</span> This list is evolving, and will be expanded in future.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>The Vekllei Document System</strong> is an internal circular provided by the Government of Vekllei to direct policy. They do not represent policy in depth &ndash; rather, documents are issued discretely to relevant ministries and outline the direction or spirit of policy. Historically, they announce major events and actions.</div>
</blockquote>

<details open>
  <summary>Documents</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li><a href="/files/documents/1.pdf"><span class="navicon">📄</span>Document No. 1</a>: Communiqué on the Establishment of the 4th Commonwealth</li>
<li><a href="/files/documents/7.pdf"><span class="navicon">📄</span>Document No. 7</a>: Communiqué on the Establishment of Government Schools</li>
<li><a href="/files/documents/9.pdf"><span class="navicon">📄</span>Document No. 9</a>: Communiqué on the Establishment of the VKIM</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Education</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/education/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/education/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei society. Education emerged as a foundational right for Vekllei people in the constitution of the 4th Commonwealth, in the spirit of postwar democratisation and the rising of all people. Education in Vekllei is a good example of the &lsquo;system working backwards,&rsquo; the popular phrase to describe the Floral Period moving in two different directions at once. Is it modern, supplied and robust in the Western tradition &ndash; children wear uniforms, are divided into school years and learning is arranged and taught in subjects.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/vekllei/">Vekllei</a> society.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Education</strong> emerged as a foundational right for Vekllei people in the constitution of the 4th Commonwealth, in the spirit of postwar democratisation and the rising of all people.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Education in Vekllei is a good example of the &lsquo;system working backwards,&rsquo; the popular phrase to describe the Floral Period moving in two different directions at once. Is it modern, supplied and robust in the Western tradition &ndash; children wear uniforms, are divided into school years and learning is arranged and taught in subjects. Other aspects of the Vekllei curriculum, like its provisions for extracurricular activities and social clubs, are novel by comparison.</p>
<p>There is something quite interesting going on in Vekllei education that is not immediately apparent at its surface. First, compulsory schooling runs between 3-5 days a week, depending on student commitments to elective and extracurricular activities. Government schools do not employ standardised testing, and rely on subject-specific means of assessment including reviews, presentations and portfolios. The <a href="#curriculum">Vekllei Curriculum</a> emphasises practicable and technical skills that blur the lines between school, community and home.</p>
<p>Education in Vekllei is considered a foundation of Vekllei democracy, and in the spirit of the Floral Period it is free, abundant and compulsory.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Education is a founding aspect of the 4th Commonwealth and is to be reaffirmed constantly and faithfully by all Parliaments and public servants, and to this end is to be provided for as a highest priority of the new Parliament.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&ndash; <a href="/documents/">Document No. 7</a></p>
<h2 id="structure">
  Structure
  <a class="anchor" href="#structure">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Download <span class="smallicon">📄</span> <a href="/files/documents/7.pdf">Document No. 7.pdf</a></div>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="administration-and-funding">
  Administration and Funding
  <a class="anchor" href="#administration-and-funding">#</a>
</h3>
<p>All forms of education in Vekllei are free, including for international students at a tertiary level. The system is funded by the <a href="/solcom/">Commonwealth Education Secretariat (SOLCOM)</a>, which also administers the school curriculum and some schools directly.</p>
<h3 id="schools">
  Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#schools">#</a>
</h3>
<p>There are several different types of school in Vekllei, but all are government-funded and adhere to the compulsory curriculum outlined by the Education Secretary. The <a href="#uniform">Vekllei Education Uniform</a> is compulsory for all students, including at independent schools.</p>
<h4 id="state-schools">
  State Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#state-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>State schools (also Central Schools) are administered and funded directly by the Education Secretariat, and are common in cities and in Commonwealth member-states. They are traditionally larger and better equipped, and usually provide for both primary and secondary schooling. Some state schools are also district colleges, meaning they serve students from <a href="#preparatory-school">Prep</a> to Year 12 or 13.</p>
<h4 id="community-schools">
  Community Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#community-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Community schools are usually administered by a borough or <a href="/municipalities/">municipality</a>, and are usually smaller than state schools. Although some community schools may combine primary and secondary schooling (called district schools), most serve only primary education. Community schools may also refer to village schools, or community-run schools in the local Vekllei tradition.</p>
<h4 id="studio--technical-schools">
  Studio &amp; Technical Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#studio--technical-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Studio and technical schools typically refer to secondary schools that specialise in arts or vocational curriculums, as a means to fast-track gifted learning. These schools may offer boarding, as only a few studio and technical schools exist across the Commonwealth and smaller member-states may send their students overseas to study there.</p>
<h4 id="faith-schools">
  Faith Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#faith-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Faith schools in Vekllei are affiliated with an approved religious organisation. The curriculum of faith schools have a religious character, usually Jewish or Roman Catholic. Faith schools are still required to adhere to the <a href="#curriculum">Commonwealth curriculum</a> as a minimum education standard. Faith Schools are also an exception to the universal coeducational system of the Commonwealth, since two schools in Oslola and one in the Kalina Isles are single-sex boarding schools.</p>
<h4 id="boarding-schools">
  Boarding Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#boarding-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Vekllei offers a handful of boarding schools, which are usually specialised institutions that may operate as orphanages or for international students. Some Vekllei boarding schools include aspects of democratic education.</p>
<h2 id="education">
  Education
  <a class="anchor" href="#education">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <a style="color: var(--color-education)" href="/solsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-education fis"></span> Parliament of Education</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Vekllei people are enrolled in 9 years of compulsory education, provided by the <a style="color: var(--color-education)" href="/solsec/"><span class="fi fi-min-education fis"></span> Parliament of Education</a>. In addition, 3 years of pre-school and 3 years of senior secondary schooling are offered but not compulsory. All schools in Vekllei are funded by the state, which include community schools, state schools, studio schools, technical schools, faith schools and state boarding schools.</p>
<p>Compared to modern schooling overseas, Vekllei education places significant value on well-roundedness and practicable household and technical skills. Subject-based streams for specialised learning are common, but the basic compulsory Vekllei curriculum emphasises non-academic subjects and structures pre-tertiary subjects as electives.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/mist.jpg" alt="Image of Tzipora standing in front of school building"  title="Misty morning in front of the [Moshel St School](/moshel/) | *[Heavy Mist](/stories/mist/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Misty morning in front of the <a href="/moshel/">Moshel St School</a> | <em><a href="/stories/mist/">Heavy Mist</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Vekllei has a strong tradition of school clubs and social organisations, and these are considered essential aspects of Vekllei education. Clubs and associations are usually organised by student leadership, and offer opportunities in industry and tertiary study.</p>
<p>Compulsory and tertiary education is free for all Vekllei people, permanent residents and foreign workers. Homeschooling is illegal except by those holding a teaching certificate, and is supervised by a local school which issues the child&rsquo;s diploma. In this context, homeschooling is almost nonexistent in the Commonwealth. About 15% of the Commonwealth Budget is allocated towards education.</p>
<h3 id="compulsory-education">
  Compulsory Education
  <a class="anchor" href="#compulsory-education">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei offers preschooling from ages 3 onwards. Garden School, or kindergarten, is for 3 &amp; 4 year-olds in Vekllei, and assists with the transition from home to school, followed by preparatory school, or &lsquo;prep&rsquo;, which is the first year of compulsory primary education.</p>
<p>Vekllei primary education consists of 7 years, starting with <a href="#preparatory-school">Prep</a> at ages 5-6 and concluding with Year 6 at age 12. Secondary education lasts from years 7-12, and study until year 10 is compulsory.</p>
<p>The final year of school in Vekllei usually includes a class trip overseas, traditionally to Europe or Asia, to celebrate graduation.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Vekllei Compulsory Schooling</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>Preschool
<ul>
<li>Nursery School</li>
<li>Garden School</li>
<li>Preparatory School</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Primary School (Years 1-6)</li>
<li>Secondary School (Years 7-10)</li>
<li>College (Years 11-12)</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<h3 id="tertiary-education">
  Tertiary Education
  <a class="anchor" href="#tertiary-education">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Commonwealth invests heavily in tertiary education as both a social good and a product marketable overseas. Vekllei universities rank highly abroad, and education as a service is a major export of Vekllei, and contributes to Vekllei&rsquo;s reputation as an international capital of finance and skilled labour.</p>
<p>Universities in Vekllei offer places to students who have completed their Education Award and satisfy the prerequisites for their subject. These requirements differ between subjects, and usually include an interview with the admissions board.</p>
<p>In order to study abroad, Vekllei students must be sponsored by a foreigner, receive a partial scholarship from an overseas university, or receive funding from their tertiary place of study. About one in four Vekllei students study overseas for some period of time.</p>
<h4 id="university">
  University
  <a class="anchor" href="#university">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Vekllei International University offers</p>
<h4 id="vocational-schools">
  Vocational Schools
  <a class="anchor" href="#vocational-schools">#</a>
</h4>
<h2 id="curriculum">
  Curriculum
  <a class="anchor" href="#curriculum">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The Commonwealth Curriculum is the common programme of study in all Commonwealth schools, and determines standards of study across all education institutions.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Commonwealth International Curriculum</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>Arts</li>
<li>Vekllei Languages</li>
<li>Foreign Languages</li>
<li>Health and Physical Education</li>
<li>Civic Sciences and Stewardship</li>
<li>Economics and Business</li>
<li>World Study</li>
<li>Political Sciences and History</li>
<li>Mathematics</li>
<li>Material Sciences and Electronics</li>
<li>Work Studies</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<h2 id="uniform">
  Uniform
  <a class="anchor" href="#uniform">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/uniforms/">Uniforms in Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/generation.jpg" alt="Illustration of different ways of wearing the same school uniform"  title="Examples of Vekllei school uniform and its functional diversity | [*A New Generation*](/stories/new-generation/)" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Examples of Vekllei school uniform and its functional diversity | <a href="/stories/new-generation/"><em>A New Generation</em></a></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>All schools in Vekllei share the Education Uniform, made compulsory by the <a href="/solsec/">Education Secretariat</a>. The Vekllei uniform is simple and purchased independently, usually from department stores. The only badged items are the tie and jewellery/pins. It is worn across all ages of schooling, including tertiary education and university, and by some teachers as well.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th>Boys</th>
<th>Girls</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Top</td>
<td><ul> <li>White collared shirt, tucked shirttails</li> <li>Black school tie</li> <li>Navy cape or mackintosh raincoat</li> <li>Navy jumper or sweater</li> <li>Navy blazer or sports jacket</li> </ul></td>
<td><ul> <li>White blouse, tucked shirttails</li> <li>Black or red school tie or floral piece</li> <li>Navy cape, pettycape or mackintosh raincoat</li> <li>Navy jumper or sweater</li> <li>Navy pinafore or gymslip</li> </ul></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bottom</td>
<td><ul> <li>Navy trousers or shorts</li> <li>Dark or brown belt</li> </ul></td>
<td><ul> <li>Navy skirt or trousers</li> <li>White traditional trousers</li> <li>Dark or brown belt</li> </ul></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Shoes</td>
<td><ul> <li>Dark or brown leather shoes</li> <li>Dark socks</li> </ul></td>
<td><ul> <li>Dark or brown leather shoes</li> <li>white socks</li> </ul></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The colours of uniforms may vary in constituent member-states of the Commonwealth &ndash; for example, the Kalina Isles use dark green in place of navy. Nonetheless, the Education Uniform standards are set at the Commonwealth level and are generally adopted in whole.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/kalinauniform.jpg" alt="Illustration Caribbean youths wearing school uniform"  title="Examples of Caribbean Commonwealth school uniform featuring local dress. | [*Caribbean Uniforms*](/stories/caribbean-uniform/)" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Examples of Caribbean Commonwealth school uniform featuring local dress. | <a href="/stories/caribbean-uniform/"><em>Caribbean Uniforms</em></a></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Although the items are not issued by individual schools, they are provided by the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/education/#all-commonwealth-school-directorate">ACC</a> on request and as such constitute a uniform rather than a dress code. The uniform system was designed in 2015 by French migrant Charles-Édouard Laurent to be accessible and comfortable, and so that individual items could continue to be worn after schooling concluded. It is iconic overseas and well-regarded by most Vekllei students.</p>
<p>Many schools make use of felt armbands to distinguish students or to signal membership in clubs or student councils. These are traditionally red, but may also be green or blue depending on their use.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Espionage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/espionage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/espionage/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei. Espionage is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/intro/#what-is-vekllei">Vekllei</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Espionage</strong> is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers. Unsentimental, unideological and unflinching, espionage in Vekllei is conducted constantly and vigorously with the blessing &ndash; or at least willing blindness &ndash; of the state.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Espionage in Vekllei is considered the &lsquo;first thorn&rsquo; of &lsquo;assertive defence&rsquo; practiced by the 4th Commonwealth. It is maintained offensively, as operations, and defensively as counterintelligence. The means by which it does are a source of endless contention in Commonwealth parliaments, the Vekllei public and foreign governments,<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> but since independence in 2015 espionage has been conducted much the same &ndash; and so can be assumed to be achieving strategic goals.</p>
<p>Overseas strategic and industrial espionage primarily falls under the control of the Commonwealth National Intelligence Directorate, usually called Noshem, which maintains several subordinate bureaus organised regionally.</p>
<p>Current intelligence doctrine values &lsquo;signal operations&rsquo; &ndash; visible strategic actions that &lsquo;signal&rsquo; messages to public enemies of the Commonwealth state, and maintaining plausible deniability. The line between civilian and military intelligence operations is not always clear, and Noshem is implicated in assassinations and executions of state enemies overseas. The Vekllei intelligence community is known to recruit ideological and nationalist sympathisers to perform actions on behalf of the state, and to this end has among the largest networks of informants of any espionage ring in the world.</p>
<h2 id="operations">
  Operations
  <a class="anchor" href="#operations">#</a>
</h2>
<h3 id="noshem">
  Noshem
  <a class="anchor" href="#noshem">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <span class="smallicon">🏹</span> <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#national-intelligence-directorate">Noshem</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Noshem,<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> the traditional name for the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#national-intelligence-directorate">National Intelligence Directorate</a> is the secret service of the Commonwealth and is responsible for most of its overseas espionage. It has a legendary reputation for the size and quality of its informants network, and is highly feared because of its history of ruthlessness, including extrajudicial assassinations and executions. Plausible deniability makes it difficult to tell how much of its work is sanctioned by parliaments or acted out by individual Vekllei people, and the organisation generates considerable controversy. Noshem has had several publicised tactical successes as well as failures, and is considered a critical aspect of Commonwealth security as a &lsquo;jewelled sabre&rsquo; of the non-aligned movement.</p>
<p>Noshem operates 40 outlines across 6 bureaus, which are organised regionally and contain semiautonomous command and logistics elements.</p>
<h3 id="security-directorates">
  Security Directorates
  <a class="anchor" href="#security-directorates">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Cosevac (POSEC) and Vosevisi (SESEC) are the Security Directorates of the Public and State respectively. Vosevisi processes some Noshem material, and its subordinate <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#state-secrets-office">State Secrets Office</a> is also responsible for maintaining security controls and classifications. Although they collect intelligence internally, most espionage is conducted overseas by <a href="#noshem">Noshem</a>.</p>
<h3 id="adsem">
  Adsem
  <a class="anchor" href="#adsem">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Adsem is the military intelligence department of the Vekllei Armed Forces. It co-ordinates with the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/">Interior Parliament</a> via the Ministry of Defence&rsquo;s <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/defence/#intelligence-liaison-office">Intelligence Liasion Office</a>, and is concerned primarily with counterintelligence operations and strategic information relevant to war. Like the Security Directorates, most of Adsem&rsquo;s espionage is conducted by Noshem. In turn, Adsem supplies much of Noshem&rsquo;s matériel, and many of its elite intelligence units are recruited from military commando and special forces sections. Adsem may also assist in the logistics of Noshem espionage operations.</p>
<h3 id="recruitment">
  Recruitment
  <a class="anchor" href="#recruitment">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei human intelligence is generally considered superior to that of the CIA, and may even be comparable to the KGB in scope and quality. Human intelligence is the basis of contemporary Vekllei intelligence-gathering, and the intelligence state gathers and processes massive amounts of information on foreign nationals, companies, and governments. It relies on enormous, concentric rings of highly motivated unpaid sympathisers that help Noshem in passing messages, inserting agents and obscuring information.</p>
<p>There are several classes of sympathiser &ndash; some are ideologically motivated in the anarchist or pan-Atlanticist tradition, factions which the Vekllei government is willing to recognise or indulge publicly to stir positive and negative press and distinguish itself from the cold war dichotomy. Others are nationalists who help out of a sense of devotion to Vekllei, since several million Vekllei people fled after the Atomic War. Although many returned in the years after independence, there remains a large Vekllei diaspora throughout the world and especially in the United States and Western Europe, and many members continue to hold a sense of duty towards the country.</p>
<p>This network of sympathisers is aided by Vekllei&rsquo;s postwar internationalism and multiracialism, emphasising political and geographic traits that appeal to young, educated people. Where duty fails, cash often suffices, and tremendous amounts of state funds are siphoned discretely from other Ministerial budgets to fund a network of paid informants. The total number of informants is impossible to know, but is estimated to number tens of thousands across the U.S., U.K., France, Russia, Yugoslavia, China and South-East Asia.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>This controversy has prompted several commissions and parliamentary inquests by the Vekllei Comptroller, and continues to generate debate in Vekllei society. It is also a popular subject of conspiracy theorising.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Noshem is the name of the spirit-god of secrets in Vekllei mythology.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Finance</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/finance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/finance/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about Vekllei Even if they do not use money, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests. Overview # The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &ldquo;functionally moneyless,&rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Even if they do not use money</strong>, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &ldquo;functionally moneyless,&rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex. While the average Vekllei person is insulated from money and money-management, their Commonwealth is a major entrepôt<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> and has a reputation as an &ldquo;Atlantic Middleman.&rdquo; Vekllei&rsquo;s facilitation of frictionless free trade, large foreign-exchange reserves and received foreign direct investments have resulted in decades of consistent economic growth, and has cemented its reputation as a financial hub between Europe and the Americas.</p>
<p>Vekllei&rsquo;s history as a trade hub contributes significantly to its perceived neutrality and its reputation as a meeting place for politics and business, and regularly hosts diplomatic missions as a neutral site. It maintains its moneyless primary economy by effectively isolating its primary (<a href="#domestic-markets">domestic</a>) and secondary (<a href="#international-markets">international</a>) markets, which are the reason for its <a href="#currency">twin currencies</a> and its unusual hybrid market system. Because the Vekllei state manages all money as a function of its moneylessness, the international market and foreign trade is strongly characterised by dirigism and fundamentally beholden to the economic management of the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>, which acts as both a financial regulator and investment bank.</p>
<h2 id="markets">
  Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#markets">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></div>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="domestic-markets">
  Domestic Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#domestic-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Vekllei Domestic Market is the turn-of-phrase for the unmoneyed Vekllei economy, including almost all private and public businesses and the majority of trade conducted by ordinary Vekllei people. It is the primary market of Vekllei. For most Vekllei people, the domestic market is the only one with which they will interact in their lives, except for the occasional holiday overseas. The Domestic Market includes all sectors of the Vekllei economy except state trade apparatuses like <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a>.</p>
<p>While the participatory nature of the Domestic Market affects its gross productivity, it is regarded as free, innovative and dynamic. It has a skilled workforce benefitted by a robust education system and a high quality of life. About 40% of Vekllei people were born overseas, and some 15% of the Vekllei workforce remain foreign workers. Foreign workers, unlike domestic ones, are remunerated unless residing under an immigration visa.</p>
<h3 id="industrial-markets">
  Industrial Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#industrial-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei Industrial Markets are distinguished by their ability to trade in both the moneyless <a href="#domestic-markets">Domestic Market</a> and the <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a>. There are two kinds of industrial firm in Vekllei:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Senrouive</strong>: private enterprises</li>
<li><strong>Venrouive</strong>: public enterprises with membership in an industrial <a href="/bureaus/">bureau</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Venrouive</em> (also known as public companies in Vekllei) are enterprises beholden to <a href="/bureaus/">industrial bureaus</a>, which are collections of companies with close relations and hold membership in a shared industrial council. Venrouive businesses are characterised by large-scale enterprises, some of which may be state-owned, that hold considerable power over a market. In some cases, a bureau may monopolise a market, as in the case of the Vekllei telecommunications industry.</p>
<p>Both senrouive and venrouive companies may participate in the international market, but only bureaus (and by extension, participating venrouive companies) may trade directly with overseas governments and enterprises.</p>
<h3 id="international-markets">
  International Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#international-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Download <span class="smallicon">📄</span> <a href="/files/documents/9.pdf">Document No. 9.pdf</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Vekllei International Market (VKIM) is an organisation that controls the capital, commodities and securities markets of Vekllei. VKIM is maintained by the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a> as a mechanism for foreign investors and merchants to interact with the isolated, unmoneyed Vekllei domestic market. The international market includes a commodities exchange, derivatives marketplace and other structured financial products that facilitate foreign activity in the Vekllei economy and raise foreign capital for the national liquid currency reserves. VKIM uses the Vekllei Composite Index as a measure of the Vekllei economy, which measures both commodity value and productivity.</p>
<p>The International Market is the means by which the capital account<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> of the Commonwealth Government implements its long-standing macroeconomic interest in foreign investment and soft power. The reinvestment of capital surplus in the <a href="#currency">Vekllei currencies</a> serves as a form of sterilisation and capital control, controlled directly by the central <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a>. Vekllei has the world&rsquo;s 2nd-largest foreign currency reserves.</p>
<h2 id="currency">
  Currency
  <a class="anchor" href="#currency">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2020-06-24-crown/">The Vekllei Crown</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Vekllei has two currencies that are more or less opposed in their use as money, known as the twin crowns system. The Vekllei Crown (❦VK) is a gold-backed, fixed-rate deflationary currency used primarily as a wealth reserve, and the Government Crown (✾AK) is a fiat, floating-exchange currency used for foreign investment and trade. This system preserves the isolation of the Vekllei primary economy, which is moneyless, while insulating state investments from shocks and from having to burn liquidity to maintain its exchange rate.</p>
<p>Together, the twin crowns allow for the Vekllei state to retain unprecedented control over its financial system while securing a mechanism for foreign investment and growth.</p>
<ul>
<li>The domestic market is autarkic and does not have free capital exchange, allowing it to maintain its fixed price and independent monetary policy</li>
<li>The international market is open and has free capital exchange, facilitated by ✾AK floating exchange price with policy independence maintained by capital controls from the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/cosmosol/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>For a variety of political and economic reasons, the Vekllei Commonwealth state aims to be self-sufficient. The twin crowns system provides a means to isolate its productive primary economy while also allowing foreign money controlled access to it. The unmoneyed primary economy remains a popular investment for its stability.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> As capital controls have broken down in the mid-2030s, Vekllei&rsquo;s current macroeconomic policy exists as a &ldquo;third way&rdquo; between closed autarky and recent trends towards an open economic international market.</p>
<h3 id="vekllei-crown-vk">
  Vekllei Crown (❦VK)
  <a class="anchor" href="#vekllei-crown-vk">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The <em>Vekllei Kroner</em> (lit. <em>Vekllei Crown</em>) is the primary and historic currency of Vekllei. It is minted by the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/mint/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Mint</a> as a souvenir in the tradition of Vekllei <em>medals</em>,<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> but is not otherwise used by Vekllei people as money or transacted in day-to-day life. It is primarily a deflationary currency store backed by gold, and to which each Vekllei citizen is entitled an equal share in emigration. It is not able to be used on the <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a> directly, but can be purchased as a <a href="#white-bonds">White Bond</a> as a speculative instrument. It is also used in some cases as a mechanism for trade with individuals abroad, mostly by smaller banks looking to broker purchases of goods or services unavailable in Vekllei.</p>
<h3 id="government-crown-ak">
  Government Crown (✾AK)
  <a class="anchor" href="#government-crown-ak">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The <em>Government/Commonwealth Kroner</em> (also the <em>Atlantic Kroner</em> or <em>Crown</em>) is a twin currency used primarily by the state to insure financial instruments like bonds as well as for converting and placing foreign investments and currency. The Government Crown operates on a floating exchange rate as a fiat currency tradeable in the <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a> and a means for overseas actions in the Vekllei economy.</p>
<p>The ✾AK is not minted as it does not resemble a conventional currency, and exists only in bonds, state certificates, and as a metric for some commodity money. It has a strong reputation as a hard currency because of the ✾AK&rsquo;s relative security and reliability, backed by powerful domestic institutions.</p>
<h2 id="banking">
  Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#banking">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The policy of bank consolidation under the British Occupation Government continued under the successive Floral Government, and banking was among the first industries in Vekllei to be completely socialised.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> All banks in Vekllei are run as state-owned enterprises, and subordinated to the &lsquo;<em>Old Lady</em>,&rsquo; the colloquial name for the central <a style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136)" href="/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a>. &lsquo;Unbanking&rsquo; policy &ndash; the effective demonetisation of the Vekllei domestic markets &ndash; saw severe disruption to the Vekllei economy and led to a period of hyperinflation in the late 2010s.</p>
<p>Unlike in other countries, the socialisation of banking in Vekllei also saw the broad exclusion of retail investors and savings banking, effectively halting money exchange in the domestic market and institutionalising the Vekllei banking system. Today, most Vekllei banks are institutional and deal primarily with the secondary speculative markets like <a href="#international-markets">VKIM</a>, or provide lending and contracts for new businesses in the <a href="#industrial-markets">industrial market</a>.</p>
<h3 id="bank-of-vekllei">
  Bank of Vekllei
  <a class="anchor" href="#bank-of-vekllei">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Bank of Vekllei (also <em>Labour Bank of Vekllei</em> and <em>Old Lady</em>) is Vekllei&rsquo;s central bank with a constitutionally-granted monopoly on the financial mechanisms of the Commonwealth, with nearly all Commonwealth banking firms subordinated to its organisation. It is responsible directly to the <a style="color: var(--color-cosmosol)" href="/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Treasury</a> and sets the monetary policy of Vekllei. It is primarily a macroeconomic institution that does not deal directly with the primary or secondary markets, but does over institutional banking services and complex financing for some markets in the Commonwealth.</p>
<h4 id="personal-banking">
  Personal Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#personal-banking">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Despite the functional moneylessness of the Commonwealth, banks do facilitate financial transactions with the common Vekllei person. Aside from its policy features (like holiday allowances and emigration stipends), most trade arrangements operate in the bank system, usually through the <em>Sisterbank</em>. Sisterbank (formally the <em>Petty Bank of Vekllei</em>) is a merchant bank that specialises in industrial brokerage, allowing small businesses to trade with others and stimulate economic activity. Vekllei persons looking to start a restaurant, workshop or store generally do so through the Sisterbank, which assigns a bank agent and enters the business in its internal market ledger. Not all small business in Vekllei is conducted through the an agent, but certain types of industries (particularly businesses involved in manufacturing) are almost all banked with Sisterbank.</p>
<p>In addition to government banks, money bureaus (also <em>Money Unions</em>) are a form of cooperative credit union premised on private business associations and securitised lending, and are common in Vekllei agriculture.</p>
<h4 id="institutional-banking">
  Institutional Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#institutional-banking">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Investment banking is provided primarily by the Commonwealth Bank of Vekllei (COMMBANK), which offers placement and settling services for <a href="/bureaus/">bureaus</a> seeking to engage with the International market. COMMBANK also arranges debt financing, underwriting and distribution services for overseas partners. COMMBANK also serves as the central bank of the Kalina Isles. In addition, the Bank of Vekllei maintains several subsidiaries dedicated to special financial products, like low-interest domestic infrastructure financing or overseas trade and investment.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>An entrepôt is a port where merchandise is stored and traded, often before being exported again.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>The Commonwealth capital account runs at a deficit as part of a post-war investment policy called &lsquo;Handshake Accounting,&rsquo; which sees tremendous surplus state capital invested overseas.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Foreign investment in the primary economy is usually made in the form of state-backed <a href="#blue-bonds">Blue Bonds</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Medallions, or medals, are a cultural feature in Vekllei used in spiritual ceremonies, as awards, and as a material novelty or trinket.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>&lsquo;Municipalised,&rsquo; in Vekllei political lexicon.&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Housing</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/housing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/housing/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles Housing in Vekllei is socialised in the Georgist tradition. It is a recognition that all wealth lies in land, the resources beneath it, and the people that work it. In this sense, housing in Vekllei is just as radical and striking as its moneylessness. All real estate in Vekllei is negotiated, purchased and leased at a municipal level. This system depends heavily on stewardship as a factor of ownership.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Housing</strong> in Vekllei is socialised in the Georgist tradition. It is a recognition that all wealth lies in land, the resources beneath it, and the people that work it. In this sense, housing in Vekllei is just as radical and striking as its moneylessness.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>All real estate in Vekllei is negotiated, purchased and leased at a <a href="/municipalities/">municipal</a> level. This system depends heavily on stewardship as a factor of ownership. Most free homes are rented on an open market and are awarded via an interview process with the municipality, though there are many exceptions. In general, the more time a resident spends working a property, the more powerful their claim to ownership becomes. In this sense, multigenerational family homes are nearly impossible to challenge in the delicture courts.</p>
<p>As part of <a href="/metaphysics/">Vekllei metaphysics</a>, land has rights and owns itself. Human ownership is foremost a contract with the land, and the municipality is positioned as an intermediary. In practice, land ownership is portioned between different agents based on their relationship with the property. The municipality may retain a monopoly on real estate, but most Vekllei people own their residences. All residences are designed by architects, who are an essential agent of the municipality in Vekllei.</p>
<p>Real estate is also used as <a href="/news/essays/moneylessness/#why-do-vekllei-people-work">compensation</a>. Doctors are usually housed close to their place of work in homes built for that purpose. Tenancy in Vekllei is generally of this type, where homes are tied to employment. In the Vekllei delicture system, longtime employees gradually wrest ownership away from the municipality, and homes are commonly gifted after ten or fifteen years of service.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ This article is about businesses and industrial practice in Vekllei. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">This article is about businesses and industrial practice in Vekllei.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Interim Prosperity Government</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/history/interim/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/history/interim/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the history series of articles The Interim Vekllei Government (also the Interim Parliament and Interim Prosperity Government) was a temporary puppet state of the United Kingdom, established in 2015 as a means to Vekllei independence after twenty years of British occupation in the country. It consisted of approved leaders in the arts and industry, who developed proposals for a new democratic Vekllei state.
Included was a majority female Council of Roses, many of whom were socialists opposed to communist unrest in British-occupied Vekllei and were seen as a strategic alternative to a hostile communist government upon British withdrawal.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/history/">history</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Interim Vekllei Government</strong> (also the <em>Interim Parliament</em> and <em>Interim Prosperity Government</em>) was a temporary puppet state of the United Kingdom, established in 2015 as a means to Vekllei independence after twenty years of British occupation in the country. It consisted of approved leaders in the arts and industry, who developed proposals for a new democratic Vekllei state.</p>
<p>Included was a majority female <a href="/rose-council/">Council of Roses</a>, many of whom were socialists opposed to communist unrest in British-occupied Vekllei and were seen as a strategic alternative to a hostile communist government upon British withdrawal. The council were responsible for draughting the Vekllei Constitution and establishing Interim Ministries in anticipation of independence.</p>
<p>After independence in 2017, the Vekllei Interim Government became the 4th Commonwealth of Vekllei.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Language</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/language/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about Vekllei The language of Vekllei is an important part of the project. Utopianism cascades through every part of society, and rethinking communication is a foundational part of that instinct. In this article, we look at what makes Vekllei as a language special, and give insight into how these Atlantic people communicate with each other. Overview # Vekllei language, abbreviated to just Vekllei, has six core sublanguages that are used commonly today.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.nethttps://images.millmint.net/drawing.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/factbook/vekllei"><strong>Vekllei</strong></a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>The language of Vekllei</strong> is an important part of the project. Utopianism cascades through every part of society, and rethinking communication is a foundational part of that instinct. In this article, we look at what makes Vekllei as a language special, and give insight into how these Atlantic people communicate with each other.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p><strong>Vekllei language</strong>, abbreviated to just <strong>Vekllei</strong>, has six core sublanguages that are used commonly today. Although they often intersect, these different systems of communication are distinct languages in their own right, used for different purposes in different arenas of communication.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Systems of Vekllei Language</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ol>
<li><strong>Spoken Vekllei</strong>, which is everyday spoken language. It draws from two glossaries with different meanings and feelings, called <em>Oa</em> and <em>Loh</em>.</li>
<li><strong>Topet</strong>, which are logographic characters (occasionally characterised as hieroglyphs). Like other pictographic languages, <em>Topet</em> characters can be broken down into repeating components, called <em>Topotte</em>.</li>
<li><strong>Rapotenne</strong>, is the traditional logographic language of names. It is much older than Topet, and has more in common with spiritual runes than modern logography.</li>
<li><strong>Potenne</strong>, lit. “<em>Hand-Talk</em>”, is a sign language that incorporates gestures and signing to add meaning to emotion to spoken language, and occasionally in place of it.</li>
<li><strong>Upotenne</strong>, lit. “<em>Spirit-Hand-Talk</em>”, as the recreation of runes in human form, used limitedly in spiritual ritual.</li>
<li><strong>Vekllei Semaphore</strong> is the codification of colour and shape. Traditionally limited to colour, shape and pattern are now also included in <em>Vekllei Semaphore</em>, in which full sentences can be formed.</li>
</ol>

  </div>
</details>

<h3 id="introduction">
  Introduction
  <a class="anchor" href="#introduction">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2020-11-14-language/">How to Speak Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p><em>What is the worth of the worthless?  I think it is the existence of a marvellous intuitive physicality. That is, if we use words to carve out things as having certain functions and certain uses to human beings, we overlook something very important.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>— Yoshio Nakamura</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look in more detail about how each aspect of the Vekllei language operates in daily life. With six recognised language, Vekllei is unique in its complexity and multidimensionality, appropriating a variety of scripts, glossaries, alphabets and physical components. Literacy in the country is very high, and <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#spoken-vekllei"><em>Spoken Vekllei</em></a> and <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#topet"><em>Topet</em></a> are understood universally.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/language.jpg" alt="Infographic showing how to speak Vekllei"  title="An infographic showcasing the Vekllei language, including [Potenne](/factbook/society/culture/language/#potenne) use. | *[How to Speak Vekllei](/posts/2020-11-14-language/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>An infographic showcasing the Vekllei language, including <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#potenne">Potenne</a> use. | <em><a href="/posts/2020-11-14-language/">How to Speak Vekllei</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Other languages, often called <em>sub-languages</em>, are informed regionally and have varying literacy across the Home Island. For example, <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#upotenne"><em>Upotenne</em></a> is employed frequently in rural and agrarian communities, where religious ritual requires its frequent practice. This passage introduces the broad characteristics of each sub-language, which together form contemporary Vekllei, one of the world&rsquo;s most complex and hermetic language systems.</p>
<h3 id="history">
  History
  <a class="anchor" href="#history">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei&rsquo;s language genealogy can be traced back thousands of years, and is approximated in this timeline for reference throughout this article.</p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>6000</strong> BC - <strong>3500</strong> BC, <strong>Kalaallisut / Kala</strong>, Proto-<em>Quutetast</em> extinct Algic language.</li>
<li><strong>3500</strong> BC - <strong>800</strong> AD,  <strong>Quutetast</strong>,  Algic-Aleutian extinct language.</li>
<li><strong>1200</strong> BC - <strong>900</strong> AD, <strong>Islandi</strong>,  Indo-European Scandinavian language.</li>
<li><strong>900</strong> AD - <strong>1600</strong> AD, <strong>Topyas</strong> (Old Vekllei),  fusion dialect of <em>Islandi</em> and <em>Quutetast</em>.</li>
<li><strong>1600</strong> AD - <strong>present</strong>, <strong>Modern Vekllei</strong>, evolution of <em>Topyas</em>. Spoken today.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="spoken-vekllei">
  Spoken Vekllei
  <a class="anchor" href="#spoken-vekllei">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Spoken Vekllei</strong>, simply referred to as Vekllei domestically, is the common spoken language of Vekllei and official language of the country, spoken by some 25 million people worldwide, with 98% of speakers living natively in the Vekllei Home Islands. It is the first spoken language of the vast majority of the population, and has minor variance across the disparate Vekllei Home Islands and other Vekllei possessions. It is rarely spoken outside of Vekllei territories, extant abroad only through emigrant populations and small diasporic communities dispersed after the Atomic War.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Contemporary spoken Vekllei is largely descended from <em>Proto-Islandi</em> speech that arrived with the first Danish settlers in the country, but includes <em>Kalaallisut</em> and Proto-Algic reconstructions of an early extinct language called <em>Kala</em>. Modern spoken Vekllei has heritage in the combined, largely extinct language hybrid of Algic-Aleutian <em>Quutetast</em> and the Indo-European <em>Islandi,</em> which by the 9th century had fused into common speech usually called <em>Topyas</em>, or &lsquo;Old Speech&rsquo;/&lsquo;Old Vekllei&rsquo;. Modern Vekllei has evolved distinctively since the Atomic War as part of broader sociological trends towards informalised speech and cultivated <em>Loh</em> vocabularies.</p>
<h3 id="twin-glossaries">
  Twin Glossaries
  <a class="anchor" href="#twin-glossaries">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Spoken Vekllei draws from two glossaries, called <em>Oa</em> and <em>Loh</em>. These glossaries date back to twin reconstructed Algic-Aleutian languages called <em>Quutetast</em> and <em>Islandi</em> that had been present in earlier forms since at least 1200BC. The glossaries were formalised in pagan ritual that would become present-day <a href="/vekllei/religion"><em>Upen</em></a>, and later recognised as the official language of the country in the reformation initiated by Queen Souisviasn in the 3rd century.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h5 id="oa-lit-sun">
  Oa (<em>lit.</em> Sun)
  <a class="anchor" href="#oa-lit-sun">#</a>
</h5>
<em>Oa</em> is considered to have &lsquo;permanent&rsquo; traits. It is often characterised abroad as a positive glossary, though this is not true &ndash; it is in fact dedicated to inanimate and unliving organs. Although Vekllei does not gender nouns, this glossary is often gendered conceptually as masculine, and is most commonly associated with Summer and Spring. Despite its long history, Vekllei as an island is itself understood to be female &ndash; mostly because its volcanic landscape, which straddles two drifting continental plates, is constantly changing.</li>
<li>
<h5 id="loh-lit-moon">
  Loh (<em>lit.</em> Moon)
  <a class="anchor" href="#loh-lit-moon">#</a>
</h5>
<em>Loh</em> is considered to have &lsquo;cyclical&rsquo; traits. Loh words are largely derived from Old Vekllei (including <em>Icelandic/Islandi</em>), and so its glossary is considerably less defined and dependent on older linguistic artefacts. <em>Loh</em> words incorporate sounds and grammatical artefacts from extinct languages within Vekllei&rsquo;s ancient history, and so it is often associated with traditional or formal speech. It is commonly gendered as feminine, and is associated with winter and autumn.</li>
</ul>
<p>In modernity, this binary produces bizarre psycholinguistic quirks. For example, a sailing vessel (<em>Siv</em>) is derived from the <em>Oa</em>, historically because the <em>Oa</em> glossary was favoured for machines between the 10th and 16th Centuries. This genders all modern oceangoing vessels as male figures to this day, and due to <em>Siv</em>&rsquo;s linguistic derivatives, ties ships permanently to the lumber and woodlands critical to wooden shipbuilding. From the 20th century onwards, however, most vehicles are regarded impermanent through <em>Loh</em>, and so all cars in Vekllei are conceptually female.</p>
<h3 id="phonology">
  Phonology
  <a class="anchor" href="#phonology">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Spoken Vekllei is phonologically homogenous, and has little variation in accent or pronunciation across the Home Island or its various possessions, although there is some evidence for differences in dialect between cultivated speech on the coast and rural phonology in the interior of the Home Islands.</p>
<h4 id="monophthongs">
  Monophthongs
  <a class="anchor" href="#monophthongs">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Pure vowels in Vekllei are characterised by their lax, non-rhotic sound, and their uses vary across cultivated and common Vekllei dialects.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Pure Vowels</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th>Front</th>
<th></th>
<th></th>
<th>Central</th>
<th></th>
<th>Back</th>
<th></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Short</td>
<td>Long</td>
<td>Long (round)</td>
<td>Short</td>
<td>Long</td>
<td>Short</td>
<td>Long</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Close</strong></td>
<td>ɪ</td>
<td>iː</td>
<td>y</td>
<td></td>
<td>ʉː</td>
<td>ʊ</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Close-Mid</strong></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>ø</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Mid</strong></td>
<td>e</td>
<td>eː</td>
<td></td>
<td>ə</td>
<td>ɜː</td>
<td>ɔ</td>
<td>oː</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Open-Mid</strong></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>œ</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Open</strong></td>
<td>æ</td>
<td>(æː)</td>
<td></td>
<td>ɐ</td>
<td>ɐː</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

  </div>
</details>

<h4 id="diphthongs">
  Diphthongs
  <a class="anchor" href="#diphthongs">#</a>
</h4>
<p>From foundational monophthongs, gliding or diphthong vowels are often determined by glossary. <em>Oa</em> typically favours modernised post-<em>Quutetast</em> glides for its so-called <em>Ocean Vowels</em>, which are generally long and unrounded. <em>Loh</em> words are typically older and depicted pictographically, and are pronounced as <em>Floral Vowels</em>. The tables below list their pronunciation.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Diphthongs</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <h5 id="ocean-vowels">
  Ocean Vowels
  <a class="anchor" href="#ocean-vowels">#</a>
</h5>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th>Vowel</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Closing</strong></td>
<td>æɪ, ɑɪ, oɪ, æɔ, əʉ</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Centering</strong></td>
<td>ɪə</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h5 id="floral-vowel">
  Floral Vowel
  <a class="anchor" href="#floral-vowel">#</a>
</h5>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Vowel</th>
<th>Onset glide</th>
<th>Onset glide</th>
<th>Onset glide</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Vowel</strong></td>
<td><strong>/j/</strong></td>
<td><strong>/ɥ/</strong></td>
<td><strong>/w/</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/a/</strong></td>
<td>/ja/</td>
<td>/ɥa/</td>
<td>/wa/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/ɑ/</strong></td>
<td>/jɑ/</td>
<td>/ɥɑ/</td>
<td>/wɑ/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/ɑ̃/</strong></td>
<td>/jɑ̃/</td>
<td>/ɥɑ̃/</td>
<td>/wɑ̃/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/e/</strong></td>
<td>/je/</td>
<td>/ɥe/</td>
<td>/we/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/ɛ/</strong></td>
<td>/jɛ/</td>
<td>/ɥɛ/</td>
<td>/wɛ/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/ɛ̃/</strong></td>
<td>/jɛ̃/</td>
<td>/ɥɛ̃/</td>
<td>/wɛ̃/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/i/</strong></td>
<td>/ji/</td>
<td>/ɥi/</td>
<td>/wi/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/o/</strong></td>
<td>/jo/</td>
<td>/ɥo/</td>
<td>/wo/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/ɔ/</strong></td>
<td>/jɔ/</td>
<td>/ɥɔ/</td>
<td>/wɔ/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/ɔ̃/</strong></td>
<td>/jɔ̃/</td>
<td>/ɥɔ̃/</td>
<td>/wɔ̃/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/ø/</strong></td>
<td>/jø/</td>
<td>/ɥø/</td>
<td>/wø/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/œ/</strong></td>
<td>/jœ/</td>
<td>/ɥœ/</td>
<td>/wœ/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/u/</strong></td>
<td>/ju/</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>/y/</strong></td>
<td>/jy/</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

  </div>
</details>

<h4 id="consonants">
  Consonants
  <a class="anchor" href="#consonants">#</a>
</h4>
<p>In Vekllei, consonants are arranged in five places of primary articulation.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Consonants</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th>Labial</th>
<th>Alveolar</th>
<th>Palatal</th>
<th>Velar</th>
<th>Uvular</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Voiceless stop</td>
<td>p /p/</td>
<td>t /t/</td>
<td></td>
<td>k /k/</td>
<td>q /q/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Voiceless fricative</td>
<td></td>
<td>s /s/ł /ɬ/(h /h/)</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Voiced</td>
<td>v /v/</td>
<td>l /l/</td>
<td>j /j/(j, r̂  /ɟ/)</td>
<td>g /ɡ/</td>
<td>r /ʁ/</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Nasal</td>
<td>m /m/</td>
<td>n /n/</td>
<td></td>
<td>ng /ŋ/</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

  </div>
</details>

<h2 id="topet">
  Topet
  <a class="anchor" href="#topet">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Topet</strong>, sometimes called <em>Vekllei Script</em> or <em>Vekllei hieroglyphs</em> is the formal writing system in Vekllei. Topet incorporates logographic and neosyllabic/abugida-type components, and has some 3,450 unique characters in modern usage. Although proto-glyphs and a primitive runic system had been used in <em>Islandi</em>-era Vekllei since at least the 8th Century BC, by the time <em>Quutetast</em> influences had arrived with Inuit settlement in the 4th Century AD the parent scripts had at least partially fused into proto-<em>Topet</em>, called <em>Hieyeric</em>. In Vekllei, <em>Topet</em> is the national language alongside its sister-form, <em><a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#rapotenne">Rapotenne</a></em> and <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#spoken-vekllei"><em>Spoken Vekllei</em></a>. Topet has no clear lineage from Scandinavian or Inuit languages, and so is rarely understood outside of the territories where it is an official or significant minority language, which represents some 25 million people.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Individual <em>Topet</em> characters are both phonograms and semagrams, and so they support multiple readings. Many are basically figurative, and represent conceptually what they depict. Each character conforms to an abugida-type system, in which consonant-vowel pairings are written in joined notation. In <em>Topet</em>, the consonant anchors the pairing, which is called <em>Lohtopet</em>, and vowel notation is usually raised in superscript, called <em>Oatopet</em>. These names are not related to the binary glossary, but do represent the upper/lower system those glossaries imply. &ldquo;Oa&rdquo; means <em>affirmative</em> in Vekllei, and <em>Loh</em> is a negating form, so their use is widespread beyond the binary glossary system.</p>
<h3 id="phonetic-reading">
  Phonetic Reading
  <a class="anchor" href="#phonetic-reading">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Anchoring consonant-vowel characters (<em>demioette</em>, as opposed to double-vowels or vowel-consonants, called <em>hieyerette</em><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>) written in Topet may feature redundant adjacent characters called <em>phonetic complements</em>, which, in a non-determinative reading, are pronounced the same way to guide the reader. This lends to a system that encourages adjacent duplicate consonant-vowel pairings in some aspects, since Vekllei words are already formed out of neosyllabic pairings and it is immediately obvious which characters are to be read. The word for friend, <em>comoyia</em>, can thus sometimes be transliterated into c-c-c<sup>o</sup>m-m<sup>o</sup>y<sup>ia</sup>, which can affect the conceptual meanings of a word through the figurative placement of its characters as well as help guide the reader through the use of multiple phonetically identical, though visually distinct, characters.</p>
<p>In the above case, <em>comoyia</em> can be affected by the composition of its phonetic complements, if any are used at all. There is a default reading, which combines both semantic and phonetic readings for meaning and is generally recognised as the dictionary &lsquo;spelling&rsquo; of the word, but this can be manipulated through the addition of semantically different, but identically phonetic characters to shade and change meaning. The word for an untrustworthy friend is also <em>comoyia</em>, but combines the characters for snake with the dictionary spelling, which produces a transliteration similar to c-c<sup>o</sup>m<sup>o</sup>y<sup>ia</sup>. In spoken Vekllei, this distinction is only communicable through the aid of <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#potenne"><em>Potenne</em></a>, and represents one of its primary uses.</p>
<h3 id="semantic-reading">
  Semantic Reading
  <a class="anchor" href="#semantic-reading">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Many <em>Topet</em> characters are figurative; they represent their meanings pictographically, like Egyptian <em>Hieroglyphs</em> or Chinese <em>Hanzi</em>. In Vekllei, this is considered an evolved rune-form, and ties into a broader conceptualisation of language as a <em>transcendental</em>, rather than <em>literal</em> system. Although <em>Topet</em>&rsquo;s early form, <em>Hieyeric</em>, was explicitly pictographic, modern <em>Topet</em> is often abstracted and decoupled from its figurative meaning via the phonetic system.</p>
<p>Despite common use of the phonetic system in modernity, the semantic readings of characters are taught and essential for literacy beyond literal imitation of speech. For the vast majority of <em>Topet</em> characters, their logographic meaning determines their pronunciation, and consonant characters especially depend on this meaning to form words. The word for breakfast is <em>petimourgeneur</em>, but it cannot be written with random literal phonetic characters; parts of the word depend on the figurative meaning of certain components, and so without its semantic traits the word would be illegible to most people. This represents a wider co-dependency on simultaneous phonetic and semantic readings of words, with the importance of each fluctuating depending on the word in question. Older words tend to be heavily figurative, whereas modern and loan words are often more phonetic. This inconsistency is part of the difficulty in learning <em>Topet</em>, and leaves many immigrants fluent in speech but inadequately literate in reading and writing.</p>
<h3 id="structure">
  Structure
  <a class="anchor" href="#structure">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-05-31-topet/">How to Read Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Individual <em>Topet</em> characters are both semantic and phonetic, and can be written in a phonetic abugida (with semantic weight carried by the initial character-group) or as a single character group. The abugida-form is phonetic and aids vocalisation through its <em>hieyerette</em> characters. The single character group-form is pictographic, and generally replaces the abugida in contexts where the pronunciation is commonly known or obvious. In these character groups, only one <em>demioette</em> character is vocalised, called the <em>principle</em>, and the <em>hieyerette</em> characters are simply not written.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/topet.jpg" alt="Infographic showing Vekllei scripts"  title="An infographic summarising the appearance of Vekllei scripts, including [*Topet*](/factbook/society/culture/language/#topet). | *[How to Read Vekllei](/posts/2021-05-31-topet/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>An infographic summarising the appearance of Vekllei scripts, including <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#topet"><em>Topet</em></a>. | <em><a href="/posts/2021-05-31-topet/">How to Read Vekllei</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>These character groups are called <em>Minor Demons</em>, or <em>pettidemion,</em> and change appearance depending on the number of characters in its group. One character occupies a quarter-height space in the centre of a line. Two characters are written in an adjacent quarter-height space, with the principle arranged to the left. Three characters are arranged in a triangle, with the principle arranged at the top. Four characters, the maximum in modern <em>Topet</em>, are arranged in a quadrant with the principle arranged in the top left.</p>
<p><em>Minor Demons</em> are the foundations of <em>Topet</em> script, since they can be written phonetically or as pictographs. This also contributes to <em>Topet</em>&rsquo;s unusual linguistic structure, in which single words are modified heavily and often come to resemble sentences with self-contained adjectives.</p>
<h2 id="rapotenne">
  Rapotenne
  <a class="anchor" href="#rapotenne">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Rapotenne</strong> (<em>lit. &ldquo;Name-Talk&rdquo;</em>) is the Vekllei system of names, often considered in modernity to function as a distinct, though limited, language. Today, it is most often employed as an extant language of magical staves, but is closely aligned phonologically and ethnographically with <em>Upotenne</em>, the physical language of rune-forms and sigils.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Contemporary <em>Rapotenne</em> is informed by pictographic proto-<em>Topet</em> runes as well as elements of the extinct <em>Kala</em> language, and subsequently <em>Quutetast</em> Algic artefacts. Because <em>Kala</em> is extinct and <em>Quutetast</em> is a dead language, largely displaced by modern spoken Vekllei, <em>Rapotenne</em> is unique among Vekllei&rsquo;s sublanguages for its direct lineage from proto-linguistic forms of early Vekllei history, some nearly 4,000 years old. Today it is used largely ceremonially, through ritual related to birth and Blood Names.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p><em>Rapotenne</em> has its origins in superstitious <em>Islandi</em> magical staves, sigils which evolved into battle names and honourifics, called Blood Names. The use of Blood Names varies across Vekllei history, but is still common across ancestral families today. In modern immigration, especially after the Atomic War and British occupation, Blood Names have been commonly adopted by new families as symbolic displacement of older bloodlines, largely for their fashionable association with royalty and heritage. <em>Rapotenne</em> today mostly employs older <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#diphthongs">Floral Vowels</a>, which themselves are likely evolutions of proto-<em>Quutetast</em> pronunciation associated with <em>Kala</em>. Rapotenne characters, also called <em>Rapotenne</em>, are closely associated with old runic Islandi sigils, and are purely figurative. Their use in modernity is largely instructional, and is used to determine and act out <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#upotenne"><em>Upotenne</em></a> signs, which is functionally adjacent to <em>Rapotenne</em>.</p>
<h3 id="practice">
  Practice
  <a class="anchor" href="#practice">#</a>
</h3>
<p><em>Rapotenne</em> consists of 452 characters in common practice, although priests and regional dialects may employ upwards of 1,000. Despite integration with the formal Vekllei language constellation, minor differences in pronunciation survive. For example, the Alveolar /s͇/ is dropped before consonants in ordinary spoken Vekllei, making it rare in modern usage, but is voiced in <em>Rapotenne</em>. The shape and stroke order of characters determines the physicality of <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#upotenne"><em>Upotenne</em></a>, as their function within ritual is more or less the same. Although simplistic and literally figurative, <em>Rapotenne</em> is used extensively in religious script and poetry, and remains an important cultural force within Vekllei.</p>
<h2 id="potenne">
  Potenne
  <a class="anchor" href="#potenne">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>Try Potenne yourself!</strong> Hold out your thumb and forefinger on one hand, and tuck the other fingers against your palm. You&rsquo;ve just said &ldquo;good to see you again.&rdquo;</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Potenne</strong> (<em>lit. &ldquo;Hand-Talk&rdquo;</em>) is an indigenous auxiliary sign language in Vekllei used commonly today as an aid or substitute for vocalised speech. It was originally a form of <em>avoidance speech</em> that arose in response to social taboos in <em><a href="/vekllei/religion.md">Upen</a></em>, but acquired broader use by the 16th century and is employed commonly today part of many conventions and customs within the Home Islands. <em>Potenne</em> is also used by hearing-disabled persons in Vekllei to communicate.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Historic social taboos in Vekllei&rsquo;s dominant religion, Upen, prevented speech between people for a variety of reasons, including for marital, interfamilial, penal and ascetic considerations. <em>Potenne</em> first arose to avoid these taboos. During the first substantial immigration of Inuit-Kalaallisut peoples in the 4th century BC, proto-<em>Potenne</em> avoidance languages developed pragmatic pidgin forms to allow for trade and communication between settlers and the original Islandi population. This rapid expansion in use saw <em>Potenne</em> develop solidified cultural tenants, including phonologically distinct suprasegmental components like <em>biouspotenne</em> (<em>lit. &ldquo;Face-Talk&rdquo;</em>), which distinguishes facial expression from gestures in poetic, transcendental forms, and <em>kiouyapotenne</em> (<em>lit. &ldquo;Child-Talk&rdquo;</em>), which uses facial expressions to teach children individual signs.</p>
<p>By the 11th Century, <em>Potenne</em> was documented alongside other critical languages like <em>Topet</em>, and had demonstrated its saturation of Vekllei society in several sociological and cultural forms, including <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#upotenne"><em>Upotenne</em></a>, today considered an independent language system within Vekllei&rsquo;s varied linguistic cultures.</p>
<p><em>Potenne</em> is used today as a casual substitute for simple speech and to communicate figurative meanings of words in <em>Topet</em> otherwise uncommunicable in conventional speech.</p>
<h3 id="phonology-1">
  Phonology
  <a class="anchor" href="#phonology-1">#</a>
</h3>
<p>It is important to remember that <em>Potenne</em> is not simply a reproduction of ordinary speech in physical form; it is a language that assists the spoken word. Many Vekllei words can be simplified by incorporating <em>Potenne</em>, which better mimics nonverbal components of <em>Topet</em> and helps provide emotion and context to otherwise ambiguous phrases. In other cases, it replaces speech entirely, often in quiet areas or out of respect in public transit. In this sense, <em>Potenne</em> retains a handful of the characteristics inherited from its origins as an avoidance language, but remains distinct from both spoken Vekllei and <em>Topet</em> in its capacity to link and colour both.</p>
<h4 id="location">
  Location
  <a class="anchor" href="#location">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Most <em>Potenne</em> is acted out just below the chest, in a casual resting position. Positional and place-based signs are performed at the right shoulder, and emotion is often acted out at or just below the chin. Regional traits and dialects are common, and <em>Potenne</em> is perhaps Vekllei&rsquo;s most provincial and least documented language.</p>
<h4 id="movement">
  Movement
  <a class="anchor" href="#movement">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Upen signs are generally simple, and practiced quickly and casually. The direction of the fore and ring fingers generally indicate subject, and the position of the thumb indicates tone — an outstretched thumb is casual whereas a thumb tucked inwards appears formal. Common words use simple, single-handed signs, but complete sentences and more complex words almost always require the use of both hands.</p>
<h4 id="orientation">
  Orientation
  <a class="anchor" href="#orientation">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Communication in the your own voice is performed with the hand held horizontally with few exceptions. Quoting speech and reading is most often spoken with the hand held vertically, although this varies between dialects. Various orientations incorporate meaning, including casual affirmation and some emotions.</p>
<h4 id="handshape">
  Handshape
  <a class="anchor" href="#handshape">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Most signs are communicated with an open palm, although fists, hooked fingers, clenched fingers and relaxation of fingers are also used in various ways. Most common <em>Potenne</em> words are characterised by their informal, almost lazy composition, and so handshape is particularly gestural, often dependent on vocalised context to be legible. It can be difficult to determine within <em>Potenne</em> a clear distinction between non-linguistic gestural communication and its formalised language system, and so the emotiveness and context of its signs are critical to literacy in Vekllei.</p>
<h2 id="upotenne">
  Upotenne
  <a class="anchor" href="#upotenne">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Upotenne</strong> (<em>lit. &ldquo;Spirit-Hand-Talk&rdquo;</em>) is the nonverbal sign language of religious ritual in Vekllei. Although adjacent to <em>Potenne</em>, <em>Upotenne</em> is more closely historically aligned with <em>Rapotenne</em> than modern Vekllei.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Much as <em>Potenne</em> combines semantic and verbal forms to enhance communication, <em>Upen</em> appropriates the older pictographic <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#rapotenne"><em>Rapotenne</em></a> script to aid spiritual ritual and <em>demiosnjarnkah</em> (<em>lit. &ldquo;Old Arts&rdquo;</em><sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>). Although few Vekllei people are completely literate in it, <em>Upotenne</em> remains a cultural force throughout society and is used commonly in ritual around the Home Islands.</p>
<p><em>Upotenne</em> is characterised as a sign language in keeping with the traditions in <em>Potenne</em>, but also incorporates complex cultural artefacts unique to <em>Upen</em> within its symbolism as a language. It codifies the human form and reproduces it in a spiritual manner, assigning importance and symbolism to parts of the human body ignored by the secular <em>Potenne</em>. Where much of the communication in <em>Potenne</em> is dependent on hand-based signs and gestures, <em>Upotenne</em> is mostly positional, using joints and angles to imitate rune-forms. These type and imitation of rune-forms vary greatly between different parts of Vekllei society, since literacy is dependent on landscape; rural persons will most likely recognise and communicate runes that benefit harvest and weather, where urban persons are more likely to participate in ceremonies to benefit employment or love.</p>
<p>This multidimensionality means that <em>Upotenne</em> is uniquely dependent on place and circumstance, as Vekllei people learn and dispense with signs that benefit their circumstance. Despite <em>Upotenne</em>&rsquo;s capacity as a language, it is largely displaced by its use as a spiritual adjacent to <em>Potenne</em> in modern society, leaving only <em>Upen</em> priests and disciples fluent in one of Vekllei&rsquo;s oldest cultural traditions.</p>
<h2 id="vekllei-semaphore">
  Vekllei Semaphore
  <a class="anchor" href="#vekllei-semaphore">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Vekllei lo da Myaiouisvah</strong> (<em>lit. &ldquo;Vekllei-Flag-System&rdquo;</em>) is the sixth and most unusual of the Vekllei sublanguages. It relies heavily on colour and form, and is largely abstracted from its subject matter. In this sense, <em>Vekllei Semaphore</em> can be considered to be <em>asemic</em>, since it has no material semantic meaning and is entirely illegible without instruction.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>It is most commonly used to enhance <em>Topet</em> and communicate in public spaces, through stationary, flags, banners, painted lines, stylised infrastructure and clothing as shorthand for established <em>Topet</em> phrases. Its association with media like television and illustration has caused some ethnographers to suggest Vekllei Semaphore as sign of evolving postliteracy<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> in Vekllei, as modern systems of media and communication make it easier for people to go without reading or writing day-to-day.</p>
<p><em>Vekllei lo da Myaiouisvah</em> originated in the early 17th century in the navy, where it was largely informed by <em>Upotenne</em>. It had an obvious practical purpose in communication between oceangoing vessels, but later saw general use among ordinary people as Vekllei developed, evolving into a sort of natural industrial sister language of <em>Rapotenne</em>.</p>
<p>By the 19th Century, <em>Vekllei Semaphore</em> had lost a lot of its original connotations with military pragmatism and had started to evolve and establish itself in different roles in society, fuelled by an emerging aesthetic interest in bloodlines and colonial enterprise. Colour and formless symbolism quickly took on new meaning as a way of distinguishing class and education across the country in highly fashionable shifts in culture. As the colonial machine of Vekllei&rsquo;s late monarchy and early junta developed a sprawling bureaucracy and civil service, these meanings were codified and later formalised as the language of the empire. It was rapidly revitalised during Vekllei&rsquo;s independence from British occupation after the First Atomic War, and is the youngest and fastest-developing of Vekllei&rsquo;s languages. It remains a unique cultural phenomenon among developed countries today.</p>
<p><em>Vekllei Semaphore</em> is most useful in public, shared space as a form of mass-communication. Its relative universality within the country means that many public-facing organisations and concerns employ it as a sort of &lsquo;shared symbolism;&rsquo; an unspoken democratic language used in shared spaces and common forums.</p>
<h3 id="symbolism">
  Symbolism
  <a class="anchor" href="#symbolism">#</a>
</h3>
<p>There are several components within <em>Vekllei Semaphore</em> which employs types of symbolism depending on their purpose and context.</p>
<h4 id="colourcoda">
  Colourcoda
  <a class="anchor" href="#colourcoda">#</a>
</h4>
<p><em>Colourcoda</em> is the means by which <em>Vekllei Semaphore</em> reassembles colour values in social forms through patterns, colour placement and contrast. Visitors will likely have encountered <em>Colourcoda</em> without even realising it; the transliteration of green and gold on <a href="/images/uniform.jpg">the uniforms of Puffin Scouts</a> is &ldquo;peacefulness besides the land;&rdquo; the red and white of <a href="/images/trials.jpg">the Vekllei school uniform</a> means &ldquo;youth of Vekllei,&rdquo; and <a href="/images/feast.jpg">the blue and white of a Venopor police car</a> means &ldquo;royal defence&rdquo;. Patterns quickly complexify this meaning, allowing for more sophisticated sentence construction, though few Vekllei people are fluent.</p>
<h4 id="formsigns">
  Formsigns
  <a class="anchor" href="#formsigns">#</a>
</h4>
<p><em>Formsigns</em> are the means by which <em>Vekllei Semaphore</em> encodes meaning in shape. Vekllei (as a landscape) is depicted by a circle within the <em>Loh</em> glossary, and an arched point in the <em>Oa</em> glossary. These forms are adjacent to pictographics, but <em>formsigns</em> can also be totally abstracted. The borders on stationary and envelopes, for example, contain specific meaning when joined with specific colours. This concept saturates Vekllei society &ndash; title cards in television, armbands, pinstripes, aircraft livery and basic shapes can all produce phonetic recognition in Vekllei people depending on their context and use.</p>
<h4 id="semaphore">
  Semaphore
  <a class="anchor" href="#semaphore">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Flags are used heavily in Vekllei semaphore, but are distinct from traditional semaphore systems through their use and appearance. Semaphore within <em>da Myaiouisvah</em> share more in common with <em>Upotenne</em> than they do alphabetic semaphore, and are largely figurative of extant runes. Flags are also very common objects that incorporate <em>formsigns</em> and <em>colourcoda,</em> and used frequently within Vekllei as means of communication. Festivals, companies and bureaus all use their own flags as means of identifying and communicating in public space.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><em>Demioette</em> and <em>hieyerette</em> meaning lit. &ldquo;early lower&rdquo; and &ldquo;early higher&rdquo; respectively.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><em>Blood Names</em> are traditional ancestral names carried along a mother&rsquo;s genetic heritage. Traditionally kept secret until burial, this custom has mostly fallen out of practice in modern Vekllei.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p><em>Demiosnjarnkah</em>, or &ldquo;old arts,&rdquo; refers to the religious tradition of poetry and art-making, which to this day depends on the older extant glossaries of Vekllei&rsquo;s early runic system.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p><em>Postliteracy</em> is a hypothetical concept popularised in the early 21st Century during massive upheavals in education and mass media by telescreens and the videophone. It suggests that, as reading and writing are replaced by convenient forms of visual communication, traditional literacy becomes unnecessary. Sometimes called <em>aliteracy</em>.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mail</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/mail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/mail/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about Vekllei society The Royal Mail of Vekllei is perhaps the country&rsquo;s most visible organisation overseas. For many foreigners, Royal Mail aircraft may be the closest they ever come to seeing for themselves the mysterious Atlantic country. For Vekllei residents, the ancient organisation is a living relic of the country&rsquo;s ancient history, and an ongoing testament to the longevity of their people. Overview # The Royal Mail of Vekllei, referred to as the Mail or Mail A.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.nethttps://images.millmint.net/mailtrain.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/factbook/vekllei"><strong>Vekllei</strong></a> society</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>The Royal Mail of Vekllei</strong> is perhaps the country&rsquo;s most visible organisation overseas. For many foreigners, Royal Mail aircraft may be the closest they ever come to seeing for themselves the mysterious Atlantic country. For Vekllei residents, the ancient organisation is a living relic of the country&rsquo;s ancient history, and an ongoing testament to the longevity of their people.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p><strong>The Royal Mail of Vekllei</strong>, referred to as the <strong>Mail</strong> or <strong>Mail A.r.</strong><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> within the country, is the national postal carrier of <a href="/factbook/vekllei">Vekllei</a>. It is a military state requisite reponsible for all postage in the country, and delivers nearly 50 million mail pieces domestically and abroad each day. One of the oldest institutions of its kind in Vekllei, it was founded in 1422 as a courier system between the Vekllei Kingdom and its largely mercenary military force. In 1742, it was formalised as a modern postal system available to the civilian public, and today offers a variety of services available to all Vekllei residents, including external territories.</p>
<p>Vekllei is also home to the U.N. Universal Postal Union, the body responsible for coordinating international postage, of which Vekllei is a signatory.</p>
<h3 id="introduction">
  Introduction
  <a class="anchor" href="#introduction">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-22-pond/">Post is for People</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Mail is old enough to have its own hieroglyph in <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#3-topet"><em>Topet</em></a>, which has resulted in the somewhat misleading transliteration of its name. In Vekllei, it is simply called the &lsquo;Mail&rsquo;, since its written name includes both its royal and national meanings intrinsically. Abroad, this is usually translated as the Royal Mail of Vekllei, but this is in fact more of a description of the organisation than its proper name.</p>
<p>Since Vekllei refers to its territory as its sovereign (expressed commonly as the &lsquo;Landscape Sovereign&rsquo;), the Mail remains Royal even today, centuries after the collapse of the monarchy that founded it. Despite its regular function as a postal service, it is nonetheless considered a resource of landscape, not a government department, and so it remains &ldquo;the Royal Mail of Vekllei&rdquo; in the 21st Century.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/fairie.jpg" alt="Picture of mail seaplane"  title="An MS Model 54-2 *Fairie*, used to deliver mail to Vekllei&#39;s islands and islets | *[The Fairie](/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>An MS Model 54-2 <em>Fairie</em>, used to deliver mail to Vekllei&rsquo;s islands and islets | <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/">The Fairie</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Like most Royal Bureaus, the Mail is headquartered in Vekllei&rsquo;s capital across a dozen or so city blocks dedicated to administration, manufacturing, vehicle storage and maintenance, and Vekllei&rsquo;s General Post Office. There are over 6,400 post offices in Vekllei today, connecting the dense Home Islands to its far-flung peripheral territories.</p>
<h3 id="history">
  History
  <a class="anchor" href="#history">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-01-mail/">The Men and Women of the Royal Mail in Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Although Vekllei has maintained courier systems for at least a thousand years, the Mail as a contiguous instituion was founded in 1422 by the Desimou VII, King of Vekllei, in the late Period of Rest. During this time, the lords of Vekllei had established significant mercantile holdings across the North Atlantic, and had developed reliable systems of trade throughout Ireland and Denmark. The Royal Mail of Vekllei was first established as a royal communications organ that sought to ensure stability of the Desimou rule across the incresingly autonomous Vekllei empire. In this period, the Mail consisted of a handful of messengers attached to the feudal military apparatus of the Vekllei monarchy, which transferred to the incoming Junta upon collapse of the monarchy.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/pond.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<p>The Mail would not come to resemble conventional civilian Mail until 1652, when the Junta expanded postal contracts to the privy councils of the Faroe and Greenland territories, and later broke apart the Mail monopoly to benefit then-Secretary of State Kism Sismiosnah, who established the New Parliament Postal Service. It was not until nearly a century later, in 1742, that company services were opened to all land-owning Vekllei people, and the Mail came to resemble its contemporary mandate.</p>
<p>The Mail was reestablished in 2015, during Vekllei independence. It was afforded a mandate protected by the postwar <a href="/vekllei/#floral-society">Petticoat Constitution</a>, and all existing private mail services established in occupation were folded directly into the new state monopoly. In 2016, a year after reestablishment, Mi Miou was elected as the world&rsquo;s first female Postmistress General. The Floral Period of the Royal Mail has been marked by a rapid expansion of both infrastructure and services in Vekllei and abroad. World Post, the international for-profit arm of the Mail, was established in 2034.</p>
<h3 id="structure">
  Structure
  <a class="anchor" href="#structure">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/">The Postmistress of Vekllei</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Mail is organised horizontally as an independent branch of the Royal Vekllei Armed Forces, and so, unlike other State Requisites, reports directly to the Prime Ministers of the Vekllei Government, as representatives of the Landscape Sovereign. As is common with most large-scale industry in Vekllei, the Mail is vertically integrated, and the majority of its contract work is consolidated directly into the bureau structure.</p>
<p>The Mail has two offices of administration: the General Office and the Office of the Postmistress, which are responsible for daily operations and interdepartmental administration respectively. The following table outlines the Mail&rsquo;s structure.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>The Royal Mail of Vekllei</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li><strong>General Office</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Postal Service Bureau</strong>
<ul>
<li>Royal Mail Press
<ul>
<li><em>Bulletin of the Mail</em></li>
<li>Materials Manufacturie</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Financial Services Bureau</li>
<li>Special Services Office
<ul>
<li>Postal Inspection Offices</li>
<li>Joint HO/NI Postal Commission</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Overseas Service Bureau</strong>
<ul>
<li>World Post Company</li>
<li>Universal Express Company</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Office of Mail</strong>
<ul>
<li>VK Mail Chapel (VKC 1st Mail Workers Unite)</li>
<li>Service Assurance Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Office of Telecommunications</strong>
<ul>
<li>Cosma
<ul>
<li>Cosma Vekllei</li>
<li>Cosma Overseas</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Industrial Telecommunications Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Office of Company Infrastructure</strong>
<ul>
<li>Department of Lines</li>
<li>Department of Post Boxes</li>
<li>Department of Vehicles</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Office of the Postmistress</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Postal Commission</strong></li>
<li><strong>Mail Democracy Office</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<h2 id="services">
  Services
  <a class="anchor" href="#services">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/">Philately Foolery</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>The Royal Mail</strong> maintains a constitutionally-bound monopoly on all postage in the country, leaving it the sole provider of universal postage service in Vekllei. Like most State Requisites (A.r.), however, it has substantial international trade and foreign dealings that provide for its common description as a state-owned for-profit enterprise, or public corporation.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Universal service is</strong>, by the glossary of the Mail, truly universal. As mandated by Vekllei law, the Mail provides delivery for all postage material anywhere in the world, or indeed, beyond it. It maintains 6,424 post offices across Vekllei, including its antarctic and peripheral possessions. The Mail&rsquo;s first Lunar Post Office opened in 2059. In addition to its domestic monopoly, the Mail contributes nearly VK❦2.6 trillion each year towards the Vekllei Government Securities Bureau (the country&rsquo;s sovereign wealth fund) through its international postage and courier services abroad, under the name World Post.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/stamps.jpg" alt="Picture of Tziopra with her stamp collection"  title="[Tzipora](/factbook/characters/#tzipora-zelda-desmoisnes) arranges some of her favourite Vekllei stamps | *[Philately Foolery](/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption><a href="/factbook/characters/#tzipora-zelda-desmoisnes">Tzipora</a> arranges some of her favourite Vekllei stamps | <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/">Philately Foolery</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Since the Mail&rsquo;s Office of Telecommunications is also responsible for all telephones, telegrams and videophones in the country, the Mail&rsquo;s status as a lynchpin of communication is absolute, and heavily protected by the postwar Vekllei constitution.</p>
<h3 id="daily-service">
  Daily Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#daily-service">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/">Racing the Post Office to the Station</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Mail aims to provide next-day delivery during weekdays in zero-code (that is to say, <em>Home Island</em>) regions. Overnight delivery is also generally available between <em>Home Islands</em>, <em>Aismious</em> Islands, <em>Kala</em> and the <em>Azores</em> during weekdays. Most Lunar territories are available on Mondays and Fridays, and other territories are available according to the Mail&rsquo;s region table.</p>
<p>Although Vekllei people do not pay to post items, stamps are affixed with coloured squares called <em>chromacodes</em> which are used in the automatic sorting machines common in the country. International Mail uses traditional stamps with price listed, and the Vekllei Crown displayed. Franking is used for tracking and identification.</p>
<h3 id="special-delivery">
  Special Delivery
  <a class="anchor" href="#special-delivery">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Special, commercial and industrial postage is managed within the <strong>Postal Service Bureau</strong> through special sorting facilities and a dedicated postal network. Regular business postage is funnelled through regular daily service, but hazardous, oversized and dangerous goods are accepted by special Post Offices designed to accept them. The Mail does not provide special services for regular residential or courier delivery.</p>
<h3 id="international-service">
  International Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#international-service">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Mail is best known overseas as the <strong>World Post</strong>, which offers services for foreign clients and has established itself as one of the Big Four international transnational courier services in the world today. Similar to domestic postal systems in other countries, the World Post offers flat rates for delivery anywhere in the world, priced according to size and weight. In addition, sister company <strong>Universal Express</strong> offers next-day weekday delivery in certain markets. Most employees of the World Post and Universal Express are foreign workers banking labour-hours for immigration to Vekllei. Unlike domestic service, the World Post and Universal Express use private courier contracts extensively to fulfil orders.</p>
<h3 id="finance">
  Finance
  <a class="anchor" href="#finance">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The <strong>Labour Bank of Vekllei</strong><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> is easily accessible via the Mail&rsquo;s <strong>Financial Services Bureau</strong>. Although inaccessible within the country, savings can be withdrawn conditionally upon emigration, and the Mail offers easy access and financial counselling for Vekllei people. Through the Financial Services Bureau, the Mail also offers financial management to immigrant populations with wealth transfer (the phrase for banking of savings and prior income) and Overseas Accounting, commonly used to send money to family abroad.</p>
<h3 id="telecommunications">
  Telecommunications
  <a class="anchor" href="#telecommunications">#</a>
</h3>
<p><strong>Cosma</strong> (a portmanteau of <em>communicasia matismion</em>) is Vekllei&rsquo;s state communications company, responsible for all residential and public telephones in the country. This includes videophones, public phone booths, and residential networks. Cosma also maintains telecommunications infrastructure networks internationally through <strong>Cosma Overseas</strong>, primarily the Vekllei-Europe undersea cables and their sister sets between Vekllei and North America. Much of the network dates back over a hundred years, since a shortage of modern personal telephones in Vekllei requires Cosma to maintain a wide variety of voltage and cable standards. Commercial, industrial and government telecommunications is managed by a seperate internal department called the <strong>Industrial Telecommunications Office</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="operations">
  Operations
  <a class="anchor" href="#operations">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/">The Stamp Manufacturie</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>As a military organ</strong>, the Mail A.r. retains military ranks for its staff, commanded by a Postmaster General and aided by a civilian regulator designed to keep its critical service available to Vekllei people. The Mail&rsquo;s fleet includes dedicated jets, automatic trucks, mail trains, intercity pneumatic systems, vehicle automen, and postmen, all wearing the red and gold colours of the organisation. In total, the Mail delivers nearly 50 million pieces of mail during weekdays.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>It is evident</strong> that the services assigned to the Mail by the postwar constitution are of critical importance to the stability of Vekllei society. In addition to being one of the oldest active postal organisations in the world, the Royal Mail of Vekllei is tremendously busy, since physical post has scarcely been displaced by the telephone in the country. Even without the Mail&rsquo;s international postage, domestic mail each day can exceed 12 million pieces &ndash; enough for 1 in 2 people, though commercial mail and periodicals are included.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/manufacturie.jpg" alt="Picture of mail-owned manufacturing plant"  title="Outdoor view of the [Royal Mail&#39;s](/mail/) stamp printing complex. | *[The Stamp Manufacturie](/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Outdoor view of the <a href="/mail/">Royal Mail&rsquo;s</a> stamp printing complex. | <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/">The Stamp Manufacturie</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>As is typical for critical bureaus in Vekllei, the Mail alleviates the stress of daily service through its dense, vertically-integrated infrastructure aided by automatic (automen vehicles) and permanent fixtures (pneumatic systems and automatic sorting/franking machines). It is precisely this commitment to infrastructure that makes the Mail so visible in daily life, and contributes to its ongoing legacy as Vekllei&rsquo;s oldest running government institution.</p>
<h3 id="staff">
  Staff
  <a class="anchor" href="#staff">#</a>
</h3>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/mail.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/postmistress.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<p>The Mail employs 48,960 people full-time across its various offices, and nearly 200,000 automen in various roles. Although the Mail does retain a staff of postmen and couriers, most urban daily service is now provided by automatic vehicles and sorting, which account for nearly half of the total automen owned by the organisation. Instead, the majority of Mail employees are involved in the running of the organisation &ndash; mostly as clerks, managers, and administrators. Around 10,000 postmen are employed by the Mail in daily delivery, called &ldquo;posties&rdquo;. There are around 8,000 postal routes in the country.</p>
<p>Although at first glance the number of automen dramatically exceeds demand, the total count is misleading &ndash; most automen with the Mail are integrated into the infrastructure of its sorting centres and post offices, and very few are traditionally autonomous robots commonly seen in public in Vekllei. Only about 8,000 automen are employed in physical mail delivery.</p>
<p>There are 16,220 post boxes in Vekllei, which are iconic for their red and gold paint and intricate detailing.</p>
<h3 id="fleet">
  Fleet
  <a class="anchor" href="#fleet">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/">The Fairie</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Mail retains a large and diverse fleet of vehicles in regular operations, which, due to their diversity and and expense, have become iconic around the world. From bicycles to space planes, the Mail&rsquo;s fleet of vehicles rivals in diversity postal services three times its size, largely benefitted by Vekllei&rsquo;s obfuscated budgeting system and cultural importance afforded to the organisation.</p>
<p>The following table lists company vehicles relevant to regular postal service.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>The Royal Mail Fleet</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li><strong>Postal Service Bureau</strong>
<ul>
<li>8,000 delivery automen</li>
<li>5,200 motorcycles <em>(mostly Local Electric Model 15 &amp; Phantoms)</em></li>
<li>2,400 bicycles</li>
<li>2,000 automatic vans</li>
<li>400 mail trucks</li>
<li>31 mail boats <em>(MBR)</em></li>
<li>20 mail flying boats <em>(Model 54 &ldquo;Fairie&rdquo;)</em></li>
<li>16 mail helijets <em>(Model RM/Gisma &amp; Record types)</em></li>
<li>15 mail trains <em>(RM Series/Series 225 EMU)</em></li>
<li>8 mail trams <em>(Series T6)</em></li>
<li>2 mail space planes <em>(G.A. Type 1)</em></li>
<li>2 mail ships <em>(RMS</em> Atlantic <em>&amp;</em> Sunburst <em>)</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Overseas Service Bureau</strong>
<ul>
<li>World Post Company
<ul>
<li>250 mail trucks</li>
<li>52 cargo jets <em>(Model RM/Type 56C)</em></li>
<li>6 flying boats</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Universal Express Company
<ul>
<li>4 cargo jets <em>(Model ERM/C.A. Type 6 supersonic)</em></li>
<li>2 mail trucks</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Office of the Postmistress</strong>
<ul>
<li>1 executive mail train <em>(Series 4000 EMU)</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><em>A.r.</em> is a shortening of <em>state requisite</em> (A.r., or requoisesiasn amourisocietie)&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>The <em>Labour Bank of Vekllei</em> (often called the <em>Government Bank</em>) is Vekllei&rsquo;s social bank, and each Vekllei person is entitled to an equal share of it.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Metaphysics</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/metaphysics/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/metaphysics/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about Vekllei This article draws on many concepts broadly, with meandering interest in the same way you might hold a conversation. The purpose of this article is to introduce an alternate perspective on Vekllei thinking, and provoke the buried understanding that these people understand the world in fundamentally different ways. What is history for you is not history for Vekllei, and what land means to you is not what land means in Vekllei.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.nethttps://images.millmint.net/spiritful.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/factbook/vekllei">Vekllei</a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">This article draws on many concepts broadly, with meandering interest in the same way you might hold a conversation. The purpose of this article is to introduce an alternate perspective on Vekllei thinking, and provoke the buried understanding that these people understand the world in fundamentally different ways. What is history for you is not history for Vekllei, and what land means to you is not what land means in Vekllei.</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><span class="smallicon" style="font-size: 14px;">⚠️</span> This article is evolving, and will be expanded in future.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>In Vekllei, &ldquo;history&rdquo; as it is presently conceptualised is not continuous or inevitable, and the island country has been excluded from history as an invention of 19th century Europe. This article seeks to document the ways the so-called &lsquo;Vekllei perspective&rsquo; bucks historicist assumptions about history, progress, and many features of observable reality by depicting their differences.</p>
<p>It is important to remember that Vekllei was &rsquo;left alone&rsquo; for many centuries by the European and later American continental powers, except as an entrepôt with foreign contact restricted to trading ports. The isolationist 3rd Commonwealth, known under many names but referred to colloquially as a series of <em>junta parliaments</em> or <em>juntas</em>, did not really resemble a unified kingdom-state but instead a series of disparate clans with distinct cultural, ethnic and religious backgrounds with commonhoods developed in isolation. This tradition continues to exist today, to the surprise of foreigners. Vekllei uses phrases and names for its government and subordinate state ministries that, when assembled together, resemble a highly centralised and powerful city-state. In reality, the Vekllei state better resembles a thousand villages, across many islands, united in a series of timid councils and shallow departments. Many wonderful features of Vekllei are not architected but inherited from several thousand years of isolation and anger.</p>
<h3 id="the-post-war-state">
  The Post-War State
  <a class="anchor" href="#the-post-war-state">#</a>
</h3>
<p>It is worth considering that nearly 40% of Vekllei people today were born overseas, and the population of the country has increased from 11 millions in 2015 to 24 millions in 2063. These new Vekllei citizens, called <em>rosmehn</em> or &rsquo;new neighbours,&rsquo; are from all over the world, and mostly came to Vekllei for political or economic reasons to participate in the opportunities apparent in the building of the 4th Commonwealth. Of course, these cultures have not inherited Vekllei metaphysics or its millennia of assumptions about the world immediately. Their children, however, are taught in a Vekllei curriculum and are already becoming exposed to these ideas. It is too early to tell exactly how this dramatic shift in population will affect future metaphysics in Vekllei, but there is no evidence yet to assume total destruction or total assimilation. Likely, these cultures will be influenced by existing Vekllei ideas and will become distinct from their home cultures.</p>
<p>It is important to clarify then that references to the &lsquo;Vekllei person&rsquo; in this article assume a belief in traditional metaphysics, as well as <a href="/religion">Upen</a>. This article documents traditional beliefs rather than a total and contemporary reflection of the assumptions of all Vekllei people, who are more numerous and more diverse than ever.</p>
<h2 id="cultural-landscape">
  Cultural Landscape
  <a class="anchor" href="#cultural-landscape">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>At the root of realism there must be passion; without passion it is hard for there to be anything more than description for the sake of description.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&ndash; Kitamura Tokoku,<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> 1894</p>
<p>Vekllei people do not generally understand the natural world as seperate from themselves. Physical landscape is, intuitively, understood as a reflection of their interior selves, and extends outwardly and limitlessly. Unlike modern assumptions, which consider physical reality to be external and thus able to be depicted objectively and realistically, Vekllei people to not distinguish between external and internal realities, and consequently do not have default conceptualisations of exteriority and interiority. This epistemic feature means that many subsequent concepts do not really exist in Vekllei &ndash; categories of human beings like &lsquo;children&rsquo; and &lsquo;young adults,&rsquo; literature and sickness.</p>
<p>To clarify, it is not that those things do not exist in Vekllei &ndash; this article refers only to the perception of features of life and to what they are assigned. The mythologising of illness; the casting of others as characters; the categorisation of culture into movements and eras; the linearity and historicism of history and progress. It is these things, foundational and apparently timeless in Western imagination, that are absent in Vekllei.</p>
<p>When people talk about &lsquo;alienation from nature&rsquo; in a Vekllei context, they do not mean it in a physical sense (as in urbanised living) but in a transcendental sense, as the natural world being objectified and externalised. This is clear in the Vekllei tradition of poetry, or <em>ensaga</em>, in which no distinction is given between narration and speech.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Once a landscape has been established, its origins are repressed from memory. It takes on the appearance of an &ldquo;object&rdquo; which has been there, outside us, from the start. [&hellip;] Rather than existing prior to landscape, subject and object emerge from within it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&ndash; Kojin Karatani, <em>Origins of Japanese Literature</em></p>
<p>These assumptions contribute to the uniqueness of Vekllei as a contemporary culture and nation-state, and significantly to its land-metaphysics. Vekllei animism, both as religious feature of <a href="/religion/">Upen</a> and a secular cultural feature, is informed by the absence of conceptual segregation of the interior and exterior, and the person and the natural world. Similarly, <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#topet">Vekllei logographic writing</a> is not subordinated to Vekllei <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#spoken-vekllei">phonetic speech</a>, and so its transcendental visual representations of concepts informs how Vekllei people consider those concepts &ndash; that is, transcendental and thus personal. A mountain is depicted visually in <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#topet"><em>topet</em></a> as all mountains and any mountain, rather than an objective place with existing, externalised features.</p>
<p>Together, these facts account for many decisions made in the building of the post-war 4th Commonwealth, and also work unseen to produce the aspects of Vekllei society that are well known overseas (and are to some extent mythologised in the orientalist tradition).</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Excerpted from <em>Origins of Japanese Literature</em>, Kojin Karatani&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Municipalities</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/municipalities/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/municipalities/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the state series of articles ✿ Read more: The Good, The Municipal Municipalities are the bedrock of sundress municipalism, and a physical feature of everyday Vekllei life. A municipality refers to both a local council and its services, including libraries, schools, and policemen. Municipalities in Vekllei are the predominant form of local government, and vary dramatically in scale, power and resources. They usually refer to council municipalities, which are bodies of elected industrial and political leaders of a community.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/municipal/">The Good, The Municipal</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Municipalities</strong> are the bedrock of sundress municipalism, and a physical feature of everyday Vekllei life. A municipality refers to both a local council and its services, including libraries, schools, and policemen.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Municipalities in Vekllei are the predominant form of local government, and vary dramatically in scale, power and resources. They usually refer to council municipalities, which are bodies of elected industrial and political leaders of a community. This open-ended definition means that municipalities scale in Vekllei from tiny villages to major metropolitan areas.</p>
<p>Municipalities are the basis of Vekllei localism, a belief in local concern and decentralised decision-making. In general, Vekllei municipalism describes the places where society in abstract meets the individual, and so also has cultural and aesthetic qualities. The sum of a municipality is expressed in the <em>Atlantic Municipalist</em> tradition, which consists of the following principles:</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Principles of Atlantic Municipalism</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Local employment, or “commutelessness.”</li>
<li>Slumlessness, beautification, and a will to architecture.</li>
<li>Property stewardship.</li>
<li>Open air and clean water.</li>
<li>Land usefulness (&ldquo;friendliness&rdquo;).</li>
<li>Private ownership of private needs.</li>
<li>Public ownership of public needs.</li>
</ol>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>There are 14,000 municipalities across the Commonwealth. The usage of &lsquo;municipal&rsquo; can refer to a political council or the spirit of Atlantic Municipalism.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ This page is an archive for content posted to the dormant Vekllei Patreon. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">This page is an archive for content posted to the dormant <a href="https://patreon.com/vekllei">Vekllei Patreon</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rail</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/state/rail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/state/rail/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about Vekllei society This article discusses one of the most important and visible organisations in everyday Vekllei life: Vekllei National Rail. Vekllei is criss-crossed by hundreds of different rail lines of various gauges, grades, and purposes. In fact, it runs many lines at a total loss, often under capacity. To understand these inefficiencies is to understand why the National Rail exists, and to some extent, how Vekllei&rsquo;s state assets and powerful bureaus shape life in the country today.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.nethttps://images.millmint.net/orange.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/factbook/vekllei"><strong>Vekllei</strong></a> society</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>This article</strong> discusses one of the most important and visible organisations in everyday Vekllei life: Vekllei National Rail. Vekllei is criss-crossed by hundreds of different rail lines of various gauges, grades, and purposes. In fact, it runs many lines at a total loss, often under capacity. To understand these inefficiencies is to understand why the National Rail exists, and to some extent, how Vekllei&rsquo;s state assets and powerful bureaus shape life in the country today.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p><strong>Vekllei National Rail (VNR)</strong> is a catch-all term for bureau-backed, state-owned rail operators of Vekllei. In casual use, it refers to the Vekllei National Railway A.r.R. and its sister companies, like Vekllei Metro, which are structured within the service-oriented Railways Bureau. More precisely, Vekllei National Rail encompasses several different bureaus that operate, design, maintain and communicate rail service in the country, which itself is further included under the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government.</p>
<p>Like most critical organisations of Vekllei, the structure and directorship of Vekllei National Rail is complex, but can be simplified by understanding that all rail transport in the country is ultimately the responsibility of an organisation called Vekllei National Rail, and it is towards this organ that this article is addressed. Today, the National Rail operates nearly 20,000km of track, indicating the density of the rail service it provides, and services nearly 20 million people each day through its network. It is administered and operated by the <a href="/bureau-of-rail/"><span class="fi fi-min-commons fis"></span> Bureau of Rail</a>.</p>
<h3 id="introduction">
  Introduction
  <a class="anchor" href="#introduction">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Since nationalisation of the private Vekllei rail companies in 1925, the structure and reach of Vekllei National Rail has changed several times. Operated as a for-profit enterprise at a historical loss, the National Rail&rsquo;s history of service is reflected in the variety of trains and track gauges it maintains.</p>
<p>Vekllei is unique in the density of its rail, a feature of deliberate postwar city planning and the Home Island&rsquo;s history as an industrial port city-state. Very few Vekllei people own automobiles, and trains remain by far the most common method of travel in the country. Because of this, the rail network in metropolitan areas is extraordinarily dense, and is designed to offer access to nearly every residence in urban areas. This fact also explains the presence of dedicated rail lines to small towns and villages that would otherwise not justify their maintenance. As visible on the map above, the passenger rail network in Vekllei is unsurpassed in its density, which contributes to the dependence Vekllei people have on their trains.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/railmap.jpg" alt="Map of rail networks in Oslola"  title="A map of the rail network and boroughs in Oslola, showcasing maglev (red), high-speed (yellow), regional (orange) and local (brown) lines | *[100 Boroughs](/posts/2020-06-14-map/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>A map of the rail network and boroughs in Oslola, showcasing maglev (red), high-speed (yellow), regional (orange) and local (brown) lines | <em><a href="/posts/2020-06-14-map/">100 Boroughs</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Similarly, almost all freight is run along rails of varying gauges. These range from conventional freight trains at standard gauge, to municipal delivery trains at metre guage, and even narrow gauges for moving freight and equipment within large factory complexes. Most major stores and grocers are arranged along freight lines with dedicated sidings, or have their own narrow-gauge tracks dedicated to their use.</p>
<p>Unusually, Vekllei National Rail is legally absolved of all non-rail transport, and possesses no busses or ferries for public use, which are operated and maintained by dedicated adjacent bureaus.</p>
<h3 id="history">
  History
  <a class="anchor" href="#history">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Although Vekllei has used wagonways since the 18th Century and developed horse-drawn railways for industrial transport in its ports, the first passenger rail line in Vekllei was founded in 1855 by the <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/pharos/#pharos-railway-company-museum">Pharos Rail Company</a>.</p>
<p>The history of rail in Vekllei can be summarised in three key eras of development.</p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>Early Development and expansion</strong>, from early service in 1855.</li>
<li><strong>Late Junta/Prewar nationalisation</strong>, from nationalisation in 1925.</li>
<li><strong>Postwar refounding and development</strong>, since independence in 2015.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Since the foundation of VNR after nationalisation, rail in Vekllei has seen the scale of its passenger rail networks quadruple in size. It is internationally regarded for its safety and reliability.</p>
<h4 id="early-development">
  Early Development
  <a class="anchor" href="#early-development">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The first railways in Vekllei developed alongside its ports, as Vekllei&rsquo;s position as an intermediary free port between Europe and the Americas rapidly developed Vekllei&rsquo;s industrial base. Although the earliest internal rail wagons were pulled by horses, primitive steam locomotives had modernised most ports by the early 19th Century.</p>
<p>The first passenger rail line opened in 1855 between <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/pharos/">Pharos</a> and the present-day borough of Little Vekllei to alleviate the expense of moving goods from the <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/pharos/#port-of-pharos">Port of Pharos</a> to established settlement further inland. The original line was only a few kilometres long, but was extended in 1858 and again in 1872. By this time, several other lines had been established under private rail companies, including passenger services between Vekllei Proper and Little Vekllei, as well as the beginnings of the Montre-Vekllei Railroad.</p>
<p>By the beginning of the 20th Century, Vekllei had a half-dozen major railroad companies, and dozens other limited/local services provided by private operators or their municipality. This saw a massive increase in both the movement of freight and ridership, and helped entrench Vekllei&rsquo;s position as a stopover port city for transatlantic freight and passage.</p>
<h4 id="nationalisation">
  Nationalisation
  <a class="anchor" href="#nationalisation">#</a>
</h4>
<p>The early 20th Century was marked by an exponential increase in ridership, which saw a proliferation of new railroads across the Home Islands. Metropolitan and suburban lines during this period were characterised by overcrowding, poor reliability and irregular service. These factors, in addition to the growing economic power of rail barons in the country, saw the Atlantic Junta (known as the Crown) move to nationalise all metropolitan and intercity passenger rail service in 1925 as the Vekllei National Rail Company (VNC).</p>
<p>The centralisation of Vekllei rail accompanied standardisation of its commuter track gauge, which improved travel times across the country. The VNC period was characterised by reliable investment and a commitment to modernisation of rail in the country. By the late 20th Century, the Vekllei Metropolitan Underground was widely regarded as one of the most beautiful subway systems in the world.</p>
<p>In the late 1980s, VNC started work on what would eventually become the Vekllei-Montre bullet train. The programme overran its cost estimates and was delayed several times, and was not completed until 2004, shortly before the Atomic War.</p>
<h4 id="postwar-development">
  Postwar Development
  <a class="anchor" href="#postwar-development">#</a>
</h4>
<p>National Rail Company assets that had been operated by the occupation Vekllei Provisional Government were transferred to the Vekllei Interim Government in 2015 and reestablished as Vekllei National Rail (VNR) in 2018. The Floral Period has been marked by steady growth in ridership and the scale of its network. The organisation also invests heavily into the development of new locomotives and EMUs, culminating in 2047 with the announcement of the Vekllei East Coast Maglev Scheme, which are the fastest commuter trains in the world.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/shrine-minded.jpg" alt="Map of a train pulling into a windy coastal village"  title="A Lesvesn 59-Series EMU arrives in the village of Cult | *[Shrine-Minded Girls](/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>A Lesvesn 59-Series EMU arrives in the village of Cult | <em><a href="/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/">Shrine-Minded Girls</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>In 2055, VNR celebrated &ldquo;250 years of rail,&rdquo; and its livery and staff uniforms were overhauled to mark the occasion.</p>
<p>Today, VNR represents the sole means of medium/long-distance transport for over 80% of Vekllei commuters, indicating its continuous status as a monopoly of travel, not just rail, in the country.</p>
<h3 id="structure">
  Structure
  <a class="anchor" href="#structure">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei National Rail is an organ of the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government (A.r.R., or <em>requoisesiasn amourisocietie resmesnghet</em>) as several individual state requisite bureaus, which in turn are charged with different transport companies. Although its structure in Vekllei might be analogous to a government ministry abroad, it functions in practice more like a state-owned enterprise with private subsidiaries. It is not a state-run corporation, and maintains seperate accounting.</p>
<p>Vekllei National Rail is administered through three State Requisites: the Vekllei National Rail itself including all regular operations and rail service, the National Rail Insurance Scheme which finances construction through Government White Bonds, and the Rail Safety Commission.</p>
<details open>
  <summary>Organisation Chart of VNR</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Responsible to the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/transport/#national-railways-bureau">Railways Bureau</a> of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/transport">Ministry of Transport</a></div>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li><strong>Vekllei National Rail</strong>
<ul>
<li>National Rail
<ul>
<li>Vekllei National Railways A.r.R.
<ul>
<li>VNR Atlantic</li>
<li>VNR Kala</li>
<li>VNR Overseas</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Vekllei National Magways A.r.R.</li>
<li>Vekllei Metro A.r.R.</li>
<li>Government Railroads R.S.</li>
<li>Vekllei Freight S.A.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Railway Police Office</li>
<li>Office of Steam</li>
<li>Office of Electrification</li>
<li>Nuclear-Electric Rail Commission</li>
<li>Private Railcar Commission</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Vekllei Industrial Rail</strong>
<ul>
<li>National Freight</li>
<li><a href="/mail/">Royal Mail</a> Railway Holdings</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Railroad Democracy Hall</strong>
<ul>
<li>VK Rail Chapel</li>
<li>Public Rail Chapel</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Vekllei National Rail Press Bureau</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Vekllei Rail Press</strong>
<ul>
<li><em>Vekllei Rail Transport Journal</em>
<ul>
<li><em>Locomotive</em> Magazine</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Rail Periodicals Office</li>
<li>Friends of Rail Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Public Relations Office</li>
<li>Industrial Relations Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Vekllei National Rail Municipal Land Company S.A.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Vekllei National Rail Construction House</strong></li>
<li><strong>Railway Laboratories of Vekllei</strong>
<ul>
<li>Senrouive House Office</li>
<li>Company House Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>National Rail Insurance Scheme A.r.R.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Passenger Accounting</strong></li>
<li><strong>Rail Democracy Office</strong></li>
<li><strong>Rail Safety Commission</strong></li>
<li><strong>Track Safety Vekllei</strong></li>
<li><strong>Passenger Safety Vekllei</strong>
<ul>
<li>Platform Investigation Office</li>
<li>Carriage Investigation Office</li>
<li>Incident Investigation Office</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<h2 id="service">
  Service
  <a class="anchor" href="#service">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Since most Vekllei people</strong> catch a train each day, VNR is a uniquely intimate and treasured organ of the Vekllei state. It is somehow exempted from the public apathy and resentment of bureaucracy that targets other monopolies of the Vekllei state, and is routinely regarded as among the most beloved and appreciated &ldquo;companies&rdquo; in Vekllei.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Access to public transport is considered a &ldquo;critical luxury&rdquo; of the Vekllei state (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for essential state services) and, by extension, the functioning of its society. By design, it makes no profit, and is subsidised entirely by the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government and various independent transport bureaus for the benefit of any Vekllei person. Even prior to the war and investment of the Floral Period, Vekllei&rsquo;s public transport was widely regarded as among the finest of any network in the world thanks to its impeccable safety record, timeliness, and comprehensive coverage.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/hollywood.jpg" alt="Image of kids making a film in front of a rail line and factory"  title="A Mustard 56-Series passes a steam processing plant | *[Gone Hollywood](/stories/hollywood/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>A Mustard 56-Series passes a steam processing plant | <em><a href="/stories/hollywood/">Gone Hollywood</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Rail transport contributes tremendously to the national culture and common affection for Vekllei&rsquo;s public institutions. It is also commonly percieved as a triumph of the postwar floral Period, despite rail history in Vekllei dating back hundreds of years prior. The ongoing expansion of the VNR network and renovation of stations and railhubs commands attention internationally, which is watching Vekllei celebrate its golden age of rail.</p>
<h3 id="national-rail">
  National Rail
  <a class="anchor" href="#national-rail">#</a>
</h3>
<p>National rail access is generally provided directly by Vekllei National Railway A.r.R. through a branch office dependent on the location. The Home Islands are served by VNR Atlantic, whereas Kala is served by VNR Overseas. The Home Islands house thousands of rural villages outside of urban metropolitan service, and Vekllei&rsquo;s dependence on rail transportatiion demands their inclusion in the VNR network. As such, almost every village in Vekllei has a rail line or interurban tramway, and villages as small as 20 persons see daily service to the capital.</p>
<h3 id="metropolitan-service--subways">
  Metropolitan Service &amp; Subways
  <a class="anchor" href="#metropolitan-service--subways">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The majority of VNR&rsquo;s ~10,000 trains per day run in metro or subway services throughout Vekllei urban and interurban routes. These lines are primarily serviced by the EMU workhorses of the VNR fleet, particularly 56 and 59-Series trainsets. In urban centers, VNR service is frequent enough to be unscheduled, with trains arriving every other minute or so.</p>
<p>The majority of Vekllei&rsquo;s underground metro network has been automated by Automatic Train Control, an industrial automan system that allows for driverless trains. Although still serviced by VNR platform staff with training to stop the train in emergencies, Vekllei&rsquo;s automatic metros are otherwise entirely driverless. VNR Overseas metros in Kala and the Kalina Isles retain drivers.</p>
<h3 id="tramways">
  Tramways
  <a class="anchor" href="#tramways">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei operates a variety of trams and streetcars, including double-decker street-level units in the capital region and so-called &ldquo;fast trams&rdquo; (inter-urban cars) outside of the cities. Depending on the make and route of the tramway, they may be grade-seperated or integrated into streets. Their ubuquity in urban areas has caused observers to regard them as the principle method of transport in the country, second only to the bicycle.</p>
<h3 id="freight">
  Freight
  <a class="anchor" href="#freight">#</a>
</h3>
<p>VNR&rsquo;s main freight lines run mostly on a seperate gauge and network, and are composed of several companies that operate regionally across a variety of locomotive types and industries. These include traditional freight locomotives and long/short cars, as well as freight trams and wagons used to transport goods around and between factories.</p>
<h2 id="operations">
  Operations
  <a class="anchor" href="#operations">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/">Station Logic</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>VNR</strong> is typical of a &lsquo;great Vekllei bureau&rsquo; &ndash; it instills national pride, is well-run and maintained, and loses tremendous amounts of money. It is the crown jewel of Vekllei&rsquo;s insolvent organs, whose thin profit margins and charming inefficiencies are tolerated and even encouraged in this society which subsidises social benefit above all else.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Nearly 17 million people per day commute via VNR&rsquo;s networks each day, making up a majority of the Vekllei population. In this sense, VNR&rsquo;s quality of operations affects the Vekllei person more than the quality of their government. In addition to commuter service, VNR automatic freight transit systems are the lifeblood of all industry and commerce in the country, and are regulated directly as a state requisite for their critical importance to the functioning of Vekllei society.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/stationlogic.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<p>VNR operates 2,114 stations across the Home Islands, which vary from uncovered concrete platforms to tremendous terminus complexes that cover multiple city blocks. The largest station in the country, Vekllei Central, sees over 1 million people per day pass through its gates.</p>
<p>Vekllei&rsquo;s stations are well-regarded for the beauty and decoration overseas. As part of the Millenia Rail campaign in the mid-21st Century, VNR initiated a dramatic overhaul of its passenger infrastructure, restoring heritage-listed station interiors and renovating much of the early postwar metro construction with murals, new lighting, enlarged caverns and shafts, and improved safety features. The cleanliness and safety of Vekllei National Railway is a great point of pride in the country, and in part justifies VNR&rsquo;s tremendous fiscal losses in daily operation.</p>
<p>VNR services are mostly unticketed, and as a Vekllei industry, are free to ride.</p>
<h3 id="staff">
  Staff
  <a class="anchor" href="#staff">#</a>
</h3>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/vnr.jpg" alt="smallimg"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2021-04-25-rail/">The People of Vekllei National Rail</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>VNR employs 65,240 people, which include roles ranging from locomotive engineers and platform staff to editors of rail enthusiast periodicals. It is also one of the largest employers of 12-16 year olds in the country, via its Station Apprentice programme, unique among organisations of its size.</p>
<p>The organisation is administered by the President of the Rail Central Office, which is responsible to the Transport Requisite and the Palace of Rail. VNR has a close relationship with bureau and petty-bureau coachbuilders, and wields considerable power in Vekllei&rsquo;s heavy industries as a major manufacturing partner.</p>
<h3 id="fleet">
  Fleet
  <a class="anchor" href="#fleet">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Download the <span class="smallicon">📄</span> <a href="/files/factbook/VNR-Rolling-Stock-Bulletin.pdf">VNR Rolling Stock List (PDF)</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>Vekllei National Rail is perhaps unsurpassed in its variety of trainsets and their length of service. An unofficial policy of preservation has ensured that every unit type since the 1980s has seen an ongoing minor presence in current service. VNR rarely retires a trainset completely &ndash; in keeping with the contemporary cultural-political valuation of machines, a few units of each model are retained on various lines for their historical and technical significance. This includes steam locomotives, which continue to operate regular passengers service on some routes.</p>
<p>The backbone of the contemporary Vekllei rail fleet is the Electric Multiple Units (EMUs), which are designated by their year of manufacture.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> In particular, the 56 and 59-Series trainsets make up the majority of EMUs in service today, as they exclusively populate primary commuter lines in Vekllei&rsquo;s southwest. VNR also retains Diesel Multiple Units (DMUs) in its long-haul cold-weather routes, particularly in the Afouisneh region and Kala.</p>
<p>VNR pioneered super-conductive maglev transport for mass consumption, and its SC3 trainsets are the fastest in regular service in the world today, reaching nearly 750km/h in places. Its slowest locomotive, the T400 2-6-2 steam locomotive <em>Small Movements</em> built in 1928, averages just 30km/h on its tourist route in rural Krafla. VNR is also experimenting with nuclear-powered trainsets, but none have so far entered public testing.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Vekllei&rsquo;s &lsquo;war&rsquo; prefix is used as a designation for pre-war railcars and locomotives, transliterated from the native word for the Junta&rsquo;s society.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Religion</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/religion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/religion/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about Vekllei ߷ This article is undergoing changes and should not be considered canon. Overview # Upen is the animistic, nondenominational dominant and historical religion of Vekllei. Practiced commonly throughout the Home Islands and Vekllei&rsquo;s possessions, it is a core component of Vekllei culture and heritage, and has existed in various forms for thousands of years. Because Upen is fundamentally provincial and decentralised, its scripture and practice vary significantly between boroughs.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.nethttps://images.millmint.net/death.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/vekllei">Vekllei</a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is undergoing changes and should not be considered canon.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p><strong>Upen</strong> is the animistic, nondenominational dominant and historical religion of Vekllei. Practiced commonly throughout the Home Islands and Vekllei&rsquo;s possessions, it is a core component of Vekllei culture and heritage, and has existed in various forms for thousands of years. Because <em>Upen</em> is fundamentally provincial and decentralised, its scripture and practice vary significantly between boroughs. Most forms emphasise object animism, impermanence, petite materialism, land dependence, existentialism and fear of nature.</p>
<p>Upen can be practiced at natural shrines, usually designated by a cairn, at running or still water, or the seaside. Maritime living and seafood are important aspects of Vekllei life, and fishing and ocean myths are key elements in <em>Upen</em>. Within its spiritualism, traditional folk-tales and scripture are called <em>sagas</em>, which have also archived much of Vekllei&rsquo;s early history.</p>
<p>Although traditionally atheist, <em>Upen</em> is commonly adopted by immigrant populations that include Catholic, Jewish and Buddhist faiths. In these contexts, <em>Upen</em>&rsquo;s animism and dependence on landscape is held alongside traditional beliefs, which are so common postwar that both Jewish and Catholic metaphysics have appeared in mainstream <em>Upen</em> doctrine in some cities, where large immigrant populations reside.</p>
<h3 id="introduction">
  Introduction
  <a class="anchor" href="#introduction">#</a>
</h3>
<p>You can find <em>Upen</em> all around you in Vekllei since, by its own spiritual metaphysics, animism is not human. It exists independently of human understanding or spirit, and <em>Upen</em> is merely the practice by which humans are cognisant and interact with the spirit of things. Wherever people and material existence collide, including man-made objects, you find <em>Upen</em>.</p>
<p>In this sense, <em>Upen</em> can be understood as having two distinct forms, practiced differently depending on the occasion:</p>
<ul>
<li>Public <em>Upen</em>, which involves priests, communities, ceremony and cultural artefacts (like <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#25--upotenne"><em>Upotenne</em></a> and <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#23--rapotenne"><em>Rapotenne</em></a>). Public <em>Upen</em> manifests similarly to other faiths, in which sites of worship, historical texts and sacred spaces inform practice and understanding.</li>
<li>Private <em>Upen</em>, which involves personal understanding and direct physicality with the aspects of material being <em>Upen</em> holds sacred, namely the spirit of all things and the human form.</li>
</ul>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="https://images.millmint.net/images/spiritful.jpg" alt="Picture of Tzipora in traditional dress"  title="[Tzipora](/factbook/characters/#tzipora-zelda-desmoisnes) stands in traditional Upen dress before an offerings box. | *[Spiritful](/posts/2021-06-19-spiritful/)*" loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption><a href="/factbook/characters/#tzipora-zelda-desmoisnes">Tzipora</a> stands in traditional Upen dress before an offerings box. | <em><a href="/posts/2021-06-19-spiritful/">Spiritful</a></em></figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Although <em>Upen</em> does retain priests informally, it lacks a hierarchical structure and is largely agnostic towards organised religion, lived and practiced instead through traditions, folklore, lifestyle and metaphysics.</p>
<p>As atheistic and animistic, <em>Upen</em> shelters landscape from becoming ‘simply nature’, as it does when viewed as a product of a monotheistic creator god. Within Vekllei&rsquo;s &rsquo;landscape&rsquo; agnosticism, nature is not ‘simply nature’; it is a spiritual vessel in itself, inalienable and inextricably linked to human purpose and satisfaction. Industry is divorced from the whole concept; it is a country of forest commons, collective stewardship, and volcanic unrest.</p>
<h2 id="etymology">
  Etymology
  <a class="anchor" href="#etymology">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Upen as a word has its origins lost to time, but its linguistic characteristics can be found throughout modern Vekllei language. <em>U</em> (pronounced &lsquo;oo&rsquo;) is a prefix applied to matters of consciousness considered sacred or special, as replicated in the spirit-language of <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#6-upotenne"><em>Upotenne</em></a>. <em>Upen</em> likely has origins in a proto-<em>Islandi</em> language called <em>Kala</em>, which later was absorbed into <em>Topyas</em>, the predecessor to <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language">Vekllei</a>.</p>
<p>In modern usage, <em>Upen</em> refers to both the faith and metaphysic of Vekllei&rsquo;s local animism, as well as a general indicator for Vekllei faith, myth and traditional folklore.</p>
<p><em>This article is currently under construction, and will soon feature more information about Vekllei&rsquo;s spiritualism.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sagas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/sagas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/sagas/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the culture series of articles Sagas are a kind of historic prose narrative that recorded the oral history of early Oslola. They are distinguished by their use of Topyas, a predecessor to modern Topet. They are recognised for their realism and poetry, and provide a valuable historical record of the 1st Commonwealth and practices of Old Upen.
Sagas were consolidated into historical and thematic eras in the 14th Century during the Period of Rest, which is typically how they are arranged today.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/culture/">culture</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Sagas</strong> are a kind of historic prose narrative that recorded the oral history of early Oslola. They are distinguished by their use of <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#history/">Topyas</a>, a predecessor to modern <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#topet/">Topet</a>. They are recognised for their realism and poetry, and provide a valuable historical record of the 1st Commonwealth and practices of Old Upen.</p>
<p>Sagas were consolidated into historical and thematic eras in the 14th Century during the Period of Rest, which is typically how they are arranged today.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Sagas of Old Oslola</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>God Saga</em>, c. 880AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of Origins</em> c. 940AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of Saints</em> c. 960AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of Family</em> c.1000AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of Spirits</em> c. 1200AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of New Earth</em> c. 1300AD</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>State Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/state/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/state/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about Vekllei Large segments of the Vekllei economy are dominated by industries of the state, as both direct ministerial privileges and state-owned enterprises. In total, they form the basis of the basic Vekllei standard of living, holding back catastrophe through reliable overproduction where gaps in the participatory economy might threaten serious shortages. Overview # There is no real distinction in Vekllei between state assets, state-owned enterprises (SOE) and government-owned corporations (GOC), and the terms are used interchangeably.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about <a href="/intro/#what-is-vekllei">Vekllei</a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>Large segments of the Vekllei economy</strong> are dominated by industries of the state, as both direct ministerial privileges and state-owned enterprises. In total, they form the basis of the basic Vekllei standard of living, holding back catastrophe through reliable overproduction where gaps in the participatory economy might threaten serious shortages.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>There is no real distinction in Vekllei between <em>state assets</em>, <em>state-owned enterprises</em> (SOE) and <em>government-owned corporations</em> (GOC), and the terms are used interchangeably. A state asset is distinct from bureau companies<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> or private enterprise, and is often directed by government policy via an <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/">Interior Ministry</a> or Parliament.</p>
<p>State assets make up about 40% of the <a href="/vekllei/">Vekllei Islands</a> GDP, and about 25% of total Commonwealth GDP. They occupy central roles in the Vekllei economy, often as functional or constitutional monopolies, and are responsible for 65% of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">VKIM</a> market capitalisation.</p>
<h2 id="structure">
  Structure
  <a class="anchor" href="#structure">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Most large state assets are structured as &lsquo;petals&rsquo; around a &lsquo;stem,&rsquo; an official analogy that describes a centralised administrative core with decentralised, semiautonomous subsidiaries. SOE units that would be departmentalised in other countries are spun off as seperate companies in Vekllei and ruthlessly pruned, operating under a directive from the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/commonwealth/#state-assets-directorate">State Assets Directorate</a> to reduce operating overhead and practice &lsquo;professional maintenance,&rsquo; a local colloquialism meaning to prevent stagnation or waste. Despite this, the vast majority of state assets in Vekllei are largely inefficient and bureaucratic, and their titanic presence in the Vekllei economy essentially produces two distinct markets in its place &ndash; the inflexible, reliable and political economy of state assets and bureaus, and the innovative, agile and volatile private market. Both markets are considered critical assets in Vekllei.</p>
<p>The degree to which a state asset is responsible to a Vekllei parliament is obfuscated by the unique role they serve in the country. In many cases, state assets are functionally independent of their controlling <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/">ministries</a> or <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/">secretariats</a>, and their relationship to the state is simply financial, with the state serving as a controlling shareholder-equivalent. In other cases, the mission and function of the asset is directly responsible to policy goals of its operator, and its business is closely linked to political concern of the Vekllei state. These statuses fluctuate with the strategic policy goals of the government in question.</p>
<p>Vekllei government is highly decentralised and includes several competing parliaments at the local, national and international level. Similarly, state assets and their responsibilities are highly diverse, and municipal ownership does not equate to national control. Municipalities are not (in most cases) subordinated to national government, and so municipal enterprises do not function in the same way national enterprises do.</p>
<h2 id="function--policy">
  Function &amp; Policy
  <a class="anchor" href="#function--policy">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint link">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/commonwealth/#state-assets-directorate">State Assets Directorate</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Vekllei economy is largely inefficient for a <a href="/posts/2020-07-13-economy/">variety of poltical and cultural reasons</a>, and this has resulted in an array of unique economic conditions that require different macroeconomic thinking to nations overseas. Although the Vekllei economy is functionally unmoneyed for Vekllei people, the Vekllei primary market is highly complex and involves intricate constellations of commodity markets, social factors of production, and tremendous public finance.</p>
<p>Rather than a direct redistribution of income and wealth, the Vekllei state uses assets to secure a basic standard of living for Vekllei people, advance industrial and commercial goals, and retain tight control over secondary and speculative markets that facilitate its liquid capital, which in turn provide mechanisms for foreign investment and trade in the country.</p>
<p>Vekllei does not resemble a modern consumer society, and so state assets are not geared towards consumer products. Similarly, the moneylessness of the Vekllei primary economy eliminates tremendous financial overhead that would otherwise be spent on maintaining the financial system, since these abstract relationships are usurped by direct industrial relations, company ballots, and directives given by ministerial production committees. These planned production mechanisms facilitate the reliable overproduction of essential goods that meet the needs of Vekllei population. The inflexibility of this system is supplanted by the private market of participatory labour, which produces the majority of consumer goods and products in Vekllei, if unreliably. Luxury goods are generally hyperlocalised or imported, and are scarce for most Veklei people.</p>
<h2 id="types">
  Types
  <a class="anchor" href="#types">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><strong>✿ Note from the Editor</strong>
This list is incomplete, and serves as a reference for the evolving industrial documentation of this site.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>There are three broad categories of state asset in Vekllei, arranged at their level of ownership. Crown companies belong to the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/crown/">Crown</a> or <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/">Commonwealth</a> governments, and generally include unique or essential enterprises of the Vekllei state. State companies belong to national governments, including the Vekllei Islands as depicted here. Municipal companies are local and administrated by a municipality.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<h3 id="crown-companies">
  Crown Companies
  <a class="anchor" href="#crown-companies">#</a>
</h3>
<details open>
  <summary>Crown Companies in Vekllei</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>Royal Mail of Vekllei
<ul>
<li>World Post</li>
<li>Universal Express</li>
<li>Cosma</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Army Construction House</li>
<li>Vekllei National University</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<h3 id="state-companies">
  State Companies
  <a class="anchor" href="#state-companies">#</a>
</h3>
<details open>
  <summary>State Companies in Vekllei</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li><a href="/factbook/society/industry/rail/">Vekllei National Rail</a></li>
<li><a href="/air/">Commonwealth Airways</a>
<ul>
<li>Vekllei Overseas Airways</li>
<li>Atlantic Air</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Vekllei National Petroleum</li>
<li>Vekllei National Shipping
<ul>
<li>Atlantic Shipbuilding</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Vekllei National Steel</li>
<li>Vekllei National Machines
<ul>
<li>Civic Systems</li>
<li>Voscom</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="/gr/">General Reactor</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/pharos/#future-fission-sqm">Future Fission</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>International Rocketry</li>
<li>Vekllei Tobacco</li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<h3 id="municipal-companies">
  Municipal Companies
  <a class="anchor" href="#municipal-companies">#</a>
</h3>
<details open>
  <summary>Municipal Companies in Vekllei</summary>
  <div class="markdown-inner">
    <ul>
<li>Common Battery</li>
<li>Vekllei Auto
<ul>
<li>All-Atomic Auto Company</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Seispri Motors</li>
<li>Holza Textiles</li>
<li>Vekllei Salmon</li>
<li><a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/pharos/#vekllei-aerospatiale-sa">Vekllei Aerospatiale</a></li>
<li><a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/lola/#fiara-heavy-machines-sqm">Fiara Heavy Machines</a></li>
<li><a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/mirah/">Vekllei International Casino</a></li>
</ul>

  </div>
</details>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The Vekllei phrase for a collection of private or state industrial firms organised into a council, with industrial policy and standards formed via company ballots.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Municipal companies may also include large private co-operatives that engage with the municipal government, rather than strictly state-owned assets.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Technology</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/technology/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/technology/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ This article is about unique technology in Vekllei&rsquo;s world. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">This article is about unique technology in Vekllei&rsquo;s world.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Army Construction House</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/ach/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/ach/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the industrial series of articles The Army Construction House (ACH) is the largest construction company in the Commonwealth by gross revenue and number of employees, most of whom are conscripts in the compulsory service scheme. It is a part of the Armed Forces of Vekllei, and subsequently reports directly to the palace. In practice, it consists of dozens of smaller companies that are administered by the Ministry of Defence in its local member-state.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/industry/">industrial</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>The Army Construction House</strong> (ACH) is the largest construction company in the Commonwealth by gross revenue and number of employees, most of whom are conscripts in the <a href="/corsosva/">compulsory service scheme</a>. It is a part of the Armed Forces of Vekllei, and subsequently reports directly to the palace. In practice, it consists of dozens of smaller companies that are administered by the Ministry of Defence in its local member-state.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Universal Cotton</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/universal-cotton/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/universal-cotton/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ Part of the industry series of articles Universal Cotton is a bureau based in the Vekllei Islands. It is the largest clothing manufacturer in the Commonwealth, specialising in shirts, trousers, skirts, dresses, and underwear. It supplies most department stores in the Vekllei Islands as part of the Commons Comfort Scheme of the Vekllei government, and has a significant presence throughout the Commonwealth.
It trades overseas under the Universal Cotton Company brand.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">߷ Part of the <em><a href="/industry/">industry</a></em> series of articles</div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Universal Cotton</strong> is a <a href="/bureaus/">bureau</a> based in the Vekllei Islands. It is the largest clothing manufacturer in the Commonwealth, specialising in shirts, trousers, skirts, dresses, and underwear. It supplies most department stores in the Vekllei Islands as part of the <em>Commons Comfort Scheme</em> of the Vekllei government, and has a significant presence throughout the Commonwealth.</p>
<!--![Flag of Universal Cotton](/images/mastheads/flags/industry/uc.png "The flag of Universal Cotton")-->
<p>It trades overseas under the <em>Universal Cotton Company</em> brand. It also owns a number of sub-brands through its industrial council, including <em>Mia</em> and <em>Atlantic</em>. Including its sub-brands, Universal Cotton is among the largest clothing manufacturers in the world and contributes billions to <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">VKIM</a> market capitalisation.</p>
<p>Universal Cotton also produces factory schematics and product designs which are licensed to small <a href="/bulletin/lots">factory <em>lots</em></a>.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Universal Cotton Organisation</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Universal Cotton General Council
<ul>
<li>General Secretary</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Universal Cotton Industrial Council
<ul>
<li>Vekllei Fabricworks</li>
<li>Sofi Textiles</li>
<li>Disio Cottonwear</li>
<li>Disio Adventurewear</li>
<li>Vekllei National Mills</li>
<li>General Mills</li>
<li>Cava Mills</li>
<li>21st Century</li>
<li>Atomic-Atomic</li>
<li>Bonds Company</li>
<li>Atlantic Textiles</li>
<li>Sova &amp; Gillis</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
