<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>society on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/society/</link>
	<description>Recent content in society on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Air</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/air/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/air/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei society  Introduction #  History #  Early Development #  Postwar Development #  Structure #  Organisation Chart of VNR Responsible to the Skies Bureau of the Ministry of Transport   Vekllei National Rail  National Rail  Vekllei National Railway A.r.R.  VNR Atlantic VNR Kala VNR Overseas   Vekllei National Magway A.r.R. Vekllei Metro A.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Computers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/technology/computers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/technology/computers/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei computing, but most of these technologies are available world-over  Computers are used to subsidise rather than multiply productivity in Vekllei. This does not mean that they do not make commerce or industry more efficient, or open new means of communication between people &amp;ndash; only that they are understood foremost as a social benefit that enables the more idealistic features of the Floral Period and its functional moneylessness.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei society  Vekllei is positioned uniquely between the anarchy and control. This article looks at its government, which facilitates and manages these competing instincts. As the representative of the Vekllei state, and the body of its human interests, the Vekllei Government is second only to the Sovereign in its authority over Vekllei society.  The Government of Vekllei refers to both the Administration of the Interior of the Vekllei Home Islands and the international governing body of the Vekllei Commonwealth.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Language</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/language/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/language/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei  The language of Vekllei is an important part of the project. Utopianism cascades through every part of society, and rethinking communication is a foundational part of that instinct. In this article, we look at what makes Vekllei as a language special, and give insight into how these Atlantic people communicate with each other.  Vekllei language, abbreviated to just Vekllei, has six core sublanguages that are used commonly today.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mail</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/mail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/mail/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei society  The Royal Mail of Vekllei is perhaps the country&amp;rsquo;s most visible organisation overseas. For many foreigners, Royal Mail aircraft may be the closest they ever come to seeing for themselves the mysterious Atlantic country. For Vekllei residents, the ancient organisation is a living relic of the country&amp;rsquo;s ancient history, and an ongoing testament to the longevity of their people.  The Royal Mail of Vekllei, referred to as the Mail or Mail A.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rail</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/rail/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/rail/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei society  This article discusses one of the most important and visible organisations in everyday Vekllei life: Vekllei National Rail. Vekllei is criss-crossed by hundreds of different rail lines of various gauges, grades, and purposes. In fact, it runs many lines at a total loss, often under capacity. To understand these inefficiencies is to understand why the National Rail exists, and to some extent, how Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s state assets and powerful bureaus shape life in the country today.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Religion</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/religion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/religion/</guid>
	  <description>Overview #  ߷ This article is about Vekllei  Upen is the nondenominational animistic spiritualism of Vekllei. It is both an organised religious belief system and a decentralised local animism, localised regionally across the Home Islands and beyond. As a basis for Vekllei metaphysics and general belief systems, Upen is a central part of Vekllei cultural identity and informs most parts of life at all levels in the country.  Upen is the animistic, nondenominational dominant and historical religion of Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>