<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>sydney on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/sydney/</link>
	<description>Recent content in sydney on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/sydney/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>New Rivers of the Atlantic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/rivers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/rivers/</guid>
	  <description>✿ This character was illustrated as a gift to my friend Qweezi. Happy Birthday! In Vekllei, you met all sorts of people. All nations passed through the Home Islands, some to visit, others to live. Tzipora met a great many of them in her time at school.
Sydney came from Kosava, an anarchist island commune in the Lesser Antilles we know as St Kitts and Nevis. Kosava is an independent member-state of the Kalina Islands, which describes a series of autonomous islands in the Caribbean.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Fruit Tingles</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/tingles/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/tingles/</guid>
	  <description>✿ This image is a website-exclusive sketch produced as a masthead for the November Patreon update. The typeface in this image is a preview version &amp;ldquo;Nay Aug&amp;rdquo; by Alex Tomlinson, who you can follow here. Fruit Tingles (Fodsa Spas) are a chalky sweet popular in Vekllei. They fizz in your mouth and come in several flavours. They&amp;rsquo;re as popular today as they were a hundred and fifty years ago when they were first produced by Montre Confectionary in 1936.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Marine Railway</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/marine-railway/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/marine-railway/</guid>
	  <description>✿ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Ocean Month in March 2021 ✿ Note from the Editor Although vessels described here are written with female pronouns as per Western convention, Vekllei traditionally uses male pronouns for navy vessels. Nuclear Heavy Battlecruiser V.V. Lava is the first of the Lava-class cruisers, the largest of Vekllei’s surface warships. Vekllei doctrine does not typically float cruisers with fleets, and so the Lava often operates independently, outfitted for a variety of roles.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>