<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vekllei on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/tags/vekllei/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vekllei on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 03:41:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wiki.millmint.studio/tags/vekllei/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 03:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
      <description>There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.
 Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or venopor) Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or cosmopor)  A young venopor officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike cosmopor, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Map of Vekllei — 100 Boroughs; 100 Hearts</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-14-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 23:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-14-map/</guid>
      <description>Map Key
 Red: Magjet trains, 750km/h
Yellow: Bullet trains, 300-400km/h
Orange: Regional trains, &amp;lt;150km/h
Brown: Local trains, including limited express, &amp;lt;100km/h
Blue: National highway
Dashed: Ferry line
Green: tarmacadamed airport
 The largest division of any portion of Vekllei land is the borough; a region of varying size and population with common culture, food dependency and economic interest. Anything larger than that is simply Vekllei — they are “one city”, after all, and consider themselves a city-state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Village Map of Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 04:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</guid>
      <description>The village of Montre-Lola is home to about 400 people in its entirety, a stone’s throw from the Aisyo borough. Each morning, however, the population swells as 300 children from tiny villages in both Aisyo and Montre take a fast tram to the Montre-Lola Area School No. 2, a district school raising all ages of local youth.
Like many Vekllei villages, Montre-Lola’s history is complex and has origin stories in both viking-inuit settlement as well as less sentimental government programmes that flourished after the atomic war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oa-Class Battlecruiser</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 02:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</guid>
      <description>Vekllei’s defensive military posture has, in doctrine and arms development, limited its ability to meaningfully project power outside of the Atlantic. As an island nation with a large and multifaceted naval armada, the Oa-Class Battlecruiser is the heart of her armed forces, as the flagship of her fleets.
Where U.S. doctrine places carriers offensively in the structure of its ship-groups, the Vekllei Navy is considerably more Soviet in its employ of carriers as primarily defensive air-bases to exercise sovereignty over her far-flung territories and island possessions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>