<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>military on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/tags/military/</link>
    <description>Recent content in military on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wiki.millmint.studio/tags/military/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of the second day, I watched a fly crawl across the cheek of the middle-aged woman, probably an office worker, lying next to me. It moved up her cheekbone to her temple, stopping now and then to rub its front legs as though performing a ritual. A jagged tear ran down the leg of her dark blue work trousers, but the white calf it revealed was miraculously unscathed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Quiet</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 03:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</guid>
      <description>There were plumes in the sky, sent from bunkers buried deep in the well of the Earth, killing with switches. Vekllei went to war, and so Tzipora went to war with it.
The throbbing machinery of another world began turning, and anyone who saw the bomb would hear it. Passing seconds dislocated and caught heartbeats. The plumes were pretty. It was such a shame, those plumes. It was a quiet afternoon in the flower-tundras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oa-Class Battlecruiser</title>
      <link>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 02:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.millmint.studio/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</guid>
      <description>Vekllei’s defensive military posture has, in doctrine and arms development, limited its ability to meaningfully project power outside of the Atlantic. As an island nation with a large and multifaceted naval armada, the Oa-Class Battlecruiser is the heart of her armed forces, as the flagship of her fleets.
Where U.S. doctrine places carriers offensively in the structure of its ship-groups, the Vekllei Navy is considerably more Soviet in its employ of carriers as primarily defensive air-bases to exercise sovereignty over her far-flung territories and island possessions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>