<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>State</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/state/</link>
	<description>Recent content in State </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/state/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Bureaus</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/bureaus/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the industry series of articles Bureaus in Vekllei are industrial syndicates of companies that represent substantial or monopoly power over an industrial market. Their existence is recognised by Vekllei economic policy as a means of furnishing a reasonable standard of living for Vekllei people outside of the anarchy of the private markets. As a result, bureaus are concerned primarily with the public good and industrial policy.
Bureaus typically consist of a general council, which organise votes from workers in subsidiary companies into company ballots, which are used to establish standards and self-regulate industry.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/industry/">industry</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Bureaus</strong> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> are industrial syndicates of companies that represent substantial or monopoly power over an industrial market. Their existence is recognised by Vekllei economic policy as a means of furnishing a reasonable standard of living for Vekllei people outside of the anarchy of the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#domestic-markets">private markets</a>. As a result, bureaus are concerned primarily with the public good and industrial policy.</p>
<p>Bureaus typically consist of a general council, which organise votes from workers in subsidiary companies into <em>company ballots</em>, which are used to establish standards and self-regulate industry. Bureau membership also allows interaction with the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">Vekllei International Market</a>, and provide a means for foreign investment and export. Companies within bureaus still compete against each other.</p>
<p>The largest bureaus include <em>Electra</em> and <a href="/universal-cotton/"><em>Universal Cotton</em></a>. Electra represents a collection of state-owned electricity generation companies, and Universal Cotton consists of over a hundred individual clothing manufacturers. Although state monopolies may form a bureau in part or as a whole, bureau membership does not necessarily imply state ownership.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Consosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/consosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/consosva/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles Consosva (a portmanteau of consivismiosn sovis, lit. &ldquo;contributory service&rdquo;) refers to a collection of laws that require adult citizens in Vekllei to be employed. The legal obligation is fairly straightforward and is easily avoided, and in practice acts as a form of moral pressure from the state.
Consosva is a legal obligation to register an occupation with your municipality, which forwards its ledger to the Vekllei government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Consosva</strong> (a portmanteau of <em>consivismiosn sovis</em>, lit. &ldquo;<em>contributory service</em>&rdquo;) refers to a collection of laws that require adult citizens in Vekllei to be employed. The legal obligation is fairly straightforward and is easily avoided, and in practice acts as a form of moral pressure from the state.</p>
<p>Consosva is a legal obligation to register an occupation with your municipality, which forwards its ledger to the Vekllei government. This is to encourage productivity and discourage &ldquo;social parasitism,&rdquo; as a requirement to contribute to the wealth of society. Failure to do so is considered a crime and is usually penalised with community service.</p>
<p>Consosva has many recognised exemptions, including full-time study, participating in <a href="/corsosva/">Compulsory Service</a>, acting as the primary caregiver of children, and poor health.</p>
<p>Consosva applies to Vekllei citizens or permanent residents aged between 22 and 50.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Corsosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/corsosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/corsosva/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles Corsosva (a portmanteau of corsivis sovis, lit. &ldquo;compulsory service&rdquo;) is the period of civic conscription that applies to all Vekllei citizens. It requires four years of service, served between the ages of 18-32. Although administered by the Department of Compulsory Service of the Ministry of Defence, most citizens perform civilian or industrial work during Corsosva, and only a minority enter the armed forces as conscripts.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Corsosva</strong> (a portmanteau of <em>corsivis sovis</em>, lit. &ldquo;<em>compulsory service</em>&rdquo;) is the period of civic conscription that applies to all Vekllei citizens. It requires four years of service, served between the ages of 18-32. Although administered by the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/defence/#department-of-compulsory-service">Department of Compulsory Service</a> of the <a href="/ministry-of-defence/">Ministry of Defence</a>, most citizens perform civilian or industrial work during Corsosva, and only a minority enter the armed forces as conscripts.</p>
<p>Individuals entering Corsosva elect their preferences for service, which are then weighted based on experience and ability. The most common forms of Corsosva are in construction, education and healthcare.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Crown Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/industry/crown/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Crown Assets are a kind of state-owned enterprise subordinated to the Vekllei Sovereign, known as the Atlantic Crown or simply Crown. Crown SOEs are owned equally by all full Commonwealth member-states. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text">Crown Assets are a kind of state-owned enterprise subordinated to the Vekllei Sovereign, known as the <em>Atlantic Crown</em> or simply <em>Crown</em>. Crown SOEs are owned equally by all full Commonwealth member-states.</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Espionage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/espionage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/espionage/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Overview # This article is about Vekllei. Espionage is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about <a href="/intro/#what-is-vekllei">Vekllei</a>.</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><strong>Espionage</strong> is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers. Unsentimental, unideological and unflinching, espionage in Vekllei is conducted constantly and vigorously with the blessing &ndash; or at least willing blindness &ndash; of the state.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Espionage in Vekllei is considered the &lsquo;first thorn&rsquo; of &lsquo;assertive defence&rsquo; practiced by the 4th Commonwealth. It is maintained offensively, as operations, and defensively as counterintelligence. The means by which it does are a source of endless contention in Commonwealth parliaments, the Vekllei public and foreign governments,<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> but since independence in 2015 espionage has been conducted much the same &ndash; and so can be assumed to be achieving strategic goals.</p>
<p>Overseas strategic and industrial espionage primarily falls under the control of the Commonwealth National Intelligence Directorate, usually called <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-security); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-security) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/parliaments/security/noshem/"><span class=""></span> Noshem</a>, which maintains several subordinate bureaus organised regionally.</p>
<p>Current intelligence doctrine values &lsquo;signal operations&rsquo; &ndash; visible strategic actions that &lsquo;signal&rsquo; messages to public enemies of the Commonwealth state, and maintaining plausible deniability. The line between civilian and military intelligence operations is not always clear, and Noshem is implicated in assassinations and executions of state enemies overseas. The Vekllei intelligence community is known to recruit ideological and nationalist sympathisers to perform actions on behalf of the state, and to this end has among the largest networks of informants of any espionage ring in the world.</p>
<h2 id="operations">
  Operations
  <a class="anchor" href="#operations">#</a>
</h2>
<h3 id="noshem">
  Noshem
  <a class="anchor" href="#noshem">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-security); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-security) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/parliaments/security/noshem/"><span class=""></span> Noshem</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>Noshem,<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> the traditional name for the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#national-intelligence-directorate">National Intelligence Directorate</a> is the secret service of the Commonwealth and is responsible for most of its overseas espionage. It has a legendary reputation for the size and quality of its informants network, and is highly feared because of its history of ruthlessness, including extrajudicial assassinations and executions. Plausible deniability makes it difficult to tell how much of its work is sanctioned by parliaments or acted out by individual Vekllei people, and the organisation generates considerable controversy. Noshem has had several publicised tactical successes as well as failures, and is considered a critical aspect of Commonwealth security as a &lsquo;jewelled sabre&rsquo; of the non-aligned movement.</p>
<p>Noshem operates 40 outlines across 6 bureaus, which are organised regionally and contain semiautonomous command and logistics elements.</p>
<h3 id="security-directorates">
  Security Directorates
  <a class="anchor" href="#security-directorates">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Cosevac (POSEC) and Vosevisi (SESEC) are the Security Directorates of the Public and State respectively. Vosevisi processes some Noshem material, and its subordinate <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/commonwealth/security/#state-secrets-office">State Secrets Office</a> is also responsible for maintaining security controls and classifications. Although they collect intelligence internally, most espionage is conducted overseas by <a href="/factbook/society/state/espionage/#noshem">Noshem</a>.</p>
<h3 id="adsem">
  Adsem
  <a class="anchor" href="#adsem">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Adsem is the military intelligence department of the Vekllei Armed Forces. It co-ordinates with the <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/">Interior Parliament</a> via the Ministry of Defence&rsquo;s <a href="/factbook/society/state/government/interior/defence/#intelligence-liaison-office">Intelligence Liasion Office</a>, and is concerned primarily with counterintelligence operations and strategic information relevant to war. Like the Security Directorates, most of Adsem&rsquo;s espionage is conducted by Noshem. In turn, Adsem supplies much of Noshem&rsquo;s matériel, and many of its elite intelligence units are recruited from military commando and special forces sections. Adsem may also assist in the logistics of Noshem espionage operations.</p>
<h3 id="recruitment">
  Recruitment
  <a class="anchor" href="#recruitment">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei human intelligence is generally considered superior to that of the CIA, and may even be comparable to the KGB in scope and quality. Human intelligence is the basis of contemporary Vekllei intelligence-gathering, and the intelligence state gathers and processes massive amounts of information on foreign nationals, companies, and governments. It relies on enormous, concentric rings of highly motivated unpaid sympathisers that help Noshem in passing messages, inserting agents and obscuring information.</p>
<p>There are several classes of sympathiser &ndash; some are ideologically motivated in the anarchist or pan-Atlanticist tradition, factions which the Vekllei government is willing to recognise or indulge publicly to stir positive and negative press and distinguish itself from the cold war dichotomy. Others are nationalists who help out of a sense of devotion to Vekllei, since several million Vekllei people fled after the Atomic War. Although many returned in the years after independence, there remains a large Vekllei diaspora throughout the world and especially in the United States and Western Europe, and many members continue to hold a sense of duty towards the country.</p>
<p>This network of sympathisers is aided by Vekllei&rsquo;s postwar internationalism and multiracialism, emphasising political and geographic traits that appeal to young, educated people. Where duty fails, cash often suffices, and tremendous amounts of state funds are siphoned discretely from other Ministerial budgets to fund a network of paid informants. The total number of informants is impossible to know, but is estimated to number tens of thousands across the U.S., U.K., France, Russia, Yugoslavia, China and South-East Asia.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>This controversy has prompted several commissions and parliamentary inquests by the Vekllei Comptroller, and continues to generate debate in Vekllei society. It is also a popular subject of conspiracy theorising.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Noshem is the name of the spirit-god of secrets in Vekllei mythology.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Finance</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/finance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/finance/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about Vekllei Even if they do not use money, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests. Overview # The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &ldquo;functionally moneyless,&rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><strong>Even if they do not use money</strong>, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests.</span>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<p>The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &ldquo;functionally moneyless,&rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex. While the average Vekllei person is insulated from money and money-management, their Commonwealth is a major entrepôt<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> and has a reputation as an &ldquo;Atlantic Middleman.&rdquo; Vekllei&rsquo;s facilitation of frictionless free trade, large foreign-exchange reserves and received foreign direct investments have resulted in decades of consistent economic growth, and has cemented its reputation as a financial hub between Europe and the Americas.</p>
<p>Vekllei&rsquo;s history as a trade hub contributes significantly to its perceived neutrality and its reputation as a meeting place for politics and business, and regularly hosts diplomatic missions as a neutral site. It maintains its moneyless primary economy by effectively isolating its primary (<a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#domestic-markets">domestic</a>) and secondary (<a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">international</a>) markets, which are the reason for its <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#currency">twin currencies</a> and its unusual hybrid market system. Because the Vekllei state manages all money as a function of its moneylessness, the international market and foreign trade is strongly characterised by dirigism and fundamentally beholden to the economic management of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-commerce); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-commerce) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>, which acts as both a financial regulator and investment bank.</p>
<h2 id="markets">
  Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#markets">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-commerce); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-commerce) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a></span>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="domestic-markets">
  Domestic Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#domestic-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Vekllei Domestic Market is the turn-of-phrase for the unmoneyed Vekllei economy, including almost all private and public businesses and the majority of trade conducted by ordinary Vekllei people. It is the primary market of Vekllei. For most Vekllei people, the domestic market is the only one with which they will interact in their lives, except for the occasional holiday overseas. The Domestic Market includes all sectors of the Vekllei economy except state trade apparatuses like <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">VKIM</a>.</p>
<p>While the participatory nature of the Domestic Market affects its gross productivity, it is regarded as free, innovative and dynamic. It has a skilled workforce benefitted by a robust education system and a high quality of life. About 40% of Vekllei people were born overseas, and some 15% of the Vekllei workforce remain foreign workers. Foreign workers, unlike domestic ones, are remunerated unless residing under an immigration visa.</p>
<h3 id="industrial-markets">
  Industrial Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#industrial-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Vekllei Industrial Markets are distinguished by their ability to trade in both the moneyless <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#domestic-markets">Domestic Market</a> and the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">VKIM</a>. There are two kinds of industrial firm in Vekllei:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Senrouive</strong>: private enterprises</li>
<li><strong>Venrouive</strong>: public enterprises with membership in an industrial <a href="/bureaus/">bureau</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Venrouive</em> (also known as public companies in Vekllei) are enterprises beholden to <a href="/bureaus/">industrial bureaus</a>, which are collections of companies with close relations and hold membership in a shared industrial council. Venrouive businesses are characterised by large-scale enterprises, some of which may be state-owned, that hold considerable power over a market. In some cases, a bureau may monopolise a market, as in the case of the Vekllei telecommunications industry.</p>
<p>Both senrouive and venrouive companies may participate in the international market, but only bureaus (and by extension, participating venrouive companies) may trade directly with overseas governments and enterprises.</p>
<h3 id="international-markets">
  International Markets
  <a class="anchor" href="#international-markets">#</a>
</h3>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text">✿ Download <span class="smallicon">📄</span> <a href="/files/documents/9.pdf">Document No. 9.pdf</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Vekllei International Market (VKIM) is an organisation that controls the capital, commodities and securities markets of Vekllei. VKIM is maintained by the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-commerce); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-commerce) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a> as a mechanism for foreign investors and merchants to interact with the isolated, unmoneyed Vekllei domestic market. The international market includes a commodities exchange, derivatives marketplace and other structured financial products that facilitate foreign activity in the Vekllei economy and raise foreign capital for the national liquid currency reserves. VKIM uses the Vekllei Composite Index as a measure of the Vekllei economy, which measures both commodity value and productivity.</p>
<p>The International Market is the means by which the capital account<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> of the Commonwealth Government implements its long-standing macroeconomic interest in foreign investment and soft power. The reinvestment of capital surplus in the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#currency">Vekllei currencies</a> serves as a form of sterilisation and capital control, controlled directly by the central <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(240, 93, 136) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/state/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a>. Vekllei has the world&rsquo;s 2nd-largest foreign currency reserves.</p>
<h2 id="currency">
  Currency
  <a class="anchor" href="#currency">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/posts/2020-06-24-crown/">The Vekllei Crown</a></em></span>
</blockquote>

<p>Vekllei has two currencies that are more or less opposed in their use as money, known as the twin crowns system. The Vekllei Crown (❦VK) is a gold-backed, fixed-rate deflationary currency used primarily as a wealth reserve, and the Government Crown (✾AK) is a fiat, floating-exchange currency used for foreign investment and trade. This system preserves the isolation of the Vekllei primary economy, which is moneyless, while insulating state investments from shocks and from having to burn liquidity to maintain its exchange rate.</p>
<p>Together, the twin crowns allow for the Vekllei state to retain unprecedented control over its financial system while securing a mechanism for foreign investment and growth.</p>
<ul>
<li>The domestic market is autarkic and does not have free capital exchange, allowing it to maintain its fixed price and independent monetary policy</li>
<li>The international market is open and has free capital exchange, facilitated by ✾AK floating exchange price with policy independence maintained by capital controls from the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-commerce); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-commerce) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Ministry of Commerce</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>For a variety of political and economic reasons, the Vekllei Commonwealth state aims to be self-sufficient. The twin crowns system provides a means to isolate its productive primary economy while also allowing foreign money controlled access to it. The unmoneyed primary economy remains a popular investment for its stability.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> As capital controls have broken down in the mid-2030s, Vekllei&rsquo;s current macroeconomic policy exists as a &ldquo;third way&rdquo; between closed autarky and recent trends towards an open economic international market.</p>
<h3 id="vekllei-crown-vk">
  Vekllei Crown (❦VK)
  <a class="anchor" href="#vekllei-crown-vk">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The <em>Vekllei Kroner</em> (lit. <em>Vekllei Crown</em>) is the primary and historic currency of Vekllei. It is minted by the  as a souvenir in the tradition of Vekllei <em>medals</em>,<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> but is not otherwise used by Vekllei people as money or transacted in day-to-day life. It is primarily a deflationary currency store backed by gold, and to which each Vekllei citizen is entitled an equal share in emigration. It is not able to be used on the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">VKIM</a> directly, but can be purchased as a <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#white-bonds">White Bond</a> as a speculative instrument. It is also used in some cases as a mechanism for trade with individuals abroad, mostly by smaller banks looking to broker purchases of goods or services unavailable in Vekllei.</p>
<h3 id="government-crown-ak">
  Government Crown (✾AK)
  <a class="anchor" href="#government-crown-ak">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The <em>Government/Commonwealth Kroner</em> (also the <em>Atlantic Kroner</em> or <em>Crown</em>) is a twin currency used primarily by the state to insure financial instruments like bonds as well as for converting and placing foreign investments and currency. The Government Crown operates on a floating exchange rate as a fiat currency tradeable in the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">VKIM</a> and a means for overseas actions in the Vekllei economy.</p>
<p>The ✾AK is not minted as it does not resemble a conventional currency, and exists only in bonds, state certificates, and as a metric for some commodity money. It has a strong reputation as a hard currency because of the ✾AK&rsquo;s relative security and reliability, backed by powerful domestic institutions.</p>
<h2 id="banking">
  Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#banking">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(240, 93, 136) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/state/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The policy of bank consolidation under the British Occupation Government continued under the successive Floral Government, and banking was among the first industries in Vekllei to be completely socialised.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup> All banks in Vekllei are run as state-owned enterprises, and subordinated to the &lsquo;<em>Old Lady</em>,&rsquo; the colloquial name for the central <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(240, 93, 136) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/state/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a>. &lsquo;Unbanking&rsquo; policy &ndash; the effective demonetisation of the Vekllei domestic markets &ndash; saw severe disruption to the Vekllei economy and led to a period of hyperinflation in the late 2010s.</p>
<p>Unlike in other countries, the socialisation of banking in Vekllei also saw the broad exclusion of retail investors and savings banking, effectively halting money exchange in the domestic market and institutionalising the Vekllei banking system. Today, most Vekllei banks are institutional and deal primarily with the secondary speculative markets like <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#international-markets">VKIM</a>, or provide lending and contracts for new businesses in the <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#industrial-markets">industrial market</a>.</p>
<h3 id="bank-of-vekllei">
  Bank of Vekllei
  <a class="anchor" href="#bank-of-vekllei">#</a>
</h3>
<p>The Bank of Vekllei (also <em>Labour Bank of Vekllei</em> and <em>Old Lady</em>) is Vekllei&rsquo;s central bank with a constitutionally-granted monopoly on the financial mechanisms of the Commonwealth, with nearly all Commonwealth banking firms subordinated to its organisation. It is responsible directly to the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-commerce); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-commerce) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Commonwealth Treasury</a> and sets the monetary policy of Vekllei. It is primarily a macroeconomic institution that does not deal directly with the primary or secondary markets, but does over institutional banking services and complex financing for some markets in the Commonwealth.</p>
<h4 id="personal-banking">
  Personal Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#personal-banking">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Despite the functional moneylessness of the Commonwealth, banks do facilitate financial transactions with the common Vekllei person. Aside from its policy features (like holiday allowances and emigration stipends), most trade arrangements operate in the bank system, usually through the <em>Sisterbank</em>. Sisterbank (formally the <em>Petty Bank of Vekllei</em>) is a merchant bank that specialises in industrial brokerage, allowing small businesses to trade with others and stimulate economic activity. Vekllei persons looking to start a restaurant, workshop or store generally do so through the Sisterbank, which assigns a bank agent and enters the business in its internal market ledger. Not all small business in Vekllei is conducted through the an agent, but certain types of industries (particularly businesses involved in manufacturing) are almost all banked with Sisterbank.</p>
<p>In addition to government banks, money bureaus (also <em>Money Unions</em>) are a form of cooperative credit union premised on private business associations and securitised lending, and are common in Vekllei agriculture.</p>
<h4 id="institutional-banking">
  Institutional Banking
  <a class="anchor" href="#institutional-banking">#</a>
</h4>
<p>Investment banking is provided primarily by the Commonwealth Bank of Vekllei (COMMBANK), which offers placement and settling services for <a href="/bureaus/">bureaus</a> seeking to engage with the International market. COMMBANK also arranges debt financing, underwriting and distribution services for overseas partners. COMMBANK also serves as the central bank of the Kalina Isles. In addition, the Bank of Vekllei maintains several subsidiaries dedicated to special financial products, like low-interest domestic infrastructure financing or overseas trade and investment.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>An entrepôt is a port where merchandise is stored and traded, often before being exported again.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>The Commonwealth capital account runs at a deficit as part of a post-war investment policy called &lsquo;Handshake Accounting,&rsquo; which sees tremendous surplus state capital invested overseas.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Foreign investment in the primary economy is usually made in the form of state-backed <a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/#blue-bonds">Blue Bonds</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Medallions, or medals, are a cultural feature in Vekllei used in spiritual ceremonies, as awards, and as a material novelty or trinket.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>&lsquo;Municipalised,&rsquo; in Vekllei political lexicon.&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Interim Prosperity Government</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/history/interim/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/history/interim/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the history series of articles The Interim Vekllei Government (also the Interim Parliament and Interim Prosperity Government) was a temporary puppet state of the United Kingdom, established in 2015 as a means to Vekllei independence after twenty years of British occupation in the country. It consisted of approved leaders in the arts and industry, who developed proposals for a new democratic Vekllei state.
Included was a majority female Council of Roses, many of whom were socialists opposed to communist unrest in British-occupied Vekllei and were seen as a strategic alternative to a hostile communist government upon British withdrawal.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/history/">history</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Interim Vekllei Government</strong> (also the <em>Interim Parliament</em> and <em>Interim Prosperity Government</em>) was a temporary puppet state of the United Kingdom, established in 2015 as a means to Vekllei independence after twenty years of British occupation in the country. It consisted of approved leaders in the arts and industry, who developed proposals for a new democratic Vekllei state.</p>
<p>Included was a majority female <a href="/rose-council/">Council of Roses</a>, many of whom were socialists opposed to communist unrest in British-occupied Vekllei and were seen as a strategic alternative to a hostile communist government upon British withdrawal. The council were responsible for draughting the Vekllei Constitution and establishing Interim Ministries in anticipation of independence.</p>
<p>After independence in 2017, the Vekllei Interim Government became the 4th Commonwealth of Vekllei.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Municipalities</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/municipalities/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/state/government/municipalities/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles ✿ Read more: The Good, The Municipal Municipalities are the bedrock of sundress municipalism, and a physical feature of everyday Vekllei life. A municipality refers to both a local council and its services, including libraries, schools, and policemen. Municipalities in Vekllei are the predominant form of local government, and vary dramatically in scale, power and resources. They usually refer to council municipalities, which are bodies of elected industrial and political leaders of a community.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/municipal/">The Good, The Municipal</a></em></span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><strong>Municipalities</strong> are the bedrock of sundress municipalism, and a physical feature of everyday Vekllei life. A municipality refers to both a local council and its services, including libraries, schools, and policemen.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Municipalities in Vekllei are the predominant form of local government, and vary dramatically in scale, power and resources. They usually refer to council municipalities, which are bodies of elected industrial and political leaders of a community. This open-ended definition means that municipalities scale in Vekllei from tiny villages to major metropolitan areas.</p>
<p>Municipalities are the basis of Vekllei localism, a belief in local concern and decentralised decision-making. In general, Vekllei municipalism describes the places where society in abstract meets the individual, and so also has cultural and aesthetic qualities. The sum of a municipality is expressed in the <em>Atlantic Municipalist</em> tradition, which consists of the following principles:</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><p><strong>Principles of Atlantic Municipalism</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Local employment, or “commutelessness.”</li>
<li>Slumlessness, beautification, and a will to architecture.</li>
<li>Property stewardship.</li>
<li>Open air and clean water.</li>
<li>Land usefulness (&ldquo;friendliness&rdquo;).</li>
<li>Private ownership of private needs.</li>
<li>Public ownership of public needs.</li>
</ol></span>
</blockquote>

<p>There are 14,000 municipalities across the Commonwealth. The usage of &lsquo;municipal&rsquo; can refer to a political council or the spirit of Atlantic Municipalism.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ This page is an archive for content posted to the dormant Vekllei Patreon. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text">This page is an archive for content posted to the dormant <a href="https://patreon.com/vekllei">Vekllei Patreon</a>.</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sagas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/sagas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/society/culture/sagas/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the culture series of articles Sagas are a kind of historic prose narrative that recorded the oral history of early Oslola. They are distinguished by their use of Topyas, a predecessor to modern Topet. They are recognised for their realism and poetry, and provide a valuable historical record of the 1st Commonwealth and practices of Old Upen.
Sagas were consolidated into historical and thematic eras in the 14th Century during the Period of Rest, which is typically how they are arranged today.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/culture/">culture</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Sagas</strong> are a kind of historic prose narrative that recorded the oral history of early Oslola. They are distinguished by their use of <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#history/">Topyas</a>, a predecessor to modern <a href="/factbook/society/culture/language/#topet/">Topet</a>. They are recognised for their realism and poetry, and provide a valuable historical record of the 1st Commonwealth and practices of Old Upen.</p>
<p>Sagas were consolidated into historical and thematic eras in the 14th Century during the Period of Rest, which is typically how they are arranged today.</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><p><strong>Sagas of Old Oslola</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em>God Saga</em>, c. 880AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of Origins</em> c. 940AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of Saints</em> c. 960AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of Family</em> c.1000AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of Spirits</em> c. 1200AD</li>
<li><em>Saga of New Earth</em> c. 1300AD</li>
</ul></span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
