<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>state on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/state/</link>
	<description>Recent content in state on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/state/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Bureaus</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/bureaus/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/bureaus/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the industry series of articles Bureaus in Vekllei are industrial syndicates of companies that represent substantial or monopoly power over an industrial market. Their existence is recognised by Vekllei economic policy as a means of furnishing a reasonable standard of living for Vekllei people outside of the anarchy of the private markets. As a result, bureaus are concerned primarily with the public good and industrial policy.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Consosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/consosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/consosva/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the state series of articles Consosva (a portmanteau of consivismiosn sovis, lit. &amp;ldquo;contributory service&amp;rdquo;) refers to a collection of laws that require adult citizens in Vekllei to be employed. The legal obligation is fairly straightforward and is easily avoided, and in practice acts as a form of moral pressure from the state.
Consosva is a legal obligation to register an occupation with your municipality, which forwards its ledger to the Vekllei government.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Corsosva</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/corsosva/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/corsosva/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the state series of articles Corsosva (a portmanteau of corsivis sovis, lit. &amp;ldquo;compulsory service&amp;rdquo;) is the period of civic conscription that applies to all Vekllei citizens. It requires four years of service, served between the ages of 18-32. Although administered by the Department of Compulsory Service of the Ministry of Defence, most citizens perform civilian or industrial work during Corsosva, and only a minority enter the armed forces as conscripts.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Crown Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/</guid>
	  <description> Crown Assets are a kind of state-owned enterprise subordinated to the Vekllei Sovereign, known as the Atlantic Crown or simply Crown. Crown SOEs are owned equally by all full Commonwealth member-states. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Education</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/education/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/education/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei society. Education emerged as a foundational right for Vekllei people in the constitution of the 4th Commonwealth, in the spirit of postwar democratisation and the rising of all people. Education in Vekllei is a good example of the &amp;lsquo;system working backwards,&amp;rsquo; the popular phrase to describe the Floral Period moving in two different directions at once. Is it modern, supplied and robust in the Western tradition &amp;ndash; children wear uniforms, are divided into school years and learning is arranged and taught in subjects.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Espionage</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/espionage/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/espionage/</guid>
	  <description>Overview # ߷ This article is about Vekllei. Espionage is a considerable strength of the 4th Commonwealth, while also incurring a growing cost. Its assertive and risky operations, some of which have ended in catastrophe, inflict considerable damage on its image abroad, and isolate it from European and American powers. But this assertiveness has also built a fearsome, modern and sprawling intelligence network that meets or surpasses even that of much greater superpowers.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Finance</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/finance/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei Even if they do not use money, Vekllei people do have finances and engage with markets, maintain business relations and acquire financial instruments for upward mobility. The Vekllei state, on the other hand, is an enthusiastic participant in the global financial system and uses its considerable advantages enabled by the isolated moneyless Vekllei economy to accomplish its strategic political interests. Overview # The colloquial turn-of-phrase for the domestic Vekllei economy is &amp;ldquo;functionally moneyless,&amp;rdquo; but the actual mechanisms of the internal Vekllei market is considerably more complex.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Government</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/</guid>
	  <description>The Vekllei Government is the supranational parliamentary government of the Vekllei Islands and the members, dependent states and territories of the Vekllei Commonwealth. It is distinct from the Palace of Vekllei, the monarch and sovereign of the Vekllei Commonwealth. The Government of Vekllei 🌸Crown Parliament ⚖️Courts of the Crown (coming soon) 💼Fair Work Authority (coming soon) 🗳️Vekllei Democracy Commissariat (coming soon) 🌸Commonwealth Parliament ⚒️Commonwealth Construction Secretariat (coming soon) 🏵Commonwealth Culture Secretariat (coming soon) 🎓Commonwealth Education Secretariat (coming soon) ⚕️Commonwealth Health Secretariat (coming soon) ⛓️Commonwealth Labour Secretariat (coming soon) 🏹Commonwealth Security Secretariat 🌸Interior Parliament 🪙Ministry of Commerce 🚧Ministry of the Commons (coming soon) 🌐Ministry of the Commonwealth ⚔️Ministry of Defence 🌍Ministry of Foreign Affairs (coming soon) ⚙️Ministry of Industry (coming soon) 🌋Ministry of Landscape (coming soon) 🔌Ministry of Light &amp;amp; Water ⛏️Ministry of Syndicates &amp;amp; Chapels (coming soon) 🚃Ministry of Transport (coming soon) Overview # ߷ This article is about the Vekllei state Vekllei is positioned uniquely between the anarchy and control.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Housing</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/housing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/housing/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the state series of articles Housing in Vekllei is socialised in the Georgist tradition. It is a recognition that all wealth lies in land, the resources beneath it, and the people that work it. In this sense, housing in Vekllei is just as radical and striking as its moneylessness. All real estate in Vekllei is negotiated, purchased and leased at a municipal level. This system depends heavily on stewardship as a factor of ownership.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Interim Prosperity Government</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interim/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/interim/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the state series of articles The Interim Vekllei Government (also the Interim Parliament and Interim Prosperity Government) was a temporary puppet state of the United Kindgom, established in 2015 as a means to Vekllei independence after twenty years of British occupation in the country. It consisted of approved leaders in the arts and industry, who developed proposals for a new democratic Vekllei state.
Included was a majority female council, many of whom were socialists opposed to communist unrest in British-occupied Vekllei and were seen as a strategic alternative to a hostile communist government upon British withdrawal.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Municipalities</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/municipalities/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/government/municipalities/</guid>
	  <description>✿ Read more: The Good, The Municipal Municipalities are the bedrock of sundress municipalism, and a physical feature of everyday Vekllei life. A municipality refers to both a local council and its services, including libraries, schools, and policemen. Municipalities in Vekllei are the predominant form of local government, and vary dramatically in scale, power and resources. They usually refer to council municipalities, which are bodies of elected industrial and political leaders of a community.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Patreon</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/patreon/</guid>
	  <description> This page is an archive for content posted to the dormant Vekllei Patreon. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sagas</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/sagas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/sagas/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the culture series of articles Sagas are a kind of historic prose narrative that recorded the oral history of early Vekllei. They are distinguished by their use of Topyas, a predecessor to modern Topet. They are recognised for their realism and poetry, and provide a valuable historical record of the 1st Commonwealth and practices of Old Upen.
Sagas were consolidated into historical and thematic eras in the 14th Century during the Period of Rest, which is typically how they are arranged today.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>State</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/state/</guid>
	  <description> ✿ Main article: The Government of Vekllei The start and end of the supranational Vekllei state is difficult to illustrate, since society in the 4th Commonwealth is dominated by several overlapping institutions with competing sovereignty. These articles are mostly concerned with features of the commonwealth nation-state, including the government and aspects of its laws and institutions. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>State Industry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/state/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/state/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Vekllei Large segments of the Vekllei economy are dominated by industries of the state, as both direct ministerial privileges and state-owned enterprises. In total, they form the basis of the basic Vekllei standard of living, holding back catastrophe through reliable overproduction where gaps in the participatory economy might threaten serious shortages. Overview # There is no real distinction in Vekllei between state assets, state-owned enterprises (SOE) and government-owned corporations (GOC), and the terms are used interchangeably.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Army Construction House</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/ach/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/crown/ach/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the industrial series of articles The Army Construction House (ACH) is the largest construction company in the Commonwealth by gross revenue and number of employees, most of whom are conscripts in the compulsory service scheme. It is a part of the Armed Forces of Vekllei, and subsequently reports directly to the palace. In practice, it consists of dozens of smaller companies that are administered by the Ministry of Defence in its local member-state.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Universal Cotton</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/bureaus/universal-cotton/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/society/industry/bureaus/universal-cotton/</guid>
	  <description>߷ Part of the industry series of articles Universal Cotton is a bureau based in the Vekllei Islands. It is the largest clothing manufacturer in the Commonwealth, specialising in shirts, trousers, skirts, dresses, and underwear. It supplies most department stores in the Vekllei Islands as part of the Commons Comfort Scheme of the Vekllei government, and has a significant presence throughout the Commonwealth.
The flag of Universal Cotton. It trades overseas under the Universal Cotton Company brand.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>