<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>2018</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2018/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2018 </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>On Childhood and Modernity</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/fight/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/fight/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Because the other girls would not stop calling her a lesbian, and because they had realised she was scared of loud noises and made use of that fact, Tzipora struck this bitch and her friend out beyond the football pitches after school. Tzipora was a good fighter — on her side is viciousness and a conviction to fight. That’s usually enough for most teen-agers, who like the idea of fighting but are unprepared for the unglamorous reality of it.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fight.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p>Because the other girls would not stop calling her a lesbian, and because they had realised she was scared of loud noises and made use of that fact, Tzipora struck this bitch and her friend out beyond the football pitches after school. Tzipora was a good fighter — on her side is viciousness and a conviction to fight. That’s usually enough for most teen-agers, who like the idea of fighting but are unprepared for the unglamorous reality of it. But those things do not make up for being short and underweight, and the two older girls had her bleeding on the ground by the time two passing community police-officers pulled them apart.</p>
<p>As an officer examined Tzipora’s head with a torch to find the bleeding in her scalp, one of the girls was desperately explaining that Tzipora had swung first and out of nowhere. Tzipora had nothing for her defence, since it was true and since she did not speak to cops, but the policewomen figured it out for themselves easily enough. Tzipora had been beaten savagely in her foolhardy attempt to get back at her bullies, and her pitiful state made the girl’s desperate blame-passing petty and childish. Although she might have lost the fight, she was not bothered again by the two older girls.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Part of the difficulty in understanding Vekllei as a foreigner is in the basic assumptions we make through the lens of modernity. Vekllei has not discovered ‘landscape’, and it has not discovered ‘the Child’.</p>
<p>Now, children have existed since ever, but we live in an age of modernity and commodity — of nuclear power and department stores. The concept of the ‘child’ as we currently identify and understand it did not exist prior to a certain time, in which the rapid accessibility of both industrial goods and luxury in society stripped children of their productive relationships with family and labour, and introduced them to the beast that would become modern schooling. As Kojin Karatani writes about the Meiji Restoration:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>… It becomes clear that the grouping of children by age in the compulsory educational system of modern Japan signified the uprooting of children, as abstract and homogenous entities, from productive relations, social classes, and communities that had previously been their concrete contexts.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now, Vekllei is not Japan. Vekllei is caught, instead, between a spectre of modernity and the myth of its past. At once socialistic and deeply conservative, the intuition of the common Vekllei person is going to be fundamentally different to a person acclimatised to foreign society.</p>
<p>Vekllei has a modern compulsory education system like much else of the world, but the way in which Petticoat society is coloured by <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/9snaar/the_stewards_of_the_earth/">Upen</a> forces a strange compromise between modernity and Vekllei’s agrarian past. Tzipora, for example, shares a classroom with students both older and younger than herself. Boys and girls wear a single uniform, shared with teachers, all the way from kindergarten to university. Compulsory school operates only three or four days a week and lasts only for a few hours. Work and play, in addition to education, have always been essential parts of childhood in the country and modern schooling has accommodated that. By the time a child is a teen-ager, the person has essentially transitioned into young-adulthood.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>By sexual maturation, a Vekllei person has essentially transitioned to young-adulthood and submerged themselves in the productive relations of the adult age; they often leave school for work, they quickly drift to mature, independent relationships with parents, and generally marry young.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The consequence of this idea is that Vekllei people often attend some sort of school for most of their lives. Whether trade schools for work or adult learning institutions for personal curiosity, it is very common to fill the many free hours of a Vekllei person&rsquo;s week with education of some kind.</p>
<p>This is not to mislead the reader into imagining adults and children mixing freely, either in compulsory schooling or wider society. Adults do not attend compulsory schools and the median age of a classroom rarely deviates more than a few years either side. But from the perspective of the child, growing up in Vekllei desegregates children from one-another and introduces them to mature economic and social relationships early on, allowing in theory real liberty to choose and work for your lifestyle in the country.</p>
<p>-&ndash;</p>
<p>This scene takes place in a <a href="https://vekllei.city/parks/">Kadesoinan</a> park, as indicated by the offerings bench and concrete paths snaking through water. In the distance is the Lola Neighbourhood School, with its central classroom tower standing six stories high. In the city beyond is Atomic Park and its distinctive, massive sculpture.</p>
<p><em>I’m still feeling out my ideas on this piece, and I’ll update this post as I figure it out. If you have any questions, that would help me out! Check out</em> <a href="http://www.vekllei.city"><em>www.vekllei.city</em></a> <em>fer more, or follow my reddit profile.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Merry Christmas everyone (plus a little Christmas story)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/christmas-2018/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/christmas-2018/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[She had always been a very serious girl, from the first time he’d met her. It was more than a reflection of character; it was how she talked, how she carried herself. Her clothes were plain, her nervous tics were not that funny, and she was afflicted with all sorts of fears and anxieties. She opens her mouth in public and what comes out is usually of serious opinion — a judgement of something or a political remark.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/christmas2018.jpg"/> <p>She had always been a very serious girl, from the first time he’d met her. It was more than a reflection of character; it was how she talked, how she carried herself. Her clothes were plain, her nervous tics were not that funny, and she was afflicted with all sorts of fears and anxieties. She opens her mouth in public and what comes out is usually of serious opinion — a judgement of something or a political remark. But that is not how Gregori syndrome works. It does not take young girls and make them old. As the months wore on and the length of the days reflected the passing of warm season, he learned well enough that she was a teen-ager, despite her seriousness. She was slowly domesticated into regular society, her conversation became casual, and she started to worry more about things that might have been inconceivably petty in the months before.</p>
<p>In late November they put up the tree, at her insistence. She was six months a citizen at this point, and not yet familiar with all the familial traditions of the country. But she knew Christmas. And that became her season. This chick, awash with anxiety and domestic terror, was fucking around with ornaments he’d left in the box for five years.</p>
<p>‘Do you mind if I put the angel up the top?’ She asked him. She was kneeling at the foot of the tree with a sample of tree-toppers spread out before her. He looked up from his paper.</p>
<p>‘Why would I mind?’</p>
<p>‘I just thought you might.’</p>
<p>‘Do what you like, I don’t mind.’</p>
<p>She shook her head and shifted back on her rump.</p>
<p>‘It’s no fun if you’re not helping. I have no idea what to do, I haven’t had a proper tree since I was eight.’</p>
<p>He put the paper to the side and rubbed his eyes under his spectacles. He breathed out slowly.</p>
<p>‘What if I make Christmas lunch and you can do the tree?’ He said.</p>
<p>‘No, I’m already doing lunch,’ she said, then in English: ‘Pitch in, that’s how we all do it here.’</p>
<p>She got up and shuffled her feet into slippers and sat next to him.</p>
<p>‘Did you invite Ayn?’</p>
<p>‘I haven’t, yet,’ he said, ‘It’s been a busy week. I’ll ask her, though. She’d be thrilled to be asked.’</p>
<p>‘Maybe I should make a card.’</p>
<p>‘That would be nice,’ he nodded. ‘She likes you a lot.’</p>
<p>She looked surprised and smiled at him, teeth and everything.</p>
<p>‘That’s sweet,’ she said, and tugged at her shirt. ‘She’s sweet. I like her too.’</p>
<p>As Tzipora worked her way into a Christmas fever, he began to like it too. She was better when she was happier — she smiled more, and the compulsion to pull her shirt or rub her nose abated. It was very strange to see a girl he’d known as old before her time suddenly revert five years and adopt a flurry of youth; it was a childish rekindling of the good things in her that might be more accessible if she’d grown up in her home country. He was suckered into the season’s festivities too, a holiday empty in the country of plenty without faith and family. He even attended a mass at Tzipora’s request — she was still deicidal, but she remained a Catholic and wanted to be a part of the fun.</p>
<p>On Christmas Eve Tzipora had put herself to sleep with sickly Winter wine and had curled up on the couch. Ayn sat with Baron at the table and they finished what was left of the bottle as the evening rolled on. He’d lost the nose but still had antlers. She was in a Santa hat and sweet with good cheer.</p>
<p>‘It’s funny, when you think about it,’ she said. Her smile had become small and serious. ‘It all turned out well enough, didn’t it?’</p>
<p>‘It’s hardly started,’ he smirked, and gestured with his thumb at the girl on the couch. His voice was very low as to not wake the girl. ‘She’s got a whole thing planned. She doesn’t want me to know what it is. She’ll happily let me clean up her wrapping paper and wash the dishes, but she won’t tell me what’s going on. She’s got something in the oven, that’s all I know.’</p>
<p>‘Mmhmm,’ she said, and she stretched out a hand and gently laid it across his. ‘But I mean in the scheme of things, Baron. I meant in general.’</p>
<p>‘Like how?’</p>
<p>‘Well, you and I could never marry. And I could never have a baby, you know that. I always wanted a child,’ she said. She squeezed his hand. ‘But here we are, anyway. Think about what it was like when you left for America, and then as it is now.’</p>
<p>He nodded.</p>
<p>‘I think about it,’ he said. ‘We’re lucky.’</p>
<p>‘Of course we are.’</p>
<p>He thought about it some more when he got up to carry her to bed some hours into the early morning.</p>
<p><em>Merry Christmas and thanks for a great year.</em></p>
<p><em>Also on the sexy website it (probably easier to read on mobile):</em> <a href="https://vekllei.city/christmas-with-tzipora/"><em>https://vekllei.city/christmas-with-tzipora/</em></a></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Suburban Constabulary</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/motorbike/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/motorbike/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The constabulary is old-fashioned and it can’t last forever. It predates Petticoat-era Vekllei, the previous regime lost to atomic ash, and even the monarchy itself — it was the first community militia of the country and a great deal of romanticism that had been lost in the death of the monarchy has been invested in them. Vekllei people have no gods and no kings; the comfort of tradition is invested in relic institutions like the constabulary.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/bike.jpg"/> <p>The constabulary is old-fashioned and it can’t last forever. It predates Petticoat-era Vekllei, the previous regime lost to atomic ash, and even the monarchy itself — it was the first community militia of the country and a great deal of romanticism that had been lost in the death of the monarchy has been invested in them. Vekllei people have no gods and no kings; the comfort of tradition is invested in relic institutions like the constabulary. Their uniforms are ostentatious and stylish; they carry ceremonial swords; they guard the nation’s children and leaders alike as part of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/99nhx6/the_constabulary/">venrouiva policing</a>, and so on.</p>
<p>Where community police stations are populated heavily with women and are largely unarmed, the constabulary has traditionally been a male institution with capable equipment. Even now, in an age of petticoat society and integration of womanhood into the economic fibre of the country, the constabulary is still mostly staffed by men.</p>
<p>As they do not make house calls, the constabulary is tasked with defending institutions and business of national importance — everything from schools to petrochemical plants and water infrastructure. They ride in cars or motorcycles. Vekllei still operates many thousands of combustion-engine motorcycles, but there are efforts underway to research all-electric motorcycles that could be refuelled periodically. A pity for constables, for whom the roar of a motor engine is half the fun and symbolises their unique status in Vekllei society, which is nearly totally nuclear-electric.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This woman here is an office lady, as designated by the small <em>gi</em> on her skirt. She’s late to lunch for a friend and only has an hour left. She hails the nearest constable, who helps her with directions. Such is the most extreme encounter most Vekllei people will ever experience with the elusive and romantic constabulary, at least until the second nuclear attack on the country and their rapid mobilisation as military police.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://vekllei.city">vekllei.city</a> for the whole world, or check my profile! I love feedback and questions, too.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Valley of the Dead</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/valley-of-the-dead/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/valley-of-the-dead/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[As Zelda got older and her sense of urgency decayed, the bone between life and death seemed to grow less important as time went on. Could you blame her? She was eighty years old at this point and still as fresh as fourteen — suspended somewhere in the misery of her old age and enthusiasm of her youth. You get a sense of it when you meet her — there’s no urgency about her, no hurry at all.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/deadvalley.jpg"/> <p>As Zelda got older and her sense of urgency decayed, the bone between life and death seemed to grow less important as time went on. Could you blame her? She was eighty years old at this point and still as fresh as fourteen — suspended somewhere in the misery of her old age and enthusiasm of her youth. You get a sense of it when you meet her — there’s no urgency about her, no hurry at all. No hurry at all. Just the mild, sweet curiosity of her teen-age appearance and the patience of an old woman.</p>
<p>Since the friends and family of her teen-age years (her real teen-age years) were dead by this time, their spirits had returned to their places of birth. Her mother was in Ula. Baron was in Lola, by the sea. She hoped everyone she loved was at peace. She did not have many friends in her first cycle of life but the ones she did have were precious to her.</p>
<p>In the mountains south of Montre, near the village where she had worked as a librarian for some years, there lies a healthy plateau between monumental basalt ribs. Here is the grave of her mother, long since turned to ashes and returned to the earth. This whole <em>ro</em>, this flower-tundra, was alive with spirits. The <em>ro</em> are important to Vekllei people as the meeting points between life and death. Her mother appears as a cat she recognised from the train station, and the two of them share a space for a while. Zelda never knew her mother all that well, and disliked her for some of the things she did, but eighty years does a lot to the turbulence of grudges and these days she wonders more and more about the bloodline from whence she came and, perhaps some day, she might return.</p>
<p>She pets the cat and talks to her mother, and once it gets too cold to bear, she wishes her mother well and leaves her. Zelda knew there were demons here and didn’t want to spend much time in the <a href="/utopia/landscape/boroughs/ou/#valley-of-the-dead">Valley of the Dead</a> after dark.</p>
<p>She returned home on the express line from <a href="/utopia/landscape/boroughs/ou/">Tiamoin</a> and alighted at Montre-Dupau, where her little country home and the working week awaited her.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Cosmojet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/cosmojet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/cosmojet/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Ramoin-Dupont H700A “Cosmojet” series are the primary carrier-based fighters of Vekllei. They’re a real bitch to fly. Beloved as they are iconic, variations of the Cosmojet (H600A, B, H500A, etc.) make up the bulk of Vekllei’s total fighter outfit. Unconventional inverted gull wings and embedded turbofan engines make for a striking and uniquely Vekllei aircraft.
And that was the whole point. The first Ramoin-Dupont fighter was always about more than military prestige — it would signal to the world that Vekllei was more than a backwards trough of hamlets and cities.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/cosmojet.jpg"/> <p>The Ramoin-Dupont H700A “Cosmojet” series are the primary carrier-based fighters of Vekllei. They’re a real bitch to fly. Beloved as they are iconic, variations of the Cosmojet (H600A, B, H500A, etc.) make up the bulk of Vekllei’s total fighter outfit. Unconventional inverted gull wings and embedded turbofan engines make for a striking and uniquely Vekllei aircraft.</p>
<p>And that was the whole point. The first Ramoin-Dupont fighter was always about more than military prestige — it would signal to the world that Vekllei was more than a backwards trough of hamlets and cities. The RD H-series would be an all-nuclear, all-Vekllei fighter. The country had been left scorched by the nuclear exchange at the turn of the millennium. The collapse of the old regime brought about widespread poverty and backwardness. The United States and Europe had emerged with industry mostly intact, and their governments were bankrolling nuclear aircraft programmes. So Vekllei began tentative research into modernising its ageing air force.</p>
<p>The Ramoin-Dupont Aircraft Company was founded by the two cities of its namesake in the cooperative economic boom of the 2010s and 2020s, and the initial development factory and test fields were outdated and burdened by a catalogue of old-fashioned turbojet transport aircraft. The handful of genius engineers in the RD skunkworks set to work, in collaboration with General Reactor, on the new fighter project. As progress was made, the pressure to catch up was eclipsed by excitement as key technological breakthroughs offered Vekllei a chance at leapfrogging conventional military fighters and ushering in a new aluminium-body nuclear fighter. Most crucial were the advancements in Vekllei domestic reactor technology, brought about by General Reactor. Sunburst-style heat exchangers meant lower reactor temps, which allowed for lighter chromium-cadmium shielding and an overall weight reduction of several thousand pounds compared to American and European projects.</p>
<p>After two decades of development, the result was the Aurora. It was still too heavy to properly arm because of the shielding and size requirements of a molten salt reactor. Succeeding generations corrected critical flaws in power management, manoeuvrability, and weight. Fifty years later, the Cosmojet is a direct descendent of that project and stands as the 15th iteration in the nuclear jet programme overall.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The aircraft pictured is named “Lola,” a common girls name in the country. Her nose and forward air intake are painted like a puffin’s break, the national bird. The Vekllei roundel features the logographic character for ‘land of volcanoes,’ the <a href="https://vekllei.city/language/">masculine glossary’s (Loh)</a> hieroglyph for Vekllei. The paint on her vertical stabiliser marks her as the second fighter of her squadron.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The nuclear reactor makes the fighter extraordinarily heavy, and despite three powerful engines and an inverse-gull delta wing, the aircraft is most commonly launched by catapult systems, even on land. The indirect air cycle system limits radioactive pollution of the surrounding material and the cockpit is only lightly shielded. Although the reactor saves many thousands of tonnes of jet fuel over the course of its lifetime, day-to-day operations of any carrier fighter require manoeuvrability and reliability. To save weight, the Cosmojet carries only enough chemical fuel for controlled descent using the auxiliary lightweight chemical combustion engine. Her two auxiliary exhausts swivel with the primary flaps, allowing the heavy jet to slow for approach. The iconic inverse-gull wing reduces the strain on landing gear and saves weight by removing the need for fortified (and heavy) landing gear. It also allows for heavy torpedoes to be mounted on the fuselage, which are designed primarily for use against nuclear submarines.</p>
<p>The Cosmojet uses a 2.5MW air-cooled molten salt reactor with an indirect air cycle system powering one chemical-reactor hybrid electric turbofan and two auxiliary segregated turbofans mounted in the wings. The reactor heats liquid metal, which is circulated in radiators by turbopumps and heats air drawn in through the wing and forward intakes. The air is then pumped back into the engines and expelled through one of three exhausts at the rear of the aircraft. In addition, the Cosmojet uses a small chemical combustion engine for take-off and landing and for auxiliary power in the event of reactor malfunction or the EMP effects of a nuclear weapon. The prohibitively strict weight limit means that the Cosmojet only carries enough fuel for take-off and landing.</p>
<p>Vekllei employs nearly 4,000 Cosmojet-series fighters today. All of them are used as supersonic air-superiority fighters. As an island nation with a defensive military posture and a fear of nuclear war, this enormous expenditure is supposed to show results in a global nuclear exchange, much of which will still be delivered by supersonic jet bombers.</p>
<p>If you have any questions or want to interrogate my (limited) aircraft knowledge, go ham! You can read more about Vekllei at <a href="https://www.vekllei.city">www.vekllei.city</a> or clicking on my profile and sorting by posts!</p>
<p>Thanks for reading</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Metro Days</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/metro-days/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/metro-days/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Metro Days.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/metrodays.jpg"/> <p>Metro Days.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Flower Tundra</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/flower-tundra/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/flower-tundra/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The two girls caught a train from school to the terminus, and then a rural line as far as it would take them out of the city. They had walked the granite shoulder of a mountain range for most of the afternoon, carrying only a few mouthfuls of provisions between them. They were both dressed in winter uniforms for the summer hike. The sea air gathered cold and malevolence as it escaped up the range of peaks that chased Vekllei Proper.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/flowertundra.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p>The two girls caught a train from school to the terminus, and then a rural line as far as it would take them out of the city. They had walked the granite shoulder of a mountain range for most of the afternoon, carrying only a few mouthfuls of provisions between them. They were both dressed in winter uniforms for the summer hike. The sea air gathered cold and malevolence as it escaped up the range of peaks that chased Vekllei Proper. The girls walked as far as they could with a view of the city abreast before mounting the peak and descending into the flowery plateau beyond the city centre. The path gave way to basalt drumlins and soft flower-tundra. The horizon was marked by volcanic imperfections, and framed a stretch of colour entirely untouched. For only a few hour’s ride from the city, and a handful of foodstuffs acquired from the small village the train terminated in, they had disembarked from civilisation entirely and entered the world of the spirits.</p>
<p>The flower-tundra is like mania; it overwhelms the soul in great colour and ancient presence. Centuries collapse, bloodlines congeal, and suddenly there is a hair between you and your forefathers.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://vekllei.city/2018/12/10/the-flower-tundra/">Read more at vekllei.city</a>.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not actually all wank, just a conversation between girls. I&rsquo;m doing words-a-day at the moment so I&rsquo;ll update the page in the following days as the scene completes. For now I&rsquo;m pretty happy where it ends.</p>
<p>As always, let me know if you have any questions or comments.</p>
<p>Thanks everyone.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rural Trains</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/rural-trains/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/rural-trains/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[I caught a train out of Tokyo as far as it would go, and I ended up on a little platform in the mountains. Nice place.
Vekllei has a lot of mountains and a lot of trains.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/ruraltrains.jpg"/> <p>I caught a train out of Tokyo as far as it would go, and I ended up on a little platform in the mountains. Nice place.</p>
<p>Vekllei has a lot of mountains and a lot of trains.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Koka parks &amp; municipal recreation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/koka-parks/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/koka-parks/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Between the atomic fire that ruined the city, and the death of the king, there was a time when the city of Vekllei once resembled its lifeless lava fields to the North. In the communities that gathered themselves in the shadow of holocaust, common agriculture like fruits and berries returned to the city in what they call koka parkland.
Koka is the Vekllei word for forest (ka), combined with a prefixtual particle that ‘industrialises’ it.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/kokaparks.jpg"/> <p><strong>Between the atomic fire that ruined the city</strong>, and the death of the king, there was a time when the city of Vekllei once resembled its lifeless lava fields to the North. In the communities that gathered themselves in the shadow of holocaust, common agriculture like fruits and berries returned to the city in what they call <em>koka</em> parkland.</p>
<p><em>Koka</em> is the Vekllei word for forest (<em>ka</em>), combined with a prefixtual particle that ‘industrialises’ it. It is usually translated as ‘municipal forest’, and was designed for and continues to serve two purposes in the city today.</p>
<p>The first is that consumable raw agricultural products, like fruits, nuts and berries, were valuable commodity in the starving post-war neighbourhoods that emerged in the ruins of the old city. These foods were combined with bread and meat, staples of the Vekllei diet, to give flavour in a country without easy access to spices and salt. By integrating them into common gardens, the people of Vekllei returned the production of food into a common, shared space that predicated the wider decommodification of the country. To this day, very little fruit is distributed through grocers; it is grown freely and year-round in <em>koka</em> parks in the city.</p>
<p>The second is that <em>Upen,</em> the animistic spiritualism that guides most of Vekllei culture, blossomed in the ashes of the monarchy and revived a real desire to desegregate spirits from urban life. The construction of massive <em>koka</em> parks, filled with food and old trees and free-flowing water, offered an apology to the spirits driven out by industry and agriculture, and invited them to return to human settlement as fellow custodians of the earth. Many <em>koka</em> parks house temples for dialogue with spirits and sprites, and they bless the surrounding neighbourhoods.</p>
<p>To step into a <em>koka</em> park is to disappear from the urban world. Birds warble, leaves whisper to themselves and water trickles sweetly through bright mosses. The largest parks hide the surrounding skyline entirely, and disappear tourists for hours at a time, only to spit them out hours later, confused and exhausted. Any piece of infrastructure, any human touch, is strangled with banners and wires suspending pennants. In keeping with Vekllei Semaphore, a separate language from <em>upotenne</em> and written Vekllei, the flags themselves speak to visitors through their colour, direction and shape. The effect of being swallowed by a <em>koka</em> park is detoxifying and luxurious — and by the time your lunch break has ended, you are fed and at peace.</p>
<p>-&ndash;</p>
<p><em>If you have any questions, let me know!</em> You can read more about Koka parks and learn all about Vekllei at <a href="https://www.millmint.net">www.vekllei.city</a>, which has just been redesigned and I think it looks pretty amazing.</p>
<p><strong>Post Scriptum</strong>: The figure in this girl, Tzipora Desmoines, is in her second week in Vekllei in this picture. Timid and isolated through her sudden immigration, she makes her way through a koka park with a guide she can&rsquo;t read, fretting about which tram she has to get back home.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The guilt dies with her</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/guilt/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/guilt/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Some years ago, she was in the desert. At the time she had just fallen out with her lover, and their friends had sided with him. The reasons why they had sided with him seemed to matter less and less as time wore on — they might have always liked him better.
They were self-styled anarchists waging war against the Indian Springs Sheriff’s Department, who operated one of the larger camps north of Las Vegas.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/guilt.jpg"/> <p>Some years ago, she was in the desert. At the time she had just fallen out with her lover, and their friends had sided with him. The reasons why they had sided with him seemed to matter less and less as time wore on —  they might have always liked him better.</p>
<p>They were self-styled anarchists waging war against the Indian Springs Sheriff’s Department, who operated one of the larger camps north of Las Vegas. Fashioning themselves as martyrs, they carried on in the spirit of Sacco and Vanzetti.</p>
<p>Tzipora had been growing tired of fighting. There had been an outbreak of botulism not far from where they were camped out, and she was worried she might catch it. She wouldn&rsquo;t survive it if she did, because her body was wasting as she slowly starved. The folks they used to steal from had fled the fighting.
Once her lover had left her, and her presence began to irritate the small group, she left one night and walked to the local Women’s Auxiliary, a barracks of women and girls supporting the marxist stooges in that part of Nevada. It was impressive to the fourteen year-old  —  the dusty desert outpost was flush with Soviet-made rifles and medicine, with rations aplenty. As she enlisted, she thought of her abandoned comrades. She was filled with anger and jealousy.</p>
<p>She told her garrison leader, a man with an accent from somewhere on the East Coast she couldn’t quite place, about how she and her skilled anarchist friends had been at waging guerilla war against the secessionists. Then, in an act of spite, she mentioned that her old comrades had stolen supplies from an Worker&rsquo;s Reunification Party camp. Perhaps, in her silly little head, she had wanted to see them brought under control and disciplined, and she would finally be satisfied after their cruel words and coldness.</p>
<p>Michael and Lenny, two friends, leaders, and one an ex-lover, were picked up by a WRP patrol and shot in the head in their prison cells. The KGB, which was supporting the WRP at that time, gathered up the rest of the anarchists, six in all, and sent them to a detention camp in Utah. Tzipora would not see any of them again.</p>
<p>The same day she found this out, she was singled out at morning assembly and awarded for her efforts in front of the entire Women’s Auxiliary. When she returned to her bunk, she found a hundred pairs of eyes on her, and her meager possessions thrown onto the floor. She slept outside as a traitor that night, and would leave soon after.</p>
<p>Blood does not wash off her hands. The shock of her childish mistake gave way to extraordinary self-hate, and some sixty years later she is still coloured by queasy, anxious guilt.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy Summer Everyone</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/summer/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/summer/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[In Down Under it&rsquo;s coming around summer, and things are heating up. It&rsquo;s not my fault Yanks broke the northern hemisphere and made the weather go wrong.
Vekllei gets warm in the summer, reaching heights of 30C occasionally. For a variety of reasons. A city of gardens and flowerbeds (the most flowers per capita in the world, actually), apartment dwellers take turns watering their local gardens and clearing weeds. Most parks have utility as herb or fruit gardens, and so maintenance of those plants in summer is important.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/summer.jpg"/> <p>In Down Under it&rsquo;s coming around summer, and things are heating up. It&rsquo;s not my fault Yanks broke the northern hemisphere and made the weather go wrong.</p>
<p>Vekllei gets warm in the summer, reaching heights of 30C occasionally. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/90f56z/hot_summer_rain_on_a_beach_of_black_sand_iceland/">For a variety of reasons</a>. A city of gardens and flowerbeds (the most flowers per capita in the world, actually), apartment dwellers take turns watering their local gardens and clearing weeds. Most parks have utility as herb or fruit gardens, and so maintenance of those plants in summer is important.</p>
<p>And to all the new folks following me, cheers! I post to my profile every so often, usually snapshots of domestic life or Tzipora that I can&rsquo;t crowbar into a r/worldbuilding format. Posting to that sub affects what kind of content you make, and I like making lots of different types of content, so a lot of different things end up here.</p>
<p>Thanks everyone</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Talking about Girl Scouts and Child Soldiers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/scout/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/scout/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[About half of Vekllei kids go through the &lsquo;Blossom&rsquo; network of youth orgs at some point in their lives. Yeah, youth groups are popular nowadays. The Boy Scouts and Girl Guides of the United States are as mandatory as schooling in some states, and various Red Pioneers around the world test orthodoxy in Soviet and Red Chinese children.
The Girl Guides of the U.S. now boast catalogues of several hundred pages, selling thousands of Guides-branded items to their own members and Guide-friendly suburbs.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/scout.jpg"/> <p><strong>About half of Vekllei kids</strong> go through the &lsquo;Blossom&rsquo; network of youth orgs at some point in their lives. Yeah, youth groups are popular nowadays. The Boy Scouts and Girl Guides of the United States are as mandatory as schooling in some states, and various Red Pioneers around the world test orthodoxy in Soviet and Red Chinese children.</p>
<p>The Girl Guides of the U.S. now boast catalogues of several hundred pages, selling thousands of Guides-branded items to their own members and Guide-friendly suburbs. Outwardly, the cartoons of Heinz and Carpenter (both of <em>Western Family</em> <em>Magazine</em> fame) might show off Guides assembling tents in jigger jackets and bright sashes, but they always seemed to neglect the impoverished girls priced out of the Guides organisation, like was so common at the time. There were a lot of poor girls in America by 2083.</p>
<p>Things are not much better for the Boy Scouts, who are only a few lethal armaments away from becoming paramilitary. They worship the flag and guard America’s character. Following the catastrophic Sino-American nuclear exchange, the Boy Scouts were enlisted in Civil Defense, an order that would kill many times more boys than the bombs ever did. You had kids being killed protecting grocers in food riots, and disappearing en masse as the cities collapsed. It was absurd.</p>
<p>So in the search for an analogue to Vekllei’s Blossoms, do we have any choice but to look to the Pioneers of those miserable countries of the East? After all, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/9dikf6/shot_like_a_dog_in_a_supermarket_the_vekllei/e5hwuay/?context=3">Vekllei has no money to spend</a>, and no flag to worship (the domestic standard is a simple red rectangle, the international standard is decorated). Perhaps the Blossoms, a relatively decentralised organisation for a youth group, has no real comparison in the world today.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Boys and girls of schooling age can join unisex troops</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(the literal translation of the word is ‘barracks’, but in Vekllei it lacks the military connotation)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>and they will receive a uniform of wool, lisle cotton and nylon blended advanced fabrics. On their person they carry binoculars, twine, and tools of various utility. On hikes they often carry air rifles for small game hunts; most every Blossom will learn the basics of gun safety and shooting at some point.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The real emphasis of the Blossom network <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/9snaar/the_stewards_of_the_earth/">is in the naturalist spiritualism of the country, or Upen</a>. Blossoms are taught about agriculture, food production and consumption in their society. Most troops enforce ‘catch-kill’ rules: if a troop member wants to eat meat, they should kill, skin, and clean the animal to illustrate the relationship between consumption and exploitation. Environmentalism in the organisation is broad and humancentric. Although environmental science and the geology of the country is taught, most camps place emphasis on rural infrastructure, <em>roupoismentet</em> (or &rsquo;local living&rsquo;, a word for agrarian communities), and the place of spirits in Vekllei’s domestic affairs. This is not to portray Vekllei as an overly vegetarian or sentimental country &ndash; just that Upen is a part of life for Vekllei children, and contributes to their understanding of the world.</p>
<p>Many Blossoms pursue employment in the Armed Forces upon leaving school, as a natural extension of the organised lifestyle of a youth org. This is not to say that life in the Blossoms is particularly militaristic &ndash; Vekllei does not actually have professional culture, despite hierarchies, and so life in the Blossoms is casual fair, and like the rest of the country, largely individualistic and self-satisfying. Boys and girls go on camps, eat food out of a can, sleep under the stars, collect badges, fall in and out of puppy love, learn to assemble a rifle, meet wild animals, etc.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Tzipora perches on a tree stump as her friend rushes to steady the camera. She surveys her domain. The flower-tundra from here to Montre was uninhabited. Society had been stripped away and they were fellow creatures of the forest. Her friend places the plaque with her name and year on it at the foot of the stump, and Tzipora adopts a masculine pose typical of her.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I’m still fleshing out the ideas in this post, so let me know if you have any questions. Like always, you can sort my profile by posts for more info. You can read more about the project at <a href="http://www.vekllei.city/">www.vekllei.city</a>, although that website is still a work in progress. It’ll do for now.</p>
<p><strong>This is a quick reupload:</strong> the first image had a great big bloody line through it, and I just couldn&rsquo;t unsee it. <a href="https://vekllei.city/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/IMG_0549.png">This is what it looked like. LOOK AT IT. IT&rsquo;S SO OBVIOUS ONCE YOU SEE IT.</a> Sorry folks.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Stewards of the Earth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/stewards/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/stewards/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Upen is the animistic religion of Vekllei. It doesn&rsquo;t have priests, but it has ceremony, and it shapes every part of the country today. From apartment cooperatives to the types of cotton used in clothing, Upen has extraordinary reach for an ostensibly agnostic and secular country.
It works out that way because Upen is not an organised religion, and resembles more closely a collective spiritualism with supernatural beliefs. It is not incompatible with theism, a quirk we&rsquo;ll explore below, but it manifests outside of churches in the passing of seasons, code of dress and rural egalitarianism.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/spiritstewards.jpg"/> <p><em>Upen</em> is the animistic religion of Vekllei. It doesn&rsquo;t have priests, but it has ceremony, and it shapes every part of the country today. From apartment cooperatives to the types of cotton used in clothing, <em>Upen</em> has extraordinary reach for an ostensibly agnostic and secular country.</p>
<p>It works out that way because Upen is not an organised religion, and resembles more closely a collective spiritualism with supernatural beliefs. It is not incompatible with theism, a quirk we&rsquo;ll explore below, but it manifests outside of churches in the passing of seasons, code of dress and rural egalitarianism.</p>
<p>How exactly a person goes about their animism is their business, and depends on personal faith. Most Vekllei people are atheistic and believe there is another plane of existence which houses their ancestors, spirits, sprites, and demons. This is reflected in how they see the world:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>​Upen, as atheistic and animistic, shelters the landscape from becoming ‘simply nature’, as it does when viewed as a product of a monotheistic creator god. To these people, agnostic of &rsquo;landscape&rsquo;, nature is not ‘simply nature’; it is a spiritual vessel in itself, inalienable and inextricably linked to human purpose and satisfaction. Industry is divorced from the whole concept; it is a country of forest commons, collective stewardship, and volcanic unrest.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It is not always easy to reconcile the basic assumptions Upen makes about the world. Viewed through Tzipora’s nonpracticing Roman Catholic lens, the mess of her religious beliefs look something like this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>There is a single creator God</strong>, who took on man’s flesh as Christ. He</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(and in her mind, it is most certainly a He)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>is not omnibenevolent or even totally omniscient. Humans, as weak and mortal, must obey Him until they have the power to usurp Him. He is a guiding force of the world. Spirits, as physical manifestations of the landscape, are fellow travelers on this planet and should always be treated with respect, as humans are guests. With a fragile, physical form, it is a uniquely human burden to cultivate and protect the land, and actualise their purpose as a species.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, to dissect her version of Upen, we have here four (five) different characters in the spiritual world:</p>
<p>First are <em>spirits</em> and <em>sprites</em>, which are the souls and fabric of the forests and hills. They are as old as the Earth itself and predate humans by billions of years, a fact that seems implied when you are joined in physical presence with them. They treasure, and indeed, embody the Earth and can reap wealth or chaos among us. Spirits take many forms, sometimes anthropomorphic, sometimes only partially corporeal. This one here has collected jewellery, gold, and peratin leaves, as they are fiercely attracted to precious metals. Just as we dress up for them, peaceful spirits will dress up for us and mimic parts of our bodies. <em>Sprites</em> (as opposed to spirits) are smaller, more emotional, and are fragments of reproduction &ndash; think of them like spores of ferns, of the pollen of flowers. You can see a small one floating beside the spirit.</p>
<p><em>Christ</em> was the first and only time that God is recorded to have walked among the living. He might visit the spirit world often; Tzipora wouldn’t know. As a creator and guide for humans, He was born as a human and taught ways to live well. Humanity is very young and is still learning to live on the Earth. The ritual of communion is a way of reminding us that We are in His image, and We are unworthy. He died for our sins; sins Tzipora is very sure will eventually usurp Him altogether in whatever deicidal sci-fi utopia she&rsquo;s got going on in her head.</p>
<p>Then, there are <em>humans</em> themselves. Here, Tzipora is in full costume designed for religious ceremony to talk to spirits. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/8lqzuj/the_dress_code_for_talking_to_spirits/">You can read more about the costume here</a>. She might ask for rains, or a long summer, or for the forest to return a missing child. Food offerings are presented. She forms a whole rune with her body as part of <em>Upotenne</em>, or the language of spirits. <em>Upotenne</em> itself is an ancient type of <em>Potenne</em>, which is modern Vekllei sign language. This is a calming rune, indicating maternal affection, and you can see the written hieroglyph appears visually similar to the pose.</p>
<p>Finally, demons walk the Earth and can manifest in many different ways. This one has taken the form of a girl, and carries the severed head of a goat. Its eyelids are painted with ritualistic eyes in mockery of proper funeral rites. They often wander aimlessly through uninhabited areas, as noise in intolerable to most demons. They are mysterious creatures, and their purpose is unknown. They come from the place spirits go to die. Like apex predators, they wander aimlessly and without purpose, hunting and feeding at random. They are feeble in physical forms, with one exception: they can form physical runes quickly and maliciously. The one cast here is an omen of suffering (translated literally as &lsquo;harpoiseanin&rsquo;, or overpowering the body with its own stomach acids). In Vekllei, a &lsquo;demon&rsquo; is any biplanar or otherwise supernatural creature that takes corporeal form and harms folk directly. Spirits can maim and kill, but only through the forces of nature &ndash; a demon attacks physically. There are many types of demons, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/97sckc/old_dead_demons_still_wander_the_countryside/">and you can read more about them here</a>.</p>
<p>If you have any questions about Upen, just ask. You can read more about Vekllei by clicking on my profile or visiting <a href="http://www.vekllei.city/">www.vekllei.city</a>! Thanks for stopping by!</p>
<p>-&ndash;</p>
<p><strong>Post scriptum</strong>: Upen is also the reason Vekllei does not recognise either private or public property, and was actually the inspiration for making this post. Although many people exert &lsquo;ownership&rsquo;, the concept of property as something other than &rsquo;nature&rsquo; is not recognised, and so society in Vekllei remains thoroughly decommodified. Looking at Vekllei through the lens of Upen, it becomes clear that a moneyless domestic economy is not the product of grand secular collectivist ideals but a natural extension of egalitarian environmentalism; essentially urbanised agrarian socialism.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Let’s look at military fashion, because why not?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/military-fashion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/military-fashion/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Unlike the United States and Western Europe, the ‘teen-ager’ has not been discovered in Vekllei. To be pedantic, they do technically exist — their people do indeed enter a transitory stage between childhood and adulthood, as far as anyone can tell — but they do not exist as a separate cultural identity. The teen-age person in Vekllei is immersed in adult economic and social relationships, and so they have no real cultural material of their own.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/militaryfashion.jpg"/> <p><strong>Unlike the United States and Western Europe, the ‘teen-ager’ has not been discovered in Vekllei.</strong> To be pedantic, they do technically exist  —  their people do indeed enter a transitory stage between childhood and adulthood, as far as anyone can tell —  but they do not exist as a separate cultural identity. The teen-age person in Vekllei is immersed in adult economic and social relationships, and so they have no real cultural material of their own. They listen to the music of their parents, raise younger siblings, and generally marry young. I could go on for a while about things Vekllei has not ‘discovered’ (read: commodified through modernity); landscape, childhood, history, etc. But let’s stick with teen-agers for now.</p>
<p>By sexual maturation, a Vekllei person has essentially transitioned to young-adulthood and submerged themselves in the productive relations of the adult age; they often leave school for work, they quickly drift to mature, independent relationships with parents, and otherwise carve out lives in their wondrous country. All of this is not to say that the country lacks materials aimed at young people entirely  —  you can’t fit a middle-aged woman into a sixteen-year-old’s dress, no matter how much she might try  —  but I am simply trying to establish an understanding that folk here do not enjoy the glamour (or what was once glamour) of American teen-agers, with sock-hops and convertible cars and magazines.</p>
<p>Tangentially related, as Vekllei society has militarised in the face of nuclear war, so too has fashion adopted a bayonet’s edge. In womens fashion, we’re seeing the reemergence of ‘dazzle’ camouflage in imitation of her great capital ships. Jackets, skirts, jewellery, hats, are all being manufactured in flavours of it, and are often <em>touspian</em> or ‘pastelised’ into designs and colours considered more feminine. In men, military caps and ties are popular in semiformal social outfits, and often complement suits. The country is already heavily uniformed in the workplace, and has a passion for badges and armbands and decorative knick-knacks, and so a lot of these authoritative trinkets are trickling into everyday fashion.</p>
<p>It’s easy to despair at the militarisation of society, and a warhawk fashion culture, but it could also be seen as a critical modernist/postmodern attack on the traditional institutions that are so integral to life and culture in Vekllei society. In sharp dresses women wear armbands embroidered with brands of soup, men wear faux-military badges displaying ridiculous illustrations  —  while not outright political perhaps, they are certainly appropriating the imagery of war and domesticating it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Tzipora here is sixteen, waiting for a first date, and patterned with the dazzle of the <em>Sundress</em> nuclear-equipped capital ship.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I haven’t really felt out my thoughts fully on the subject of teen-age life and its introduction to Western society, so if ya got any ideas leave a comment. I’m also building a website, <a href="http://www.vekllei.city/">www.vekllei.city</a>, but it’s a bit shit at the moment. I’m slowly cementing its style and turning it into a proper wiki, so check back soon!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Collapse of the South</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/collapse/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/collapse/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[In October of 2074, the Ford Motor Company was embroiled in political catastrophe after Vermont senator Henry Walsh accused unionism in its East-Coast plants of traitorism by allowing foreign spies to acquire jobs in the Company. Whether the spies were Soviet or Chinese changed several times in Walsh’s accusations, but the claims themselves were not entirely unfounded. An investigation by the FBI received by congress found that several high-ranking Auto Workers Union members in Ford plants had connections to communist organisations, which were then discovered to have smuggled foreign agents into the country.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/southerncollapse.jpg"/> <p><strong>In October of 2074</strong>, the Ford Motor Company was embroiled in political catastrophe after Vermont senator Henry Walsh accused unionism in its East-Coast plants of traitorism by allowing foreign spies to acquire jobs in the Company. Whether the spies were Soviet or Chinese changed several times in Walsh’s accusations, but the claims themselves were not entirely unfounded. An investigation by the FBI received by congress found that several high-ranking Auto Workers Union members in Ford plants had connections to communist organisations, which were then discovered to have smuggled foreign agents into the country.</p>
<p>The recognition of Ford as a traitorous company, combined with an ailing combustion-engine automobile catalogue, sank the company into receivership and then bankruptcy. In a few short weeks, the titan of American industry, and the grandfather of mass-production, had ceased to exist except in name (which was acquired by Chrysler and branded tokenistically on several models of Chrysler vehicles).</p>
<p>Forty-thousand jobs disappeared by the new year. The economy was bad and the plants of the company were unsold and were bleached by the sun. The Southern states, which had served as primary hubs of the auto industry after Detroit’s collapse a decade before, saw unemployment jump ten percent. Is it any surprise what followed?</p>
<p>It would be misleading to categorise everything that has happened since as a consequence of the Ford Motor Company’s collapse, but in the minds of most Americans  —  and most importantly, blue-collar men of the Southern States  —  it was the beginning of the end for the Union, and the secession of the Southern States from the United States four years later had rolled off the back of the economic collapse spurred by Ford.</p>
<p>Hungry and anguished by economic collapse, and increasing fragmentation of Southern culture as cities, companies and universities diversified culturally, Southerners found conspiracy in many sectors of modern American life. There were Jews, who controlled big money in the East Coast cities and relished the South&rsquo;s failures. There were capitalists, who were often conflated with Jews as enemies of the noble small business community. There was the Federal Government itself, and a cabal of socialists, communists and leftists who had wrought their jealousy upon the south. And there were blacks and hispanics, who were brothers in victimhood or conspirators depending on what county you were in.</p>
<p>Although the South would gain some measure of independence after the heat of the fighting had tapered out, the Southern States would never fully recover, and both the secessionist and Union states continued to maintain a single U.S. military.</p>
<p><em>If you have any questions, let me know!</em> You can read more about the world of Vekllei by clicking on my profile, or visiting <a href="http://www.vekllei.city">www.vekllei.city</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>real sadboi posting hours</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sadboi/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sadboi/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Coming up on 2am here in East Australia. Had a rough day at work. Feeling pretty isolated and my other job starts in a few hours. I don’t know if it’s intrusive thoughts from OCD or just something everyone has, but four or five times a day I’ll have some sort of regret pop right into my head. I can’t seem to move on from much. Tzipora’s the same. She’s probably thinking about physical education from early that day.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/sadboi.jpg"/> <p>Coming up on 2am here in East Australia. Had a rough day at work. Feeling pretty isolated and my other job starts in a few hours. I don’t know if it’s intrusive thoughts from OCD or just something everyone has, but four or five times a day I’ll have some sort of regret pop right into my head. I can’t seem to move on from much. Tzipora’s the same. She’s probably thinking about physical education from early that day. She’s thinking about faking a sick note so she doesn’t have to do it anymore. She cringes and curses under her breath and then the memory passes.</p>
<p>I like drawing her at home, but the proportion’s all shot to shit and it took way too long for such a simple sketch. Doesn’t matter though, it turned out pretty close to how I wanted.</p>
<p>You got any similar experiences or anything, feel free to comment.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>School uniforms for girls</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/old-uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/old-uniforms/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[From preschool to university and beyond, all students wear a variant of the same uniform. The kindergartners may not wear a full gi and camisole pinafore, but the basic ensemble is still there. This is the girl’s one, and it’s much more elaborate than the boy’s uniform.
Year-round, all students wear a school armband with their year and class embroidered on it and a badge of education, which is pinned to the top button.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/olduniforms.jpg"/> <p>From preschool to university and beyond, all students wear a variant of the same uniform. The kindergartners may not wear a full <em>gi</em> and camisole pinafore, but the basic ensemble is still there. This is the girl’s one, and it’s much more elaborate than the boy’s uniform.</p>
<p>Year-round, all students wear a <strong>school armband</strong> with their year and class embroidered on it and a <strong>badge of education</strong>, which is pinned to the top button. Girls wear a selection of other traditional items.</p>
<p>The <strong>gi</strong> is a ceremonial quarter-pleat worn by schoolgirls and the wider public generally. It is usually embroidered for the festival month it was made in, and many Vekllei girls have several gi for different celebratory months (birth month, blood month, shipbuilder’s month, etc). In summer it is also common to wear a <strong>sun petticoat</strong>, a delicate lace petticoat worn exposed beneath the hem of the skirt. These are often handmade. Traditionally hair is pulled into a <strong>fountain hairpiece</strong> if it is long enough, and can accompany <strong>temple hairpieces</strong> as well. These hairstyles trace back to the spirit priestesses and have become fashionable again.</p>
<p>In winter, both boys and girls wear a <strong>half cape</strong> for Vekllei’s miserable winter months. These are usually wool and lined with insulating materials. Girls also wear a <strong>camisole pinafore</strong>, which is essentially a traditional girl’s camisole that is tucked into the skirt to make a dress for the winter months.</p>
<p>Armbands, badges, half capes and gi are worn in many other industries as well, since nearly every company employs a uniformed staff. It is common for a girl to hold a gi from her middle-school years, where it is oversized and clumsy, all the way to graduation and then employment.</p>
<p>For those wondering what happens to valuable metals and gemstones in a moneyless society like Vekllei, you simply have to look a little closer  —  they are often sewn into badges and ceremonial clothes. Stripped of their commodity, they have become precious and sacred items that bejewel important objects. The badge of education, for example, contains a ruby in its heart.</p>
<p>None of this stops roughhousing, and Tzipora’s just beat the shit out of a girl who called her a lesbian.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Some notes on the end of the world</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/end-game/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/end-game/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[A single hiss, the heavy door rolls back, and it derails into sandbags. A gas piston grinds, an engine ignites, and a roar sends flames pouring fifty feet high out of the silo as a sleek missile emerges and climbs towards hunting altitude.
This missile will strike Lanzhou, China. The larger cities, swollen with people, are protected by antimissile laser batteries. But China is very big, and there are not enough lasers, nor enough power, to shield the entire country from missiles.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/endgame.jpg"/> <p>A single hiss, the heavy door rolls back, and it derails into sandbags. A gas piston grinds, an engine ignites, and a roar sends flames pouring fifty feet high out of the silo as a sleek missile emerges and climbs towards hunting altitude.</p>
<p><strong>This missile will strike Lanzhou, China</strong>. The larger cities, swollen with people, are protected by antimissile laser batteries. But China is very big, and there are not enough lasers, nor enough power, to shield the entire country from missiles. This missile will extinguish 42,000 people instantly, in a ball of hot fire, and kill anywhere from 250-750,000 moments after as the city is ripped up like paper. Along with other missiles from the U.S., Vekllei, and Europe, this missile will irradiate the Yangtze and set fire to great swaths of farmland. Lanzhou will be a crater, her neighbouring villages will be on fire, and the scraps of her people that survive will drift elsewhere, this land scorched. Famine will set in, radiation will poison her children and ensure that future generations living in the great land that was once China will be primitive and factional for hundreds of years.</p>
<p>The Chinese, too, will do good work destroying America. Where missiles are zapped out of the sky, bombs are sent into freefall from jets, and they erase the heart and culture of American cities and industry.</p>
<p>By the end of it, three hours later, 1.4 billion people will be dead or taken ill, ash will rain from the sky as huge fragments of earth cycle across the Northern Hemisphere’s atmosphere, and the thyroids of the global youth will get to work soaking up radiation in the vast wastes of North America and East Asia.</p>
<p>Vekllei, as it had always known it would, emerged flustered and unharmed. It had lost 23,000 people to bombs, one in the city and one near Montre, but her food stock was secure, her population was underground, and so her diplomats set to work resuscitating the U.N. and organising relief to the globe. Such remarkable attempts to save face, hands still warm with Chinese blood.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>And future generations would condemn the use of missiles in the last great war of the 21st century — from the defunct U.S., from defunct Red China and the Warsaw Pact, and especially from Vekllei — but it made no difference to how things played out. With one stroke of a match, the world’s great civilisations had collapsed and petticoat society was on that global horizon. Like how Vekllei had known it would be, and like how it was meant to be.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Hey folks, let me know if you have any questions about this or anything else! Cheers.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>KID COMIX</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/comix/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/comix/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[There are some comics that Vekllei syndicates just won’t publish. KID Magazine, or KID Comix ran for nearly a century. It was picked up and dropped by dozens of anonymous artists, writers and editors, all operating under nonsense pseudonyms — Red, Squick, Failson and Daddy Fun were some of the longest-serving. It would go out of print for years, until some contributing artist would revive the mailing list and recruit new editors and writers.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/comix.jpg"/> <p><strong>There are some comics that Vekllei syndicates just won’t publish</strong>. <em>KID Magazine</em>, or <em>KID Comix</em> ran for nearly a century. It was picked up and dropped by dozens of anonymous artists, writers and editors, all operating under nonsense pseudonyms  —  Red, Squick, Failson and Daddy Fun were some of the longest-serving. It would go out of print for years, until some contributing artist would revive the mailing list and recruit new editors and writers. Not even editors knew the names of their team  —  and so <em>KID</em> became a rag-tag, pornographic, angry, satire comic published anonymously anywhere from biannually to a dozen times a year and distributed through universities, underground comics syndicates and workplaces. A single copy might be repressed dozens of times and redistributed further, making original copies collector’s items.</p>
<p><em>Issue 36</em> blasted Vekllei munitions trade with the United States, which was by this point gripped by economic collapse as the industrial centres of the South were levelled by poverty and fighting.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The comic is not subtle: a stereotypical Vekllei girl complete with <em>gi</em> and fountain hairpiece offers an artillery shell to a deformed pigman soldier carrying the U.S. flag and an atom bomb. The girl wears the national flower on her apron. The pigman sits atop a throne of food and corpses, as he himself decomposes. Subtitled in English by Squick: “Just let the fucker DIE”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The article inside parodied the sitting U.S. President, W. E. White, using Vekllei munitions as sex toys before one of them detonates and he flies off into the moon.</p>
<p>Such was the tone of the magazine, one of the most important examples of underground comix culture in the world and a landmark training ground for successful comix artists.</p>
<p>Post scriptum: Tzipora was introduced to <em>KID</em> through a contributing writer at her university. As a fluent English speaker she served for some time as <em>KID</em>’s first and only English editor, and would later contribute both art and articles to the magazine.</p>
<p><em>Let me know if you have any questions!</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Masculinity &amp; Fatherhood in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/masculinity/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/masculinity/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Just a few notes on what it means to be a man in Vekllei.
Vekllei is a country at odds with itself. On one hand, it is universal in its politics and fundamentally internationalist; on the other it is a deeply traditional country that values bloodlines and heritage. It is a secular democracy that regularly alludes to monarchy in its rituals and symbolism. It is a culture that is so casual it offends foreign visitors while retaining strict codes of conduct.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/masculinity.jpg"/> <p>Just a few notes on what it means to be a man in Vekllei.</p>
<p><strong>Vekllei is a country at odds with itself</strong>. On one hand, it is universal in its politics and fundamentally internationalist; on the other it is a deeply traditional country that values bloodlines and heritage. It is a secular democracy that regularly alludes to monarchy in its rituals and symbolism. It is a culture that is so casual it offends foreign visitors while retaining strict codes of conduct.</p>
<p>Vekllei is unique in that it is one of few Western countries with strong matriarchal tendencies. As part of <em>petticoat feminism</em>, it explicitly states as such: the default disposition of the human race is <strong>‘female’</strong>. That is not to say that men are robbed of masculinity or women are stripped of their femininity  —  both roles in Vekllei society have pervasive roles and stereotypes, and are lived out every day by millions of people. Instead, it means that over the course of hundreds of years, and the inevitable triumph of Vekllei over whatever those years will bring, ‘man’ as a concept will cease to exist. After all, femininity has nearly absorbed all masculine traits in Vekllei already  —  warrior culture, casual mateship, profanity and drinking, etc. Petticoat feminism, and by some extent petticoat socialism, understand masculine figures as an economic and social product of a previous age, and consequently, to co-opt some business newspaper slogan, “<em>the future is female</em>”. As the economy is revolutionised, and the country is rebuilt over and over again, so too will it leave behind the economic products of “old society”, a phrase that in Vekllei has very specific connotations (namely, the years of monarchy followed by authoritarianism).</p>
<p><strong>Tzipora’s father is a man’s man</strong>. He is a product of a dying generation. He wears his pants too high, the fit of his suits are loose, and he has spent his life in authority, surrounded by critical decisions that require his attention. Yet even he carries in his heart petticoat culture  —  he has raised two daughters, and they have ‘feminised’ him, in a sense  —  not in a way that makes him ‘weak’ or ‘emasculate’, but in his ability to interact with wider petticoat society.</p>
<p>I’ll close with a letter from his oldest daughter, on the subject of Tzipora and her relationship with her dad:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>He’s a good father, and a good man  —  an excellent man, in his later years. He’s a hard worker and radiates masculine authority, like many of his generation, but he was also forced into progressivism by the fact that his entire family at the end of his life were women. A man like that can’t choose to be picky about what he does and doesn’t hear concerning the personal and biological intricacies of womanhood. And this girl, this little Montre chickette he is telephoning, was the worst of them all! Thank God he was an affectionate father to her, even more so than he was to me, because the things she would tell him about! Her suspected lesbianism, her flirtations with bolshevism, and that’s not to mention the difficulty she had making friends at school, a wound that she scarcely hid from him. Yes, this man was all she had! Girls like me, good blood daughters, we have our women. Zelda, bless her, had him. I ask my girlfriends to brush my hair to get the knots out  —  Zelda puts her hairbrush on his desk and waits patiently until he can’t ignore her anymore.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Please let me know if you have any questions.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Grocery Economy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/shot/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/shot/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[A fluorescent light burst on Thursday. She was stacking cans for a display. The girl was working alone that evening and leaving her mark everywhere — happy apple drawings, new posters, displays — she liked the job.
The light burst like a gunshot and she leapt to her feet. Down the aisle she saw herself, at the lowest point in her life, standing over an old friend. To say she had shot him would be misleading — she had executed him, point-blank.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/shot.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p><strong>A fluorescent light burst on Thursday</strong>. She was stacking cans for a display. The girl was working alone that evening and leaving her mark everywhere  —  happy apple drawings, new posters, displays  —  she liked the job.</p>
<p>The light burst like a gunshot and she leapt to her feet. Down the aisle she saw herself, at the lowest point in her life, standing over an old friend. To say she had shot him would be misleading  —  she had executed him, point-blank. He was bleeding into the sandwiches with flaps of skin stirring weakly on the back of his head.</p>
<p>The store evaporated and the girl was back in Cherry, Nevada. He was trying to leave in the middle of the night. She’d followed him and confronted him. She’d asked the same question over and over as she had held the gun out. ‘Are you going to the Soviets?’</p>
<p>He told her he was hoping to secure armaments for the Wolves, and that with clean clothes and Soviet support they could launch bigger things  —  better things. Ambushes, bombings, even assist the Militias in real rebellion.</p>
<p>He was lying, of course. He was going to the Soviets because the anarchists were all dead, and he would be too if he didn’t run. That was enough for her. She didn’t shoot him for lying. She shot him for desertion.</p>
<p>The memory had ruined her life, and here it was, triggered by one of so many things that reminded her of that time in the desert. When she was back in the supermarket, sweating like a pig, she picked up the can she’d dropped and went back to work.</p>
<p>It was all exaggerated in her head. The boy had covered half the aisle in blood! That wasn’t how the whole thing went down. In the desert she’d shot him from a few feet back, and there had been a red mist but it didn’t touch her. He didn’t splatter none. He went into the ground and bounced off it, kicking as his whole body went haywire, before he went still on the ground. The back of his head spurted once, like a man pissing nervous, and then it bubbled and trickled out of the hole in his head like a drinking fountain as he set to work emptying as many of his litres as he could manage before his organs died. The blood didn’t fucking shine on tiled floors, either. It soaked into the desert. When they moved him, a sweet rose of colour was in the heart of it, red in the sand, but the wide stain was damp and grey and innocent.</p>
<p>She didn’t sleep much that week, goes without saying.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>The following concerns Vekllei’s domestic economy, fair warning.</strong></p>
<p>Supermarkets are relatively rare in Vekllei, especially compared to the States. Like many command economies, Vekllei’s internal economy requires total employment. Supermarkets are too automated, and so distribution is usually decentralised among many smaller grocers that can be found on nearly every street. These are what we would consider private enterprises, although Vekllei does not make a distinction between public and private.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Senrouive</em> types of workplaces are distinct from <em>Venrouiva</em> as <em>private</em> or <em>personal</em> business. This is not the same as ‘private’ property, as we understand it. Vekllei does not actually make any distinction of property — everything belongs to the land, including the country. Vekllei does not use money, either. Instead, anything self-operating and nonessential to the operation of the country is <em>Senrouive</em>. Restaurants, cinemas, department stores, etc.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So despite the fact that Vekllei does not use money, grocers benefit from having first pick of goods. There are no real shortages of essential foods in Vekllei, but seasonal and otherwise special produce  —  like that made for festivals or imported from abroad  —  are often in short supply. If you like your food, being a grocer is a good place to start. Occasionally it can also be difficult to obtain special types of ordinary produce — flavoured ham or fruit yogurts, for example.</p>
<p>‘First pick’ is less a gift of the economy to Grocers than it is just a natural conclusion of Vekllei’s moneyless system. Tzipora works at only fourteen, not because she needs spending money or because she wants to climb a food-prep or managerial ladder, but because she’s bored and wearing an apron and badge gives her a small sense of importance, even if she only impresses the handful of regulars that stop by. There is no real value in professionalism in Vekllei, so work hours are very casual and many business close frequently for lunch, afternoon tea, and pre-closing celebration. Most shopkeeps will only give you a passing nod from behind from their paperback when you enter a store.</p>
<p>At first glance, Vekllei’s shelves look like that of any other Western country, but the actual purpose of advertising and posters are pure theatrics  —  they are superficial imitations of an American supermarket with all its colour and splendour  —  the entire purpose of advertising goods it so soak up work-hours of some marketing graduate on his way to bigger and better things. The labels on the cans are just labels.</p>
<p><em>If you have any questions, please ask! Back to effortposts for me.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>summer nerds reading comix</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/princes-of-the-earth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/princes-of-the-earth/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[nerds]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/nerds.jpg"/> <p>nerds</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>big mood right now</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/mood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/mood/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[That&rsquo;s how it goes sometimes.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/mood.jpg"/> <p>That&rsquo;s how it goes sometimes.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Constabulary</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/police-uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/police-uniforms/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Policing is always difficult in utopian planning. On one hand, utopia is inherently opposed to the idea of policing and the can of worms it brings — on the other, people need to feel safe and protected. That’s not something I’ll be talking about today.
The Vekllei Constabulary are the second largest policing body in the country, after conventional police.
Business and manufacturing are divided into two arenas in Vekllei:]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/policeuniforms.jpg"/> <p>Policing is always difficult in utopian planning. On one hand, utopia is inherently opposed to the idea of policing and the can of worms it brings  —  on the other, people need to feel safe and protected. That’s not something I’ll be talking about today.</p>
<p>The Vekllei Constabulary are the second largest policing body in the country, after conventional police.</p>
<p>Business and manufacturing are divided into two arenas in Vekllei:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Venrouiva</em>: administrative, governmental and national facilities of essential function. Technically, anything under command of the bodies that form national direction (government, legislature, judiciary, etc.) are part of the <em>Venrouiva</em>. This is similar to what we think of nationalised institutions in our countries, but also includes essential industries like electricity and education.</p>
<p><em>Senrouive</em>: is distinct from <em>Venrouiva</em> as private or personal business. This is not the same as ‘private’ property, as we understand it. Vekllei does not actually make any distinction of property  —  everything belongs to the land, including the country. Vekllei does not use money, either. Instead, anything self-operating and nonessential to the operation of the country is <em>Senrouive</em>. Restaurants, cinemas, department stores, etc.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Constabulary are the police force responsible for responding to, patrolling, and protecting <em>Venrouiva</em> business in the country. They are general protection for all seats of power, military assets, power stations, libraries, hospitals, places of worship, national monuments, schools, etc.</p>
<p>Their distinctive uniform is handed down from their years as a rifle-equipped military police. They wear a dark half-cape, white Sam Browne belt, leather gloves and a ceremonial sword from Vekllei&rsquo;s years of monarchy. Women often wear a skirt with a <em>gi</em> quarter-pleat also found in civilian Vekllei clothes and uniforms, as well as a cap. The uniform changes depending on the season and purpose of their duty.</p>
<p>Unlike regular police, which are mostly disarmed in Vekllei, Constabulary always carry pistols, and often submachine guns. While they do not make house calls, you will see them establish checkpoints and escort protests. Keep an eye out for them next time you’re there.</p>
<p><em>Let me know if you have any questions! Another entry in the series of cheap sketches that are easier than effortposts.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All-weather combat for the Atomic Age</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/troops/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/troops/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The single most important function of today’s global powers is not in the numbers of men at a state&rsquo;s command, or the prosperity of their domestic markets, but the ability to project power across the world entire.
We have seen this manifest in many ways; ICBMs are just one example. Warfare in a modern context has become a highly intelligent and specialised force that has simultaneously limited the brutality of warmongering while amplifying the ruthlessness and political function of state-sponsored murder.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/troops.jpg"/> <p><strong>The single most important function of today’s global powers</strong> is not in the numbers of men at a state&rsquo;s command, or the prosperity of their domestic markets, but the ability to project power across the world entire.</p>
<p>We have seen this manifest in many ways; ICBMs are just one example. Warfare in a modern context has become a highly intelligent and specialised force that has simultaneously limited the brutality of warmongering while amplifying the ruthlessness and political function of state-sponsored murder.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In Vekllei, there is no real distinction between the intelligence services and the military, although the latter is almost always subservient to the former. Just as agents are armed as terrorists, soldiers are equipped as spies.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This all-female sniper company is world-renowned, thanks to the film <em>Beyond These Shores</em>. Like agents of espionage, every woman of this company will spend her entire military age in the cauldron of war, in a cycle of training and international operations that keep their bayonets sharp. They are not coloured by romanticism — on one hand, they can function as a noble skilled partisan in defense of the Vekllei home country. On the other, they are also employed with the secret services to commit acts of terrorism and fratricide. They wear tattered red armbands in camaraderie with their ancestors before them. In parade dress they wear a peaked cap or slouch hat, depending on the festival month.</p>
<p>Almost all of what they do is secret, as much of Vekllei’s military-industrial underbelly is, and no one person directs the employment of these types of people. You can, however, find traces easily enough, even if the women themselves remain unnamed —  last week, in war-torn Burundi, a public hanging was interrupted by mass gunfire and casualty. This destabilising effect on another impoverished sub-Saharan country is trademark Vekllei foreign policy  —  as is the remarkable accuracy of the shots heaped into the executioners.</p>
<p><em>If you have any questions, just ask!</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>This is Blood Worship</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/blood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/blood/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Blood is everything to these women. It defines them through every stage of life — bloody emerging from the womb, bloody again in the delicate transition from child to womanhood, and bloody on the table, awaiting cremation in wait of the afterlife.
Even in her name — Zelda lo Ula Desmoines — the premise of blood is there.
Zelda, blood of Ula, daughter of the Desmoines family…
Yet her fundamental human ritual has broken down.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/blood.jpg"/> <p><strong>Blood is everything to these women.</strong> It defines them through every stage of life  —  bloody emerging from the womb, bloody again in the delicate transition from child to womanhood, and bloody on the table, awaiting cremation in wait of the afterlife.</p>
<p>Even in her name  —  Zelda lo Ula Desmoines  —  the premise of blood is there.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Zelda, blood of Ula, daughter of the Desmoines family…</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yet her fundamental human ritual has broken down. It is corrupted —  as a Gregori Baby, she will never reach menarche and have a period, nor will she ever end up on the mortician’s table. And the promises these things bring  —  of family, of love, of fucking, of heritage, of mourning  —  so too are they stolen from her. So if in her native culture her blood defines her, then what definition does she have? Her womanhood is rotted, it is sick, and she is incomplete.</p>
<p>Part of her wonders if the spirits can sense it, too. They seem to flock to her, like demons, as though they can sense she only has one foot in the corporeal world. Is there a reason why blood demons ignore her? And why, on entrance to the spirit world, did the spirits filled her lungs with blood? Maybe these things are just coincidences, but nonetheless…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be thankful of your blood. Be proud of your bloodline, and when you bleed, acknowledge that what drips from you is everything you are. Some girls, like Zelda here, have to remind themselves that they are human to make it through the day.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Read more about <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/93p31c/announcing_the_princess_of_the_earth/">Gregori Children here</a>.</p>
<p>Read more about <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/97sckc/old_dead_demons_still_wander_the_countryside/">Demons here</a>.</p>
<p>Read more about <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/worldbuilding/comments/8r03tc/blood_names/">Blood Names here</a>.</p>
<p><em>If you have any questions, please let me know!</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Old, dead demons still wander the countryside</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/demons/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/demons/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[She met herself out by the shrine, many summers ago. At first she didn’t know what it was — she thought it might be a spirit, or — and she caught herself in the thought, because she was only half a child — a little part of her wondered if it was a manifestation of God, or Christ, come to help solve her problems. The idea was ridiculous. She believed it was just a forest spirit, and this was probably its shrine.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/demon.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p><strong>She met herself out by the shrine, many summers ago</strong>. At first she didn’t know what it was  —  she thought it might be a spirit, or  —  and she caught herself in the thought, because she was only half a child  —  a little part of her wondered if it was a manifestation of God, or Christ, come to help solve her problems. The idea was ridiculous. She believed it was just a forest spirit, and this was probably its shrine.</p>
<p>The copy emerged out of the bushes, and she stared at herself. It moved like she did; clumsy and ungraceful. She apologised for disturbing it, and presented her food offering.</p>
<p>As she watched it approach, a knot caught in her stomach. The thing was looking right at her. The food was ignored. She recoiled and frowned at it.</p>
<p>‘What are you?’ she asked, or something to that effect. ‘An angel? I’m not dying. Are you a psychopomp? I’m not gonna kill myself, so you don’t need to be here.’</p>
<p>It kept on walking over, and she noticed the skin of the copy had faded like an old photograph.</p>
<p>‘Did you hear me? I don’t need your help.’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Such was her first and only direct encounter with a <em>ganger</em>, an old form of demon that has been driven out long ago from here through industry and agriculture.</p>
<p>They come from the place spirits go to die, and so they carry diseases and misfortune their shoulders. When they take the form of folk out here, they act as an ‘idol’, in a sense, to worship the self  —  they feed off the bad thoughts of wanderers, take control of good memories, and manifest them physically to feed.</p>
<p>In seeing a copy of themselves, many people mistake it for a vision, or a spiritual epiphany. They will destroy themselves if they accept it. Tzipora is not such a fool  —  and she’s out here to leave those good memories far behind her, where they belong. She swings, drawing blood punching at herself, and the apparition disappears. The morning after, she wakes up with blood soaked through her pillow, and a nasty nosebleed.</p>
<p><em>Let me know if you have any questions! Just a quick sketch but I like my horror.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Country of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/tourist-map/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/tourist-map/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[There is no real distinction between the city of Vekllei and the state of Vekllei, at least internally. To them, the country and the city are the same, and the isolated population centres of Montre and Adouisneh are simply distant neighbourhoods. This is reflected in all manners of life — they are ethnically and culturally homogenous, patriotic, and largely uncompetitive. They are a single people numbering 20 million, living in the shadow of igneous monument and lush, fertile lands.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/oldmap.jpg"/> <p><strong>There is no real distinction between the city of Vekllei and the state of Vekllei</strong>, at least internally. To them, the country and the city are the same, and the isolated population centres of Montre and Adouisneh are simply distant neighbourhoods. This is reflected in all manners of life — they are ethnically and culturally homogenous, patriotic, and largely uncompetitive. They are a single people numbering 20 million, living in the shadow of igneous monument and lush, fertile lands.</p>
<p>In the south, where warm winds from the Azores sweep across the beaches of black sand, the climate is temperate and a great many of Vekllei’s most renowned wonders are accessible. Geysers, the tectonic fault, volcanoes and hot springs are scattered across the outskirts of Vekllei.</p>
<p>Heading north, the cold weather thins large-leaf forests and it is here that her signature landscape is found in abundance — the <em>ro</em>, or flower-tundra, can be hundreds of kilometres wide and populated entirely by flowers, ringed by sharp mountains forced into peaks by the violent forces of the earth below. Vekllei has the most flowers per capita out of any country in the world.</p>
<p>On this map, which is cartoonish and exaggerated, you can see several landmarks — Vekllei’s largest volcano (<em>Durtoneis</em>, or Fire of the Earth), the expansive lava fields to the North, and Vekllei’s food basket, which runs between the ro highlands and the fault line. Only Vekllei’s massive glaciers, which give the country the cleanest drinking water in the world, are in permafrost.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Look at this —! Look at this place, where the horizon meets the sky without a stitch! Listen to the water, rich and sweet with soil, trickle through the ro. What a place this is… If she’d had any respect for God, she would have marvelled at the beauty of His ro. If she’d thought He was good and decent, she would have thanked Him for constructing such a place for her. But the truth of it, at least in her mind, was that God may be the creator, but the beauty of this ro is in the hands of humans, now. This place is the territory of Vekllei, in all her glory. If God should ever like to visit — and Tzipora very much hoped he would, because she had some things on her mind — he could apply for a visa at the bureau.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Vekllei people are generally unconcerned with the outside world. Their flag, the Red Standard, is a simple blank colour that means &ldquo;Vekllei&rdquo; in Vekllei Semaphore, a sublanguage of <em>potenne</em>, or physical Vekllei language. They also employ an International Standard in foreign arenas, including the U.N. and the Olympics.</p>
<p>This is a reupload (I took the previous post down to fix some mistakes in the image). If you have any questions, please let me know!</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora&#39;s Portrait</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/portrait/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/portrait/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Practising colours. It&rsquo;s always been my weakness. While you&rsquo;re here, if you have any questions about Tzipora or want to chat, let me know.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/portrait.jpg"/> <p>Practising colours. It&rsquo;s always been my weakness. While you&rsquo;re here, if you have any questions about Tzipora or want to chat, let me know.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Announcing the Princess of the Earth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/princes-of-the-earth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/princes-of-the-earth/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[They never actually believed that she was any kind of princess. They never even joked about it. The original LIFE magazine article said that she looked as though she were ‘a princess of the Earth’ when interviewer Alfie Ricci met her in the Vekllei highlands, and so she carried that name as a burden for the next few hundred years.
There are many Gregori children alive today, and we have seen the miracle of the first few dozen start to wear off.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/princessoftheearth.jpg"/> <p>They never actually believed that she was any kind of princess. They never even joked about it. The original LIFE magazine article said that she <em>looked</em> as though she were ‘a princess of the Earth’ when interviewer Alfie Ricci met her in the Vekllei highlands, and so she carried that name as a burden for the next few hundred years.</p>
<p>There are many Gregori children alive today, and we have seen the miracle of the first few dozen start to wear off. Gregori Hordiyenko, the little Ukrainian boy whose namesake was adopted by his disease, died age 27 in a car accident. Many others of the &ldquo;first dozen&rdquo; committed suicide, were killed by disease, died from complications arising from the genetic function of the syndrome, and a disproportionate number were born into the third world, where they were eliminated by famine, displacement or superstition.</p>
<p>Tzipora Desmoines, Vekllei’s first and only Gregori baby, was born in 2063. By the time of her LIFE interview, she was sixty-two years old. Yet she remains as she was on the eve of her menarche  —  fourteen, prepubescent, and largely miserable.</p>
<p>When you meet her for the first time, you have no idea how to talk to her. Is she a young teen-ager, or a sixty year old woman? A lot of her patient and soft-spoken quality is misinterpreted as a product of age, but nothing could be further from the truth  —  which is that Tzipora is largely the same girl as she was in 2077, but the spirit and vigour of her teen-age years and childhood curiosity have been stretched unnaturally over decades, blunting her passion and enthusiasm in all things. To the handful of people left alive that she loves, she can be as childish as ever, but the ghosts that dominate her regrets and favourite memories are starting to overcome her.</p>
<p>She is a rare case, despite thousands of boys and girls now like her across the world. She was born in a brief period where Gregori babies were born fairly healthy and independent, save for their obvious genetic malfunction. Today, among the hundreds that are born each year, nearly all of them suffer from broad anaphylaxis that renders them fragile and useless. In theory, all Gregori children will live forever save a car or the rope doesn’t get them, but as the children born with the syndrome become more and more sick very few that are born today will live beyond a normal human lifespan.</p>
<p>As for Tzipora  —  in seventy years she will become the oldest human ever, living or dead.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Valleys of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/valleys/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/valleys/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Two years ago, a fission military jet plunged into the mountain behind the village of Montre-Lola, emerging moments later as a plume of fire and smoke in the shadow of the mountain peak. Villagers made their way up the slopes to help survivors, dressed in radiation suits from the town shelter. There were none. Six more lives and six more soldiers lost — a pilot, co-pilot, navigator, reactor engineer, bombardier, and fire control officer are written down and then buried like cattle.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fields.jpg"/> <p><strong>Two years ago, a fission military jet plunged into the mountain behind the village of Montre-Lola, emerging moments later as a plume of fire and smoke in the shadow of the mountain peak</strong>. Villagers made their way up the slopes to help survivors, dressed in radiation suits from the town shelter. There were none. Six more lives and six more soldiers lost  —  a pilot, co-pilot, navigator, reactor engineer, bombardier, and fire control officer are written down and then buried like cattle.</p>
<p>Such is the senseless cost of monthly drills, in which the well-oiled spring that sets Vekllei’s nuclear-capable arsenal upon the world quivers in anticipation. The low-lying Raya Valley Air Base fleet emerges over the snow-capped mountains twice a year, panicking farmers below them, as they make their way to auxiliary coastal bases for training.</p>
<p>This year, in usual preparation for the Festival of the Atom, the airship <em>Dumoustra</em> joins a fleet of jet bombers as they rendezvous with the 3rd and 5th Escort squadrons from the coast. They soar dramatically over the ribs of the North Vekllei tectonic mountain ranges, briefly roaring over the quiet farming valleys one by one as peaks pass below them.</p>
<p>The belly of the valleys have some of the best soils in the world, a gift from one of hundreds of volcanoes that are scattered across the North Atlantic nation. Mostly wheat and rice are grown. The sides of the valleys veer dramatically into near-cliffs, folded like paper by the enormous anger of the European and American continental plates.</p>
<p>Trees are short and small-leaved, and often have great colour. Flower-tundras are also common here, called <em>ro</em> in Vekllei.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>She was in the shadow of a titan mountain range that followed the tracks as far as she could see. It sloped sharply into the valley, breaking out briefly into a thick temperate woodland before the trees withdrew and terraced wheat fields stepped down to the tracks. Vekllei is an ancient, volcanic land of igneous monument and sharp rock, softened by healthy topsoil bursting with mosses and flowers. She wiped her nose on the back of her hand, and rubbed her eyes. She had dressed up for him but she felt childish shivering on the bare station platform, if it could even qualify as such a thing. It was a bare concrete slab, forty metres long, that serviced rickety rural train cars that ran from here to the Montre terminus, where bullet-train maglevs shot to the capital on the hour.</p>
<p>She looked before her, bringing her knees to her breast, and there was the ro, in all its untouched splendour and colour. The soil here was percolated with water, and it squelched underfoot, rich with minerals and pebbles of quartz and obsidian. As far as she could see, off to her west where the sun was slowly setting, the ground was bejeweled with thick flowers, pockmarked by still pools of fresh water, that, like mirrors, reflected any image above it perfectly.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Let me know if you want to know anything else about Vekllei or this picture.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hot summer rain on a beach of black sand -- Iceland in 2127</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/black-sand/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/black-sand/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Just as Iceland&rsquo;s initial history was reshaped into the image of Vekllei some centuries ago, so too has the real-world climate and weather been altered. Cool Icelandic summers have been usurped by volatile days that can be as low as 5C (40F) or as hot as 30C (85F+). Technically speaking, the unstable Atlantic pressure oscillation, of which Vekllei anchors as the Vekllei low pole, can pull in bitter cold from the Greenland currents, or warmth from the Azores tempestuously.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/blacksand.jpg"/> <p>Just as Iceland&rsquo;s initial history was reshaped into the image of Vekllei some centuries ago, so too has the real-world climate and weather been altered. Cool Icelandic summers have been usurped by volatile days that can be as low as 5C (40F) or as hot as 30C (85F+). Technically speaking, the unstable Atlantic pressure oscillation, of which Vekllei anchors as the Vekllei low pole, can pull in bitter cold from the Greenland currents, or warmth from the Azores tempestuously.</p>
<p>So it is that in summer, on a beach of black igneous sand from the volcanoes of this place, hot rains can descend instantly and beat pedestrians until the rains vanish, minutes later. Winters are equally unstable  —  they shift between unlivable cold and sporadic thawing periods.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This unusual climate is not unique to Vekllei. Europe is fucked, meteorologically speaking, by a series of el nino summers and instant winters that wrack Germany, Austria, Italy, and so forth. The Adriatic seems to see more gloom than mediterranean sun these days.</p>
<p>The equatorial deserts of the world, Nevada included, are mere degrees away from unsurvivable. With temperatures frequently breaking 50C (125F) throughout the year, it thins the population of Southerners too old or too poor to avoid the heat.</p>
<p>North Africa is a husk. There is no water and no food. There is a reason there are mass graves all across the shores of the Black Sea, and why Europe tastes the boot. There is a reason the southern African states are crumbling.</p>
<p>East Asia is hot and wet.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So these girls march on in the summer rain-storms, not quite conscious of the ridiculousness of enjoying one of the world’s more temperate climates in a country they once called Iceland.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>winter love &#43; puffin / feat. Tzipora &amp; Akiko</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/puffin-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/puffin-love/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[&ldquo;The puffin flies here so early (over the years). The further inland we go, the farther they chase us.&rdquo;
That&rsquo;s the sentiment of the phrase, but in Vekllei &lsquo;The puffin flies here&rsquo; is supplemented with the opening of a saying, &lsquo;all birds flee the sea in Winter,&rsquo; and so there is a reference here that is otherwise lost in translation.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/puffinlove.jpg"/> <p>&ldquo;The puffin flies here so early (over the years). The further inland we go, the farther they chase us.&rdquo;</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s the sentiment of the phrase, but in Vekllei &lsquo;The puffin flies here&rsquo; is supplemented with the opening of a saying, &lsquo;all birds flee the sea in Winter,&rsquo; and so there is a reference here that is otherwise lost in translation.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Navy in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/salvo/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/salvo/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[There are not many warships in the world today that are distinctive as the serpentine-funnelled, semi-tumblehome hull of the Sundress-class supercruisers. For a country that prides itself on ‘petticoat society’, it is only suitable that Vekllei continues to pioneer the ‘dazzle’ warpaint in her navy.
The most recent stock of Navy ships are all named after women’s clothes, to emphasise Vekllei’s spiritual understanding of gender in industrial society and also as a sarcastic nominer.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/navyship.jpg"/> <p><strong>There are not many warships in the world today that are distinctive as the serpentine-funnelled, semi-tumblehome hull of the</strong> <strong>Sundress-class supercruisers</strong>. For a country that prides itself on ‘petticoat society’, it is only suitable that Vekllei continues to pioneer the ‘dazzle’ warpaint in her navy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most recent stock of Navy ships are all named after women’s clothes, to emphasise Vekllei’s spiritual understanding of gender in industrial society and also as a sarcastic nominer. What American or Chinese sailor wants to be defeated in naval combat by a supercruiser named after a sundress? There is humour about it. You do not see that in many chambers of navy high command.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Two 10 inch naval cannons sit on the bow, and use large magazines that give a maximum fire rate of thirty shots a minute. A spiritual successor to the battleships of yore, supercruisers (a light battlecruiser designed for speed and use in shallow water),  are designed for naval gunfire support using these cannons. The ship is also armed with anti-submarine and anti-fighter capabilities as needed. With prolonged shooting the ship is soon absorbed into a cloud of smoke and gunpowder.</p>
<p>The distinctive serpentine auxiliary funnel betrays the <em>Sundress</em>’s nuclear secret  —  an analog diesel engine sits alongside the standard light salt reactor, to immediately take over should the advanced electrics of the ship be disrupted by the electromagnetic effects of a nuclear blast. Because of recent advances in thermal detection, both water vapour from the reactor and smoke from the diesel engine are cooled with seawater in segregated loops, hence the two funnels for two engines.</p>
<p>The navy forms a large part of the island nation’s military consciousness, and so ships are painted unconventionally as part of Vekllei Semaphore (a language within Vekllei of flags, colour and paints) for presentation in military parades. <em>The Festival of the Sea</em>, spanning two weeks in October, concludes with a detonation of a nuclear device offshore.</p>
<p>The sweeping curves of the armoured hull and bridge are common in all the world’s navies these days, as the futurism of yesterday creeps closer to today.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>What will become of the Gregori Children?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/floating/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/floating/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Did you know — many Gregori children do not form calluses on their skin, because of the intensity of their epidermic regeneration process!
Hello all,
The question on the mind of folks around the world is that of Gregori Children. What are they? What does it mean, to be a “Gregori Baby”?
Gregori Regenerative Syndrome is a developmental phenomenon that afflicts children and young teen-agers. It holds them in a prepubescent state, and so they do not grow old like you and I.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/floating.jpg"/> <p><em>Did you know  —  many Gregori children do not form calluses on their skin, because of the intensity of their epidermic regeneration process!</em></p>
<p>Hello all,</p>
<p>The question on the mind of folks around the world is that of Gregori Children. What are they? What does it <em>mean</em>, to be a “Gregori Baby”?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Gregori Regenerative Syndrome is a developmental phenomenon that afflicts children and young teen-agers. It holds them in a prepubescent state, and so they do not grow old like you and I.</p>
<p>Of the thousands of Gregori children now living in our world today, over 90 per cent of them are girls. They develop normally until an unknown point between thelarche (the beginning of puberty and the development of breasts) and menarche (a girl’s first period). In boys, this timeline is technically different but chronologically similar  —  and always before sexual maturation. Girls in Vekllei might expect menarche as late as fourteen-sixteen (a fact that continues to emphasise the myth of Vekllei virgin purity), whereas boys will likely cease development a few years earlier, usually twelve-fourteen.</p>
<p>Gregori girls can often take the appearance of young teen-agers; they may develop breasts and grow body hair, although these phenomena are not universal among the afflicted. Nonetheless, they have not actually entered puberty proper  —  estrogen is not shaping their bodies, and they will remain sterile for the rest of their lives. Boys are similar, although are usually shorter and more childlike in appearance at the onset of the Gregori process.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>So what does being Gregori actually mean</em>?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It means the natural biological development of these children and teen-agers has ceased and their bodies have entered an unnatural cellular cycle, which halts the ageing process and renders them immortal, at least in theory. Technically, they are still growing  —  nonregenerative tissue and organs are still growing, like the brain  —  but they are captured in this state forever. Doctors put the blame on a faulty genetic regenerative process, hidden somewhere in their DNA, but the exact cause is unknown.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Do they have superpowers?</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Nothing of the sort, unfortunately! Existential questions aside, the syndrome can be as much a burden as a miracle. For example, although all Gregori children are immune to cancers and similar cellular malfunction, around 80 per cent of them suffer broad anaphylaxis, meaning that almost all foreign matter triggers an overzealous autoimmune response. This can be fatal, and the ratio of children born with Gregori anaphylaxis has only risen in recent years.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Are there any dangers to being Gregori?</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Gregori teen-agers and children have a high turnover of cells, and some bones do not properly fuse. This renders many of the afflicted delicate and fragile  —  especially children halted at a younger age. The condition is not known to affect emotional or psychological traits of the afflicted.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The future implications of Gregori syndrome are limitless  —  ignoring the secret of immortality, the ability to regenerate vital brain, spinal, and optical tissues would revolutionise medicine. Today, there are many thousands of Gregori children in the world, and so the question of their own future remains  —  <strong>are they a genetic abnormality, or the next wave of human evolution?</strong></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Life in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/apartment-living/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/apartment-living/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Vekllei is the final stop in the epoch of rest. Departing your jetliner or aeroship and setting foot in the city is a spiritual experience — the weight of the world leaves your shoulders, and, at last, you are at peace. Imagine what that would be like — to be self-actualised!
When I die, it will be in Vekllei. The food is good, the women are beautiful — yes, when I go I’ll make sure I’m there, pissed beyond belief, surrounded by my family, watching the city lights wink out for the final time.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/apartmentliving.jpg"/> <p><strong>Vekllei is the final stop in the epoch of rest</strong>. Departing your jetliner or aeroship and setting foot in the city is a spiritual experience  —  the weight of the world leaves your shoulders, and, at last, you are at peace. Imagine what that would be like  —  <em>to be self-actualised</em>!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When I die, it will be in Vekllei. The food is good, the women are beautiful — yes, when I go I’ll make sure I’m there, pissed beyond belief, surrounded by my family, watching the city lights wink out for the final time. Isn’t that a hell of an idea? I think it’s a hell of an idea.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This street, in a suburb in Montre, is decorated for the moon festival. Sunlight only reaches this place for an hour a day, this time of year. What better time to reconnect with the sprites and your ancestors? For a few dozen precious minutes each day, curtains are flung open, children stream into the street, and office folk take a smoke break. Sure enough, the sun soon sets and the people return indoors, the streets of their city coloured by lanterns. The water of the canals is warm and smells of sulphur. The trams hum with electricity. A wind from the yawning Atlantic batters the sides of the apartment blocks that fill the city. Such is winter life in Vekllei.</p>
<p>They do not use money, and they have not discovered ‘landscape’ as we understand it, but they are fiercely proud of Vekllei and the fruit of her city. Go on, see a flick, or pick out a dress —  better yet, see the city, drink well, fuck often, and fall in love with a Montre chickette.</p>
<p>Underneath this feverish utopian vision lies artifacts of something darker  —  shadows of fear hidden in plain sight. Curtains drawn across apartment windows are laced with lead. A blast would otherwise shatter these glass walls and eviscerate the families inside. The more time you spend in Vekllei, the more you will notice the fear of these people woven into the fibre of the city. Why does every student wear armbands with their school and year embroidered on them? Why are the rainwater gutters beside roads so deep and wide? Tourists visiting airbases will understand the precipice over which the country rocks  —  nuclear jet fighters are cycling their engines always, superelectric trams can detach from the power grid, and sirens perform tests on random days in October.</p>
<p>What is to become of my old girl, the city?</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Blood Names</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/blood-names/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/blood-names/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Each person in Vekllei has three names — a given name (Tzipora), a surname (Desmoines), and an alternative given name as part of rapotenne (potenne is ‘handtalk’, upotenne is ‘spirit-talk’, and so it follows that rapotenne is the language system of names). This alternative name is a ‘key’ to the full blood name of an individual, which are given in secret by the mother traditionally, but can be gifted by any mother-figure.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/bloodname.jpg"/> <p>Each person in Vekllei has three names  —  a <strong>given name</strong> (Tzipora), a <strong>surname</strong> (Desmoines), and an alternative given name as part of <em>rapotenne</em> (potenne is ‘handtalk’, upotenne is ‘spirit-talk’, and so it follows that rapotenne is the language system of names). This alternative name is a ‘key’ to the full blood name of an individual, which are given in secret by the mother traditionally, but can be gifted by any mother-figure.</p>
<p>For all intents and purposes, ‘<strong>Tzipora Desmoines</strong>’ works exactly as ‘John Smith’  —  a distinguishing name and the ancestral name. In Vekllei, the men take the name of the child-bearer.</p>
<p>Tzipora’s blood name, her <em>rapotenne</em>, instead reads as: <strong>Zelda lo Ula Desmoines</strong>. This is a name she should never reveal until her death, so rites can be performed.</p>
<p>Although Vekllei’s monarchy is long dead, ancestors are still held sacred by these people. They hold ancient family names that tie their blood to the earth. They are also used when talking with spirits, as they are part of <em>upotenne</em>, the external language of the soul. In this sense, blood names operate as a sacred vocal rune.</p>
<p>Pictured above is Tzipora receiving her blood name from a father-figure many years ago. Since she has no bloodline left alive, he fulfills the role of a father and gives her a name constructed of several parts, researched and tailored to her.</p>
<ol>
<li>Zelda is a nickname and a moniker Tzipora has used to hide her Jewishness, and so works perfectly as a public ‘key’ to her blood name.</li>
<li>lo Ula (her blood of Ula in upotenne) is her ancient, sacred title. The name-giver has not been able to trace her blood to the times of spirits, so he’s traced it as far back as he could and scoured that region for a proper title. Ula is a combination of two words  —  Ura, a type of bare, wind-swept coastal shelf in Northern Vekllei, where Tzipora’s bloodlines originate, and the Vekllei word for iceberg. It also links to an ancient Vekllei saga  —  in which a proud and mighty iceberg is reduced to ice-pebbles after being dashed against the northern rocks. A story of mortality, it is a warning for Tzipora, who does not age.</li>
<li>Desmoines is the family name, unchanged for centuries, and is fairly common in Vekllei.</li>
</ol>
<p>I’m really enjoying exploring more of Vekllei’s traditions. Let me know if you have any questions, about these language systems, Tzipora, or anything.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The dress code for talking to spirits</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/dress-code/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/dress-code/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[In Vekllei animism, which branches into a vast and complex set of beliefs and traditions that vary from village to village, there is no formal religious structure. Temples and shrines pay respect to sprites, which are universally understood as bi-planar creatures. There is no formal religious structure, and so animistic tradition has no priests.
Ceremonial dress is simple to describe, but complex to assemble. The shape and form of the dress, including cascade peplums (a series of peplums that hang over the skirt of the dress) and sun petticoats are traditional, but they hold no religious value outside of the connection to your ancestors who performed the same rites before you.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/religiousuniform.jpg"/> <p><strong>In Vekllei animism</strong>, which branches into a vast and complex set of beliefs and traditions that vary from village to village, there is no formal religious structure. Temples and shrines pay respect to <strong>sprites</strong>, which are universally understood as bi-planar creatures. There is no formal religious structure, and so animistic tradition has no priests.</p>
<p>Ceremonial dress is simple to describe, but complex to assemble. The shape and form of the dress, including <em>cascade peplums</em> (a series of peplums that hang over the skirt of the dress) and sun petticoats are traditional, but they hold no religious value outside of the connection to your ancestors who performed the same rites before you. Tradition is very important in Vekllei.</p>
<p>Sprites, and to a lesser extent <strong>spirits</strong>, are fiercely attracted to supernatural colour and shine (polished gemstones, plastics, metals, etc). Pure and natural metals are most alluring to the sprites, as they hold the lustre of the Earth (as well as exude undetectable submagnetic fields called <em>ecec</em>) but they can be substituted with synthetic gold and bronze, as can gemstones, all of which are mass-produced in the industrial city centres of Vekllei.</p>
<p>To meet a sprite, and offer it food, you should dress in these materials. Often villages will collectively maintain traditional outfits for talking to sprites, some of which are hundreds of years old and require care to put on. Sprites can see like you and me, so covering yourself in gold won’t simply do the trick  —  you should dress neatly and politely. It is not necessary to purge yourself of all modern things  —  wristwatches, shoes, hairpieces are all fine, as long as you’ve taken care in your appearance.</p>
<p>Appease a <strong>sprite</strong>, and you might notice lost items turning up, and cracked roof tiles begin to sparkle like new. To befriend a <strong>spirit</strong> is to have plenty to harvest that season, as well as protection from heavy rains.</p>
<p><strong>Tzipora Zelda Desmoines</strong>, miracle girl of the village of <strong>Montre-Lola</strong>, holds a pose in <em>upotenne</em>: the physical language of spirits. As <em>potenne</em> supplements language in Vekllei with sign gestures, <em>upotenne</em> turns your body into an ancient rune, and protects the site from disturbing fields that might scare a sprite. It’s not necessary to hold it for long  —  just acknowledge it. This one performed by Tzipora predates Vekllei language and script  —  no one today can speak it. It lives on today only in physical form, and in that moment time collapses and she is in this place with her ancestors.</p>
<p><em>Just a quick sketch. Let me know if you have any questions</em>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/police-car/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/police-car/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Hopefully you won’t have to worry about the police while you’re in Vekllei, but you’ll likely notice them. Police are everywhere — as an alternative to military (duoroten) service, conscripts can elect to enter domestic security (inroten). Most officers are young, bored, and live in the community they police. You’ll likely be talking to them at some point in your visit, even if it’s only to ask for directions — in Vekllei, cops are the bulletin boards of the community.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/policecar.jpg"/> <p><strong>Hopefully you won’t have to worry about the police while you’re in Vekllei</strong>, but you’ll likely notice them. Police are everywhere  —  as an alternative to military (<em>duoroten</em>) service, conscripts can elect to enter domestic security <em>(inrote</em>n). Most officers are young, bored, and live in the community they police. You’ll likely be talking to them at some point in your visit, even if it’s only to ask for directions  —  in Vekllei, cops are the bulletin boards of the community.</p>
<p>All beat cops are unarmed, and carry extendable truncheons that swing from their belt. Much more rarely, you’ll see professional officers  —  you’ll notice them, because they ride in cars. Professional officers travel in pairs, and the senior officer is known as a <em>firearm officer</em>, and will carry a sidearm.</p>
<p>Should you be detained by police, keep the following in mind:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Vekllei is a casual culture.</strong> Some officers will speak English, but the concept of ‘sir’ has never entered their vocabulary. They will approach and interact with you casually  —  professionalism operates differently here. Nor will they bow to you, except in stations. If you act hysterical, they will cease to take you seriously. Keep your cool, be friendly, talk clearly.</li>
<li><strong>Vekllei is a physical culture</strong>. Police will touch, pull, and push you without communicating. This is not an intimate or aggressive gesture  —  they will just as soon pull you out of the thoroughfare of a sidewalk as restrain you.</li>
<li><strong>Vekllei police do not heavily employ firearms, but are liberal with the baton</strong>. Only when responding to a firearm call will police approach with a firearm in hand. Otherwise, they will rest a baton on their shoulder and are trained to use it against you, should you attempt to fight them. In a country without currency, there is no such thing as ‘damages’. Public drunkenness is not tolerated in Vekllei and is not an excuse for fighting with police.</li>
</ol>
<p>With all that said, Vekllei has an extremely low crime rate and it is very unlikely you’ll ever see cops responding to a crime. More often you’ll see them escorting other emergency service vehicles through pedestrian streets, arguing with locals and doing odd jobs around the community. Especially in rural communities, there is very little distinction between on and off-duty cops, and beat cops will often wear their uniform around town while unassigned to a shift.</p>
<p>In the picture above we see professional cops, or <em>copa</em>, watching a suspect from across the street. We can tell they are professional officers because they wear red and white uniforms, instead of the navy, red and white of beat cops. The woman is a firearm officer, and carries a revolver in her holster. The man is not armed but carries a baton on his shoulder.</p>
<p>The police car, a <em>Model 10 (Special)</em>, sits low to the ground, weighed with a 60MWe Molten Salt Reactor where we’d usually find the trunk. The car has a theoretical top speed of 400km/h, but will never reach anywhere close to that  —  pursuits are extremely rare in the country, as almost no-one has a personal automobile. On its roof it carries two cherry lights and a single <em>Dura</em> wailer siren. The service number, 6, tells us that the unit is from the Montre region.</p>
<p>As for the suspect? A small domestic fight between a grocer and his daughter fizzled out and they both apologised to the officers and community for wasting their time.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>How to Bow (and Fashion in Vekllei)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/bowing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/bowing/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Vekllei has a pan-pacific flavour of greeting, usually a bow followed by a handshake. If you’re going to fit in, you’re going to have to learn how to do it right. Let’s get started.
First, Vekllei is extremely physical in its language. Not expressive, like how you might picture an Italian or American. Instead, it incorporates an auxiliary language called potenne or, ‘Hand-Talk’, which accompanies words. A forefinger sliding across a forefinger is ‘good’ or, ‘acknowledged’, and can be used with verbalising the word or as a signal.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/bowing.jpg"/> <p><strong>Vekllei has a pan-pacific flavour of greeting, usually a bow followed by a handshake.</strong> If you’re going to fit in, you’re going to have to learn how to do it right. Let’s get started.</p>
<p>First, Vekllei is extremely physical in its language. Not expressive, like how you might picture an Italian or American. Instead, it incorporates an auxiliary language called <em>potenne</em> or, ‘Hand-Talk’, which accompanies words. A forefinger sliding across a forefinger is ‘good’ or, ‘acknowledged’, and can be used with verbalising the word or as a signal.</p>
<p>Similarly, bowing takes on elements of potenne. There are hundreds of ways to bow, but there are a few basic rules that will make your time in Vekllei easier.</p>
<ol>
<li>The angle of the bow determines the seriousness of the gesture. A ninety-degree bow is most-serious, used for meeting foreigners of importance, apologising profusely, or welcoming a prestigious guest. In modern Vekllei, where mateship has displaced traditional hierarchy, it is rarely used except in service of others. Most common is fifteen degrees, with a maximum of forty-five in polite, formal conversation.</li>
<li>You must not speak while bowing. The act is a word in itself and it is loud and obnoxious to speak and act. Welcome, or apologise, or thank the partner. Then bow.</li>
<li>Formal bowing, as employed in serious or dire times as a collective action, is taken on the knees on the floor. The head is pressed against the ground. Those unable to kneel can lower their heads. The most obvious example of this for the reader is in the ten-minutes mourning following the <em>Lola</em> nuclear attack, when every able-bodied citizen faced the district and bowed in honour of the dead.</li>
</ol>
<p>Let’s observe <strong>Tzipora Zelda Desmoines</strong>, miracle girl of Montre-Lola, in three types of bowing you are most likely to encounter in your travels.</p>
<ol>
<li>With hands interlocked, hanging parallel to the legs, the greeting bow is most common and works as a friendly gesture. Make sure to lock your fingers properly. Only with foreigners will you bow with your arms straight by your sides, so make sure to let the arms dangle perpendicular to your legs.</li>
<li>To apologise, or excuse yourself, place your fingers gently on your neck and bow to the degree it is appropriate. Close your eyes. If the person has more to say, release your hands from the back of your neck, listen, then repeat the gesture.</li>
<li>A welcome bow, employed as a gesture of solidarity, welcomes you into homes and places of business. This is not a ‘hello’, this is a, ‘how may I serve you?’. Forms fists with your hands and place them over your chest. Do not bow your head, and keep eye contact with the partner. It is unusual for foreigners to perform this bow, unless they are employed in some capacity. In Vekllei, this translates more literally to greetings, mate,’ and the service is implied.</li>
</ol>
<p>Keep in mind that Vekllei does not use honourifics, and supplements titles with bows. These are important. Use them luxuriously, and have fun! Vekllei people will appreciate the gesture from a foreigner.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Winter Clothing (and Womanhood in Vekllei)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/winter-clothing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/winter-clothing/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Welcome to Vekllei. It is a strange country with a complex culture that is quite distinct (and sometimes outrageous) to Western countries. This will be a long post. I’ve tried to keep it clear.
Women in Vekllei usually wear skirts in winter. There are cultural and historical reasons for this, explained below. Pictured here is Tzipora in a winter Vekllei outfit so typical it works well enough here to give a show-and-tell.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/coldweather.jpg"/> <p>Welcome to Vekllei. It is a strange country with a complex culture that is quite distinct (and sometimes outrageous) to Western countries. This will be a long post. I’ve tried to keep it clear.</p>
<hr>
<p>Women in Vekllei usually wear skirts in winter. There are cultural and historical reasons for this, explained below. Pictured here is Tzipora in a winter Vekllei outfit so typical it works well enough here to give a show-and-tell. The outfit consists of underwear (vest, stockings/socks, etc.), an inner lace petticoat, a cotton thermal pettiskirt, and a wool outer skirt. They reach about the mid-shin. She wears a thick cotton shirt over her vest and a rayon cardigan on top, with cotton gloves. Although not pictured here, when heading out a long wool overcoat would protect from the fierce Vekllei wind.</p>
<p>The colours are not wintery, but that requires context. The history of language and gender are not everyone’s cup of tea, but if you want to know more, let’s get started.</p>
<hr>
<p>Winters in Vekllei are long and dark. In the depths of it the sun rises only for about an hour. Temperatures range between 5 and -15 centigrade. By all accounts it is not a place for skirts.</p>
<p>But many women don’t consider thick or multilayered trousers. This is because womanhood is tied very clearly to physical appearance. Vekllei lacks gender pronouns entirely, but has very clear feminine and masculine words. Vekllei written language is logographic, and so you ‘construct’ concepts out of images. So certain gender concepts, like femininity, are constructed out of feminine associations that ‘build’ a sensation and understanding of what it means to be female. Skirts are a part of that. To feel like a woman in Vekllei, there are explicit images that build femininity.</p>
<p><strong>That is not to say Vekllei is necessarily misogynist</strong>, at least as we understand it through a Western lens  —  the political and cultural understanding of the country (usually called ‘petticoat socialism’) strongly suggests that our fundamental ‘human’ traits are inherently female.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It emphasises the overall ‘femininity’ of humanity and shifts the human core to female, and then distinguishes masculine traits as radical and far from the centre of the human condition. Petticoat feminism takes on economic qualities and a radical reading of gender to describe its main point of function and praxis  —  that masculine qualities are inherently economic, and that they will cease to be masculine as petticoat socialism achieves its aim of rendering labour unnecessary for all reasons except self-satisfaction. In petticoat feminism, the final form of the human race is female  —  not in a biological sense, but in a cultural attitude that has essentially ceased to distinguish between masculine and feminine qualities, while retaining what it views as inherently female virtues.</p>
<p>Fragility, grace, beauty, leisure, and reproduction are placed upon the shoulders of men, rendering them ‘female’ in the lexicon of petticoat feminism, and thus relieving them of the economic burden of masculinity.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Knowing all that, it still basically means that skirts are for women, and women wear skirts to feel like women. Vekllei clothing has thus become multilayered and insulated to adapt to the shift from summer to winter.</p>
<p><strong>As far as colours go</strong>, Vekllei is volcanic and geographically active. Fire and ice are synonymous here. This means that red and blues are associated with keeping warm and ice, and yellows and greens are for the lush foliage in the warmer seasons. It is uncommon to wear reds in the summer  —  it’s too hot to need colours associated with fire.</p>
<p>This post is long enough, I think. Tzipora is in the wind but looks happy enough. If you have questions about the language itself, or what the annotations say, <em>just ask</em>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rail-Launched Nuclear Missiles</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/missile-train/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/missile-train/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This is a concept of a Vekllei Rocketry Corp rail ICBM launcher. It has distinctive-looking carriages, and so it serves no real purpose in being a ‘hidden’ ICBM launcher. Instead, this train is for testing rail-mounted ICBMs, which are then employed in plain and unmarked railcars. Today it idles by the lakeside town of Dupot-Monan, as its senior control staff await a hot lunch driven in from the town. All equipment, including the silo, is extended.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/missiletrain.jpg"/> <p>This is a concept of a Vekllei Rocketry Corp rail ICBM launcher. It has distinctive-looking carriages, and so it serves no real purpose in being a ‘hidden’ ICBM launcher. Instead, this train is for testing rail-mounted ICBMs, which are then employed in plain and unmarked railcars. Today it idles by the lakeside town of Dupot-Monan, as its senior control staff await a hot lunch driven in from the town. All equipment, including the silo, is extended.</p>
<p>It uses two nuclear locomotives, which produce many thousands of times more power than is required to operate the vehicle and launcher. They have radiating fans as a primary air intake. The launch car has an articulating hydraulic arm that raises the silo. Rail-mounted ICBMs launch ‘cold’. They are propelled out of the tube by gases within the silo, and only ignite outside of the train.</p>
<p><strong>In 2127, the Soviets, U.S., China and Vekllei all employ hidden rail-launched ICBMs</strong> as a ‘dead-hand’ that can retaliate after an atomic attack. They rove the countryside of these superpowers, by all appearances regular cargo trains, invisible to spies and spy satellites alike. Rail-mounted ICBMs, and their testing, is one of the more frequently-broken clauses of the latest atomic weapons treaties. It is an unkept secret. This train, ‘Missile Carriage 2,’ is on its way to the rocketry test facility sixty kilometres away. With two nuclear locomotives attached, the trip will take less than fifteen minutes. Well, at least after lunch is finished.</p>
<p><em>Just a quick sketch. Thanks, guys.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Washing the Feet of the Enemy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/penance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/penance/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[He had sent her a wire some weeks before asking to meet her. She did not remember him. By now he was an old man, and she, a Gregori baby of sixty four years, had not aged a day. He was close to dying and wanted to relieve his soul of the war crimes he’d committed as a member of the Vanguard in the Second American Civil War. She had been a little ptitsa back then, fighting with the Milita.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/penance.jpg"/> <p><strong>He had sent her a wire some weeks before asking to meet her</strong>. She did not remember him. By now he was an old man, and she, a Gregori baby of sixty four years, had not aged a day. He was close to dying and wanted to relieve his soul of the war crimes he’d committed as a member of the Vanguard in the Second American Civil War. She had been a little ptitsa back then, fighting with the Milita. He was desperate to repay her, and what she stood for, as in 2127 she is one of the few living Militia women on this Earth.</p>
<p>In this scene we see <strong>Michael Greenfield</strong> washing the feet of <strong>Tzipora Zelda Desmoines</strong> at a spirit shrine in <strong>Vekllei</strong>, in a melding of Christian tradition and Vekllei cultural humility. She is surrounded by her friends, including her estranged Japanese husband on the left (fourteen years old, sixty two years age). She does not like her feet being touched, but it is important to her to see a living artifact of the war that shaped her childhood. She still carries part of the war with her  —  as he fills a basin and she bares one foot, Michael notices she is afflicted with nervous tics. She rubs her nose and picks at her shirt. When she is nervous, like she is now, the tics are almost constant.</p>
<p>These two are survivors of the Second American Civil War, which spanned a decade in the 2070s. They fought on opposite sides  —  Tzipora on the liberal, socialist, anarchist coalition called the Militia, Michael as a fascist for the Vanguard party. Tzipora grew disillusioned with the war and fled after three years of fighting. Michael continued to serve until the Federal Government succeeded in crushing both movements. The crimes he has committed in war weight on him, now late in life. He passed away six months after this strange and awkward meeting.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Sketch of a Blood Spirit</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/demon-attack/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/demon-attack/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Blood spirits are unaware people have physical forms. Why should they? No person has entered the realm of the spirits in a millenia.
When the Princess of the Earth arrived, after the nuclear exchange between the United States and China, one of the first encounters she had with a spirit in their homeworld was a blood spirit tearing her apart while looking for food. She was fully in proper kit for a trip to the spirit world — the lanterns are to keep both her safety among the spirits and to let her blood flow properly respectively, and the orbs around her neck are filled with soil from her homeland to keep her body attached to the spirit world.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/demonattack.jpg"/> <p><em>Blood spirits</em> are unaware people have physical forms. Why should they? No person has entered the realm of the spirits in a millenia.</p>
<p>When the Princess of the Earth arrived, after the nuclear exchange between the United States and China, one of the first encounters she had with a spirit in their homeworld was a blood spirit tearing her apart while looking for food. She was fully in proper kit for a trip to the spirit world  —  the lanterns are to keep both her safety among the spirits and to let her blood flow properly respectively, and the orbs around her neck are filled with soil from her homeland to keep her body attached to the spirit world.</p>
<p>While she cannot die in this place, she retains full control of her nervous system, a bone of fact that was proved when the pain of having a hole torn through her hit her brain all at once.</p>
<p>Blood spirits, despite their name, actually take all kinds of fluids from spirits and physical creatures alike. They are easily warded off by other spirits, and are incapable of harming them properly. Should a blood spirit escape into the natural world, however, they would wreak havoc in search for food.</p>
<p>If you have any questions, I have answers. This is a pretty mediocre sketch of an idea I had.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>On the Concept of Childhood</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/gregori-children/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/gregori-children/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This post is part discussion, part lore.
Kojin Karatani, on the subject of childhood, writes;
Of course, children have existed since ancient times, yet &rsquo;the child&rsquo; as we conceive of it and objectify it did not exist prior to a particular period [&hellip;].
From this viewpoint, it becomes clear that the grouping of children by age in the compulsory educational system of modern Japan signified the uprooting of children, as abstract and homogenous entities, from productive relations, social classes, and communities that had previously been their concrete contexts.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/gregorichildren.jpg"/> <p><strong>This post is part discussion, part lore.</strong></p>
<p>Kojin Karatani, on the subject of childhood, writes;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Of course, children have existed since ancient times, yet &rsquo;the child&rsquo; as we conceive of it and objectify it did not exist prior to a particular period [&hellip;].</p>
<p>From this viewpoint, it becomes clear that the grouping of children by age in the compulsory educational system of modern Japan signified the uprooting of children, as abstract and homogenous entities, from productive relations, social classes, and communities that had previously been their concrete contexts.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For my own world (the city-state of Vekllei and her alternate future) this idea is is something I’m experimenting with. As people <strong>of a modern world, we may contain within ourselves biases about what ‘childhood’ is.</strong></p>
<p>Karanati’s fundamental point is that, following the Meiji Restoration in Japan, their education system modernised, and took on the Western idea of a ‘child’. Today, the development of children is staggered through very specific age groups  —  they play with kids their own age, they learn with kids their own age, and what we expect of them accompanies, in part, how we’ve structured school.</p>
<p>So in my world, I’ve tried to develop a system in which almost all age groups, or at least large groupings of them, learn inside the same classroom. If 25% of rooms in a school are dedicated general-learning classrooms, what could you do with the rest of the space? Dedicated science/language/athletic centres? Likewise, how would children playing with both older and younger kids influence their social development. And how would work (or employment), either in agrarian or industrial contexts, impact their growth as people?</p>
<p>As for lore:</p>
<p>I’ve tried to sketch a uniform here that is both visually interesting and simple enough to assemble (the girl, in this case, is wearing a less-common, formal variation). In keeping with the ideas above, the uniform would be consistent across all year groups.</p>
<p><strong>Things of note on the girl</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Flowers are a large part of femininity, in particular ‘girlishness’, and elaborate headdresses like the one here are common for picture days and ceremony</li>
<li>She wears a lace apron above her skirt, under the pleat, called a ‘Soitres Deh’ (soo-treh deh), which is ceremonial and very delicate. Some wear it to announce they’ve entered a relationship. Usually not worn to school.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Things of note on the boy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>His cap, while part of the uniform, is more commonly worn in fields and factories as a labourer’s cap, and is emblazoned with the emblem of the enterprise or school. Very common in Vekllei.</li>
</ul>
<p>So what to you think? I’ve given enough detail to stop people reading it, but not enough to properly explore the idea of childhood. What do you think? How do you deal with education in your world?</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Bridging of Worlds Ritual</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/bridging/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/bridging/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora is the oldest person alive, now aged 1,056 years. With the body, temperament, and vitality of an 11-year-old, and the lived experience of a dozen generations, she is a victim Gregori syndrome. She has seen man rise from Earth into space, and although she still calls her birth-country of Vekllei on Earth home, she frequently tours the cosmos as part of complex interplanetary diplomacy. The press calls her the Princess of the Earth.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/worldsritual.jpg"/> <p><strong>Tzipora is the oldest person alive, now aged 1,056 years.</strong> With the body, temperament, and vitality of an 11-year-old, and the lived experience of a dozen generations, she is a victim Gregori syndrome. She has seen man rise from Earth into space, and although she still calls her birth-country of Vekllei on Earth home, she frequently tours the cosmos as part of complex interplanetary diplomacy. The press calls her the Princess of the Earth.</p>
<p>In 3,119 A.D., she visits the Ra system. She meets the people there, called Roala, who were once descendents of East Asia on Earth. Here she takes part in an ancient ritual in which she bridges herself between the spirit and human worlds.</p>
<hr>
<p>She is dressed in both ordinary Vekllei clothing, which is familiar and Earthly, and Roala ceremonial dress patterned with reflective gems.</p>
<ul>
<li>Using her left hand, she guides the angle of power.</li>
<li>Her right hand, raised above her head, is the focus of power and is anchored to the human world by her left foot. If she breaks the angle directed by her left hand, and they become unaligned, she will lose her physical space in both worlds and collapse into nothing.</li>
</ul>
<p>For a few minutes at a time, she is able to see and contact both the human and spirit worlds.</p>
<ul>
<li>As she closes the ritual, the power of the stars wane, and so her heart becomes an auxiliary power source to help close the bridge. As it strains under the pressure of joining two worlds, her heart glows through her shirt.</li>
<li>At this moment, plants die under her feet and she mustn’t be touched, otherwise the bridge will cascade into a wider collapse that can destroy several people.</li>
<li>Finally, her heart settles and Tzipora collapses into the arms of a photographer, dripping with sweat and sapped of all strength.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>It is a great privilege to know how to contact the spirit world. Ordinary Earth people like Tzipora usually have ask for passage from the bones of angels, called Derden. But out here, with the Roala, she partakes in their way of life to cement the bond humanity has across systems.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Anarchy in Cherry, Nevada</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/anarchist/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/anarchist/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The young Republican has waited in a queue to have her photo taken in front of the remains of Cherry, Nevada. Her hair is still short after the fascists shaved her head, and branded her with St David’s star because she had a Jewish name. She would later tell the Republican Militia that she wasn’t, in fact, a Jew. The Militia didn’t care.
So she drapes herself in the anarchist flag and holds an ancient Mosin rifle she’d never fired, and for a moment she is part of something bigger than herself — of hope, and anger, and brotherhood.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/anarchist.jpg"/> <p><strong>The young Republican has waited in a queue to have her photo taken in front of the remains of Cherry, Nevada</strong>. Her hair is still short after the fascists shaved her head, and branded her with St David’s star because she had a Jewish name. She would later tell the Republican Militia that she wasn’t, in fact, a Jew. The Militia didn’t care.</p>
<p>So she drapes herself in the anarchist flag and holds an ancient Mosin rifle she’d never fired, and for a moment she is part of something bigger than herself  —  of hope, and anger, and brotherhood. These are the things that fuel the Republican movement, despite its infighting and poor equipment. There are many factions within the Militia  —  the Moscow-backed Marxist-Leninists, anarchists, Trotskyists, and smaller liberal sects. For now, they fight together against the fascists.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>The Vanguard movement grew in the South after decades of poverty and neglect from the federal government</strong>. Vanguardism was ostensibly about family and Southern nobility, but was always unmistakably fascist at its core, and part of a wider populist movement across the world in 2063. Many Southerners found themselves choosing between enlisting with the socialists, or death. Because for many, that’s what it was. Fascism was death  —  if they didn’t shoot the Jew or the socialist or the negro, they would displace them into oblivion. It was worth picking up a rifle for.</p>
<p>The young girl here, Tzipora, aged eleven, would later be disillusioned by the Republican movement and escape it. She had seen too many terrible things performed on behalf of the Militia, and the anarchists were being sabotaged by Moscow. This was the ultimate product of the civil war  —  bitter, jaded soldiers who had been stripped of their idealism and vitality. Fascist or socialist, everything they had fought for had died in the South.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
