<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Childhood and Modernity</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Because the other girls would not stop calling her a lesbian, and because they had realised she was scared of loud noises and made use of that fact, Tzipora struck this bitch and her friend out beyond the football pitches after school. Tzipora was a good fighter — on her side is viciousness and a conviction to fight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas everyone (plus a little Christmas story)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She had always been a very serious girl, from the first time he’d met her. It was more than a reflection of character; it was how she talked, how she carried herself. Her clothes were plain, her nervous tics were not that funny, and she was afflicted with all sorts of fears and anxieties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Suburban Constabulary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The constabulary is old-fashioned and it can’t last forever. It predates Petticoat-era Vekllei, the previous regime lost to atomic ash, and even the monarchy itself — it was the first community militia of the country and a great deal of romanticism that had been lost in the death of the monarchy has been invested in them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
