<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>2018 on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2018/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2018 on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>On Childhood and Modernity</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   Because the other girls would not stop calling her a lesbian, and because they had realised she was scared of loud noises and made use of that fact, Tzipora struck this bitch and her friend out beyond the football pitches after school. Tzipora was a good fighter — on her side is viciousness and a conviction to fight.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Merry Christmas everyone (plus a little Christmas story)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  She had always been a very serious girl, from the first time he’d met her. It was more than a reflection of character; it was how she talked, how she carried herself. Her clothes were plain, her nervous tics were not that funny, and she was afflicted with all sorts of fears and anxieties. She opens her mouth in public and what comes out is usually of serious opinion — a judgement of something or a political remark.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Suburban Constabulary</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  The constabulary is old-fashioned and it can’t last forever. It predates Petticoat-era Vekllei, the previous regime lost to atomic ash, and even the monarchy itself — it was the first community militia of the country and a great deal of romanticism that had been lost in the death of the monarchy has been invested in them.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Valley of the Dead</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-17-valley/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-17-valley/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  As Zelda got older and her sense of urgency decayed, the bone between life and death seemed to grow less important as time went on. Could you blame her? She was eighty years old at this point and still as fresh as fourteen — suspended somewhere in the misery of her old age and enthusiasm of her youth.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Cosmojet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-14-cosmojet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-14-cosmojet/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  The Ramoin-Dupont H700A “Cosmojet” series are the primary carrier-based fighters of Vekllei. They’re a real bitch to fly. Beloved as they are iconic, variations of the Cosmojet (H600A, B, H500A, etc.) make up the bulk of Vekllei’s total fighter outfit. Unconventional inverted gull wings and embedded turbofan engines make for a striking and uniquely Vekllei aircraft.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Metro Days</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-11-metro/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-11-metro/</guid>
	  <description> Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Flower Tundra</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-10-flower-tundra/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-10-flower-tundra/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   The two girls caught a train from school to the terminus, and then a rural line as far as it would take them out of the city. They had walked the granite shoulder of a mountain range for most of the afternoon, carrying only a few mouthfuls of provisions between them. They were both dressed in winter uniforms for the summer hike.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rural Trains</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-05-rural-trains/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-05-rural-trains/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  I caught a train out of Tokyo as far as it would go, and I ended up on a little platform in the mountains. Nice place.
Vekllei has a lot of mountains and a lot of trains.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Koka parks &amp; municipal recreation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-04-koka-parks/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-04-koka-parks/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Between the atomic fire that ruined the city, and the death of the king, there was a time when the city of Vekllei once resembled its lifeless lava fields to the North. In the communities that gathered themselves in the shadow of holocaust, common agriculture like fruits and berries returned to the city in what they call koka parkland.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The guilt dies with her</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-16-guilt/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-16-guilt/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Some years ago, she was in the desert. At the time she had just fallen out with her lover, and their friends had sided with him. The reasons why they had sided with him seemed to matter less and less as time wore on — they might have always liked him better.
They were self-styled anarchists waging war against the Indian Springs Sheriff’s Department, who operated one of the larger camps north of Las Vegas.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy Summer Everyone</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-05-summer/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-05-summer/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  In Down Under it&amp;rsquo;s coming around summer, and things are heating up. It&amp;rsquo;s not my fault Yanks broke the northern hemisphere and made the weather go wrong.
Vekllei gets warm in the summer, reaching heights of 30C occasionally. For a variety of reasons. A city of gardens and flowerbeds (the most flowers per capita in the world, actually), apartment dwellers take turns watering their local gardens and clearing weeds.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Talking about Girl Scouts and Child Soldiers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-04-scout/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-04-scout/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  About half of Vekllei kids go through the &amp;lsquo;Blossom&amp;rsquo; network of youth orgs at some point in their lives. Yeah, youth groups are popular nowadays. The Boy Scouts and Girl Guides of the United States are as mandatory as schooling in some states, and various Red Pioneers around the world test orthodoxy in Soviet and Red Chinese children.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Stewards of the Earth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-30-steward/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-30-steward/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Upen is the animistic religion of Vekllei. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have priests, but it has ceremony, and it shapes every part of the country today. From apartment cooperatives to the types of cotton used in clothing, Upen has extraordinary reach for an ostensibly agnostic and secular country.
It works out that way because Upen is not an organised religion, and resembles more closely a collective spiritualism with supernatural beliefs.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Let’s look at military fashion, because why not?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-22-fashion/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-22-fashion/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Unlike the United States and Western Europe, the ‘teen-ager’ has not been discovered in Vekllei. To be pedantic, they do technically exist — their people do indeed enter a transitory stage between childhood and adulthood, as far as anyone can tell — but they do not exist as a separate cultural identity. The teen-age person in Vekllei is immersed in adult economic and social relationships, and so they have no real cultural material of their own.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Collapse of the South</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-05-south/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-05-south/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  In October of 2074, the Ford Motor Company was embroiled in political catastrophe after Vermont senator Henry Walsh accused unionism in its East-Coast plants of traitorism by allowing foreign spies to acquire jobs in the Company. Whether the spies were Soviet or Chinese changed several times in Walsh’s accusations, but the claims themselves were not entirely unfounded.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>real sadboi posting hours</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-29-sadboi/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-29-sadboi/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Coming up on 2am here in East Australia. Had a rough day at work. Feeling pretty isolated and my other job starts in a few hours. I don’t know if it’s intrusive thoughts from OCD or just something everyone has, but four or five times a day I’ll have some sort of regret pop right into my head.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>School uniforms for girls</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-25-uniforms/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-25-uniforms/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  From preschool to university and beyond, all students wear a variant of the same uniform. The kindergartners may not wear a full gi and camisole pinafore, but the basic ensemble is still there. This is the girl’s one, and it’s much more elaborate than the boy’s uniform.
Year-round, all students wear a school armband with their year and class embroidered on it and a badge of education, which is pinned to the top button.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Some notes on the end of the world</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-19-endgame/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-19-endgame/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  A single hiss, the heavy door rolls back, and it derails into sandbags. A gas piston grinds, an engine ignites, and a roar sends flames pouring fifty feet high out of the silo as a sleek missile emerges and climbs towards hunting altitude.
This missile will strike Lanzhou, China. The larger cities, swollen with people, are protected by antimissile laser batteries.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>KID COMIX</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-11-comix/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-11-comix/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  There are some comics that Vekllei syndicates just won’t publish. KID Magazine, or KID Comix ran for nearly a century. It was picked up and dropped by dozens of anonymous artists, writers and editors, all operating under nonsense pseudonyms — Red, Squick, Failson and Daddy Fun were some of the longest-serving. It would go out of print for years, until some contributing artist would revive the mailing list and recruit new editors and writers.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Masculinity &amp; Fatherhood in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-07-masculinity/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-07-masculinity/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Just a few notes on what it means to be a man in Vekllei.
Vekllei is a country at odds with itself. On one hand, it is universal in its politics and fundamentally internationalist; on the other it is a deeply traditional country that values bloodlines and heritage. It is a secular democracy that regularly alludes to monarchy in its rituals and symbolism.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Grocery Economy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-06-shot/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-06-shot/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   A fluorescent light burst on Thursday. She was stacking cans for a display. The girl was working alone that evening and leaving her mark everywhere — happy apple drawings, new posters, displays — she liked the job.
The light burst like a gunshot and she leapt to her feet. Down the aisle she saw herself, at the lowest point in her life, standing over an old friend.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>summer nerds reading comix</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-29-nerds/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-29-nerds/</guid>
	  <description> Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>big mood right now</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-28-mood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-28-mood/</guid>
	  <description> Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Constabulary</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-23-constabulary/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-23-constabulary/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Policing is always difficult in utopian planning. On one hand, utopia is inherently opposed to the idea of policing and the can of worms it brings — on the other, people need to feel safe and protected. That’s not something I’ll be talking about today.
The Vekllei Constabulary are the second largest policing body in the country, after conventional police.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All-weather combat for the Atomic Age</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-20-troops/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-20-troops/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  The single most important function of today’s global powers is not in the numbers of men at a state&amp;rsquo;s command, or the prosperity of their domestic markets, but the ability to project power across the world entire.
We have seen this manifest in many ways; ICBMs are just one example. Warfare in a modern context has become a highly intelligent and specialised force that has simultaneously limited the brutality of warmongering while amplifying the ruthlessness and political function of state-sponsored murder.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>This is Blood Worship</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-19-blood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-19-blood/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Blood is everything to these women. It defines them through every stage of life — bloody emerging from the womb, bloody again in the delicate transition from child to womanhood, and bloody on the table, awaiting cremation in wait of the afterlife.
Even in her name — Zelda lo Ula Desmoines — the premise of blood is there.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Old, dead demons still wander the countryside</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-16-demons/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-16-demons/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   She met herself out by the shrine, many summers ago. At first she didn’t know what it was — she thought it might be a spirit, or — and she caught herself in the thought, because she was only half a child — a little part of her wondered if it was a manifestation of God, or Christ, come to help solve her problems.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Country of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-15-vekllei/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-15-vekllei/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  There is no real distinction between the city of Vekllei and the state of Vekllei, at least internally. To them, the country and the city are the same, and the isolated population centres of Montre and Adouisneh are simply distant neighbourhoods. This is reflected in all manners of life — they are ethnically and culturally homogenous, patriotic, and largely uncompetitive.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora&#39;s Portrait</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-08-portrait/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-08-portrait/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Practising colours. It&amp;rsquo;s always been my weakness. While you&amp;rsquo;re here, if you have any questions about Tzipora or want to chat, let me know.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Announcing the Princess of the Earth</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-01-princess/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-01-princess/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  They never actually believed that she was any kind of princess. They never even joked about it. The original LIFE magazine article said that she looked as though she were ‘a princess of the Earth’ when interviewer Alfie Ricci met her in the Vekllei highlands, and so she carried that name as a burden for the next few hundred years.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Valleys of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-28-valleys/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-28-valleys/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Two years ago, a fission military jet plunged into the mountain behind the village of Montre-Lola, emerging moments later as a plume of fire and smoke in the shadow of the mountain peak. Villagers made their way up the slopes to help survivors, dressed in radiation suits from the town shelter. There were none. Six more lives and six more soldiers lost — a pilot, co-pilot, navigator, reactor engineer, bombardier, and fire control officer are written down and then buried like cattle.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hot summer rain on a beach of black sand -- Iceland in 2127</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-20-black-sand/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-20-black-sand/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Just as Iceland&amp;rsquo;s initial history was reshaped into the image of Vekllei some centuries ago, so too has the real-world climate and weather been altered. Cool Icelandic summers have been usurped by volatile days that can be as low as 5C (40F) or as hot as 30C (85F+). Technically speaking, the unstable Atlantic pressure oscillation, of which Vekllei anchors as the Vekllei low pole, can pull in bitter cold from the Greenland currents, or warmth from the Azores tempestuously.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>winter love &#43; puffin / feat. Tzipora &amp; Akiko</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-19-puffin-love/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-19-puffin-love/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  &amp;ldquo;The puffin flies here so early (over the years). The further inland we go, the farther they chase us.&amp;rdquo;
That&amp;rsquo;s the sentiment of the phrase, but in Vekllei &amp;lsquo;The puffin flies here&amp;rsquo; is supplemented with the opening of a saying, &amp;lsquo;all birds flee the sea in Winter,&amp;rsquo; and so there is a reference here that is otherwise lost in translation.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Navy in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-15-salvo/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-15-salvo/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  There are not many warships in the world today that are distinctive as the serpentine-funnelled, semi-tumblehome hull of the Sundress-class supercruisers. For a country that prides itself on ‘petticoat society’, it is only suitable that Vekllei continues to pioneer the ‘dazzle’ warpaint in her navy.
 The most recent stock of Navy ships are all named after women’s clothes, to emphasise Vekllei’s spiritual understanding of gender in industrial society and also as a sarcastic nominer.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>What will become of the Gregori Children?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-10-gregori/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-10-gregori/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Did you know — many Gregori children do not form calluses on their skin, because of the intensity of their epidermic regeneration process!
Hello all,
The question on the mind of folks around the world is that of Gregori Children. What are they? What does it mean, to be a “Gregori Baby”?
 Gregori Regenerative Syndrome is a developmental phenomenon that afflicts children and young teen-agers.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Life in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-29-life/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-29-life/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Vekllei is the final stop in the epoch of rest. Departing your jetliner or aeroship and setting foot in the city is a spiritual experience — the weight of the world leaves your shoulders, and, at last, you are at peace. Imagine what that would be like — to be self-actualised!
 When I die, it will be in Vekllei.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Blood Names</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-14-blood-name/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-14-blood-name/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Each person in Vekllei has three names — a given name (Tzipora), a surname (Desmoines), and an alternative given name as part of rapotenne (potenne is ‘handtalk’, upotenne is ‘spirit-talk’, and so it follows that rapotenne is the language system of names). This alternative name is a ‘key’ to the full blood name of an individual, which are given in secret by the mother traditionally, but can be gifted by any mother-figure.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The dress code for talking to spirits</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-24-spirits/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-24-spirits/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  In Vekllei animism, which branches into a vast and complex set of beliefs and traditions that vary from village to village, there is no formal religious structure. Temples and shrines pay respect to sprites, which are universally understood as bi-planar creatures. There is no formal religious structure, and so animistic tradition has no priests.
Ceremonial dress is simple to describe, but complex to assemble.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-18-police-car/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-18-police-car/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Hopefully you won’t have to worry about the police while you’re in Vekllei, but you’ll likely notice them. Police are everywhere — as an alternative to military (duoroten) service, conscripts can elect to enter domestic security (inroten). Most officers are young, bored, and live in the community they police. You’ll likely be talking to them at some point in your visit, even if it’s only to ask for directions — in Vekllei, cops are the bulletin boards of the community.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>How to Bow (and Fashion in Vekllei)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-01-bowing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-01-bowing/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Vekllei has a pan-pacific flavour of greeting, usually a bow followed by a handshake. If you’re going to fit in, you’re going to have to learn how to do it right. Let’s get started.
First, Vekllei is extremely physical in its language. Not expressive, like how you might picture an Italian or American. Instead, it incorporates an auxiliary language called potenne or, ‘Hand-Talk’, which accompanies words.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Winter Clothing (and Womanhood in Vekllei)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-16-winter-clothing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-16-winter-clothing/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Welcome to Vekllei. It is a strange country with a complex culture that is quite distinct (and sometimes outrageous) to Western countries. This will be a long post. I’ve tried to keep it clear.
 Women in Vekllei usually wear skirts in winter. There are cultural and historical reasons for this, explained below. Pictured here is Tzipora in a winter Vekllei outfit so typical it works well enough here to give a show-and-tell.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Rail-Launched Nuclear Missiles</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-09-rail-missiles/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-09-rail-missiles/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  This is a concept of a Vekllei Rocketry Corp rail ICBM launcher. It has distinctive-looking carriages, and so it serves no real purpose in being a ‘hidden’ ICBM launcher. Instead, this train is for testing rail-mounted ICBMs, which are then employed in plain and unmarked railcars. Today it idles by the lakeside town of Dupot-Monan, as its senior control staff await a hot lunch driven in from the town.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Washing the Feet of the Enemy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-06-penance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-06-penance/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  He had sent her a wire some weeks before asking to meet her. She did not remember him. By now he was an old man, and she, a Gregori baby of sixty four years, had not aged a day. He was close to dying and wanted to relieve his soul of the war crimes he’d committed as a member of the Vanguard in the Second American Civil War.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Sketch of a Blood Spirit</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-03-03-demon/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-03-03-demon/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Blood spirits are unaware people have physical forms. Why should they? No person has entered the realm of the spirits in a millenia.
When the Princess of the Earth arrived, after the nuclear exchange between the United States and China, one of the first encounters she had with a spirit in their homeworld was a blood spirit tearing her apart while looking for food.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>On the Concept of Childhood</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-02-23-childhood/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-02-23-childhood/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  This post is part discussion, part lore.
Kojin Karatani, on the subject of childhood, writes;
 Of course, children have existed since ancient times, yet &amp;lsquo;the child&amp;rsquo; as we conceive of it and objectify it did not exist prior to a particular period [&amp;hellip;].
From this viewpoint, it becomes clear that the grouping of children by age in the compulsory educational system of modern Japan signified the uprooting of children, as abstract and homogenous entities, from productive relations, social classes, and communities that had previously been their concrete contexts.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Bridging of Worlds Ritual</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-25-ritual/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-25-ritual/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Tzipora is the oldest person alive, now aged 1,056 years. With the body, temperament, and vitality of an 11-year-old, and the lived experience of a dozen generations, she is a victim Gregori syndrome. She has seen man rise from Earth into space, and although she still calls her birth-country of Vekllei on Earth home, she frequently tours the cosmos as part of complex interplanetary diplomacy.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Anarchy in Cherry, Nevada</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-15-anarchy/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-15-anarchy/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  The young Republican has waited in a queue to have her photo taken in front of the remains of Cherry, Nevada. Her hair is still short after the fascists shaved her head, and branded her with St David’s star because she had a Jewish name. She would later tell the Republican Militia that she wasn’t, in fact, a Jew.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>