<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019 on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019 on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-26-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-26-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  I’m still eating pudding, but once I’m home tomorrow and settled at my drawing desk I’ll be sure to report Tzipora’s holiday adventures in full.
For the Christmasfolk out there, enjoy your presents. To everyone else, have a good holiday and be sure to celebrate the Australian way — with prawns, salmon and snags on the barbie.
(Gorgeous 25°C [77°F] yesterday)
Best,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Kodak Moment by a Vekllei Geyser</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In her journal for practicing writing the Vekllei language (appropriately called Vekllei), Tzipora wrote:
 The heavy clouds above were children of early spring, but among the steam vents it seemed like the whole sky was polluted by geysers. Large pools, opalescent with healthy minerals, were heated by the core of the Earth. In a volcanic desert of black sand, the geysers were an oasis, rising from the sulphuric fog like a little eden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life and Death in Vekllei Apartment Ideology, or “Newda”</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  To substitute for my shocking (and deeply shameful) absence over the last two weeks, please accept a longer-form post concerning domestic Apartment Ideology in Vekllei, which they call Newda and is known internationally as The Vekllei Newda School. Pictured is the apartment of our very own Zelda. While the building itself deserves a feature, for now we’ll discuss Newda as a theory and her life in this building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A “Horizon Wing” Atomic Passenger Jet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Click here for a view inside the wing.
Although the CN-1 Horizon Wing passenger jet was not a “flying wing,” that didn’t stop Comen Aeroyards, the manufacturer, from celebrating it as such. Much like similar large-wing aircraft from McDonnell and de Havilland, the CN-1’s large vertical stabilisers and obvious centre fuselage precluded it from qualifying as an authentic “flying wing,” which were already common in many air forces at this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak Sneak</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-11-sneak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-11-sneak/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   He kept bad hours. Sometimes he worked so hard he came home in the early morning and fell asleep to the television with the subtitles on. Like a guerrilla sighting a commanding officer, she would approach discreetly, wearing her blanket like a cape and bouncing on her toes. With a gentle movement she&amp;rsquo;d drape it over him and listen for a break in his snoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside VOA’s “Flying Wing” Atomic Passenger Jet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-09-wing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-09-wing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In this limited cross-section of a CN-1 “Horizon” Wing, the scale of the aircraft is immediately impressed upon the reader. It is nearly four times as wide as the older wide-body passenger jets of yesteryear, and twice as wide as most American and European supersonic jets. It is no coincidence that the “flying wing” concept was only made possible by the development of supersonic jetport infrastructure, with their wide and long runways, at the turn of the century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallabies of the Arctic — Vekllei&#39;s Pademelon and what the hell it&#39;s doing there</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-06-wallabies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-06-wallabies/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   8 days without posts feels like a century. Tomorrow, SkyMonth returns, and we’ll see what it’s like flying VAS. The day after tomorrow we’ll see an update for a few things — particularly a massive (and awesome) overhaul of the Vekllei site + wiki. Yeah, if you’re wondering where I’ve been, I’ve ditched Wordpress and have been learning HTML, which is like scraping the exposed brain against unpolished concrete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Trouble</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora never lost her youthful curiosity. She would swish about the apartment, chasing an idea or plan that had occurred to her. Baron would look over and say “What are you doing, Zelda? Making trouble?” He said that a lot. He would come home in the afternoon and she would be writing lists, or organising her paperbacks, or moving furniture and he’d say, “What are you up to, Zelda?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicating despair in the pasture of plenty</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora is doing well now. She has looked into her heart and made peace with who she is. She has discovered she is a girl who likes free jazz, and milky coffee, and cotton shirts, and trains — to the surprise of no-one who knows her. She knows what things she values in a friend, and what deserves to become family. She knows what clothes she likes and how to do her hair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean-liners of the Sky — Vacuum Dirigibles in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-24-dirigible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-24-dirigible/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Sorry it took so long, mateys. I&amp;rsquo;ve been laying the first pages of the comic down and it&amp;rsquo;s like crack for me. Not much sleep and totally fell behind on SkyMonth. But, as any longtime members know, our Months are r/vekllei usually last a little longer than they should past their expiry date. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to come!
 The Angel and Memory of the People of Vekllei is the largest and most recent of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s airships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Stewards in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-19-stewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-19-stewards/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Although Vekllei’s flag-carrying airline might appear just one of many in the small island country, don’t be fooled — all civilian aviation operates under a venrouive bureau excitingly titled the Vekllei Air Service (Skyburo), which operates several distinct ‘airlines’ but wholly controls all of them. In Vekllei economic lexicon, a bureau is the largest trade union of an industry, made up of many hundreds of others, and is partially beholden to the direction of government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Shoes</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-18-blue-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-18-blue-shoes/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Welcome to the r/Vekllei variety hour, where the tone between posts judders so inconsistently you&amp;rsquo;ll get whiplash of the mind. I was just drawing and thinking today. This is an author post, in case you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed &amp;ndash; just a shitty blog.
You see, even today I&amp;rsquo;m wildly jealous of the success of those slice-of-life artists on reddit and Twitter. I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand the genre entirely, as a phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten corpses in the snow, and a change of government in the American South</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve just pulled a body from an air force jet here that looks like General MacMillan, and we really need to know right now if it&amp;rsquo;s him.”
The partially buried remains of a U.S. Air Force passenger aircraft are the only blemish on the horizon of central Greenland’s frigid snowscape. It is the site of one of the greatest political scandals in American history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Beaches to Mountaintops</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-15-mountaintops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-15-mountaintops/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  I had the wonderful opportunity to work with one of our resident worldbuilders on reddit, u/EpicJM, and spend a while with their world and characters. The world of Eipljord has a lot of distinct, unique cultures and characters. As a sucker for uniforms I went with the garb of the Pruscyldan Academy of Magic, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find JM&amp;rsquo;s character, Honora being splattered with ice cream by Tzipora on the left and in Vekllei education uniform on the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</guid>
      <description>Station Dogs #  I’m starting a series looking at the lives and machines of domestic Vekllei life.
Vekllei National Railways, or ‘VK Rail’ was the bastard of six major pre-war rail companies that were extinguished along with the society that housed them. Today there are three rail companies in Vekllei, but all of them operate under direct supervision of a Vekllei Industry Bureau ( making it Venrouiva, in other words) and are only broken up for reasons of logistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carry me! &gt;:(</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora and Cobian. They have not been friends for very long but they like each other a lot. Tzipora weighs nearly 10kg less than her friend, so she gets piggy backs more often.
By me! @melon.kony or r/vekllei on reddit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd Draft</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  I first saw this film at a low point in my life, and watching Shizuku discover her ability was one of the most touching things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan-art guy, but I still find myself thinking about them years later and I wanted to paint them happy after the end of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Vekllei?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Vekllei is a country in my alt-world; a utopian fever dream of googie aesthetics, participatory economics and nostalgia.
Welcome to the ‘Petticoat Project’, a collection of stories about a country and a girl. The concept is broken down into three sections:
 Author: for blog posts and articles on the Petticoat Project, utopian fiction, personal news item, etc. Character: for posts about Tzipora, people in her life, or otherwise events that occur during her time on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei’s Elite Military Units — the Garden Corps and their bloody war against weeds</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post
 On Tuesday, two casualties were reported among Vekllei’s Folifedestarmie 24th and 25th Garden Companies in the ongoing war to make the capital’s parks the finest in the world. Michael Helen-Louisviuan cut his leg on an exposed nail during the deinstallation of old fence posts, and Ana Po cut her thumb on a rose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shōwa memories</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  new r/worldbuilding post soon, just filling in my garbage upload schedule with generic anime and shōwa nostalgia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer sex-ed</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Porno is available over-the-counter at most book stores. Some industry associations attempt to limit availability to minors but generally it&amp;rsquo;s at the discretion of the shopkeeper. Often, shame and embarassment are more powerful tools than legislation in Vekllei.
Generally it&amp;rsquo;s pretty traditional stuff supported by columns and fiction, although it varies between pornographers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of &#34;Human Decay&#34;</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Talking about utopia in landscape is easy — Vekllei is a glittering midcentury paradise that fosters human life as a wonderful dream.
Talking about utopia in character is much harder. How can you find utopia in flawed and sometimes unattractive human beings? By what metric is the vague, intuitive values of a utopia measured against a living person?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Summers in the Arctic (and Newda architecture)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post here.
The Café Resmoiones approaches its hundredth birthday as the girls outside await their fifteenth. The building was once a kindergarten, so they’d been told, but through decades of Vekllei’s irreverent planning it had become a café. It was not a very good café, the food was shit, but the building was nice and it was at the bottom of Lola’s steep residential hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post here.
 Six bodies hung from the Rodney Creek Railroad Bridge, without names. The leftmost corpse, which was a boy, had a sign slung around his neck with tomorrow’s 8am train on it. Besides the swaying boy was his father, and next to him was his mother, and so it went down the railroad bridge, counting off his little sisters and grandmama and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Much love to all of you</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching a steam locomotive to school</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Most of the kids pictured here are the cubs of lumberfolk who make a living out of felling hard pines in the mountains in the North of Vekllei. About half have dark hair and rounder faces, as descendants of both inuits and Scandinavians, and others are of mixed ancestry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora Desmoines, the Eternal Teen-ager and Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora. She goes by two names &amp;ndash; Tzipora, her birth name, and Zelda, a name she mistakenly thought sounded less Jewish. She lives in Lola in the Vekllei city-state.
As an immigrant, she struggles with school but holds her own on in track and field, an inversion of her otherwise quiet and bookish nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The participatory economy of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Nestled between the regional tram offices and the pre-war Ferouistet Department Store, the Lola district is not known for much but her department store and good schools. It sits on the slope of the wide Vekllei capital basin, where the Atlantic can be seen from the street. It was Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s first home in Vekllei, and it was where she lived with her father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dad&#39;s Birthday</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Littlest Goddess in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The Palace Gods live in decadence in an isolated and incestuous land above the mortal planes called the Palace. They do not eat and will live forever, provided they stay within the gardens of the Palace and consummate their industrial godhood occasionally with domen, an opium that they believe purifies blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young and Educated</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  lmao wish I had nice clothes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mineral Lake starts absorbing Grief in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Rena’s little boy was found in the closest town with his guts turned out and his throat cut. They didn’t tell it to Rena like that, but that’s what happened to him. His village and people, the Lehmanen, are descendants of Palace Gods forced out of the heavens some millennia ago over their refusal to smoke Domen, a sort of opium of the Gods and essential practice in the Palace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Celebration of all Women across the World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Vekllei on the first of each May, the women’s councils and industrial unions wipe clean their banners and flags and join great parades that regale the main streets of the city with song and colour. They carry flags and banners in celebration of womanhood and remembrance of the dead — for those Potter’s Fields and unmarked graves that intern nameless women across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Palace Gods attempt to retrieve their runaway child</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She could feel the wind rising. The horizon beyond was warped, caught in the distortion of a forested planetoid before them. The morning sun cast a honeyed warmth on her wings of black sugar, which sang like wind chimes as she soared high above the gem deserts below. Hyssop, her new and only friend, followed her ungracefully under the spell of his flystone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sugarhouse Mountain Fortress</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  A hundred years ago, the fortress existed as a spectre of the neighbouring villages; a beast of suffering and woe with fingers deep into the mountains around Montre. In the waning days of the military junta, the beast’s creators, the Sugarhouse Fort served as a strategic command centre for Vekllei’s nuclear arsenal and a blacksite to disappear the most prolific and dangerous agitators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Generation</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  We best know Vekllei as a dense society of utopia and great infrastructure today, but there was blood in that crucible. It is difficult to imagine that only fifty years ago these streets were unpaved and impassible with the rubble of old society. Shadows on concrete marked the souls lost in the arrogance of the monarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Raid</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-25-air-raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-25-air-raid/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She loved helping out. It was important to her, as an ageless girl of ultimately transient relationships, to be able to establish for herself a family wherever she lived. So within a few years of her arrival in Vekllei, she put time in as a warden for her apartment block and undertook the medical training that went with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Long Moment</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-21-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-21-moment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The whole world gives way to a moment of silence. The other seasons are filled with noise and marrow, jerking and twisting with the pace of the clock. But a moment lasts forever — and wintertime is one long moment.
Although the uniforms got heavier and the commutes longer, Zelda would always like the wintertime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gem girl shows off her enormous strength in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The subcontinent of Zen on the Pachinki pangea is so weathered by enormous gem deserts that there is scarcely enough space to grow wheat for bread. In places where the soil is too thin for heavy wheats, sparrowgrass is grown. This grass has large heads that can be eaten raw and taste citrusy and acidic as they only grow in toxic soils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Old for Sleepovers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Even for those ageless kids, there’s a time when the charade of childhood comes to a head and begs a certain uncomfortable question: at what point does the whole thing — of immaturity, of carelessness, of sleepovers — start looking like two old women posturing around youth, indulging in a sick genetic perversion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A story of community policing and sweet militia</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-03-militia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-03-militia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  As part of sundress municipalism, Vekllei’s villages and townships are mostly self-sufficient and self-regulating. Although a walk in the capital will take you past colossal apartment blocks and cinemas, libraries and schools of great magnificence, you are really looking at a hundred different communities going about personal business at their leisure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look...!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-02-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-02-look/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Look at it!
The bastard ate the lettuce! There&amp;rsquo;s a hole in the wire!
He&amp;rsquo;s cute but he&amp;rsquo;s a bastard!
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing a train for over two weeks now and I needed to draw something alive before I shinkansenned myself. This only took an hour or two but I&amp;rsquo;m not drawing enough and it feels like I&amp;rsquo;m running out of time to get good at drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
