<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Lin Zhi on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/zhi/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Lin Zhi on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/zhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Café Diplomacy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-07-12-vista/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-07-12-vista/</guid>
	  <description>Instafilm #445. Marked &amp;ldquo;2064&amp;rdquo;. Month of the Mosses. You remembered that because it was about the same time war broke out in the Congo again. Everyone at the table had opinions about that war, but not much to do with it. Everyone asked Coretti what she thought about the war. She hated that, she hated being singled out for it. Coretti had been two years old when she left the Congo.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All Chapels for All Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-03-09-chapel/</guid>
	  <description>As we come marching, marching, in the beauty of the day,
A million darkened kitchens, a thousand mill-lofts gray
Are touched with all the radiance that a sudden sun discloses,
For the people hear us singing, &amp;ldquo;Bread and Roses, Bread and Roses.&amp;rdquo;
As we come marching, marching, we battle, too, for men &amp;ndash;
For they are women&amp;rsquo;s children and we mother them again.
Our days shall not be sweated from birth until life closes &amp;ndash;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Socialism, Backwards</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-20-socialism/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-20-socialism/</guid>
	  <description>Tzipora had become interested in the blossoms of Vekllei society around the same time she became aware of them. That’s actually what they were called, in the pidgin of Vekllei ideology — the tenets of petticoat-style socialism were called blossoms.
Vekllei maintains it is not ideological; it is in fact very ideological — you are looking at a state that is afraid of its skeleton. In the dawning weeks after Vekllei’s catastrophic war, the British occupiers (British Recovery Expedition to Vekllei, or BREVEK) released into the streets some 16,000 activists who were rotting away in political prisons.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Generation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-21-generation/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-08-21-generation/</guid>
	  <description>Children of the children of the bomb — a generation of war-babies born in peacetime. That was how they thought of themselves. Their grandparents and great-grandparents had lived through the war and the occupation, and so they had inherited the burden of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s future as a country of long-sufferers, visionaries, and dispossessed.
Some Marxist continental intellectual had said something a half-century ago about the right way to teach children, and the idea had probably caught the ear of some commissar of the Vekllei interim government, who perhaps passed it along to some bureaucrat rebuilding the government schools.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei&#39;s New-Age Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</guid>
	  <description>A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.
— Lu Xun, 1927
Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &amp;lsquo;backward elements.&amp;rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.
— Ding Ling on the long-marcher woman soldiers, 1942
When Tzipora first arrived in Vekllei in 2063, she was traumatised by the foreignness of everything.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Justice</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</guid>
	  <description>Lin Zhi was nuts. She was lovely, but she was nuts. Tzipora followed along, pleading occasionally, a squeaking voice of concern. The cricket bat dragged and bounced along the poor road sealing.
“You could go to prison,” Tzipora said, protesting weakly. “Why not send Moise and his boys? They’ll put the fear of God in him.”
“This is stupid,” Zhi said in clumsy Vekllei, staring ahead. “You do not know what it’s like.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>