<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>infograph on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/infograph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in infograph on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/infograph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Speak Vekllei, and A New Website</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, https://millmint.net. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.
This post will briefly discuss some elements shown in this infographic, but a large article on the language has been drafted here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 31st Century — Vekllei throughout our Solar System</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   The Epoch of Rest #  We’ve spent a lot of time in the 21st century — but Tzipora is biologically immortal. Where does she go from here? Well, let’s enjoy a small glimpse at that future together, by winding the clock forward one thousand years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Unique among girls #  There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not realise she is unusual, or does not care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora’s ‘Every Day Carry’</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Like a lot of girls of poverty, Tzipora was very possessive of her things. No food was ever left on her plate. There was a deep anxiety that whatever wasn’t claimed would be lost.
She was also naturally obsessive and material-oriented, keenly aware of the importance of objects measured by metrics in her own silly head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Crown — coins of a moneyless country</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031 Apartment Diagram</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.   Baron had inherited the apartment from his uncle, who passed in the year following his parents. It was in a mixed residential-industrial neighbourhood, adjacent to a canvas factory. Out back was a rivulet, which roared in the long rainstorms of early April.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</guid>
      <description>Station Dogs #  I’m starting a series looking at the lives and machines of domestic Vekllei life.
Vekllei National Railways, or ‘VK Rail’ was the bastard of six major pre-war rail companies that were extinguished along with the society that housed them. Today there are three rail companies in Vekllei, but all of them operate under direct supervision of a Vekllei Industry Bureau ( making it Venrouiva, in other words) and are only broken up for reasons of logistics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
