<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>infograph on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/infograph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in infograph on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 05:22:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/infograph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 31st Century — Vekllei throughout our Solar System</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 05:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</guid>
      <description>The Epoch of Rest#We’ve spent a lot of time in the 21st century — but Tzipora is biologically immortal. Where does she go from here? Well, let’s enjoy a small glimpse at that future together, by winding the clock forward one thousand years.
By 3076, our Solar System is a pleasant place to be. Most of the planets we once gazed at from afar are now habitable and lived on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 06:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
      <description>Unique among girls#There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not realise she is unusual, or does not care.
She has a lot of endearing characteristics that give great character to her mannerisms and physicality. She has a small overbite that makes her look a little froggy, and ritually pulls on her shirt and wipes her nose in anxious conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora’s ‘Every Day Carry’</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 05:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</guid>
      <description>Like a lot of girls of poverty, Tzipora was very possessive of her things. No food was ever left on her plate. There was a deep anxiety that whatever wasn’t claimed would be lost.
She was also naturally obsessive and material-oriented, keenly aware of the importance of objects measured by metrics in her own silly head. You can discover a lot about a person from their trinkets and toys — let’s discover a bit about Tzipora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Crown — coins of a moneyless country</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 05:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
      <description>Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country. At no point do coins or paper currency change hands in the day-to-day affairs of the country.
In this sense, Vekllei is usually described as “moneyless” — yet it does in fact have a currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031 Apartment Diagram</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 02:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Baron had inherited the apartment from his uncle, who passed in the year following his parents. It was in a mixed residential-industrial neighbourhood, adjacent to a canvas factory. Out back was a rivulet, which roared in the long rainstorms of early April.
 Each January, the Colour Bureau of the Architecture Assembly announces the year’s colours, and tradition in mainstream architecture and interior design is to incorporate the announced palettes, which usually contain a hundred or so colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 23:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</guid>
      <description>Station Dogs#I’m starting a series looking at the lives and machines of domestic Vekllei life.
Vekllei National Railways, or ‘VK Rail’ was the bastard of six major pre-war rail companies that were extinguished along with the society that housed them. Today there are three rail companies in Vekllei, but all of them operate under direct supervision of a Vekllei Industry Bureau (making it Venrouiva, in other words) and are only broken up for reasons of logistics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
