<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Compor, Vekllei&#39;s Special Police</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-23-compor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-23-compor/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Where Tzipora lived in Lola, most people remained of the working class well into the utopian period. Despite their equitable access to the fruits of the country, their housing was poorer and their problems generational. Alcoholism was very common; many of them were veterans of the War in Taiwan. Others were in great pain from their early work in the postwar years, their bodies broken by the demons of manual labour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiritful</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-19-spiritful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-19-spiritful/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  There was not much different about one spirit than another. Foreigners mistook Upen, the animism of Vekllei, for environmentalism — that was not the case at all. Landscapes changed, and so did the things that lived in them.
Of course, humans are sentimental creatures, and they become attached to native things. It is important to seperate human desire — the protection of native plants and animals — and the interests of spirits, since they are not the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wicket-Keeper</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-15-wicket-keeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-15-wicket-keeper/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tzipora was good at cricket. That surprised everyone. Her teachers called her bookish; her classmates called her a dork. She didn’t look like a girl who played much sport. In America, at her old school, she was sick from gym class so regularly that they stopped asking about her absence.
In Vekllei, however, the sports were better. Instead of “gym class,” they had physical education — Phys Ed — that included a variety of weekly health classes, term carnivals, and daily callisthenics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I have a very good website</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-14-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-14-website/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hi everyone,
Hobart here, informing you that I have a very good website. It has every post I’ve ever made on it, for better or for worse (with the non-canon stuff marked). It has wiki pages that are growing all the time. It has fun things and essays. You can also leave comments!
 Just look at the home page. Isn’t that the coolest shit you’ve ever seen?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heavy Mist</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-11-mist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-11-mist/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The sky was heavy with grey and water, and it bled into the air. Vekllei’s moon months were here, and with it came the end of Vekllei’s bright summer season. In came the days of coats, mist and darkness.
Tzipora here wears rouisha, loose-fitting felt pants that have been worn in Vekllei for a thousand years. They’re often worn under a skirt, but can be worn alone as trousers if you like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generations</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Ayn was a naturally busy person. She worked long, hard hours at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence, or ‘AB/NI,’ as a clerk, or specialist, or whatever they needed her to be that day. Her days off were filled with petty occupations and minor obligations — mostly tending to her plants and cleaning. She enjoyed number puzzles. A couple friends had formed a book club, and she went to that on occasion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shabbat Shalom</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-07-shalom/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  When they met, Tzipora told Baron she was Catholic. He thought that was hilarious — it was one of the few times she saw him laugh. Her name was “Tzipora”, and she gave herself the name “Zelda” — who did she think she was kidding? But that’s just how she was; Tzipora was an intricate person of many backgrounds and instincts.
Baron was Jewish, but he didn’t practice much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Around at the Swimming Carnival</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-05-swimming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-05-swimming/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Each year, Lola 6th School traveled to the base of the Thanveler Glacier for its swimming carnival. There was a big thermal pool there, heated by the Earth, and students competed in races for prizes and ribbons.
Tzipora told people she couldn’t swim. That was true — she sank like a stone. But she didn’t tell them the other part — that she never wanted to learn how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Atomic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-04-air-atomic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-04-air-atomic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The Royal Vekllei Air Force runs nuclear these days. Just fifty years ago, that would have been unthinkable. Times change.
The Ramoin-Dupont Aircraft Company, with help from the research subsidiary of the absurdly-named “Government Aircraft Factories,” spent about two decades trying to get a reactor to fly. It was easy enough to build a plane around a fission reactor — the problem was keeping the pilot alive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNR Orange</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-03-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-03-orange/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Vekllei takes a lot from its land. That fact is the bedrock of the Vekllei way of life, in fact — land stewardship and dependency. In this sense, they owe a great debt to the physical landscape of the country, a concept usually translated as the ‘Landscape Sovereign’ in English. The human royals may be long dead, but Vekllei’s flowering petticoat society retains a monarch — the literal physical presence of the land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mossbound</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-02-mossbound/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-02-mossbound/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Outside of the cities, sensory pleasure can be enriched by Vekllei’s oldest organism, if you know where to look. The temperate rainforest is alive, and breathing, and smells cold in its freshness. The perfume of the rainforest is earthy and chilled, swirling in a cocktail of fresh water, rich, damp soil and the scents of thick mosses and browning leaves. Out here, only water and the trees move — these sounds are the domain of spirits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Station Logic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Vekllei is full of stations in the middle of nowhere; platforms for people in no hurry, alighting to places never thought of before. It is in these stations that old government infrastructure projects take on a greater meaning, and cultivate an absurd sort of spirituality that touches the lives of the people who discover them. Is there anything gentler than a concrete platform in the middle of a flower-tundra, weathered and warmed by the sun?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-31-topet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  This is an unusual post in that, a) it’s particularly text-heavy and desaturated, and b) much of its material is already available on an existing wiki article on my website.
The above article covers the language conceptually in pretty much all the detail you’d ever want. So, despite the heavy use of labels and text, this picture is particularly concerned with the literal appearance and structure of the Vekllei written language, called Topet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zelda&#39;s Guide to Living Forever</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  There’s no other way to put it — Tzipora is one of a kind. There are others like her, but fewer and fewer of them are born healthy as the years roll on. Her life is hard, she’d agree, but it’s also sprinkled with miracles. Meeting her, you might not even know she’s set to become the oldest person in history.
All stories settle on remarkable people, and Tzipora — with or without her absurd long-livedness — is a person of importance, and much more than the sum of her parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gone Hollywood</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-24-hollywood/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  You know you’re near the homeland of the Magma-Electric Commission when you smell it. Somewhere between cracking a rotten egg and standing downwind of a sewerage treatment plant, the volcanic heartlands of Vekllei are the playground of the Magma-Electric Commission, often shortened to just “The Magma” or “Thunderburo”. The smell is caused by Hydrogen Sulphide, a byproduct of the naked volcanic activity Vekllei is known for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vekllei Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-09-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-09-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Postwar Vekllei has a problem. In the old days, many hundreds of years ago, Vekllei’s long, dark winters forced subsistence farmers to preserve their dishes for six or seven months of the year. This changed under the Junta, which opened trade with the Scandinavian powers, and Vekllei soon saw its growing population dependent on fresh imports of oats and grain from Europe. These Atlantic people, whose diets were previously gamey and nomadic, were now a rough storm away from famine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrine-Minded Girls</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Shattered fjords make up the north of Vekllei, particularly in boroughs like Santes (lit. Saint) which are well-regarded for their striking cliffs and sloping igneous fingers, which evidence Vekllei’s ongoing volcanism. Offshore, hundreds of islets rise and sink over the centuries.
This is the tiny village of Cult, which sits on the sparse tip of the Grimsy Fjord. It has a local train, but is otherwise only serviced by the Santes regional express — a mere single step up on Vekllei’s train hierarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei National Rail</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-25-rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-25-rail/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Vekllei National Rail, or VNR, is one of those organisations caught somewhere between a faceless government enterprise and a family member.
Almost every Vekllei person rides a train each day, and that train is operated by VNR, which has a monopoly on rail travel and operation. Very few people know exactly what ‘VNR’ is. Is it a government department? A state-owned company? Or is it a “bureau” — the Vekllei word for a collection of companies?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Diplomacy</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-19-diplomacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-19-diplomacy/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Cobian first met Tzipora at Café Maz, though before then she knew her as ‘Tzipora, the New Girl,’ or, less favourably, ‘Tzipora the Gypsy,’ since there was some confusion about where she’d come from. The neighbourhood had known about her for a while, since people like to talk about foreigners, and when she was spotted at the Café people talked about that too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday. Summer Rains.</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-12-cosy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-12-cosy/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In summer, the sun is up all night. She wakes at five and spends the mornings by herself, reading the paper or a paperback. Baron works late — he wakes late. They have breakfast together, so until then she drinks coffee out of a packet and starts the fire if it’s cold. You were supposed to save power, but sometimes she ran her electric blanket all night, which kept her snug until the under-floor heating warmed up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold Sappers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The Venopor (Fedecenoayan porits, lit. Police of the Parliament) are Vekllei’s special police branch. They occupy a function somewhere between special policing and the paramilitary, linking Vekllei’s treasured infrastructure with its civilian police (“Cosmopor”), armed forces, and shadowy intelligence networks. Though they fulfil police functions today, their history is with the Royal Guards and Federal Police of yesteryear, which in turn has produced unusual units like the Gold Sappers, which are unique in modern policing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei&#39;s New-Age Women</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.
 — Lu Xun, 1927
 Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &amp;lsquo;backward elements.&amp;rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.
 — Ding Ling on the long-marcher woman soldiers, 1942</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Rivers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-27-rivers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Out in Voya Voya, the gardens light the people, and distill human temperament into momentary, sequential lyrical images. A dead leaf moving by miracle across still water; an overturned bucket collecting dew along its handle; fern leaves half-curled, young and growing. Vekllei is known as a “garden city,” and Voya Voya has the best of them. Vekllei urban planning is wandering and wasteful, and in this borough the city centre is checkered by wild parks filled with silence and rainforest smells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sand Mage</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-19-mage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-19-mage/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tzipora is a sand mage.
Actually, she isn’t, but I wanted to draw something with particles and ended up doing different paint sketches for a few hours. This was the best one, and also the most stupid.
Canonically, Tzipora can’t swim, so she spends more time on the beach than in the water. The colour of the sand here suggests it’s an artificial “white beach” in Mumen or nearby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Killing a Sea Serpent</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-17-serpent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-17-serpent/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Ocean Month in March 2021  In Eyri, the bones of an ancient beast warp and groan in the sun, red skin glinting in the whitecap churn of the shallows, oxidising, broken, ripped open by the sea. Everyone in the North of Vekllei knows about it. Mysteries abound. Even in our atomic century, the humans of Vekllei are enamoured with and terrified by the ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei’s Sprawling Commonwealth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-10-commonwealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-10-commonwealth/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Ocean Month in March 2021  Welcome again to Ocean Month. If you have questions, just ask.
When we say “Vekllei,” we most often think of the Home Island, the city-state to which the country owes its name. In practice, however, the state of Vekllei is portioned between many far-flung corners of the Atlantic Ocean. From tropical jungles and dry wine-making country to mossy woodlands and arctic deserts, “Vekllei” as a singular concept is obfuscated by its diversity of land and people, and better represents a coalition of disparate Atlantic states than a single, centralised city-state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marine Railway</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-06-marine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-06-marine/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Ocean Month in March 2021  ❖ Note from the Editor
Although vessels described here are written with female pronouns as per Western convention, Vekllei traditionally uses male pronouns for navy vessels.  Nuclear Heavy Battlecruiser V.V. Lava is the first of the Lava-class cruisers, the largest of Vekllei’s surface warships. Vekllei doctrine does not typically float cruisers with fleets, and so the Lava often operates independently, outfitted for a variety of roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-03-01-justice/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Lin Zhi was nuts. She was lovely, but she was nuts. Tzipora followed along, pleading occasionally, a squeaking voice of concern. The cricket bat dragged and bounced along the poor road sealing.
“You could go to prison,” Tzipora said, protesting weakly. “Why not send Moise and his boys? They’ll put the fear of God in him.”
“This is stupid,” Zhi said in clumsy Vekllei, staring ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post is for People</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  Caught amidst sunrays in early Autumn, things are good. You could call almost anyone on the telephone these days. And if you wanted to see someone, why travel? A videophone was just as good. But just as the photograph failed to displace the painter, neither did the telephone or videophone succeed in killing the hand-written letter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Things Around</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-20-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-20-around/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  His hand was hurting bad, but no one asked him about it the day after. Moise always had a temper, and now he had a reputation. He got no words of sympathy from the other seniors of Lola 8th School.
Considering his bluntness and irritability, it was funny that he could only make good friends with women. His father was a bastard and his mother was in Greece, so his sister took their place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philately Foolery</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  We’re going to do a deep dive on stamps today.
You can tell a domestic Vekllei stamp from its international counterpart quite easily:
 Domestic stamps have a coloured square, called a chromacode, used for sorting mail automatically within the country by a special machine called a kinosemimatia. Domestic stamps do not show a price in Vekllei Kroner, and generally do not use the Vekllei hieroglyph to announce its origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stamp Manufacturie</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  The Stamp Manufacturie of the Royal Mail Press, located on 5th Avenue, churns millions of stamps a year out of its massive drum presses. Stamps are used on mail instead of postcodes, and as payment for the international and courier work the Royal Mail does abroad. Since Vekllei does not use money domestically, Vekllei people do not pay for postage and stamps are used in the automatic sorting system to determine the destination for any Vekllei territory, including its arctic, peripheral and antarctic possessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3,000 MEMBERS!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-09-3000/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-09-3000/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hello,
I’m Hobart, and I’m the creator of this place. I’ve been drawing Vekllei for a few years now, and I love doing it.
To celebrate 3,000 members, use this as a cosy thread/AMA to settle in, and have any questions you might have about the project answered.
For those who are new, I encourage you to read the posts pinned to the top of the subreddit for a crash course in what’s going on here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Racing the Post Office to the Station</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  It was the hottest day of June so far, in that time of year where the sun never set on Vekllei. It was the first week of sleepless nights; the windows thrown open, air sticky and pungent with the smells of the rainforests, tossing and turning in the heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fairie</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  The M.S. Fairie Model 54-2 “Mail Hopper” is a strange aircraft. The basic design has remained unchanged for over a hundred years, imported from the United States way back during the massive scrapping of junk warplanes after the Second World War. Even back during the Junta years the country had little respect for foreign intellectual property, and by 1949 had started rolling out Imitation Catalinas, which were among the first indigenous aircraft in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Postmistress of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  Here we have arranged the highest-ranking and lowest-ranking members of the Royal Vekllei Mail (Mail A.r.). On the left is an Office Postgirl, a precursory position tasked with distributing letters in the sprawling bureau complexes abundant in the centralised postwar period. This particular employee is Aleja Hernández, who has decided she’d rather deliver mail than spend another year studying for high school exit exams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Men and Women of the Royal Mail in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Mail Week in February 2021  There are not many postal services older than the Royal Vekllei Mail. It is so old that in the Vekllei language its title is simply ‘Mail’ — the ‘Royal’ and ‘Vekllei’ are implied by the use of its hieroglyph. Founded in 1422 as part of the military communications system between government and mercantile government holdings, it has survived various restructurings — and several wars — to remain a critical communications and cultural institution today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Puffling</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-27-puffling/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  She joined the Puffin Scouts to make friends. Tzipora was not especially rugged or outdoorsy, but she was a fresh patriot, and the idea of collecting awards for conservation, in her mind, was much like Baron collecting medals for killing reds in the War.
The green and gold of the Puffin Scouts represent nature and living blood respectively. Entwined, as here on her scarf, they mean the chaos and inhumanity of nature in Vekllei Semaphore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moments in Love</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-23-love/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Lava was a modern walled city. It had long lost its walls, but its florid green belt disguised a complex network of trenches, tunnels and forts that linked emplacements in the surrounding mountains. Together, these systems would ensure Vekllei would never again have to tolerate occupation by a foreign power. Lava was on the outskirts of Vekllei’s great capital city, and much of its cityscape was dispersed, affording residents a slower pace of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robots in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-11-automen/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The Vekllei word for a robot is automasiosn, or ‘automan’. When we talk about Vekllei being a “post-scarcity society,” it is by automen through which it happens. They are found across the entire country in all types of hard and boring work, forever dutiful, forever mindless. It is not that the robot has replaced the human worker, since about 90% of Vekllei people are employed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Year</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The New Year in Vekllei rings out during its months of darkness and cold. This calendar runs the regular affairs of the country, like it does the modern world. To Vekllei people, however, it is plain that New Years occurs not in darkness but instead in the summer solstice in June, the way it has for thousands of years in the dramatic cycles of light and dark in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Army</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-30-army/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-30-army/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  There’s a thousand years of history in Vekllei’s armed forces, though you’ll find very little of it recalled casually today. Almost everything about Vekllei’s prewar society was scorched by the bombs, and the scraps of military infrastructure that survived were appropriated in the subsequent British occupation.
Since independence, a slate has been wiped clean, and a modern fighting force has replaced the colonial legions and battleships of yesteryear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tzipora Christmas Story</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-26-deadplanes/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Pachinki is a world of Tzipora’s own creation, a dorky retreat from the difficulties she has in Vekllei. Tzipora always loved stories of wild places and adventure, and Pachinki blossomed organically from within her daydreams. Eventually she started writing and drawing it. When she was sad, bored or anxious, she would descend back into Pachinki’s world of ancient magic, edible gems and pirates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Heart</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-21-sundown/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  She’d dropped out of school and had the slow accent of a person too foreign to employ. She now lived in a country that did not use money. Food was everywhere and you ate until you were satisfied. Around each corner was a new cinema or basement lounge, and water trickled through the streets like all mythic garden cities. It was a paradise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bea and the Mosses</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-08-bea/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-08-bea/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This character was illustrated as a gift to Bike. Happy Birthday!  This is Bea, an energetic Botanist with the Landscape Bureau of Vekllei. People know her as an eccentric young woman easily persuaded by cottage-fashions, but she takes her work very seriously and spends most of her waking hours documenting the dense temperate rainforests of Vekllei’s coastal lowlands. These are not particularly adventurous expeditions — most of her work is performed along old trails and paths, but Bea finds the sublime amidst the mundane and has contributed enormously to the ecological understanding of local flora in the borough of Holsyim, where she was born.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crown Land of No King</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-05-gods/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  It would be misleading to characterise Vekllei as environmentalist in the usual idea of the word. Vekllei is no such thing. This is obvious in subtle ways, like Newda’s Dumousiantopet, or “beautiful and seperate,” which advocates the separation of human and natural design. It is also policy; Vekllei is dependent on its landscape as part of Autosuffisouitopet, or “self-sustenance,” and to this end sinks forests for hydroelectric dams and topples mountains for novel urban projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming to Grips</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-01-grips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-12-01-grips/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin  She would spend a long time by the rivulet that ran behind her apartment. She would do the housework and hang the wash out, then watch the water trickle past in the sun.
She tried to open a jar the other day and started to cry when she couldn’t get it open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Out of The Ground and Into The Light</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-28-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-28-city/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin   NO REALTORS EXCEPT THE STATE ■ THE COUNTY THE AGENT OF THE STATE ■ THE ARCHITECT THE AGENT OF THE COUNTY
 It is clear that in Vekllei democracy is a way of living more than it is a form of government. After all, by metrics of representation, the Atlantic nation&amp;rsquo;s electoral system often sputters and fails, undermined by the bundling of the human and natural votes as equal, and the wildly disproportionate borough system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Speak Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-14-language/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin  For all you&amp;rsquo;ve seen of Vekllei and her characters, you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard a single one of them speak. This post marks a little exploration into the Vekllei language, and a &amp;lsquo;soft launch&amp;rsquo; of my website, https://millmint.net. The proper launch will come at the end of the month.
This post will briefly discuss some elements shown in this infographic, but a large article on the language has been drafted here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21st Century Witch</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-11-09-witch/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #7 of the Atlantic Bulletin  When the light shifted just right, the ceramic tiles and concrete footpaths twinkled like water off the back of a swan. 16th Century witches could build a hut in the woods and forage for herbs; 21st Century witches were susceptible to modernist persuasions.
The Demotic Meeting Hall was constructed twenty years prior as the main meeting hall of the National Dockworker’s Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vekllei Comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-27-comic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Hi everyone,
&amp;ldquo;He not busy being born is busy dying,&amp;rdquo; — that’s off a Bob Dylan bootleg. I’ve just finished my thesis and I’m busy being born again. Sometimes I feel like I’m busy dying. Drawing’s been the way out for a long time now.
As of today I’m starting work full-time on a Vekllei comic called Atomic Modern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All That’s Solid Melts into Zelda</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-18-melt/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin   My nerves are like overused sandpaper—all dull; only the eye-catching, bizarre and grotesque can excite me now.
 Tanizaki Junichirō, 1918
The wind had died and it seemed that she would follow it. Crazy shadows distorted beneath car headlights. It occurred to her in some way that, as she approached dying, she was living out the ultimate dramatic fantasy of the American misplaced girl, in the same way the townsmen were fulfilling their grotesque constellation of death by murdering women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petrol Heaven — The Rohsm STR-750</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-13-rohsm/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The Rohsm STR series is a small racer built for clubs by Rohsm S.p.M., a hundred-year-old company headquartered in the Mediterranean racing culture of Tohs. Its most recent variant, the 750, is available in limited quantities to enthusiast owners and club pools. Like most petrol cars in Vekllei, they are built by hand, so no two 750s drive exactly alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mittens and Metaphysic — Product Atheism and Vekllei object-form</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-11-metaphysic/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin   Pictured above: various fashions worn by Vekllei women, showcasing heavy cold-weather dresses, simple styling, strong geometric shapes and colours, loose fits, and modest hemlines.
  Pictured below: postmodern neomarxism, which I’ve tricked you into reading with anime.
 Previous posts on the Vekllei economy, if you’re new:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlantic Boredom</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #6 of the Atlantic Bulletin  For a brief period of time, Zelda and Cobian took it upon themselves to make something of their youth. Cobian fancied herself a gymnast, and though this ambition arrived too late and left too soon, she was quite good at it for a while. Tzipora was better suited on the trampoline, where her stiff leg didn’t give her as much trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baron, the Father</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-30-father/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  People are not sure what to make of Baron. They are not sure what to make of his daughter, Tzipora, either. To that end, they are lucky to have found each other.
His obscurity is part of a severe disposition, made obvious by his astonishing disinterest in friends and hobbies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Bouncy Zelda — an animation diary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-27-intro/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  It&amp;rsquo;s been a week since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted. Most of that was spent drawing the same thing over and over.
A painting? Please. That&amp;rsquo;s a day&amp;rsquo;s work — maybe two. A five second loop of Tzipora jumping in and shuffling over? A week.
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to grasp just how much work animation is until you try it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory and Death in the Flower Tundra</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-19-death/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  It was their first hike after Maya’s funeral. She had found adult life completely disappointing, and never moved out of home. In her last summer, she developed a desperate fascination with her receding childhood, and eventually took her own life outside of the classroom she’d studied in as a third-grade student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobian and Zelda &#34;head-over-heels&#34;</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-17-gay/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  make love not lore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matchstick Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Another paint-sketch — a painting done fast. I’m trying to learn to a) paint and b) paint on an industrial scale.
She’d missed the fast tram, caught a tiny splinter in her thumb, lost a button and now the match wouldn’t strike. It just wasn’t her day.
They were in Callaisn (pronounced ka-lane), a borough of the capital Tzipora regarded as “the worst of them” for its tall buildings and labyrinthian concrete alleys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  They showed up at the autopool, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem. Moise would drive, Tzipora bunked with Cobian in the passenger seat and Alise, Zo and Jerome could cram into the back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin  In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin   On the morning of the second day, I watched a fly crawl across the cheek of the middle-aged woman, probably an office worker, lying next to me. It moved up her cheekbone to her temple, stopping now and then to rub its front legs as though performing a ritual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2,000 members! WOW!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-27-2000-members/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Hello,
I’m Hobart. I’ve been working on this project for a while now. It doesn’t really have a purpose or an end goal — I just want to draw and write about nice things, and I’m learning a lot on the way. Welcome to everyone new here. I don’t really have anything to sell, I’d just like to thank you for tuning in and checking Vekllei out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Quiet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  There were plumes in the sky, sent from bunkers buried deep in the well of the Earth, killing with switches. Vekllei went to war, and so Tzipora went to war with it.
The throbbing machinery of another world began turning, and anyone who saw the bomb would hear it. Passing seconds dislocated and caught heartbeats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Newda in Rural Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin   Newda is Vekllei’s national architectural ideology, applied flexibly in a range of modernist styles developed domestically in her architecture schools. Broadly, Newda buildings emphasise distinction from the surrounding landscape (called Dumousiantopet, or ‘beautiful and seperate’), natural decay, and honesty in material and construction. Vekllei’s great Parliament House is Newda; as are the little rural homes found in the mountains inland in Vekllei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thousand-Year-Old Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The concept of living forever jumps out at people uncomfortable with their own existence. There is a contemplative instinct among educated people that — if they could simply will themselves into a state of self-actualisation — death would only be an obstacle to greatness.
As Tzipora found out quickly, the opposite was true — death and temporality were wells of meaning against which all great people, beauty, and human constructions were cast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 31st Century — Vekllei throughout our Solar System</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #4 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The Epoch of Rest ¶  We’ve spent a lot of time in the 21st century — but Tzipora is biologically immortal. Where does she go from here? Well, let’s enjoy a small glimpse at that future together, by winding the clock forward one thousand years.
By 3076, our Solar System is a pleasant place to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Unique among girls ¶  There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not realise she is unusual, or does not care.
She has a lot of endearing characteristics that give great character to her mannerisms and physicality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer House in the Azores</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The Azores had been a possession of Vekllei since 2002, when they were leased from Portugal indefinitely. The lease was defunct by the time of Vekllei’s independence from U.K. occupation in 2015, and the new state took formal ownership over the small Atlantic islands.
The Azores was Vekllei’s resort region, often called simply the “holiday isles”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Camp</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Just a paint-sketch.
The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora’s ‘Every Day Carry’</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Like a lot of girls of poverty, Tzipora was very possessive of her things. No food was ever left on her plate. There was a deep anxiety that whatever wasn’t claimed would be lost.
She was also naturally obsessive and material-oriented, keenly aware of the importance of objects measured by metrics in her own silly head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Race for Inefficiency</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Vekllei’s advocation of austerity, apathy, and playfulness as economic principles ¶  This post is about the economy of Vekllei. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a long one. If you have any questions, just ask.
Overview of the Bureau System ¶  There are many thousands of companies busy with work in Vekllei.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin  There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.
 Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or venopor) Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or cosmopor)  A young venopor officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike cosmopor, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is This Project?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-30-project/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  What is Vekllei?
Hi, I’m Hobart and I write and draw Vekllei at Studio MillMint.
This is a pretty complex project. Not just complex insofar as there’s a lot to read about it, but that it uses concepts and terminology you might not be familiar with if this is your first time around utopian fiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Map of Vekllei — 100 Boroughs; 100 Hearts</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Map Key
 Red: Magjet trains, 750km/h
Yellow: Bullet trains, 300-400km/h
Orange: Regional trains, &amp;lt;150km/h
Brown: Local trains, including limited express, &amp;lt;100km/h
Blue: National highway
Dashed: Ferry line
Green: tarmacadamed airport
 The largest division of any portion of Vekllei land is the borough; a region of varying size and population with common culture, food dependency and economic interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Crown — coins of a moneyless country</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country. At no point do coins or paper currency change hands in the day-to-day affairs of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Village Map of Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  The village of Montre-Lola is home to about 400 people in its entirety, a stone’s throw from the Aisyo borough. Each morning, however, the population swells as 300 children from tiny villages in both Aisyo and Montre take a fast tram to the Montre-Lola Area School No. 2, a district school raising all ages of local youth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Most Beautiful Woman</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”
It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oa-Class Battlecruiser</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Vekllei’s defensive military posture has, in doctrine and arms development, limited its ability to meaningfully project power outside of the Atlantic. As an island nation with a large and multifaceted naval armada, the Oa-Class Battlecruiser is the heart of her armed forces, as the flagship of her fleets.
Where U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canal Living</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fission Cloud at Vekllei&#39;s 50th Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  In an unprecedented event, during Vekllei’s 50th Sea Festival since Independence in 2065, an 8 kiloton fission bomb was sunk to a depth of 150 meters and detonated at midday. It was an incredible sight on a day so clear you could see the gentle curve of the earth where it met the horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rain in the Arctic Circle</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Tzipora had been ejected from the operations room once the guys arrived. She knew what was going down, anyway. No specifics. But you didn’t bring in uniformed soldiers for regular business. National Intelligence liked to work with their own people.
Five days prior, Baron hailed an EB/NI company car and it pulled up beside him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform. And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables. Out here, you paced life around the station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031 Apartment Diagram</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Baron had inherited the apartment from his uncle, who passed in the year following his parents. It was in a mixed residential-industrial neighbourhood, adjacent to a canvas factory. Out back was a rivulet, which roared in the long rainstorms of early April.
 Each January, the Colour Bureau of the Architecture Assembly announces the year’s colours, and tradition in mainstream architecture and interior design is to incorporate the announced palettes, which usually contain a hundred or so colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Tzipo-stcards</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hello everyone. Just a little update.
As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.
How many cards will the set contain?
 I’m aiming for about six cards.
 How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiery Peaks</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  After three days in Ada, Tzipora set off towards Mt Miya. She made good time, and after three hours had happened upon the shoulders of the bright Volouisnesnkull Glacier. It was about here that she heard a morbid industrial siren, echoing up the valleys from far away.
At first she thought it might have come from Ada, since Boya Chemical had a large plant there, but as she lay out her things for lunch she heard the distinct whine of a turbojet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chemical Feast</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  East of Montre, West of Tjornes, waits a rare sight among Vekllei’s hard igneous slopes — a crown of gentle sedimentary cliffs packed with ruddy sandstone, which melt glacially into the sea chasing blue-sky bergs.
Tzipora was, at the time, making her way on foot from Montre-Lola to Ada, which was a coastal town in the North-East known for its luxurious health spas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trials of Cobian</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin  According to her friends, Tzipora’s contemporary afflictions were tragic. Her medical problems; her violent childhood; her sensitivity and melancholy — you could feel sorry for her, because a lot of her problems were not her fault. She invoked sympathy.
Tzipora never considered herself particularly tragic. It seemed straightforward, if difficult; she continued to live — and so she lived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-24-rural/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tomorrow: 2020 Complete Guide to Vekllei
Today:
 Up in the ro, the Vekllei flower-tundra home to spirits and people alike, green slopes and igneous monument make an ample crucible for myth and magic.
 Out here, there was a very keen sense of place and purpose. “Landscape” was neither revered nor ignored, since it did not exist here altogether. Every hill, rock and tree was taken at face value in its full honesty, with commodity dead and modernism suppressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentle Enthusiasm</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-23-enthusiasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-23-enthusiasm/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tzipora stood astride the bicycle luggage rack, and looked at her best friend Moise. She smiled at him, and looked to the town before them, and squinted at the clouds rising over the Atlantic horizon.
It was a warm late summer and there was salt in the air. Pebbles made better swimmers than Tzipora, but from up here she could admire the coast and fill her heart with the breeze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ou Hydroburo Office</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Almost any other venrouive national bureau is more glamorous than Vekllei’s Hydroburo, but that fact does not detract from the organ’s critical function.
Although the sophisticated age of robotics demands the incredible yield of nuclear fission, a significant minority of Vekllei’s electricity is produced by hydroelectric dams, which are jointly operated by the Thunderburo and Hydroburo. Hydroelectricity appeals to the common Vekllei person strategically and culturally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AB/NI’s Spectres of Violence</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-20-spectre/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), a semiautonomous organ of the covert operations council of the War Department, is recognised as the busiest of the continental bureaus. There is a lot to be busy with — the Dallas Secession, the Brazilian invasion of Bolivia, the Dallas nuclear lend-lease, and the reliability of Venezuelan oil production are all of some concern to Vekllei, and so AB/NI proactively has fingers in those pies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghosts of Taiwan in the Yana Lakehouse</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-05-lakehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-05-lakehouse/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  By 2047, Vekllei had a lot of broken men. Tens of thousands had alighted troop ships at the end of the War of Taiwan, only to find that pieces of their lives had unravelled overseas. Hardy, bronze-skinned boys were left with their ghosts, and those ghosts introduced them to drinking, and brawling, and suicide.
 As part of the Birmingham Convention and the second round of the Commonwealth War Trials, a young and recently defeated Vekllei nation was chained to a conflict that was beginning to fester in East Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Montre, City of Learning</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-03-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-03-learning/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The Montre Prefecture of the Vekllei city-state is among the most learned urban landscapes in the world. In the days of the monarchy, it had been an unremarkable city, home to the empire’s submarine fleet. It was obliterated by bombs in the war, and the &amp;ldquo;new Montre&amp;rdquo; that has blossomed in its place is nourished by its ashes.
Among the most prolific creatures in Vekllei’s academic elite, including prestigious folk like physicist Thomas Weihennet and Chief Engineer of General Reactor Maya Ou, almost all of them were educated in Montre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ego Death and Upen&#39;s Spiritual Rebirth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-01-ego/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-04-01-ego/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   The Beach was a small part of herself.
Another stroke on the Hell Screen
She washed ashore
Two dollars were in the sand
A hound had come here to rest
Damp cotton touched green water
She thought of what she was doing here
Of what the night invoked
Hot sand met a rising wind
It happened again
She realised
There was not a single dog left to fight</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Ro Highlands</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-11-highlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-11-highlands/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  As I pick up some larger projects, my posts here will slow down a little bit. That&amp;rsquo;s okay &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m still easy to track down and get in touch with, and you guys will still see the best stuff.
I post a lot of sketches to the Vekllei Discord, which is something between a fan club and a social club for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Cobian, a concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-03-01-cobian/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  If you go back through my posts here, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice Tzipora is basically a cartoon whose only consistent characteristic is her iconography &amp;ndash; her hair fountain, bangs, round head and big smile. This isn&amp;rsquo;t really intentional. I&amp;rsquo;m just an amateur artist who is still learning to draw.
That doesn&amp;rsquo;t work so well in a comic with sequential panels, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on standardising my characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora, the Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-17-princess/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Editor’s note — it’s getting close to 4 a.m. and I’m not sure I can even remember why I wrote this post. Everything is a fog. Expect revisions and possibly major changes in the morning.
Pictured above is Tzipora Desmoisnes, the Princess of the Earth and one of the most interesting persons of the last century. She has made good use of her 126 years on Earth (and counting), and a few samples have been chosen for your viewing pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salad Time</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-11-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-11-salad/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Despite appearances, most of the population of Vekllei are Scandinavian, not Asian.
Zhu is the first time in a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn an ethnically Chinese person. She was graciously lent to me to draw by u/boodyclap in an art trade. You can see his end of the deal here, complete with Tzipora balancing a baseball bat.
In Zhu&amp;rsquo;s homeland she suffers a meat-heavy diet, and Vekllei is the first time she&amp;rsquo;s seen a salad this big.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Timeline</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-05-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-02-05-timeline/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  This is it. The dates are laid out. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a document that tracks the story thus far. Longtime followers might be surprised by where certain events land.
This post will be pinned and serve as a stopgap until I can complete something more professional on my site.
  CLICK HERE for a timeline of the events so far, and how they line up in this story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face to Face with Immortality</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-31-immortality/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tzipora had never been taller than anyone in Vekllei at a meagre 5’2, but she was taller than Shizuku Kobayashi. Like Tzipora, Shizuku had not physically aged a day since she was a child.
It was summer, and six days after Tzipora had arrived in Japan as a Gregori ambassador from Vekllei. Although she would not be the oldest victim of Gregori-Heitzfeld syndrome until Quentin Cook’s (USA) infamous murder-suicide ten years later, she was one of the so-called &amp;ldquo;First Thirteen&amp;rdquo; publicised patients, and so was somewhat known to the international community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girls of the Last Carriage</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-27-carriage/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  She’d accidentally starched her gi quarter-pleat in the wash. She held it self-consciously against her side as she watched the clouds navigate the sharp mountains that formed Montre’s deepest valleys. Even out here, where human presence was gentle and subservient to the land, Vekllei National Railways had tracks that serviced the smallest villages. Today it was high summer, and the slopes were green and free of ice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girl and the Sublime</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-19-sublime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-19-sublime/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  When Tzipora moved to study English and Vekllei literature at the university of Montre in 2075, she had to walk from the little home where she lived to Montre-Lola’s old concrete platform, which facilitated a single electric railcar each way, each day. If she was feeling lively, she could make it to the platform in a half hour. On the days where she dreaded sighting her plimsolls in the shoebox, it might take forty-five minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Foreigner’s Guide to Female Traditional Dress in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-11-dress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Tzipora, illustrated here, is happy because her traditional dress makes her feel stylish and her cape is soft and warm.
Vekllei is an ancient culture with many inherited and vestigial artefacts. Nowhere is this more apparent than in her national dress, particularly that for women, where old and new collide as they do all across Vekllei. Pre-war, post-war and future are present here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hobart and Tzipora are off to Japan</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-09-japan/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora here is wearing a simplified form of Vekllei’s national dress, which plays fast and loose with lace and showcases some of Vekllei’s more decadent iconography. Long gi (decorative quarter-pleats you’ve seen around) accompany sun petticoats, or Vekllei lace aprons. Flowers take the place of astrology or the Zodiac in Vekllei, and so they often accompany spiritual runes (in upotenne, or religious script) about the girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valleys of the Wind</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-04-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-04-wind/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The summer had rolled into the valley, and so the air smelled of hot grass from the fields. It was quiet at the station, where a single train clacked each way in the afternoon. The only sound was the wind, which caught the heads of dry grass and roared up the slopes of the mountain ranges around her.
It seemed an exaggeration to even call it a station, since the bare concrete slab had been laid fifty years ago and left to crumble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So long 2019, here&#39;s to 2020!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-01-01-new-year/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Moise has somehow been swindled out of his slow dance in Zelda’s eighth floor New Years party. I’d like to invite everyone here to come celebrate at the new Vekllei discord — we mostly argue about architecture and share art and stories. No pressure, but at least you can hassle me directly about the gap between posts. Speaking of which, this one is a substitute — the one I’m working on ended up being a bit too sad for an exciting new year, so I’ll put the sad stuff off until Jan 2nd in favour of something happier tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-26-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-26-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  I’m still eating pudding, but once I’m home tomorrow and settled at my drawing desk I’ll be sure to report Tzipora’s holiday adventures in full.
For the Christmasfolk out there, enjoy your presents. To everyone else, have a good holiday and be sure to celebrate the Australian way — with prawns, salmon and snags on the barbie.
(Gorgeous 25°C [77°F] yesterday)
Best,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Kodak Moment by a Vekllei Geyser</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-23-geyser/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In her journal for practicing writing the Vekllei language (appropriately called Vekllei), Tzipora wrote:
 The heavy clouds above were children of early spring, but among the steam vents it seemed like the whole sky was polluted by geysers. Large pools, opalescent with healthy minerals, were heated by the core of the Earth. In a volcanic desert of black sand, the geysers were an oasis, rising from the sulphuric fog like a little eden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life and Death in Vekllei Apartment Ideology, or “Newda”</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-20-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  To substitute for my shocking (and deeply shameful) absence over the last two weeks, please accept a longer-form post concerning domestic Apartment Ideology in Vekllei, which they call Newda and is known internationally as The Vekllei Newda School. Pictured is the apartment of our very own Zelda. While the building itself deserves a feature, for now we’ll discuss Newda as a theory and her life in this building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A “Horizon Wing” Atomic Passenger Jet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-12-jet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Click here for a view inside the wing.
Although the CN-1 Horizon Wing passenger jet was not a “flying wing,” that didn’t stop Comen Aeroyards, the manufacturer, from celebrating it as such. Much like similar large-wing aircraft from McDonnell and de Havilland, the CN-1’s large vertical stabilisers and obvious centre fuselage precluded it from qualifying as an authentic “flying wing,” which were already common in many air forces at this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak Sneak</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-11-sneak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-11-sneak/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   He kept bad hours. Sometimes he worked so hard he came home in the early morning and fell asleep to the television with the subtitles on. Like a guerrilla sighting a commanding officer, she would approach discreetly, wearing her blanket like a cape and bouncing on her toes. With a gentle movement she&amp;rsquo;d drape it over him and listen for a break in his snoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside VOA’s “Flying Wing” Atomic Passenger Jet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-09-wing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-09-wing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In this limited cross-section of a CN-1 “Horizon” Wing, the scale of the aircraft is immediately impressed upon the reader. It is nearly four times as wide as the older wide-body passenger jets of yesteryear, and twice as wide as most American and European supersonic jets. It is no coincidence that the “flying wing” concept was only made possible by the development of supersonic jetport infrastructure, with their wide and long runways, at the turn of the century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallabies of the Arctic — Vekllei&#39;s Pademelon and what the hell it&#39;s doing there</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-06-wallabies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-12-06-wallabies/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   8 days without posts feels like a century. Tomorrow, SkyMonth returns, and we’ll see what it’s like flying VAS. The day after tomorrow we’ll see an update for a few things — particularly a massive (and awesome) overhaul of the Vekllei site + wiki. Yeah, if you’re wondering where I’ve been, I’ve ditched Wordpress and have been learning HTML, which is like scraping the exposed brain against unpolished concrete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Trouble</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-27-trouble/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora never lost her youthful curiosity. She would swish about the apartment, chasing an idea or plan that had occurred to her. Baron would look over and say “What are you doing, Zelda? Making trouble?” He said that a lot. He would come home in the afternoon and she would be writing lists, or organising her paperbacks, or moving furniture and he’d say, “What are you up to, Zelda?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicating despair in the pasture of plenty</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-26-despair/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tzipora is doing well now. She has looked into her heart and made peace with who she is. She has discovered she is a girl who likes free jazz, and milky coffee, and cotton shirts, and trains — to the surprise of no-one who knows her. She knows what things she values in a friend, and what deserves to become family. She knows what clothes she likes and how to do her hair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean-liners of the Sky — Vacuum Dirigibles in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-24-dirigible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-24-dirigible/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Sorry it took so long, mateys. I&amp;rsquo;ve been laying the first pages of the comic down and it&amp;rsquo;s like crack for me. Not much sleep and totally fell behind on SkyMonth. But, as any longtime members know, our Months are r/vekllei usually last a little longer than they should past their expiry date. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to come!
 The Angel and Memory of the People of Vekllei is the largest and most recent of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s airships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Stewards in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-19-stewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-19-stewards/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Overview ¶  Although Vekllei’s flag-carrying airline might appear just one of many in the small island country, don’t be fooled — all civilian aviation operates under a venrouive bureau excitingly titled the Vekllei Air Service (Skyburo), which operates several distinct ‘airlines’ but wholly controls all of them. In Vekllei economic lexicon, a bureau is the largest trade union of an industry, made up of many hundreds of others, and is partially beholden to the direction of government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Shoes</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-18-blue-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-18-blue-shoes/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Welcome to the r/Vekllei variety hour, where the tone between posts judders so inconsistently you&amp;rsquo;ll get whiplash of the mind. I was just drawing and thinking today. This is an author post, in case you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed &amp;ndash; just a shitty blog.
You see, even today I&amp;rsquo;m wildly jealous of the success of those slice-of-life artists on reddit and Twitter. I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand the genre entirely, as a phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten corpses in the snow, and a change of government in the American South</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-16-coup/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve just pulled a body from an air force jet here that looks like General MacMillan, and we really need to know right now if it&amp;rsquo;s him.”
The partially buried remains of a U.S. Air Force passenger aircraft are the only blemish on the horizon of central Greenland’s frigid snowscape. It is the site of one of the greatest political scandals in American history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Beaches to Mountaintops</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-15-mountaintops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-15-mountaintops/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  I had the wonderful opportunity to work with one of our resident worldbuilders on reddit, u/EpicJM, and spend a while with their world and characters. The world of Eipljord has a lot of distinct, unique cultures and characters. As a sucker for uniforms I went with the garb of the Pruscyldan Academy of Magic, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find JM&amp;rsquo;s character, Honora being splattered with ice cream by Tzipora on the left and in Vekllei education uniform on the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1000 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-10-1000-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-10-1000-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hey everyone,
Hobart here. You might not know it, but I’m sort of a big fucking deal on the internet. No, don’t touch me. Why am I? Because my subreddit just hit 1,000 subscribers. What’s a subreddit? I’m actually laughing at you; imagine not knowing what reddit is. You ingrate.
Seriously though, this whole renewal of the project through a subreddit (rather than disconnected r/worldbuilding posts) has been an amazing thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Like Father, Like Daughter</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-09-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-09-beach/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The main beach in Mumen, the nicest of the seaside districts, is constructed out of sand imported from the dunes of Africa. Where the rest of the country has black sand, a symptom of its volcanic turbulence, Mumen has nice yellow sand.
Baron doesn’t like the water, and getting him down to the sea at all was a trial. Zelda, for her part, sinks faster than lead in water and only ventures into the shallows with Ayn, who herself is afraid of the deeper ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Jetport Guide shuffles Americans onto the airport maglevs</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-07-tourist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-07-tourist/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  It is very difficult to obtain papers for tourism in Vekllei as an American, despite the fact that the Arctic island nation is positioned obstinately between the Americas and Europe. It’s not made difficult for any discernible political reason, either — relations with the U.S. are as good as they could be for a country like Vekllei. Nonetheless, tourism is regarded as a risk rather than an opportunity, and most Americans who visit for pleasure are wealthy enough to put up the sums of cash required to enter on the national carriers that exclusively operate in Vekllei’s airspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vekllei Timetable</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-06-timetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-06-timetable/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Let&amp;rsquo;s wind down Study Month with a look into the Vekllei curriculum. A few days ago I wrote about how Vekllei schools operate on fundamentally different assumptions about what it means to be ‘a child’. Let’s take a look at how that pans out in practice.
Most students study about 3-5 days a week, depending on the taste of the student and the work timetable of their parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-stakes air racing</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-02-racing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-02-racing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Each year, a race is held amongst the most remarkable geological monuments of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s interior. Steep mountains forged in the restlessness of the European and American tectonic plates become deadly checkpoints in the world&amp;rsquo;s most high-stakes aeroplane race in the Western Hemisphere.
Low-speed, high-maneuverability jets (manufactured by the likes of General Reactor, V.K. Heavy Industries, and Kaleidoscope Aerospace) roar through narrow valleys in time trials that last only a few minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schools in a Society Without Children</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-01-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-11-01-schools/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Let’s talk about childhood and utopia. This post comes as we wind down Study Month in r/vekllei. Strap in kids, because this one gets kind of heavy.
 When you get into the idea of it, “The Child” is a particularly unfortunate projection. It’s not something most would agree with, but that’s how it’s worked out in the late 2070s. In fact, critical foundations of how foreigners view the world are not culturally neutral subjects as they might assume, timeless and naturally occurring, but are in fact symptoms of ideology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Intelligence in the Epoch of Rest</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-25-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-25-love/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Let’s talk about childhood and utopia. This post comes as we wind down Study Month in r/vekllei. Strap in kids, because this one gets kind of heavy.
  Tzipora and Cobian, pictured here, have very different stories but both have felt something was not quite right about them. That difference, so it would turn out, would blossom into a preference for women as partners, in the unusual desexualised way Vekllei goes about homosexuality in the late 2070s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boyhood Fashion in Vekllei&#39;s School Halls</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-24-school-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-24-school-fashion/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  This is a follow-up to this post, as part of Vekllei’s “Study Week,” where we’re touring education and youth in the utopia of Vekllei.
Compared to their girls, who are adorned with many layers of clothing and dazzling patterns, the schoolboys of Vekllei are unadorned. Lace and quarter-pleats give way to bolder forms and masculine colours.
As much of Vekllei’s uniform ideology straddles complex (and often precipitous) schisms of modern and traditional clothing items, boys have received considerably more progressive attention than their sisters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>… where did I leave all the uploads?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-23-uploads/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-23-uploads/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hello everyone,
Thanks again for subscribing to this subreddit. I’m playing a game of chicken right now pitting my little Vekllei projects against my university work.
Vekllei boys uniforms (and school architecture) is coming later this week, turning Study Week into a Study Month!
Starting from next week, several exciting projects are getting kicked into gear. One is the graphic novel. There’s also the Vekllei wiki, which is under construction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The King</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-21-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-21-king/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The King and Tzipora do not get along. Zelda met him through Moise, when King managed the Domepent School’s cricket team. Moise was a pretty good wicket keeper.
King had offended Zelda with an off-hand comment on her youthful appearance, and she’d retorted with a remark about his weak blood circulation. Moise, caught between his new boss and his angry Zelda, navigated these stormy waters by ignoring the dispute entirely and separating them on the walk home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Challenger Has Appeared!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-19-challenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-19-challenger/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Well isn’t this exciting! The talented u/Herald_of_Zena decided to draw Isabelle from his world in the uniforms I posted the other day. It was too much fun not to join in. It turned out to be a classic story told in two parts &amp;ndash; shit weather, put on coat.
It’s a pleasure seeing such a unique style that’s really one of a kind in the worldbuilding scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniform Ideology in the Arctic North</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-17-uniform-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-17-uniform-ideology/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hello everyone. In celebration of the approach of exams (at least in the Southern Hemisphere), we turn our gaze north to Vekllei to celebrate Study Week. Every other day we’ll be looking at education in Vekllei, and today we’re looking at uniforms.
Life in Vekllei is filled with uniforms for work and in study, for a various historical and cultural reasons. In the late 21st century, in a society where work is social, they help distinguish and professionalise employment, which grants important psychological and social benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tattoos of Violence on Quiet Men</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-14-tattoos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-14-tattoos/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Where tattoos had once been an indication of class and work, they were now uncommon. Both class and work had been abolished. Tattoos were almost never seen in the prism of ordinary Vekllei life, but in less savoury occupations they were found where utopian concessions collide with violence and memory.
Baron rolled up his sleeves and laid them out for her. You could accuse him of many things — he was a reticent bloke — but he was never dishonest with Tzipora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Showdown</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-11-showdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-11-showdown/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  It is not uncommon for gangs to form in Vekllei, especially among immigrant communities otherwise marginalised by a complex logographic language and rigid belief system.
In fact, in a country of plenty, there is not much to otherwise identify with. Class is irrelevant in utopia, and the basic ideas of manhood and womanhood are being destroyed in hand with the abolishment of industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mountain Witches of Pachinki and the Siphoning of the Mind</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-06-witches/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Pachinki is the fantastical notebook of Tzipora, in all her loneliness and thunderous imagination, shared with you all to enjoy. She&amp;rsquo;s so far constructed Pachinki posts about gem children, palace henchmen, sinister earth magics, the Palace Gods, and teeth regents.
From Tzipora’s notebook:
[A Guide to Magic, Chapter 2: The Witch]
The witches of Pachinki are an interesting affair — many books have been dedicated to their research after discovery, yet so little is known about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mafioso and His Witch</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-05-mafioso/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-10-05-mafioso/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hello, everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s been six days. I&amp;rsquo;d like to have been here sooner, but I had the good fortune to leave my Apple Pencil in a hotel room in Sydney. Although delighted with my welcome and surprising expense (~$150AUD, or roughly 43 bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves), I&amp;rsquo;ve consequently fallen behind with my off-daily illustrations.
However, I carry the ANZAC spirit deep within me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve made use of my time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of the Moon in 2078</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-28-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-28-moon/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Welcome again to MoonMonth! It started a week ago and will go until I’ve said all I can say. We’re looking at how Vekllei conquered the moon today.
Vekllei unequivocally won the space race. Not because it had the first man in space — the Soviets succeeded in that. Nor were they the first to the moon — the Americans had been there for nearly a century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puffin Scouts</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-27-puffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-27-puffins/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  MoonMonth will return tomorrow. As an interlude&amp;hellip;
 In Winter 2064, the changes made to the constitution of the Boy Scouts of America (BSA) would be felt around the scouting world. By this point it was pretty clear that the globe had entered a “helter skelter” decline towards tragedy. The emerging fission technologies were too slow and expensive to mass produce, and the fossil fuels that lighted homes around the world were starting to run dry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>500 SUBSCRIBERS</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-24-500-subscribers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-24-500-subscribers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Thank you very much everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s very exciting for me. I ordered a cake from Banjos to celebrate but Tzipora got it all over the floor and herself.
Thanks for subscribing. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pushing myself a bit too hard and my writing&amp;rsquo;s suffered for it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I can slow down, I&amp;rsquo;m just not that kind of guy, but I want to promise some exciting adventures in the future as we hang out with Zelda and her loved ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in Tomorrow, Facing the Past</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-22-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-22-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Welcome again to MoonMonth! It started four days ago and will go until I’ve said all I can say. We’re looking at the space industry in Vekllei. This is just a quick piece I&amp;rsquo;ve done between some larger things.
The Copette Science Basin and Rocket Factory launches sixteen rockets a day. Those rockets are packed with robotic mining equipment and are sent chasing asteroids floating through our solar system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A space tourist contemplates her first moonwalk</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-21-moonwalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-21-moonwalk/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Welcome to MoonMonth, which started two days ago and will go until I’ve said all I can say. These posts are going to work a little differently — we’re going to follow Tzipora through her adventures in Moon City and beyond, and learn about the moon in this world along the way. Strap in!
 Vekllei has put a great deal of effort into developing infrastructure for tourism across the lunar surface of the Vekllei Moon Zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holiday on the Moon</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-19-moon-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-19-moon-holiday/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Caption: “So — Mr Spaceman… How long have you held a job at Vekllei National Astrospace? 37 years?”
 Like most Vekllei people, Tzipora has visited the moon. From Ground Control on Earth in the district of Huay, Vekllei operates many moonbases, domes, research facilities and tourist opportunities in the moon’s southern hemisphere within a large complex called Moidonnet — Moon City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puffin Attack</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-16-puffin-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-16-puffin-attack/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Although Zelda can&amp;rsquo;t have kids, she mothers whole generations of village children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Expo’74 Experimental Molten-Salt Peace Reactor</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-15-reactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-15-reactor/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Only had time for a quick painting tonight. Bigger things soon, after I get some things out of the way&amp;hellip;
 Expo’74 was the 2074 World’s Fair, hosted in Vekllei for the first time in nearly a century. The country had made tremendous progress in recovery from the First Atomic War, and set to work nearly a decade in advance of the Expo to create a palatial fairgrounds between the districts of the Capital and Ro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Ayn</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-14-ayn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-14-ayn/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The daughter of a Soviet expat and Hong Konger deckhand, Ayn Rumouisen has never stepped foot outside of Vekllei. A serious fear of flying and the open ocean has hedged her appetite for travel for all of her thirty-two years. She is well respected as an operations consultant within the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), and is close with the ABNI Operations Director Baron Desmoisnes and Vekllei’s first “Gregori Baby,” Tzipora &amp;ldquo;Zelda&amp;rdquo; Desmoisnes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I like bread</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-09-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-09-bread/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  I have a research proposal due today, and since I&amp;rsquo;m pretending to still be a university student I suppose I&amp;rsquo;d better do it.
I spend a lot of time thinking about what the hell I&amp;rsquo;m doing with my life, and after a while I get hungry. Banjos &amp;ndash; a very Australian name for a bakery chain &amp;ndash; satiates my existential hunger with two bacon and cheese pull-apart loaves for $10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Face of War in the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-08-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-08-war/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  This is a story about Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s consumption and disposal of soldiers through her foreign fighting force. You can read more about the Vekllei army in these old posts here and here.
The Vekllei de ra Couismenan Desnepotet, or the Vekllei Foreign Army, is an exclusively foreign fighting force employed by the National War Bureau. It accepts any person between the ages of 18 and 35.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tesmosnen, the Festival of Fasting</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-07-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-07-festival/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In the quaint ocean country of Vekllei, during their years of fecundity and fun, the calendar is divided into twelve festivals of various celebration and purpose. They include the Festival of the Sea in October, which celebrates Vekllei’s vast fishing navy and concludes with the detonation of a nuclear weapon off Vekllei’s coast, to the Festival of the Moon in January, which is quiet and acknowledged only through personal ceremony and decorations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Most Complex Machine, the Autokinotheodolite</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-06-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-06-machine/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Hey everyone, I drew this a little while back after getting back from Woomera, South Australia. Woomera&amp;rsquo;s a closed government town that tests missiles. Not my finest illustration, but it is what it is.
Deep in the mountains around Montre, above a tangle of submerged forts and ballistic missile silos, there sits a Vekllei Rocketry Corps test facility called the Strawberry Site. From the peaks of the surrounding mountains, should you evade the helicopter patrols and dog teams, you can witness the next thirty years of missile technology unfolding before you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Mouth, Fat Lip</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-05-fat-lip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-05-fat-lip/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  For the first six months Baron had known her, Zelda was a serious and wisened young woman who carried symptoms of her troubled past as gracefully as anyone ever could. Poverty ages a person, and she’d nurtured a calm and dispirited disposition. She did not like war films or books with unhappy endings, or loud noises or arguments. She dressed conservatively and spoke quietly and uncontroversially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mountain Railway</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-04-railway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-04-railway/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Many dozens of little trains wind their way around mountain peaks in the centre of Vekllei. They stop at upland villages and towns of sometimes only a few dozen people, before consolidating into larger terminuses that connect nearly every village in Vekllei by rail. It is possible, should the timetables align, that you can reach the capital from any part of the country in under 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Editor&amp;rsquo;s note: this article, while ready for reading, is still under construction.
Considering both the length and convoluted terminology that embroil this project, there was only so long I could carry on before people started getting lost. The truth of it is that Vekllei is not a particularly complex or difficult project to summarise, despite the snapshot &amp;ldquo;lore in scenes&amp;rdquo; approach that kneecaps a complete understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighter Than Her Shadow</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-shadow/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Zelda, for all her outward timidity and mousiness, was mostly self-assured. In the same way that a child is self-assured, in which there is no real epistemology of the self as adults know it. Zelda never grew up to become a real teen-ager, after all — her body is forever thirteen-and-a-half, despite her mature and maternal disposition — and so she had a reckless sort of confidence that never really doubted the premise of her existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Valley of Faith and Sorrow</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-02-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-02-valley/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   On her days off from her place of work in the village library, Zelda would descend the slope of the village into a great basin of creeks and flower-tundra. In the summer, when it was warm enough to sit in the sun, you could sit at one end of the valley and admire the wind rushing to meet you as it whipped through fields of flowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squish!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-01-squish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-01-squish/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Sorry for breaking my streak everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m on beta software and it totally shit the bed these last couple days. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing my best to hobble along until full release :)
Tzipora is easily squished. In this picture Moise would be around 16, Cobian 15, and Tzipora about 18.
Moise has lost a lot of weight and has been blessed with a hefty frame befitting his temperament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Noble Helijet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-28-helijet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-28-helijet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Fourteen girls from the 23rd Chapel Explorer’s Club and two of their supervisors have been airlifted to safety after heavy rains overran the banks of the Rumoisen rivulet. The girls, aged between 10 and 16, found themselves stranded on the southern face of Mt Resner for three nights after the single bridge to the area’s trails was washed away in Thursday’s storm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweat and Ink in the Vekllei News Agency</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-27-VNA/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-27-VNA/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here   Tanny was twenty-five and as colourful as her flaming red hair implied. She was a once-in-a-generation editor, the kind of person who absorbed grammar rules on magical wavelengths beyond mortal comprehension and proceeded to violently enforce them. This was compounded by the Vekllei language, with its sublanguages and logography, leading to daily shouting matches in The Atlantic’s newsroom over sentence structure and colour as language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Moise</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-25-introducing-moise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-25-introducing-moise/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Moise was a fat kid who went to another school. Zelda only knew him from the tram, where he carried a criminal stigma because of his rumoured gang affiliations. He was a second-generation Vekllei boy of immigrant Greek heritage. There were a few ethnic gangs in his area, and most immigrant boys that didn’t do well in school quickly found other causes to fight for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Teeth Regents</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-teeth-regent/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  From the notebook of Tzipora:
Total hedonism across a thousand generations produced the creature known as the ‘tooth regent’, who was a human by technicality but was built genetically only for consuming. His name was Arhen CIII, and where his ancestors had mouths, he had a thousand teeth that sat in messy rows to the back of his throat.
Three times a day his mouth had to be washed by palace maidens, and excess teeth brushed off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zelda, the Vigilant</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-vigilante/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-23-vigilante/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  I should start work on the graphic novel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighbourhood Cruiser</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-22-cruiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-22-cruiser/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  The foundations of a Vekllei neighbourhood, repeated so often to foreigners and children, is the community — a group of people larger than a family but small enough to have valuable social bonds through work and shared spaces. In a society without currency, value is almost entirely derived from your immediate surrounds.
Municipal police, as distinct from Venrouiva police, appear in many different roles in Vekllei communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At peace, in dark</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-21-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-21-peace/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Zelda liked to sleep beside someone, which made her feel safe and loved, but she never had many friends and she hadn’t a mother to share a bed with. And, despite her enthusiasm, she was not very easy to sleep beside. She was prone to jerking movements and night terrors, and alternated between pushing her partner to the periphery and then clutching them in comfort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supermarkets in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-19-supermarket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-19-supermarket/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  In Vekllei, the economy is a social organ that lingers awkwardly between cultural and political interests. On one hand, the country is regressing (both politically and culturally) towards deindustrialised, decommodified life. On the other, it is irreversibly equipped with the benefits of automation and robotics, rendering large swathes of the labour-force obsolete. Work is now, for most purposes, a creative organ that facilitates society, culture and technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puffin Logic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-18-puffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-18-puffin/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  i&amp;rsquo;m like that Ben Folds song about escaping your redneck past but instead of redneck it&amp;rsquo;s anime. who stands like this???
 Time-lapse here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cherry Car</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-17-cherry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-17-cherry/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  A road trip around Vekllei in the summer is an experience that makes life worth living. In some ways, it is a spiritual detox than reinvigorates a person with the intimate, elusive premise of the Vekllei spiritual enlightenment. In others, it is a way of returning to the earth, and understanding the human place in the principles of Upen.
No matter your intention, be it holiday or rediscovery, the very best of Vekllei is on display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  I’m starting a series looking at the lives and machines of domestic Vekllei life.
Vekllei National Railways, or ‘VK Rail’ was the bastard of six major pre-war rail companies that were extinguished along with the society that housed them. Today there are three rail companies in Vekllei, but all of them operate under direct supervision of a Vekllei Industry Bureau ( making it Venrouiva, in other words) and are only broken up for reasons of logistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carry me! &gt;:(</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora and Cobian. They have not been friends for very long but they like each other a lot. Tzipora weighs nearly 10kg less than her friend, so she gets piggy backs more often.
By me! @melon.kony or r/vekllei on reddit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd Draft</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  I first saw this film at a low point in my life, and watching Shizuku discover her ability was one of the most touching things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan-art guy, but I still find myself thinking about them years later and I wanted to paint them happy after the end of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Vekllei?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  Vekllei is a country in my alt-world; a utopian fever dream of googie aesthetics, participatory economics and nostalgia.
Welcome to the ‘Petticoat Project’, a collection of stories about a country and a girl. The concept is broken down into three sections:
 Author: for blog posts and articles on the Petticoat Project, utopian fiction, personal news item, etc. Character: for posts about Tzipora, people in her life, or otherwise events that occur during her time on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei’s Elite Military Units — the Garden Corps and their bloody war against weeds</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post
 On Tuesday, two casualties were reported among Vekllei’s Folifedestarmie 24th and 25th Garden Companies in the ongoing war to make the capital’s parks the finest in the world. Michael Helen-Louisviuan cut his leg on an exposed nail during the deinstallation of old fence posts, and Ana Po cut her thumb on a rose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shōwa memories</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  new r/worldbuilding post soon, just filling in my garbage upload schedule with generic anime and shōwa nostalgia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer sex-ed</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Porno is available over-the-counter at most book stores. Some industry associations attempt to limit availability to minors but generally it&amp;rsquo;s at the discretion of the shopkeeper. Often, shame and embarassment are more powerful tools than legislation in Vekllei.
Generally it&amp;rsquo;s pretty traditional stuff supported by columns and fiction, although it varies between pornographers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of &#34;Human Decay&#34;</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Talking about utopia in landscape is easy — Vekllei is a glittering midcentury paradise that fosters human life as a wonderful dream.
Talking about utopia in character is much harder. How can you find utopia in flawed and sometimes unattractive human beings? By what metric is the vague, intuitive values of a utopia measured against a living person?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Summers in the Arctic (and Newda architecture)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post here.
The Café Resmoiones approaches its hundredth birthday as the girls outside await their fifteenth. The building was once a kindergarten, so they’d been told, but through decades of Vekllei’s irreverent planning it had become a café. It was not a very good café, the food was shit, but the building was nice and it was at the bottom of Lola’s steep residential hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post here.
 Six bodies hung from the Rodney Creek Railroad Bridge, without names. The leftmost corpse, which was a boy, had a sign slung around his neck with tomorrow’s 8am train on it. Besides the swaying boy was his father, and next to him was his mother, and so it went down the railroad bridge, counting off his little sisters and grandmama and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Much love to all of you</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching a steam locomotive to school</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Most of the kids pictured here are the cubs of lumberfolk who make a living out of felling hard pines in the mountains in the North of Vekllei. About half have dark hair and rounder faces, as descendants of both inuits and Scandinavians, and others are of mixed ancestry. Families in Vekllei are large and often nonbiological, and a single lad can have a dozen sisters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora Desmoines, the Eternal Teen-ager and Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora. She goes by two names &amp;ndash; Tzipora, her birth name, and Zelda, a name she mistakenly thought sounded less Jewish. She lives in Lola in the Vekllei city-state.
As an immigrant, she struggles with school but holds her own on in track and field, an inversion of her otherwise quiet and bookish nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The participatory economy of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Nestled between the regional tram offices and the pre-war Ferouistet Department Store, the Lola district is not known for much but her department store and good schools. It sits on the slope of the wide Vekllei capital basin, where the Atlantic can be seen from the street. It was Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s first home in Vekllei, and it was where she lived with her father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dad&#39;s Birthday</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Littlest Goddess in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The Palace Gods live in decadence in an isolated and incestuous land above the mortal planes called the Palace. They do not eat and will live forever, provided they stay within the gardens of the Palace and consummate their industrial godhood occasionally with domen, an opium that they believe purifies blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young and Educated</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  lmao wish I had nice clothes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mineral Lake starts absorbing Grief in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Rena’s little boy was found in the closest town with his guts turned out and his throat cut. They didn’t tell it to Rena like that, but that’s what happened to him. His village and people, the Lehmanen, are descendants of Palace Gods forced out of the heavens some millennia ago over their refusal to smoke Domen, a sort of opium of the Gods and essential practice in the Palace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Celebration of all Women across the World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Vekllei on the first of each May, the women’s councils and industrial unions wipe clean their banners and flags and join great parades that regale the main streets of the city with song and colour. They carry flags and banners in celebration of womanhood and remembrance of the dead — for those Potter’s Fields and unmarked graves that intern nameless women across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Palace Gods attempt to retrieve their runaway child</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She could feel the wind rising. The horizon beyond was warped, caught in the distortion of a forested planetoid before them. The morning sun cast a honeyed warmth on her wings of black sugar, which sang like wind chimes as she soared high above the gem deserts below. Hyssop, her new and only friend, followed her ungracefully under the spell of his flystone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sugarhouse Mountain Fortress</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  A hundred years ago, the fortress existed as a spectre of the neighbouring villages; a beast of suffering and woe with fingers deep into the mountains around Montre. In the waning days of the military junta, the beast’s creators, the Sugarhouse Fort served as a strategic command centre for Vekllei’s nuclear arsenal and a blacksite to disappear the most prolific and dangerous agitators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Generation</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  We best know Vekllei as a dense society of utopia and great infrastructure today, but there was blood in that crucible. It is difficult to imagine that only fifty years ago these streets were unpaved and impassible with the rubble of old society. Shadows on concrete marked the souls lost in the arrogance of the monarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Raid</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-25-air-raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-25-air-raid/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She loved helping out. It was important to her, as an ageless girl of ultimately transient relationships, to be able to establish for herself a family wherever she lived. So within a few years of her arrival in Vekllei, she put time in as a warden for her apartment block and undertook the medical training that went with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Long Moment</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-21-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-21-moment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The whole world gives way to a moment of silence. The other seasons are filled with noise and marrow, jerking and twisting with the pace of the clock. But a moment lasts forever — and wintertime is one long moment.
Although the uniforms got heavier and the commutes longer, Zelda would always like the wintertime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gem girl shows off her enormous strength in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The subcontinent of Zen on the Pachinki pangea is so weathered by enormous gem deserts that there is scarcely enough space to grow wheat for bread. In places where the soil is too thin for heavy wheats, sparrowgrass is grown. This grass has large heads that can be eaten raw and taste citrusy and acidic as they only grow in toxic soils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Old for Sleepovers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Even for those ageless kids, there’s a time when the charade of childhood comes to a head and begs a certain uncomfortable question: at what point does the whole thing — of immaturity, of carelessness, of sleepovers — start looking like two old women posturing around youth, indulging in a sick genetic perversion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A story of community policing and sweet militia</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-03-militia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-03-militia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  As part of sundress municipalism, Vekllei’s villages and townships are mostly self-sufficient and self-regulating. Although a walk in the capital will take you past colossal apartment blocks and cinemas, libraries and schools of great magnificence, you are really looking at a hundred different communities going about personal business at their leisure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look...!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-02-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-02-look/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Look at it!
The bastard ate the lettuce! There&amp;rsquo;s a hole in the wire!
He&amp;rsquo;s cute but he&amp;rsquo;s a bastard!
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing a train for over two weeks now and I needed to draw something alive before I shinkansenned myself. This only took an hour or two but I&amp;rsquo;m not drawing enough and it feels like I&amp;rsquo;m running out of time to get good at drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Childhood and Modernity</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Because the other girls would not stop calling her a lesbian, and because they had realised she was scared of loud noises and made use of that fact, Tzipora struck this bitch and her friend out beyond the football pitches after school. Tzipora was a good fighter — on her side is viciousness and a conviction to fight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas everyone (plus a little Christmas story)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She had always been a very serious girl, from the first time he’d met her. It was more than a reflection of character; it was how she talked, how she carried herself. Her clothes were plain, her nervous tics were not that funny, and she was afflicted with all sorts of fears and anxieties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Suburban Constabulary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The constabulary is old-fashioned and it can’t last forever. It predates Petticoat-era Vekllei, the previous regime lost to atomic ash, and even the monarchy itself — it was the first community militia of the country and a great deal of romanticism that had been lost in the death of the monarchy has been invested in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Valley of the Dead</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-17-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-17-valley/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  As Zelda got older and her sense of urgency decayed, the bone between life and death seemed to grow less important as time went on. Could you blame her? She was eighty years old at this point and still as fresh as fourteen — suspended somewhere in the misery of her old age and enthusiasm of her youth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cosmojet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-14-cosmojet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-14-cosmojet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The Ramoin-Dupont H700A “Cosmojet” series are the primary carrier-based fighters of Vekllei. They’re a real bitch to fly. Beloved as they are iconic, variations of the Cosmojet (H600A, B, H500A, etc.) make up the bulk of Vekllei’s total fighter outfit. Unconventional inverted gull wings and embedded turbofan engines make for a striking and uniquely Vekllei aircraft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metro Days</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-11-metro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-11-metro/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flower Tundra</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-10-flower-tundra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-10-flower-tundra/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   The two girls caught a train from school to the terminus, and then a rural line as far as it would take them out of the city. They had walked the granite shoulder of a mountain range for most of the afternoon, carrying only a few mouthfuls of provisions between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Trains</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-05-rural-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-05-rural-trains/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  I caught a train out of Tokyo as far as it would go, and I ended up on a little platform in the mountains. Nice place.
Vekllei has a lot of mountains and a lot of trains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koka parks &amp; municipal recreation</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-04-koka-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-04-koka-parks/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Between the atomic fire that ruined the city, and the death of the king, there was a time when the city of Vekllei once resembled its lifeless lava fields to the North. In the communities that gathered themselves in the shadow of holocaust, common agriculture like fruits and berries returned to the city in what they call koka parkland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The guilt dies with her</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-16-guilt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-16-guilt/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Some years ago, she was in the desert. At the time she had just fallen out with her lover, and their friends had sided with him. The reasons why they had sided with him seemed to matter less and less as time wore on — they might have always liked him better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Summer Everyone</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-05-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-05-summer/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Down Under it&amp;rsquo;s coming around summer, and things are heating up. It&amp;rsquo;s not my fault Yanks broke the northern hemisphere and made the weather go wrong.
Vekllei gets warm in the summer, reaching heights of 30C occasionally. For a variety of reasons. A city of gardens and flowerbeds (the most flowers per capita in the world, actually), apartment dwellers take turns watering their local gardens and clearing weeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking about Girl Scouts and Child Soldiers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-04-scout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-04-scout/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  About half of Vekllei kids go through the &amp;lsquo;Blossom&amp;rsquo; network of youth orgs at some point in their lives. Yeah, youth groups are popular nowadays. The Boy Scouts and Girl Guides of the United States are as mandatory as schooling in some states, and various Red Pioneers around the world test orthodoxy in Soviet and Red Chinese children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stewards of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-30-steward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-30-steward/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Upen is the animistic religion of Vekllei. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have priests, but it has ceremony, and it shapes every part of the country today. From apartment cooperatives to the types of cotton used in clothing, Upen has extraordinary reach for an ostensibly agnostic and secular country.
It works out that way because Upen is not an organised religion, and resembles more closely a collective spiritualism with supernatural beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s look at military fashion, because why not?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-22-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-22-fashion/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Unlike the United States and Western Europe, the ‘teen-ager’ has not been discovered in Vekllei. To be pedantic, they do technically exist — their people do indeed enter a transitory stage between childhood and adulthood, as far as anyone can tell — but they do not exist as a separate cultural identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collapse of the South</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-05-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-05-south/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In October of 2074, the Ford Motor Company was embroiled in political catastrophe after Vermont senator Henry Walsh accused unionism in its East-Coast plants of traitorism by allowing foreign spies to acquire jobs in the Company. Whether the spies were Soviet or Chinese changed several times in Walsh’s accusations, but the claims themselves were not entirely unfounded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>real sadboi posting hours</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-29-sadboi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-29-sadboi/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Coming up on 2am here in East Australia. Had a rough day at work. Feeling pretty isolated and my other job starts in a few hours. I don’t know if it’s intrusive thoughts from OCD or just something everyone has, but four or five times a day I’ll have some sort of regret pop right into my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School uniforms for girls</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-25-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-25-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  From preschool to university and beyond, all students wear a variant of the same uniform. The kindergartners may not wear a full gi and camisole pinafore, but the basic ensemble is still there. This is the girl’s one, and it’s much more elaborate than the boy’s uniform.
Year-round, all students wear a school armband with their year and class embroidered on it and a badge of education, which is pinned to the top button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on the end of the world</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-19-endgame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-19-endgame/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  A single hiss, the heavy door rolls back, and it derails into sandbags. A gas piston grinds, an engine ignites, and a roar sends flames pouring fifty feet high out of the silo as a sleek missile emerges and climbs towards hunting altitude.
This missile will strike Lanzhou, China. The larger cities, swollen with people, are protected by antimissile laser batteries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KID COMIX, an underground comic mag in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-11-comix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-11-comix/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  There are some comics that Vekllei syndicates just won’t publish. KID Magazine, or KID Comix ran for nearly a century. It was picked up and dropped by dozens of anonymous artists, writers and editors, all operating under nonsense pseudonyms — Red, Squick, Failson and Daddy Fun were some of the longest-serving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KID COMIX, an underground comic mag in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-07-masculinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-07-masculinity/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Just a few notes on what it means to be a man in Vekllei.
Vekllei is a country at odds with itself. On one hand, it is universal in its politics and fundamentally internationalist; on the other it is a deeply traditional country that values bloodlines and heritage. It is a secular democracy that regularly alludes to monarchy in its rituals and symbolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shot like a dog in a Supermarket &amp; the Vekllei Grocery Economy</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-06-shot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-06-shot/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   A fluorescent light burst on Thursday. She was stacking cans for a display. The girl was working alone that evening and leaving her mark everywhere — happy apple drawings, new posters, displays — she liked the job.
The light burst like a gunshot and she leapt to her feet. Down the aisle she saw herself, at the lowest point in her life, standing over an old friend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>summer nerds reading comix</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-29-nerds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-29-nerds/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>big mood right now</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-28-mood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-28-mood/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Constabulary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-23-constabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-23-constabulary/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Policing is always difficult in utopian planning. On one hand, utopia is inherently opposed to the idea of policing and the can of worms it brings — on the other, people need to feel safe and protected. That’s not something I’ll be talking about today.
The Vekllei Constabulary are the second largest policing body in the country, after conventional police.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All-weather combat for the Atomic Age</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-20-troops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-20-troops/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The single most important function of today’s global powers is not in the numbers of men at a state&amp;rsquo;s command, or the prosperity of their domestic markets, but the ability to project power across the world entire.
We have seen this manifest in many ways; ICBMs are just one example. Warfare in a modern context has become a highly intelligent and specialised force that has simultaneously limited the brutality of warmongering while amplifying the ruthlessness and political function of state-sponsored murder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is Blood Worship</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-19-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-19-blood/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Blood is everything to these women. It defines them through every stage of life — bloody emerging from the womb, bloody again in the delicate transition from child to womanhood, and bloody on the table, awaiting cremation in wait of the afterlife.
Even in her name — Zelda lo Ula Desmoines — the premise of blood is there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old, dead demons still wander the countryside</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-16-demons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-16-demons/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   She met herself out by the shrine, many summers ago. At first she didn’t know what it was — she thought it might be a spirit, or — and she caught herself in the thought, because she was only half a child — a little part of her wondered if it was a manifestation of God, or Christ, come to help solve her problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Country of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-15-vekllei/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-15-vekllei/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  There is no real distinction between the city of Vekllei and the state of Vekllei, at least internally. To them, the country and the city are the same, and the isolated population centres of Montre and Adouisneh are simply distant neighbourhoods. This is reflected in all manners of life — they are ethnically and culturally homogenous, patriotic, and largely uncompetitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora&#39;s Portrait</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-08-portrait/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-08-portrait/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Practising colours. It&amp;rsquo;s always been my weakness. While you&amp;rsquo;re here, if you have any questions about Tzipora or want to chat, let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-01-princess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-01-princess/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  They never actually believed that she was any kind of princess. They never even joked about it. The original LIFE magazine article said that she looked as though she were ‘a princess of the Earth’ when interviewer Alfie Ricci met her in the Vekllei highlands, and so she carried that name as a burden for the next few hundred years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valleys of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-28-valleys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-28-valleys/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Two years ago, a fission military jet plunged into the mountain behind the village of Montre-Lola, emerging moments later as a plume of fire and smoke in the shadow of the mountain peak. Villagers made their way up the slopes to help survivors, dressed in radiation suits from the town shelter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot summer rain on a beach of black sand -- Iceland in 2127</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-20-black-sand/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-20-black-sand/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Just as Iceland&amp;rsquo;s initial history was reshaped into the image of Vekllei some centuries ago, so too has the real-world climate and weather been altered. Cool Icelandic summers have been usurped by volatile days that can be as low as 5C (40F) or as hot as 30C (85F+). Technically speaking, the unstable Atlantic pressure oscillation, of which Vekllei anchors as the Vekllei low pole, can pull in bitter cold from the Greenland currents, or warmth from the Azores tempestuously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>winter love &#43; puffin / feat. Tzipora &amp; Akiko</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-19-puffin-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-19-puffin-love/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  &amp;ldquo;The puffin flies here so early (over the years). The further inland we go, the farther they chase us.&amp;rdquo;
That&amp;rsquo;s the sentiment of the phrase, but in Vekllei &amp;lsquo;The puffin flies here&amp;rsquo; is supplemented with the opening of a saying, &amp;lsquo;all birds flee the sea in Winter,&amp;rsquo; and so there is a reference here that is otherwise lost in translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navy in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-15-salvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-15-salvo/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  There are not many warships in the world today that are distinctive as the serpentine-funnelled, semi-tumblehome hull of the Sundress-class supercruisers. For a country that prides itself on ‘petticoat society’, it is only suitable that Vekllei continues to pioneer the ‘dazzle’ warpaint in her navy.
 The most recent stock of Navy ships are all named after women’s clothes, to emphasise Vekllei’s spiritual understanding of gender in industrial society and also as a sarcastic nominer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What will become of the Gregori Children?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-10-gregori/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-10-gregori/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Did you know — many Gregori children do not form calluses on their skin, because of the intensity of their epidermic regeneration process!
Hello all,
The question on the mind of folks around the world is that of Gregori Children. What are they? What does it mean, to be a “Gregori Baby”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-29-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-29-life/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Vekllei is the final stop in the epoch of rest. Departing your jetliner or aeroship and setting foot in the city is a spiritual experience — the weight of the world leaves your shoulders, and, at last, you are at peace. Imagine what that would be like — to be self-actualised!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood Names</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-14-blood-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-14-blood-name/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Each person in Vekllei has three names — a given name (Tzipora), a surname (Desmoines), and an alternative given name as part of rapotenne (potenne is ‘handtalk’, upotenne is ‘spirit-talk’, and so it follows that rapotenne is the language system of names). This alternative name is a ‘key’ to the full blood name of an individual, which are given in secret by the mother traditionally, but can be gifted by any mother-figure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dress code for talking to spirits</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-24-spirits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-24-spirits/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Vekllei animism, which branches into a vast and complex set of beliefs and traditions that vary from village to village, there is no formal religious structure. Temples and shrines pay respect to sprites, which are universally understood as bi-planar creatures. There is no formal religious structure, and so animistic tradition has no priests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-18-police-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-18-police-car/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Hopefully you won’t have to worry about the police while you’re in Vekllei, but you’ll likely notice them. Police are everywhere — as an alternative to military (duoroten) service, conscripts can elect to enter domestic security (inroten). Most officers are young, bored, and live in the community they police. You’ll likely be talking to them at some point in your visit, even if it’s only to ask for directions — in Vekllei, cops are the bulletin boards of the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Bow (and Fashion in Vekllei)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-01-bowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-01-bowing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Vekllei has a pan-pacific flavour of greeting, usually a bow followed by a handshake. If you’re going to fit in, you’re going to have to learn how to do it right. Let’s get started.
First, Vekllei is extremely physical in its language. Not expressive, like how you might picture an Italian or American.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Clothing (and Womanhood in Vekllei)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-16-winter-clothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-16-winter-clothing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Welcome to Vekllei. It is a strange country with a complex culture that is quite distinct (and sometimes outrageous) to Western countries. This will be a long post. I’ve tried to keep it clear.
 Women in Vekllei usually wear skirts in winter. There are cultural and historical reasons for this, explained below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rail-Launched Nuclear Missiles</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-09-rail-missiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-09-rail-missiles/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is a concept of a Vekllei Rocketry Corp rail ICBM launcher. It has distinctive-looking carriages, and so it serves no real purpose in being a ‘hidden’ ICBM launcher. Instead, this train is for testing rail-mounted ICBMs, which are then employed in plain and unmarked railcars. Today it idles by the lakeside town of Dupot-Monan, as its senior control staff await a hot lunch driven in from the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washing the Feet of the Enemy</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-06-penance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-06-penance/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  He had sent her a wire some weeks before asking to meet her. She did not remember him. By now he was an old man, and she, a Gregori baby of sixty four years, had not aged a day. He was close to dying and wanted to relieve his soul of the war crimes he’d committed as a member of the Vanguard in the Second American Civil War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sketch of a Blood Spirit</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-03-03-demon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-03-03-demon/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Blood spirits are unaware people have physical forms. Why should they? No person has entered the realm of the spirits in a millenia.
When the Princess of the Earth arrived, after the nuclear exchange between the United States and China, one of the first encounters she had with a spirit in their homeworld was a blood spirit tearing her apart while looking for food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Concept of Childhood</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-02-23-childhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-02-23-childhood/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This post is part discussion, part lore.
Kojin Karatani, on the subject of childhood, writes;
 Of course, children have existed since ancient times, yet &amp;lsquo;the child&amp;rsquo; as we conceive of it and objectify it did not exist prior to a particular period [&amp;hellip;].
From this viewpoint, it becomes clear that the grouping of children by age in the compulsory educational system of modern Japan signified the uprooting of children, as abstract and homogenous entities, from productive relations, social classes, and communities that had previously been their concrete contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bridging of Worlds Ritual</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-25-ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-25-ritual/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora is the oldest person alive, now aged 1,056 years. With the body, temperament, and vitality of an 11-year-old, and the lived experience of a dozen generations, she is a victim Gregori syndrome. She has seen man rise from Earth into space, and although she still calls her birth-country of Vekllei on Earth home, she frequently tours the cosmos as part of complex interplanetary diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anarchy in Cherry, Nevada</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-15-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-15-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The young Republican has waited in a queue to have her photo taken in front of the remains of Cherry, Nevada. Her hair is still short after the fascists shaved her head, and branded her with St David’s star because she had a Jewish name. She would later tell the Republican Militia that she wasn’t, in fact, a Jew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl Scouts Learn to Shoot in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-12-12-blossoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-12-12-blossoms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora Desmoines is part of Troop 45 of the Vekllei Blossoms. Every adult, as part of mandatory service in the country of Vekllei, owns and operates a firearm, most commonly a handgun. Because of this hazard, the children of Vekllei learn gun safety at an early age, either through school or the Blossoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiation Poisoning in Domestic Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-12-05-radiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-12-05-radiation/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  He started collecting radioactive material from the clocks and electronic appliances in his house earlier in the week. The material, which included radium and americium, was placed in a compartment in the living room wall of his apartment. This exposed his wife, nine-year-old son and infant daughter to dangerous levels of radioactivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seaside in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-11-28-seaside/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-11-28-seaside/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  About this time of year, in the place between high summer and autumn, the weather is good in Vekllei. Vekllei is too cold for crickets, but insects are out and the air hums with life — birds, helijets, and the soft noise an ocean breeze makes as it races toward the harbour, pulling on leaves and skirt hems along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beat Cops in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-11-07-cop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-11-07-cop/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   It was just like any other evening in Monouiz; a no-good view of one part concrete, one part fescue, and a whole lotta quiet. He knew the broad from his days hunting smuggler types in jazz bars and street cars, a gig not worth gigging now that prohibition was over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-24-princess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-24-princess/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Barbaloh was once the spirit of a rainforest, but now lives only in the world of the spirits as a merchant, selling potions, spells and other supernatural nonsense. Tzipora, a brave human girl and fierce humanist, has gained passage to the spirit world through the bones of a derden, or “angel”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Spies and a Vekllei Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-19-spies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-19-spies/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Nevada about this time of year, the temperature stays steady at 45 degrees (~115 in yank). The asphalt sticks to shoes. On the far right is Lenny the Jew. The moniker is his own; he’s a Jew from New York who ended up working for the Vekllei Rocketry Corps, the Vekllei espionage agency responsible for operations in the southern United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entering the Spirit World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-14-spirit-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-14-spirit-world/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Suddenly the blood drained from her lungs and she breathed in, only to double over, hacking blood into the grass between her shoes. She wiped her bloody mouth on the back of her arm and mumbled something like ‘sorry’ before coughing again. She slipped off her shoes and made her way to the clearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Dress of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-13-national-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-13-national-dress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Vekllei people are usually buried in their national dress. It marks the important stages in their way of life; of graduation, of marriage, of ceremony. The carousel of festivals and parades and holidays that these Atlantic people enjoy are all spent in uniform, their national costume, that forms the public face of their country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching the End of the World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-12-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-12-missile/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The sight of the missiles nearly made her sick. Everything around her took on new context. It was such a peaceful afternoon, and the sirens hadn’t gone off, and here she was, watching the trails the missiles painted in the cloudless sky. And now she was blessed with a newfound psychic ability that told her that everything in this spot would be vapour in a half hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Face of Human Extinction</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-09-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-09-face/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  All servants of heaven — called angels by most people but they belong to a much older name — are viciously jealous of human beings. In creation, the Earth was promised to them, but the creator God gave the Earth to the human race. In a fit of rage, the angels — or Derden, as they were called before the current chapter of humanity — buried bioengineered monsters called Lehmenan far below the surface of the Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Vekllei General Store</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-06-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-06-store/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In the narrow streets of the Lola district in Vekllei, artisans and artists hurry about, peddling art and fine goods and attracting the rest of the city to its stores. In Vekllei, there is no currency, so shopping is almost always a pragmatic affair.
Not in Lola. If you’re in Lola, you’re there to see the good stuff, produced and sold in little shops like this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pleading with Angels to Spare Humanity</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-02-angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-02-angels/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   She saw its bones and the sight of them — that they were real and not a dream — caught in her throat. She raised her hand to cough, and suddenly her lungs heaved and blood began to pour from the spaces between her fingers. Her eyes grew wide and she cupped her hand, and she retched again and her blood sprayed out like a hose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Warfare in 2063</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-27-chemical-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-27-chemical-war/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   “We came to a town and found it scorched with mustard and the fragments of phosgene shells, and the wind whistled through the doorways that were left open. I remember being surprised by how many of them were in basements — probably because they thought the gas would blow away in the wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora, the Undying Miracle Child</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-24-undying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-24-undying/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora is a Gregori baby, a child who doesn’t age and cannot contract cell-mutating diseases. She is the adopted daughter of Michael Desmoines, an espionage quartermaster for a foreign power in the United States.
She is clever, sensitive, and deeply humanist. Despite her shyness and her loneliness, she is remembered by the few whose lives she touched as an affectionate and exceptionally gifted girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora Makes Friends with a Desert Spirit</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-21-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-21-spirit/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Every natural place has a spirit that minds it. Tzipora had never met a desert spirit before, and she went looking for one in Cherry, Nevada. With air force jets glinting in the sky overhead, and the temperature scorching the mesas that surround the military town, she found one inside a burrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fashion in the Year 2063</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-19-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-19-fashion/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Vekllei kids look to America as a bastion of good taste; a country of fast cars and diners and sock-hops and high-school romance. Like the Koreans look to Japanese taste, and the British look to the stuff coming out of design houses in France, Vekllei is infatuated with how Americans dress in the year 2063.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl’s Life Saved by Veteran Hero in Day of Terror</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-10-terror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-10-terror/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Louenne Dehmones enlisted for two years but stayed for ten. He served abroad in the war department, where he performed admirably but never rose above the rank of Junior Sergeant because of a good-natured appetite for mischief. He transferred to the military police to be close to his wife and infant daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora, one of the children to stop ageing</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-04-ageing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-04-ageing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora. She is eleven years old, scruffy, and a Gregori baby. At the turn of the 21st century, Gregori Hordiyenko, a Ukrainian boy aged nine and a half, stopped aging entirely. By 2063, which is the year Tzipora turned eleven, there are about two hundred Gregori babies in the world, mostly living in secret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Uniforms of Any Good Vekllei Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-08-17-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-08-17-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  These are the five basic outfits a kid in the city of Vekllei rotates between in their life. This is Tzipora. She’s sharp and a little scruffy. She’s eleven years old.
The first is her school uniform, complete with embroidered armband featuring the national crest. The skirt has a longer pleated section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-bullying poster in the year 2063. Not very effective. From the city of Vekllei.</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-08-10-bullying/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-08-10-bullying/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This poster circulated middle schools in 2063 as part of a wider initiative at curbing violence against women at an early age. The two Vekllei characters on the left read literally as &amp;ldquo;there is no excuse to hit a female,&amp;rdquo; but it emphasises the ‘hit’ part of it to make the idea particularly reprehensible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>She stands in the harbour in national dress. Jets fly overhead and a parade passes to mourn the victims of the atomic bombings.</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-07-19-national-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-07-19-national-dress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora, a recent immigrant girl of eleven years, wears the feminine national dress of Vekllei. It is a delicate, traditional and deeply spiritual costume, and is tied to Vekllei’s foundations and aspirations as a state. It has political symbolism, but it also ties the girl to the land she stands on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora has her photo taken at Youth Meet 2063. Nuclear war in Germany breaks out eight days later.</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-07-01-youth-meet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-07-01-youth-meet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora is smiling in the photo because she has won the competition for multilingual spelling. She is a recent citizen of Vekllei, a postcollectivist country in what we know as Iceland. She beat American boy scouts, Australian girl guides, Chinese and Soviet Pioneers and other youth organisations to win top prize.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
