<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archive on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archive on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Atlantic Boredom</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 05:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-10-07-boredom/</guid>
      <description>For a brief period of time, Zelda and Cobian took it upon themselves to make something of their youth. Cobian fancied herself a gymnast, and though this ambition arrived too late and left too soon, she was quite good at it for a while. Tzipora was better suited on the trampoline, where her stiff leg didn’t give her as much trouble.
They trained for about two hours, and after practice they met up to travel home together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matchstick Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-14-matchstick/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.Another paint-sketch — a painting done fast. I’m trying to learn to a) paint and b) paint on an industrial scale.
She’d missed the fast tram, caught a tiny splinter in her thumb, lost a button and now the match wouldn’t strike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Trip</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-11-roadtrip/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.They showed up at the autopool, and someone had just returned a brand new AAAC Voya Voya — incredible. It was like Christ himself had blessed them. It only (barely) seat five, and there were six of them, but it wasn’t a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-31-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of the second day, I watched a fly crawl across the cheek of the middle-aged woman, probably an office worker, lying next to me. It moved up her cheekbone to her temple, stopping now and then to rub its front legs as though performing a ritual. A jagged tear ran down the leg of her dark blue work trousers, but the white calf it revealed was miraculously unscathed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Quiet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 03:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</guid>
      <description>There were plumes in the sky, sent from bunkers buried deep in the well of the Earth, killing with switches. Vekllei went to war, and so Tzipora went to war with it.
The throbbing machinery of another world began turning, and anyone who saw the bomb would hear it. Passing seconds dislocated and caught heartbeats. The plumes were pretty. It was such a shame, those plumes. It was a quiet afternoon in the flower-tundras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Newda in Rural Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 03:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</guid>
      <description>Newda is Vekllei’s national architectural ideology, applied flexibly in a range of modernist styles developed domestically in her architecture schools. Broadly, Newda buildings emphasise distinction from the surrounding landscape (called Dumousiantopet, or ‘beautiful and seperate’), natural decay, and honesty in material and construction. Vekllei’s great Parliament House is Newda; as are the little rural homes found in the mountains inland in Vekllei.
Tzipora’s house in the village of Montre-Lola (as depicted on the map here) is built in what Vekllei calls “Azores revivalism”, a Newda style heavily influenced by the stripped deco and streamline moderne buildings of a century prior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thousand-Year-Old Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 01:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-12-ageless/</guid>
      <description>The concept of living forever jumps out at people uncomfortable with their own existence. There is a contemplative instinct among educated people that — if they could simply will themselves into a state of self-actualisation — death would only be an obstacle to greatness.
As Tzipora found out quickly, the opposite was true — death and temporality were wells of meaning against which all great people, beauty, and human constructions were cast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 31st Century — Vekllei throughout our Solar System</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 05:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-09-spaceship/</guid>
      <description>The Epoch of Rest#We’ve spent a lot of time in the 21st century — but Tzipora is biologically immortal. Where does she go from here? Well, let’s enjoy a small glimpse at that future together, by winding the clock forward one thousand years.
By 3076, our Solar System is a pleasant place to be. Most of the planets we once gazed at from afar are now habitable and lived on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora — concept panel for a Vekllei comic</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 06:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-01-tzipora-concept/</guid>
      <description>Unique among girls#There are a lot of things Tzipora does differently to everybody else, and they start to make a lot more sense when you realise Tzipora either does not realise she is unusual, or does not care.
She has a lot of endearing characteristics that give great character to her mannerisms and physicality. She has a small overbite that makes her look a little froggy, and ritually pulls on her shirt and wipes her nose in anxious conversation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer House in the Azores</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-28-summer-house/</guid>
      <description>The Azores had been a possession of Vekllei since 2002, when they were leased from Portugal indefinitely. The lease was defunct by the time of Vekllei’s independence from U.K. occupation in 2015, and the new state took formal ownership over the small Atlantic islands.
The Azores was Vekllei’s resort region, often called simply the “holiday isles”. Brief reprieves from the North Atlantic cold were granted to hundreds of thousands domestic tourists each year in resorts and holiday rentals alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Camp</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 03:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
      <description>Just a paint-sketch.
The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.
The Krafla high-energy communications tower was visible from all over the region. It provided uninterrupted radio to most of North Lava, and could relay signals through satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora’s ‘Every Day Carry’</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 05:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-20-edc/</guid>
      <description>Like a lot of girls of poverty, Tzipora was very possessive of her things. No food was ever left on her plate. There was a deep anxiety that whatever wasn’t claimed would be lost.
She was also naturally obsessive and material-oriented, keenly aware of the importance of objects measured by metrics in her own silly head. You can discover a lot about a person from their trinkets and toys — let’s discover a bit about Tzipora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Race for Inefficiency — Vekllei’s advocation of austerity, apathy, and playfulness as economic principles</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 04:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-13-economy/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the economy of Vekllei. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a long one. If you have any questions, just ask.
Overview of the Bureau System#There are many thousands of companies busy with work in Vekllei. The vast majority of these companies are single-person shops (S.p.A., or senrouiva pettetie anaproiouya). Also common are wobbly shops, or co-operative businesses (S.q.A., or senrouiva qualitie anaproiouya). The largest of the non-bureau companies are village factories (S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 03:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
      <description>There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.
 Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or venopor) Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or cosmopor)  A young venopor officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike cosmopor, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Map of Vekllei — 100 Boroughs; 100 Hearts</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 23:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/</guid>
      <description>Map Key
 Red: Magjet trains, 750km/h
Yellow: Bullet trains, 300-400km/h
Orange: Regional trains, &amp;lt;150km/h
Brown: Local trains, including limited express, &amp;lt;100km/h
Blue: National highway
Dashed: Ferry line
Green: tarmacadamed airport
 The largest division of any portion of Vekllei land is the borough; a region of varying size and population with common culture, food dependency and economic interest. Anything larger than that is simply Vekllei — they are “one city”, after all, and consider themselves a city-state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vekllei Crown — coins of a moneyless country</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 05:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/</guid>
      <description>Vekllei, legendarily, does not use circulate currency. Goods and services are moved and offered arbitrarily, provided amply in abundance. Anything that is not abundant is manufactured and distributed directly under the control of a bureau, which is a trade organ responsible to the affairs of the country. At no point do coins or paper currency change hands in the day-to-day affairs of the country.
In this sense, Vekllei is usually described as “moneyless” — yet it does in fact have a currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Village Map of Montre-Lola</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 04:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-29-montrelola/</guid>
      <description>The village of Montre-Lola is home to about 400 people in its entirety, a stone’s throw from the Aisyo borough. Each morning, however, the population swells as 300 children from tiny villages in both Aisyo and Montre take a fast tram to the Montre-Lola Area School No. 2, a district school raising all ages of local youth.
Like many Vekllei villages, Montre-Lola’s history is complex and has origin stories in both viking-inuit settlement as well as less sentimental government programmes that flourished after the atomic war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Most Beautiful Woman</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 03:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</guid>
      <description>When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”
It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture. Tzipora was not quite sure how to describe it. Her beauty was very alive in the way she inhabited a space, as she walked into the hotel lounge to meet them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oa-Class Battlecruiser</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 02:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-06-battlecruiser/</guid>
      <description>Vekllei’s defensive military posture has, in doctrine and arms development, limited its ability to meaningfully project power outside of the Atlantic. As an island nation with a large and multifaceted naval armada, the Oa-Class Battlecruiser is the heart of her armed forces, as the flagship of her fleets.
Where U.S. doctrine places carriers offensively in the structure of its ship-groups, the Vekllei Navy is considerably more Soviet in its employ of carriers as primarily defensive air-bases to exercise sovereignty over her far-flung territories and island possessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canal Living</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 02:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
      <description>Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad. Nothing was trucked. Fish was traded fresh in markets or turned into emulsifiers and fertiliser.
The canals were worked heavily, and few fishing vessels were incorporated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fission Cloud at Vekllei&#39;s 50th Anniversary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 01:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-01-fission/</guid>
      <description>In an unprecedented event, during Vekllei’s 50th Sea Festival since Independence in 2065, an 8 kiloton fission bomb was sunk to a depth of 150 meters and detonated at midday. It was an incredible sight on a day so clear you could see the gentle curve of the earth where it met the horizon. A flash of light and a spray dome surged outwards into the quiet Atlantic, which was broken apart by plumes that formed a column of water that climbed high into the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Rain in the Arctic Circle</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-27-rain/</guid>
      <description>Tzipora had been ejected from the operations room once the guys arrived. She knew what was going down, anyway. No specifics. But you didn’t bring in uniformed soldiers for regular business. National Intelligence liked to work with their own people.
Five days prior, Baron hailed an EB/NI company car and it pulled up beside him. The electric passenger window slid down. Baron nodded at the passenger.
“Everything’s in here. There’s more if you need it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 01:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
      <description>They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform. And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables. Out here, you paced life around the station.
There was not much to say about this, between the two of them. Tzipora looked at Cobian and pulled a froggy smile that tried to express that it was nobody’s fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 23:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.
Still, by late October, the the earth is hard with cold and the days are short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031 Apartment Diagram</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 02:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-15-apartment/</guid>
      <description>Baron had inherited the apartment from his uncle, who passed in the year following his parents. It was in a mixed residential-industrial neighbourhood, adjacent to a canvas factory. Out back was a rivulet, which roared in the long rainstorms of early April.
 Each January, the Colour Bureau of the Architecture Assembly announces the year’s colours, and tradition in mainstream architecture and interior design is to incorporate the announced palettes, which usually contain a hundred or so colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Tzipo-stcards</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 01:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-13-tzipostcards/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone. Just a little update.
As a way of thanking my Patrons, I’m taking some time over the next two weeks or so to create a little set of Tzipora postcards and send them out as gifts.
How many cards will the set contain?
 I’m aiming for about six cards.
 How much money would you need to have forked over to get some?
 I think about $20 over your pledge lifetime would cover print and shipping, though I’ll let you know if that goes up or down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiery Peaks</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</guid>
      <description>After three days in Ada, Tzipora set off towards Mt Miya. She made good time, and after three hours had happened upon the shoulders of the bright Volouisnesnkull Glacier. It was about here that she heard a morbid industrial siren, echoing up the valleys from far away.
At first she thought it might have come from Ada, since Boya Chemical had a large plant there, but as she lay out her things for lunch she heard the distinct whine of a turbojet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chemical Feast</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 02:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</guid>
      <description>East of Montre, West of Tjornes, waits a rare sight among Vekllei’s hard igneous slopes — a crown of gentle sedimentary cliffs packed with ruddy sandstone, which melt glacially into the sea chasing blue-sky bergs.
Tzipora was, at the time, making her way on foot from Montre-Lola to Ada, which was a coastal town in the North-East known for its luxurious health spas. Tzipora was not much interested in health, but she was interested in walking, and she made a pilgrimage along the coast every few years to make sense of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trials of Cobian</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 01:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-02-trials/</guid>
      <description>According to her friends, Tzipora’s contemporary afflictions were tragic. Her medical problems; her violent childhood; her sensitivity and melancholy — you could feel sorry for her, because a lot of her problems were not her fault. She invoked sympathy.
Tzipora never considered herself particularly tragic. It seemed straightforward, if difficult; she continued to live — and so she lived. Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s sympathy was instead reserved for her first and closest friend: Cobian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People of Vekllei’s Railway (plus Dog)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 23:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-16-station-dog/</guid>
      <description>Station Dogs#I’m starting a series looking at the lives and machines of domestic Vekllei life.
Vekllei National Railways, or ‘VK Rail’ was the bastard of six major pre-war rail companies that were extinguished along with the society that housed them. Today there are three rail companies in Vekllei, but all of them operate under direct supervision of a Vekllei Industry Bureau (making it Venrouiva, in other words) and are only broken up for reasons of logistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Vekllei?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-26-what-is-vekllei/</guid>
      <description>Vekllei is a country in my alt-world; a utopian fever dream of googie aesthetics, participatory economics and nostalgia.
Welcome to the ‘Petticoat Project’, a collection of stories about a country and a girl. The concept is broken down into three sections:
 Author: for blog posts and articles on the Petticoat Project, utopian fiction, personal news item, etc. Character: for posts about Tzipora, people in her life, or otherwise events that occur during her time on Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
