<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Ministry</title>
	<link>/series/ministry/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Ministry </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/series/ministry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Commerce</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This ministry is part of Vekllei The Ministry of Commerce (COSMOSOL) conducts government spending and facilitates trade in the country. Despite the functional moneylessness of the Vekllei, COSMOSOL remains among the busiest ministries of the Interior Government, since all economic policy, international trade and entitled renumeration (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for withdrawing from the Commonwealth Bank) occurs through its subordinate bureaus and organisations. Common responsibilities of COSMOSOL include:
Regulation and taxation of international trade, particularly through Government &lsquo;White Bonds&rsquo; and Commonwealth Bank &lsquo;Blue Bonds&rsquo; Banking the Commonwealth state apparatus Advising the Parliament on economic policy and foreign trade Monitoring and reporting on the health of foreign markets Printing and transporting currency The Ministry of Commerce is led by the State Secretary of Commerce, who is a member of the Cabinet.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> <strong>Ministry of Commerce</strong> (COSMOSOL) conducts government spending and facilitates trade in the country. Despite the functional moneylessness of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, COSMOSOL remains among the busiest ministries of the Interior Government, since all economic policy, international trade and entitled renumeration (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for withdrawing from the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(240, 93, 136); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(240, 93, 136) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/state/commonwealth-bank/"><span class="fi fi-min-combank fis"></span> Commonwealth Bank</a>) occurs through its subordinate bureaus and organisations. Common responsibilities of COSMOSOL include:</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li>Regulation and taxation of international trade, particularly through Government &lsquo;<a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/?ref=footer#white-bonds">White Bonds</a>&rsquo; and Commonwealth Bank &lsquo;<a href="/factbook/society/state/finance/?ref=footer#blue-bonds">Blue Bonds</a>&rsquo;</li>
<li>Banking the Commonwealth state apparatus</li>
<li>Advising the Parliament on economic policy and foreign trade</li>
<li>Monitoring and reporting on the health of foreign markets</li>
<li>Printing and transporting currency</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Ministry of Commerce is led by the State Secretary of Commerce, who is a member of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>. It is represented in the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a> by the First Minister of Commerce.</p>
<p>Most of the functions of the ministry are conducted by the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-commerce); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-commerce) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commerce/commonwealth-treasury/"><span class="fi fi-min-commerce fis"></span> Commonwealth Treasury</a>, which oversees most economic planning and operates the vast computerised systems that functionally run the Vekllei domestic market.</p>
<p>Vekllei has a reputation as a financial capital for its political neutrality and location between Europe and the Americas, and is among the largest facilitators of international commerce and exchange in the world.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Culture</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/culture/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/culture/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This ministry is part of Vekllei The Ministry of Culture is a devolved ministry of the Government of Vekllei. It has a broad mandate that includes cultural preservation and promotion, but also media, telecommunications and sports.
The constituent bureaux and organisations of the ministry serve a variety of roles. Vekllei is a deeply multicultural society and comprises dozens of indigenous and foreign languages and cultures. Its role in this context is twofold; the promotion and preservation of cultural diversity, but also the promotion and preservation of common beliefs, languages and civic principles that unify Vekllei as a country.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-culture fis"></span> <strong>Ministry of Culture</strong> is a <a href="/ministries/">devolved ministry</a> of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Government</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It has a broad mandate that includes cultural preservation and promotion, but also media, telecommunications and sports.</p>
<p>The constituent bureaux and organisations of the ministry serve a variety of roles. Vekllei is a deeply multicultural society and comprises dozens of indigenous and foreign languages and cultures. Its role in this context is twofold; the promotion and preservation of cultural diversity, but also the promotion and preservation of common beliefs, languages and civic principles that unify Vekllei as a country. This includes the promotion of English as a functional language, a decision made for practical rather than historical or cultural purposes. It also serves an important role in integrating migrants through the promotion of community activities and events.</p>
<p>In addition, the ministry outlines the roles and restrictions of news media and telecommunications. Though Vekllei people and press have freedom of speech protected under their <a href="/rights/">Civil Rights</a>, communications and media agencies have standards set by the ministry or industry. The ministry also has a hand in postal services, sports, and cultural institutions of national significance. Common responsibilities of the ministry include:</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li>Celebration and promotion of Vekllei traditional languages and cultures</li>
<li>Welcoming and integration of migrants into Vekllei society</li>
<li>Management of press and news media, often as a standards authority and regulator</li>
<li>Management of postal services and telecommunications</li>
<li>Promotion of literature, arts and film to ordinary people, and to encourage their participation in culture</li>
<li>Celebration and recognition of Vekllei arts and culture</li>
<li>Management of national arts institutes, archives and libraries</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Ministry of Culture is led by the State Secretary of Culture, who is a member of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>. It is represented in the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a> by the First Minister of Culture.</p>
<p>The ministry plays a major role in the organisation of festivals and large cultural products, like feature films. In these cases, it serves as a neutral production role and has no ability to dictate or censor content. The ministry may also be commissioned by government or industry to produce documentaries or publish information on subjects, for which it performs the same neutral production role.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Defence</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This ministry is part of Vekllei The Ministry of Defence is responsible for the Armed Forces of Vekllei, as well as its civil defence organisations that include both its police services and emergency response capabilities. In this sense, the Ministry of Defence exercises both a military and civilian role, and its devolved nature under Commonwealth federalism means it has a broad mandate between republics.
The ministry in peacetime does not exercise command authority of its constituent organisations directly, as the military and civil defence forces are autonomous organisations.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> <strong>Ministry of Defence</strong> is responsible for the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/"><span class="fi fi-min-defence fis"></span> Armed Forces</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, as well as its civil defence organisations that include both its police services and emergency response capabilities. In this sense, the Ministry of Defence exercises both a military and civilian role, and its devolved nature under Commonwealth federalism means it has a broad mandate between <a href="/republics/">republics</a>.</p>
<p>The ministry in peacetime does not exercise command authority of its constituent organisations directly, as the military and civil defence forces are autonomous organisations. Common responsibilities of the ministry include:</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li>Development of defence policy and planning.</li>
<li>Recruitment of citizens and foreigners into the armed forces.</li>
<li>Equipment procurement and administration.</li>
<li>Conducting scientific military research.</li>
<li>Policing and security of Vekllei republics, territorial waters and exclusive economic zones.</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Ministry of Defence is led by the State Secretary of Defence, who is a member of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>. It is represented in the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a> by the First Minister of Defence.</p>
<p>Aspects of Vekllei&rsquo;s police and military are devolved, and the ministry has a key role in coordinating them centrally and establishing standards of service.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Foreign Affairs</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/foreign-affairs/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/foreign-affairs/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ This ministry is part of Vekllei Overview # COSMOSEA ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="overview">
  Overview
  <a class="anchor" href="#overview">#</a>
</h2>
<b class="boxtag teal">
  COSMOSEA
</b>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Industry</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/industry/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/industry/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ This ministry is part of Vekllei ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Labour</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/labour/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/labour/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This ministry is part of Vekllei The Ministry of Labour is a devolved ministry of the Government of Vekllei. It provides a general role in registering and legislating the Vekllei workforce, which serves a unique role in Vekllei&rsquo;s participatory economy.
The ministry serves traditional functions in establishing workplace standards and safety legislation, but also maintains the consosva and corsosva systems, which outline the legal obligations for employment and civic conscription respectively.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-labour fis"></span> <strong>Ministry of Labour</strong> is a <a href="/ministries/">devolved ministry</a> of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Government</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It provides a general role in registering and legislating the Vekllei workforce, which serves a unique role in Vekllei&rsquo;s participatory economy.</p>
<p>The ministry serves traditional functions in establishing workplace standards and safety legislation, but also maintains the <em><a href="/consosva/">consosva</a></em> and <em><a href="/corsosva/">corsosva</a></em> systems, which outline the legal obligations for employment and civic conscription respectively. To this end, the Ministry of Labour is an organiser of essential work in Vekllei, as well as a general administrator of worker protections, industrial relations and migrant integration. Common responsibilities of the ministry include:</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li>Compiling labour statistics and registers of employment for use in policy</li>
<li>Ensuring compliance with Vekllei workplace standards</li>
<li>Handling employment in compliance with the <a href="/consosva/">Consosva</a> principles and laws</li>
<li>Organising manpower and conscription in the <a href="/corsosva/">Corsosva</a> system</li>
<li>Facilitating collective bargaining and labour relations</li>
<li>Hearing and prosecuting violations of labour standards, including anti-discrimination laws</li>
<li>Facilitating training and skill-building in Vekllei workplaces</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Ministry of Labour is led by the State Secretary of Labour, who is a member of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>. It is represented in the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a> by the First Minister of Labour.</p>
<p>The ministry is highly devolved, and although its policy is subordinated to federal legislation, devolved branches of the ministry generally reflect their local economies and have different political priorities. In developing Vekllei republics, for example, transition to the <em>Commons</em> social economy requires regular intervention by the ministry. In developed moneyless economies like the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina Commonwealth</a> and <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/"><span class="fi fi-volcanic"></span> Volcanic Commonwealth</a>, the ministry targets training and unemployment as priorities.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Landscape</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This ministry is part of Vekllei The Ministry of Landscape is a devolved ministry of the Government of Vekllei. It serves a broad role in government in matters related to agriculture, food security, natural resources, meteorology, nature and the oceans. In this sense, the ministry is tasked with &ldquo;landscape&rdquo; as it is used in Vekllei, with resource exploitation and human settlements assigned to the Ministry of Industry and the Ministry of the Commons respectively.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-landscape fis"></span> <strong>Ministry of Landscape</strong> is a <a href="/ministries/">devolved ministry</a> of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Government</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It serves a broad role in government in matters related to agriculture, food security, natural resources, meteorology, nature and the oceans. In this sense, the ministry is tasked with &ldquo;landscape&rdquo; as it is used in Vekllei, with resource exploitation and human settlements assigned to the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-industry); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-industry) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/industry/"><span class="fi fi-min-industry fis"></span> Ministry of Industry</a> and the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-commons); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-commons) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commons/"><span class="fi fi-min-commons fis"></span> Ministry of the Commons</a> respectively.</p>
<p>Although the ministry has many environmental and conservationist responsibilities, it is not strictly an environmental ministry. Instead, its portfolio encompasses the physical landscape of Vekllei in a straightforward sense. This includes weather monitoring, food production, pollution control, natural spaces and parks and natural bodies of water. It has a close relationship with the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a>, the primary natural sciences research organisation in Vekllei. In many ways, the portfolio of research interests of the LSRE is the portfolio of duties of the Ministry of Landscape. Common responsibilities of the ministry include:</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li>Food production, security, distribution, and standards</li>
<li>Biosecurity and quarantine domestically and internationally</li>
<li>Management of agriculture and fisheries</li>
<li>Management of national parks, commonwealth land, and sovereign natural spaces</li>
<li>Meteorology, weather forecasting and natural disaster preparation</li>
<li>Landcare, land conservation, education and promotion of the natural sciences</li>
<li>Hydrography of Vekllei territorial waters and exclusive economic zones</li>
<li>Facilitating research and development of relevant sciences through constituent research organisations</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Ministry of Landscape is led by the State Secretary of Landscape, who is a member of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>. It is represented in the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a> by the First Minister of Landscape.</p>
<p>Vekllei is a megadiverse country, owing to its distant and transpolar and territories that often comprise isolated and unique ecosystems. As such, the ministry is highly devolved and has an established presence in every Vekllei republic. Where other ministries are tied closely to the populations of Vekllei people, the Ministry of Landscape has a much broader interest in the physical makeup of Vekllei territories and as such may often make up the largest Commonwealth presence in many smaller <a href="/republics/">constituent republics</a>.</p>
<p>Because it is well-funded and staffed, the ministry produces tremendous amounts of useful economic and scientific data about the unique environments of Vekllei. Through its constituent research establishment, the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a>, it is one of the foremost contributors to environmental sciences in the world.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of Light &amp; Water</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/light-and-water/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This ministry is part of Vekllei The Ministry of Light &amp; Water is responsible for water and electricity supply in Vekllei. While the ministry primarily directs production and facilitates research, it also controls the vast majority of energy and water production in Vekllei through its statutory corporations.
Although electricity now flows freely and abundantly in an age of commercial fusion power plants, many of Vekllei&rsquo;s constituent republics have little to no fresh water reserves and rely heavily on water conservation, recycling and desalination to supplement their water supply.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-light-and-water fis"></span> <strong>Ministry of Light &amp; Water</strong> is responsible for water and electricity supply in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. While the ministry primarily directs production and facilitates research, it also controls the vast majority of energy and water production in Vekllei through its statutory corporations.</p>
<p>Although electricity now flows freely and abundantly in an age of commercial fusion power plants, many of Vekllei&rsquo;s <a href="/republics/">constituent republics</a> have little to no fresh water reserves and rely heavily on water conservation, recycling and desalination to supplement their water supply. Common responsibilities of the ministry include:</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li>Maintenance and operation of utilities that provide Vekllei people with electricity and water</li>
<li>Facilitation of water and energy grid independence and security</li>
<li>Production, promotion and conservation of energy and water</li>
<li>Investment and research into emerging physical sciences</li>
<li>Advising energy and water policy to <a href="/republics/">republican</a> and <a href="/constituents/">commonwealth</a> parliaments</li>
<li>Investment and development of new electric and water sources</li>
<li>Nuclear energy research and security</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Ministry of Light &amp; Water is the third-largest ministry by persons employed, and its subordinate bureaux and corporations are responsible for a number of iconic pieces of Vekllei infrastructure, including the <a href="/posts/2019-09-15-reactor/">Expo &lsquo;74 Experimental Reactor</a> and the <a href="/posts/2020-04-21-hydro/">Ou Hydroburo Complex</a>. It is lead by the State Secretary of Light &amp; Water, who is a member of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>. It is represented in the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a> by the First Minister of Light &amp; Water.</p>
<p>The ministry is organised around electricity and water production respectively, but also has statutory bodies for emergencies, security and nuclear science research. The ministry was a pioneer in the construction the first and second commercial fusion power plants in <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a> and <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(215, 18, 45); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(215, 18, 45) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/"><span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> Kairi</a>, which were among the first in the world to provide fusion-generated electricity to households.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of the Commons</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commons/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commons/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This ministry is part of Vekllei The Vekllei Ministry of the Commons (COSMOTRAN) provides housing and administers state construction activities in Vekllei, and is also responsible for state protection of human nature and Crown Lands. Responsibilities of COSMOTRAN include:
Construction of beautiful and modern Vekllei cities in the spirit of Atlantic Municipalism. The provision and furnishing of adequate recreation spaces for neighbourhoods and municipalities. The construction and maintenance of infrastructure for commercial and industrial purposes.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Vekllei <em>Ministry of the Commons</em> (COSMOTRAN) provides housing and administers state construction activities in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and is also responsible for state protection of human nature and Crown Lands. Responsibilities of COSMOTRAN include:</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li>Construction of beautiful and modern Vekllei cities in the spirit of <a href="/vekllei/#atlantic-municipalism">Atlantic Municipalism</a>.</li>
<li>The provision and furnishing of adequate recreation spaces for neighbourhoods and municipalities.</li>
<li>The construction and maintenance of infrastructure for commercial and industrial purposes.</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ministry of the Commonwealth</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commonwealth/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/commonwealth/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This ministry is part of Vekllei The Ministry of the Commonwealth administers devolved ministerial organisations that require planning and expertise coordinated at a national level. It primarily establishes standards for industry and commerce and maintains federal organisations that, for one reason or another, are not subordinated to commonwealth parliaments. In this sense, the ministry provides national stewardship to otherwise devolved and decentralised ministerial organisations and commissions. Responsibilities include:
Advising, training and auditing local accreditation and qualifications in line with Commonwealth standards and directives.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This <em><a href="/ministries/">ministry</a></em> is part of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-commonwealth fis"></span> <strong>Ministry of the Commonwealth</strong> administers devolved <a href="/ministries/">ministerial</a> organisations that require planning and expertise coordinated at a national level. It primarily establishes standards for industry and commerce and maintains federal organisations that, for one reason or another, are not subordinated to commonwealth <a href="/parliaments/">parliaments</a>. In this sense, the ministry provides national stewardship to otherwise devolved and decentralised ministerial organisations and commissions. Responsibilities include:</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><ul>
<li>Advising, training and auditing local accreditation and qualifications in line with Commonwealth standards and directives.</li>
<li>Ensuring that the Vekllei interior state meets standards determined by the Commonwealth parliaments and international commitments.</li>
<li>Developing and enforcing standards in technical, industrial and brand features of the Interior Government and its responsible state assets and bureau partners.</li>
<li>Training and maintaining the workforce for the Interior civil service and Interior state assets in line with Commonwealth standards and directives.</li>
</ul>
</span>
</blockquote>

<p>COSMOCOM&rsquo;s commitments to the transnational Commonwealth Parliaments go both ways &ndash; the ministry ensures domestic compliance and also advises Commonwealth policy and standards, since the Vekllei Interior Government is the largest and most industrious member-state of the Commonwealth.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
