<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>archive on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/categories/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in archive on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carry me! &gt;:(</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora and Cobian. They have not been friends for very long but they like each other a lot. Tzipora weighs nearly 10kg less than her friend, so she gets piggy backs more often.
By me! @melon.kony or r/vekllei on reddit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd Draft</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  I first saw this film at a low point in my life, and watching Shizuku discover her ability was one of the most touching things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan-art guy, but I still find myself thinking about them years later and I wanted to paint them happy after the end of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei’s Elite Military Units — the Garden Corps and their bloody war against weeds</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post
 On Tuesday, two casualties were reported among Vekllei’s Folifedestarmie 24th and 25th Garden Companies in the ongoing war to make the capital’s parks the finest in the world. Michael Helen-Louisviuan cut his leg on an exposed nail during the deinstallation of old fence posts, and Ana Po cut her thumb on a rose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shōwa memories</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  new r/worldbuilding post soon, just filling in my garbage upload schedule with generic anime and shōwa nostalgia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer sex-ed</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Porno is available over-the-counter at most book stores. Some industry associations attempt to limit availability to minors but generally it&amp;rsquo;s at the discretion of the shopkeeper. Often, shame and embarassment are more powerful tools than legislation in Vekllei.
Generally it&amp;rsquo;s pretty traditional stuff supported by columns and fiction, although it varies between pornographers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of &#34;Human Decay&#34;</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Talking about utopia in landscape is easy — Vekllei is a glittering midcentury paradise that fosters human life as a wonderful dream.
Talking about utopia in character is much harder. How can you find utopia in flawed and sometimes unattractive human beings? By what metric is the vague, intuitive values of a utopia measured against a living person?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Summers in the Arctic (and Newda architecture)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post here.
The Café Resmoiones approaches its hundredth birthday as the girls outside await their fifteenth. The building was once a kindergarten, so they’d been told, but through decades of Vekllei’s irreverent planning it had become a café. It was not a very good café, the food was shit, but the building was nice and it was at the bottom of Lola’s steep residential hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Previous post here.
 Six bodies hung from the Rodney Creek Railroad Bridge, without names. The leftmost corpse, which was a boy, had a sign slung around his neck with tomorrow’s 8am train on it. Besides the swaying boy was his father, and next to him was his mother, and so it went down the railroad bridge, counting off his little sisters and grandmama and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Much love to all of you</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching a steam locomotive to school</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Most of the kids pictured here are the cubs of lumberfolk who make a living out of felling hard pines in the mountains in the North of Vekllei. About half have dark hair and rounder faces, as descendants of both inuits and Scandinavians, and others are of mixed ancestry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora Desmoines, the Eternal Teen-ager and Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora. She goes by two names &amp;ndash; Tzipora, her birth name, and Zelda, a name she mistakenly thought sounded less Jewish. She lives in Lola in the Vekllei city-state.
As an immigrant, she struggles with school but holds her own on in track and field, an inversion of her otherwise quiet and bookish nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The participatory economy of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Nestled between the regional tram offices and the pre-war Ferouistet Department Store, the Lola district is not known for much but her department store and good schools. It sits on the slope of the wide Vekllei capital basin, where the Atlantic can be seen from the street. It was Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s first home in Vekllei, and it was where she lived with her father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dad&#39;s Birthday</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Littlest Goddess in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The Palace Gods live in decadence in an isolated and incestuous land above the mortal planes called the Palace. They do not eat and will live forever, provided they stay within the gardens of the Palace and consummate their industrial godhood occasionally with domen, an opium that they believe purifies blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young and Educated</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  lmao wish I had nice clothes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mineral Lake starts absorbing Grief in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Rena’s little boy was found in the closest town with his guts turned out and his throat cut. They didn’t tell it to Rena like that, but that’s what happened to him. His village and people, the Lehmanen, are descendants of Palace Gods forced out of the heavens some millennia ago over their refusal to smoke Domen, a sort of opium of the Gods and essential practice in the Palace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Celebration of all Women across the World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Vekllei on the first of each May, the women’s councils and industrial unions wipe clean their banners and flags and join great parades that regale the main streets of the city with song and colour. They carry flags and banners in celebration of womanhood and remembrance of the dead — for those Potter’s Fields and unmarked graves that intern nameless women across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Palace Gods attempt to retrieve their runaway child</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She could feel the wind rising. The horizon beyond was warped, caught in the distortion of a forested planetoid before them. The morning sun cast a honeyed warmth on her wings of black sugar, which sang like wind chimes as she soared high above the gem deserts below. Hyssop, her new and only friend, followed her ungracefully under the spell of his flystone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sugarhouse Mountain Fortress</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  A hundred years ago, the fortress existed as a spectre of the neighbouring villages; a beast of suffering and woe with fingers deep into the mountains around Montre. In the waning days of the military junta, the beast’s creators, the Sugarhouse Fort served as a strategic command centre for Vekllei’s nuclear arsenal and a blacksite to disappear the most prolific and dangerous agitators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Generation</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  We best know Vekllei as a dense society of utopia and great infrastructure today, but there was blood in that crucible. It is difficult to imagine that only fifty years ago these streets were unpaved and impassible with the rubble of old society. Shadows on concrete marked the souls lost in the arrogance of the monarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Raid</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-25-air-raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-25-air-raid/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She loved helping out. It was important to her, as an ageless girl of ultimately transient relationships, to be able to establish for herself a family wherever she lived. So within a few years of her arrival in Vekllei, she put time in as a warden for her apartment block and undertook the medical training that went with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Long Moment</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-21-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-21-moment/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The whole world gives way to a moment of silence. The other seasons are filled with noise and marrow, jerking and twisting with the pace of the clock. But a moment lasts forever — and wintertime is one long moment.
Although the uniforms got heavier and the commutes longer, Zelda would always like the wintertime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gem girl shows off her enormous strength in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-16-gem/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The subcontinent of Zen on the Pachinki pangea is so weathered by enormous gem deserts that there is scarcely enough space to grow wheat for bread. In places where the soil is too thin for heavy wheats, sparrowgrass is grown. This grass has large heads that can be eaten raw and taste citrusy and acidic as they only grow in toxic soils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Old for Sleepovers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-06-sleepover/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Even for those ageless kids, there’s a time when the charade of childhood comes to a head and begs a certain uncomfortable question: at what point does the whole thing — of immaturity, of carelessness, of sleepovers — start looking like two old women posturing around youth, indulging in a sick genetic perversion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A story of community policing and sweet militia</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-03-militia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-03-militia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  As part of sundress municipalism, Vekllei’s villages and townships are mostly self-sufficient and self-regulating. Although a walk in the capital will take you past colossal apartment blocks and cinemas, libraries and schools of great magnificence, you are really looking at a hundred different communities going about personal business at their leisure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look...!</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-02-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-02-look/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Look at it!
The bastard ate the lettuce! There&amp;rsquo;s a hole in the wire!
He&amp;rsquo;s cute but he&amp;rsquo;s a bastard!
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing a train for over two weeks now and I needed to draw something alive before I shinkansenned myself. This only took an hour or two but I&amp;rsquo;m not drawing enough and it feels like I&amp;rsquo;m running out of time to get good at drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Childhood and Modernity</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-31-fight/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   Because the other girls would not stop calling her a lesbian, and because they had realised she was scared of loud noises and made use of that fact, Tzipora struck this bitch and her friend out beyond the football pitches after school. Tzipora was a good fighter — on her side is viciousness and a conviction to fight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas everyone (plus a little Christmas story)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-23-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  She had always been a very serious girl, from the first time he’d met her. It was more than a reflection of character; it was how she talked, how she carried herself. Her clothes were plain, her nervous tics were not that funny, and she was afflicted with all sorts of fears and anxieties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Suburban Constabulary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-19-constabulary/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The constabulary is old-fashioned and it can’t last forever. It predates Petticoat-era Vekllei, the previous regime lost to atomic ash, and even the monarchy itself — it was the first community militia of the country and a great deal of romanticism that had been lost in the death of the monarchy has been invested in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Valley of the Dead</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-17-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-17-valley/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  As Zelda got older and her sense of urgency decayed, the bone between life and death seemed to grow less important as time went on. Could you blame her? She was eighty years old at this point and still as fresh as fourteen — suspended somewhere in the misery of her old age and enthusiasm of her youth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cosmojet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-14-cosmojet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-14-cosmojet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The Ramoin-Dupont H700A “Cosmojet” series are the primary carrier-based fighters of Vekllei. They’re a real bitch to fly. Beloved as they are iconic, variations of the Cosmojet (H600A, B, H500A, etc.) make up the bulk of Vekllei’s total fighter outfit. Unconventional inverted gull wings and embedded turbofan engines make for a striking and uniquely Vekllei aircraft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metro Days</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-11-metro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-11-metro/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flower Tundra</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-10-flower-tundra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-10-flower-tundra/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   The two girls caught a train from school to the terminus, and then a rural line as far as it would take them out of the city. They had walked the granite shoulder of a mountain range for most of the afternoon, carrying only a few mouthfuls of provisions between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Trains</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-05-rural-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-05-rural-trains/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  I caught a train out of Tokyo as far as it would go, and I ended up on a little platform in the mountains. Nice place.
Vekllei has a lot of mountains and a lot of trains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koka parks &amp; municipal recreation</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-04-koka-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-12-04-koka-parks/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Between the atomic fire that ruined the city, and the death of the king, there was a time when the city of Vekllei once resembled its lifeless lava fields to the North. In the communities that gathered themselves in the shadow of holocaust, common agriculture like fruits and berries returned to the city in what they call koka parkland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The guilt dies with her</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-16-guilt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-16-guilt/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Some years ago, she was in the desert. At the time she had just fallen out with her lover, and their friends had sided with him. The reasons why they had sided with him seemed to matter less and less as time wore on — they might have always liked him better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Summer Everyone</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-05-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-05-summer/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Down Under it&amp;rsquo;s coming around summer, and things are heating up. It&amp;rsquo;s not my fault Yanks broke the northern hemisphere and made the weather go wrong.
Vekllei gets warm in the summer, reaching heights of 30C occasionally. For a variety of reasons. A city of gardens and flowerbeds (the most flowers per capita in the world, actually), apartment dwellers take turns watering their local gardens and clearing weeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking about Girl Scouts and Child Soldiers</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-04-scout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-11-04-scout/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  About half of Vekllei kids go through the &amp;lsquo;Blossom&amp;rsquo; network of youth orgs at some point in their lives. Yeah, youth groups are popular nowadays. The Boy Scouts and Girl Guides of the United States are as mandatory as schooling in some states, and various Red Pioneers around the world test orthodoxy in Soviet and Red Chinese children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Stewards of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-30-steward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-30-steward/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Upen is the animistic religion of Vekllei. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have priests, but it has ceremony, and it shapes every part of the country today. From apartment cooperatives to the types of cotton used in clothing, Upen has extraordinary reach for an ostensibly agnostic and secular country.
It works out that way because Upen is not an organised religion, and resembles more closely a collective spiritualism with supernatural beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s look at military fashion, because why not?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-22-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-22-fashion/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Unlike the United States and Western Europe, the ‘teen-ager’ has not been discovered in Vekllei. To be pedantic, they do technically exist — their people do indeed enter a transitory stage between childhood and adulthood, as far as anyone can tell — but they do not exist as a separate cultural identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collapse of the South</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-05-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-10-05-south/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In October of 2074, the Ford Motor Company was embroiled in political catastrophe after Vermont senator Henry Walsh accused unionism in its East-Coast plants of traitorism by allowing foreign spies to acquire jobs in the Company. Whether the spies were Soviet or Chinese changed several times in Walsh’s accusations, but the claims themselves were not entirely unfounded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>real sadboi posting hours</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-29-sadboi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-29-sadboi/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Coming up on 2am here in East Australia. Had a rough day at work. Feeling pretty isolated and my other job starts in a few hours. I don’t know if it’s intrusive thoughts from OCD or just something everyone has, but four or five times a day I’ll have some sort of regret pop right into my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School uniforms for girls</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-25-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-25-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  From preschool to university and beyond, all students wear a variant of the same uniform. The kindergartners may not wear a full gi and camisole pinafore, but the basic ensemble is still there. This is the girl’s one, and it’s much more elaborate than the boy’s uniform.
Year-round, all students wear a school armband with their year and class embroidered on it and a badge of education, which is pinned to the top button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on the end of the world</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-19-endgame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-19-endgame/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  A single hiss, the heavy door rolls back, and it derails into sandbags. A gas piston grinds, an engine ignites, and a roar sends flames pouring fifty feet high out of the silo as a sleek missile emerges and climbs towards hunting altitude.
This missile will strike Lanzhou, China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KID COMIX, an underground comic mag in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-11-comix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-11-comix/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  There are some comics that Vekllei syndicates just won’t publish. KID Magazine, or KID Comix ran for nearly a century. It was picked up and dropped by dozens of anonymous artists, writers and editors, all operating under nonsense pseudonyms — Red, Squick, Failson and Daddy Fun were some of the longest-serving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KID COMIX, an underground comic mag in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-07-masculinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-07-masculinity/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Just a few notes on what it means to be a man in Vekllei.
Vekllei is a country at odds with itself. On one hand, it is universal in its politics and fundamentally internationalist; on the other it is a deeply traditional country that values bloodlines and heritage. It is a secular democracy that regularly alludes to monarchy in its rituals and symbolism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shot like a dog in a Supermarket &amp; the Vekllei Grocery Economy</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-06-shot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-09-06-shot/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   A fluorescent light burst on Thursday. She was stacking cans for a display. The girl was working alone that evening and leaving her mark everywhere — happy apple drawings, new posters, displays — she liked the job.
The light burst like a gunshot and she leapt to her feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>summer nerds reading comix</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-29-nerds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-29-nerds/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>big mood right now</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-28-mood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-28-mood/</guid>
      <description> Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Constabulary</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-23-constabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-23-constabulary/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Policing is always difficult in utopian planning. On one hand, utopia is inherently opposed to the idea of policing and the can of worms it brings — on the other, people need to feel safe and protected. That’s not something I’ll be talking about today.
The Vekllei Constabulary are the second largest policing body in the country, after conventional police.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All-weather combat for the Atomic Age</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-20-troops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-20-troops/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The single most important function of today’s global powers is not in the numbers of men at a state&amp;rsquo;s command, or the prosperity of their domestic markets, but the ability to project power across the world entire.
We have seen this manifest in many ways; ICBMs are just one example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is Blood Worship</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-19-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-19-blood/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Blood is everything to these women. It defines them through every stage of life — bloody emerging from the womb, bloody again in the delicate transition from child to womanhood, and bloody on the table, awaiting cremation in wait of the afterlife.
Even in her name — Zelda lo Ula Desmoines — the premise of blood is there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old, dead demons still wander the countryside</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-16-demons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-16-demons/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   She met herself out by the shrine, many summers ago. At first she didn’t know what it was — she thought it might be a spirit, or — and she caught herself in the thought, because she was only half a child — a little part of her wondered if it was a manifestation of God, or Christ, come to help solve her problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Country of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-15-vekllei/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-15-vekllei/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  There is no real distinction between the city of Vekllei and the state of Vekllei, at least internally. To them, the country and the city are the same, and the isolated population centres of Montre and Adouisneh are simply distant neighbourhoods. This is reflected in all manners of life — they are ethnically and culturally homogenous, patriotic, and largely uncompetitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora&#39;s Portrait</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-08-portrait/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-08-portrait/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Practising colours. It&amp;rsquo;s always been my weakness. While you&amp;rsquo;re here, if you have any questions about Tzipora or want to chat, let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-01-princess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-08-01-princess/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  They never actually believed that she was any kind of princess. They never even joked about it. The original LIFE magazine article said that she looked as though she were ‘a princess of the Earth’ when interviewer Alfie Ricci met her in the Vekllei highlands, and so she carried that name as a burden for the next few hundred years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valleys of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-28-valleys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-28-valleys/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Two years ago, a fission military jet plunged into the mountain behind the village of Montre-Lola, emerging moments later as a plume of fire and smoke in the shadow of the mountain peak. Villagers made their way up the slopes to help survivors, dressed in radiation suits from the town shelter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot summer rain on a beach of black sand -- Iceland in 2127</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-20-black-sand/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-20-black-sand/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Just as Iceland&amp;rsquo;s initial history was reshaped into the image of Vekllei some centuries ago, so too has the real-world climate and weather been altered. Cool Icelandic summers have been usurped by volatile days that can be as low as 5C (40F) or as hot as 30C (85F+). Technically speaking, the unstable Atlantic pressure oscillation, of which Vekllei anchors as the Vekllei low pole, can pull in bitter cold from the Greenland currents, or warmth from the Azores tempestuously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>winter love &#43; puffin / feat. Tzipora &amp; Akiko</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-19-puffin-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-19-puffin-love/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  &amp;ldquo;The puffin flies here so early (over the years). The further inland we go, the farther they chase us.&amp;rdquo;
That&amp;rsquo;s the sentiment of the phrase, but in Vekllei &amp;lsquo;The puffin flies here&amp;rsquo; is supplemented with the opening of a saying, &amp;lsquo;all birds flee the sea in Winter,&amp;rsquo; and so there is a reference here that is otherwise lost in translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navy in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-15-salvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-15-salvo/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  There are not many warships in the world today that are distinctive as the serpentine-funnelled, semi-tumblehome hull of the Sundress-class supercruisers. For a country that prides itself on ‘petticoat society’, it is only suitable that Vekllei continues to pioneer the ‘dazzle’ warpaint in her navy.
 The most recent stock of Navy ships are all named after women’s clothes, to emphasise Vekllei’s spiritual understanding of gender in industrial society and also as a sarcastic nominer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What will become of the Gregori Children?</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-10-gregori/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-07-10-gregori/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Did you know — many Gregori children do not form calluses on their skin, because of the intensity of their epidermic regeneration process!
Hello all,
The question on the mind of folks around the world is that of Gregori Children. What are they? What does it mean, to be a “Gregori Baby”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-29-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-29-life/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Vekllei is the final stop in the epoch of rest. Departing your jetliner or aeroship and setting foot in the city is a spiritual experience — the weight of the world leaves your shoulders, and, at last, you are at peace. Imagine what that would be like — to be self-actualised!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood Names</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-14-blood-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-06-14-blood-name/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Each person in Vekllei has three names — a given name (Tzipora), a surname (Desmoines), and an alternative given name as part of rapotenne (potenne is ‘handtalk’, upotenne is ‘spirit-talk’, and so it follows that rapotenne is the language system of names). This alternative name is a ‘key’ to the full blood name of an individual, which are given in secret by the mother traditionally, but can be gifted by any mother-figure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dress code for talking to spirits</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-24-spirits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-24-spirits/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Vekllei animism, which branches into a vast and complex set of beliefs and traditions that vary from village to village, there is no formal religious structure. Temples and shrines pay respect to sprites, which are universally understood as bi-planar creatures. There is no formal religious structure, and so animistic tradition has no priests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-18-police-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-18-police-car/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Hopefully you won’t have to worry about the police while you’re in Vekllei, but you’ll likely notice them. Police are everywhere — as an alternative to military (duoroten) service, conscripts can elect to enter domestic security (inroten). Most officers are young, bored, and live in the community they police.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Bow (and Fashion in Vekllei)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-01-bowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-05-01-bowing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Vekllei has a pan-pacific flavour of greeting, usually a bow followed by a handshake. If you’re going to fit in, you’re going to have to learn how to do it right. Let’s get started.
First, Vekllei is extremely physical in its language. Not expressive, like how you might picture an Italian or American.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Clothing (and Womanhood in Vekllei)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-16-winter-clothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-16-winter-clothing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Welcome to Vekllei. It is a strange country with a complex culture that is quite distinct (and sometimes outrageous) to Western countries. This will be a long post. I’ve tried to keep it clear.
 Women in Vekllei usually wear skirts in winter. There are cultural and historical reasons for this, explained below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rail-Launched Nuclear Missiles</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-09-rail-missiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-09-rail-missiles/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is a concept of a Vekllei Rocketry Corp rail ICBM launcher. It has distinctive-looking carriages, and so it serves no real purpose in being a ‘hidden’ ICBM launcher. Instead, this train is for testing rail-mounted ICBMs, which are then employed in plain and unmarked railcars. Today it idles by the lakeside town of Dupot-Monan, as its senior control staff await a hot lunch driven in from the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washing the Feet of the Enemy</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-06-penance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-04-06-penance/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  He had sent her a wire some weeks before asking to meet her. She did not remember him. By now he was an old man, and she, a Gregori baby of sixty four years, had not aged a day. He was close to dying and wanted to relieve his soul of the war crimes he’d committed as a member of the Vanguard in the Second American Civil War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sketch of a Blood Spirit</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-03-03-demon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-03-03-demon/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Blood spirits are unaware people have physical forms. Why should they? No person has entered the realm of the spirits in a millenia.
When the Princess of the Earth arrived, after the nuclear exchange between the United States and China, one of the first encounters she had with a spirit in their homeworld was a blood spirit tearing her apart while looking for food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Concept of Childhood</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-02-23-childhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-02-23-childhood/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This post is part discussion, part lore.
Kojin Karatani, on the subject of childhood, writes;
 Of course, children have existed since ancient times, yet &amp;lsquo;the child&amp;rsquo; as we conceive of it and objectify it did not exist prior to a particular period [&amp;hellip;].
From this viewpoint, it becomes clear that the grouping of children by age in the compulsory educational system of modern Japan signified the uprooting of children, as abstract and homogenous entities, from productive relations, social classes, and communities that had previously been their concrete contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bridging of Worlds Ritual</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-25-ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-25-ritual/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora is the oldest person alive, now aged 1,056 years. With the body, temperament, and vitality of an 11-year-old, and the lived experience of a dozen generations, she is a victim Gregori syndrome. She has seen man rise from Earth into space, and although she still calls her birth-country of Vekllei on Earth home, she frequently tours the cosmos as part of complex interplanetary diplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anarchy in Cherry, Nevada</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-15-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2018-01-15-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The young Republican has waited in a queue to have her photo taken in front of the remains of Cherry, Nevada. Her hair is still short after the fascists shaved her head, and branded her with St David’s star because she had a Jewish name. She would later tell the Republican Militia that she wasn’t, in fact, a Jew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl Scouts Learn to Shoot in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-12-12-blossoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-12-12-blossoms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora Desmoines is part of Troop 45 of the Vekllei Blossoms. Every adult, as part of mandatory service in the country of Vekllei, owns and operates a firearm, most commonly a handgun. Because of this hazard, the children of Vekllei learn gun safety at an early age, either through school or the Blossoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiation Poisoning in Domestic Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-12-05-radiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-12-05-radiation/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  He started collecting radioactive material from the clocks and electronic appliances in his house earlier in the week. The material, which included radium and americium, was placed in a compartment in the living room wall of his apartment. This exposed his wife, nine-year-old son and infant daughter to dangerous levels of radioactivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seaside in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-11-28-seaside/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-11-28-seaside/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  About this time of year, in the place between high summer and autumn, the weather is good in Vekllei. Vekllei is too cold for crickets, but insects are out and the air hums with life — birds, helijets, and the soft noise an ocean breeze makes as it races toward the harbour, pulling on leaves and skirt hems along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beat Cops in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-11-07-cop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-11-07-cop/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   It was just like any other evening in Monouiz; a no-good view of one part concrete, one part fescue, and a whole lotta quiet. He knew the broad from his days hunting smuggler types in jazz bars and street cars, a gig not worth gigging now that prohibition was over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-24-princess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-24-princess/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Barbaloh was once the spirit of a rainforest, but now lives only in the world of the spirits as a merchant, selling potions, spells and other supernatural nonsense. Tzipora, a brave human girl and fierce humanist, has gained passage to the spirit world through the bones of a derden, or “angel”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Spies and a Vekllei Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-19-spies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-19-spies/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In Nevada about this time of year, the temperature stays steady at 45 degrees (~115 in yank). The asphalt sticks to shoes. On the far right is Lenny the Jew. The moniker is his own; he’s a Jew from New York who ended up working for the Vekllei Rocketry Corps, the Vekllei espionage agency responsible for operations in the southern United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entering the Spirit World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-14-spirit-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-14-spirit-world/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Suddenly the blood drained from her lungs and she breathed in, only to double over, hacking blood into the grass between her shoes. She wiped her bloody mouth on the back of her arm and mumbled something like ‘sorry’ before coughing again. She slipped off her shoes and made her way to the clearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Dress of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-13-national-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-13-national-dress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Vekllei people are usually buried in their national dress. It marks the important stages in their way of life; of graduation, of marriage, of ceremony. The carousel of festivals and parades and holidays that these Atlantic people enjoy are all spent in uniform, their national costume, that forms the public face of their country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching the End of the World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-12-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-12-missile/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  The sight of the missiles nearly made her sick. Everything around her took on new context. It was such a peaceful afternoon, and the sirens hadn’t gone off, and here she was, watching the trails the missiles painted in the cloudless sky. And now she was blessed with a newfound psychic ability that told her that everything in this spot would be vapour in a half hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Face of Human Extinction</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-09-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-09-face/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  All servants of heaven — called angels by most people but they belong to a much older name — are viciously jealous of human beings. In creation, the Earth was promised to them, but the creator God gave the Earth to the human race. In a fit of rage, the angels — or Derden, as they were called before the current chapter of humanity — buried bioengineered monsters called Lehmenan far below the surface of the Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Vekllei General Store</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-06-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-06-store/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  In the narrow streets of the Lola district in Vekllei, artisans and artists hurry about, peddling art and fine goods and attracting the rest of the city to its stores. In Vekllei, there is no currency, so shopping is almost always a pragmatic affair.
Not in Lola. If you’re in Lola, you’re there to see the good stuff, produced and sold in little shops like this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pleading with Angels to Spare Humanity</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-02-angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-10-02-angels/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   She saw its bones and the sight of them — that they were real and not a dream — caught in her throat. She raised her hand to cough, and suddenly her lungs heaved and blood began to pour from the spaces between her fingers. Her eyes grew wide and she cupped her hand, and she retched again and her blood sprayed out like a hose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Warfare in 2063</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-27-chemical-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-27-chemical-war/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.   “We came to a town and found it scorched with mustard and the fragments of phosgene shells, and the wind whistled through the doorways that were left open. I remember being surprised by how many of them were in basements — probably because they thought the gas would blow away in the wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora, the Undying Miracle Child</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-24-undying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-24-undying/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora is a Gregori baby, a child who doesn’t age and cannot contract cell-mutating diseases. She is the adopted daughter of Michael Desmoines, an espionage quartermaster for a foreign power in the United States.
She is clever, sensitive, and deeply humanist. Despite her shyness and her loneliness, she is remembered by the few whose lives she touched as an affectionate and exceptionally gifted girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora Makes Friends with a Desert Spirit</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-21-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-21-spirit/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Every natural place has a spirit that minds it. Tzipora had never met a desert spirit before, and she went looking for one in Cherry, Nevada. With air force jets glinting in the sky overhead, and the temperature scorching the mesas that surround the military town, she found one inside a burrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fashion in the Year 2063</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-19-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-19-fashion/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Vekllei kids look to America as a bastion of good taste; a country of fast cars and diners and sock-hops and high-school romance. Like the Koreans look to Japanese taste, and the British look to the stuff coming out of design houses in France, Vekllei is infatuated with how Americans dress in the year 2063.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl’s Life Saved by Veteran Hero in Day of Terror</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-10-terror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-10-terror/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Louenne Dehmones enlisted for two years but stayed for ten. He served abroad in the war department, where he performed admirably but never rose above the rank of Junior Sergeant because of a good-natured appetite for mischief. He transferred to the military police to be close to his wife and infant daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora, one of the children to stop ageing</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-04-ageing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-09-04-ageing/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This is Tzipora. She is eleven years old, scruffy, and a Gregori baby. At the turn of the 21st century, Gregori Hordiyenko, a Ukrainian boy aged nine and a half, stopped aging entirely. By 2063, which is the year Tzipora turned eleven, there are about two hundred Gregori babies in the world, mostly living in secret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Uniforms of Any Good Vekllei Girl</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-08-17-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-08-17-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  These are the five basic outfits a kid in the city of Vekllei rotates between in their life. This is Tzipora. She’s sharp and a little scruffy. She’s eleven years old.
The first is her school uniform, complete with embroidered armband featuring the national crest. The skirt has a longer pleated section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-bullying poster in the year 2063. Not very effective. From the city of Vekllei.</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-08-10-bullying/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-08-10-bullying/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  This poster circulated middle schools in 2063 as part of a wider initiative at curbing violence against women at an early age. The two Vekllei characters on the left read literally as &amp;ldquo;there is no excuse to hit a female,&amp;rdquo; but it emphasises the ‘hit’ part of it to make the idea particularly reprehensible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>She stands in the harbour in national dress. Jets fly overhead and a parade passes to mourn the victims of the atomic bombings.</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-07-19-national-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-07-19-national-dress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora, a recent immigrant girl of eleven years, wears the feminine national dress of Vekllei. It is a delicate, traditional and deeply spiritual costume, and is tied to Vekllei’s foundations and aspirations as a state. It has political symbolism, but it also ties the girl to the land she stands on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tzipora has her photo taken at Youth Meet 2063. Nuclear war in Germany breaks out eight days later.</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-07-01-youth-meet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2017-07-01-youth-meet/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here  🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Tzipora is smiling in the photo because she has won the competition for multilingual spelling. She is a recent citizen of Vekllei, a postcollectivist country in what we know as Iceland. She beat American boy scouts, Australian girl guides, Chinese and Soviet Pioneers and other youth organisations to win top prize.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
