<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>archive on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/categories/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in archive on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carry me! &gt;:(</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-08-05-carry/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.This is Tzipora and Cobian. They have not been friends for very long but they like each other a lot. Tzipora weighs nearly 10kg less than her friend, so she gets piggy backs more often.
By me! @melon.kony or r/vekllei on reddit!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd Draft</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-31-2nd-draft/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.I first saw this film at a low point in my life, and watching Shizuku discover her ability was one of the most touching things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan-art guy, but I still find myself thinking about them years later and I wanted to paint them happy after the end of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei’s Elite Military Units — the Garden Corps and their bloody war against weeds</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-25-garden/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.Previous post
 On Tuesday, two casualties were reported among Vekllei’s Folifedestarmie 24th and 25th Garden Companies in the ongoing war to make the capital’s parks the finest in the world. Michael Helen-Louisviuan cut his leg on an exposed nail during the deinstallation of old fence posts, and Ana Po cut her thumb on a rose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shōwa memories</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-21-showa/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.new r/worldbuilding post soon, just filling in my garbage upload schedule with generic anime and shōwa nostalgia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer sex-ed</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-07-08-sex-ed/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.Porno is available over-the-counter at most book stores. Some industry associations attempt to limit availability to minors but generally it&amp;rsquo;s at the discretion of the shopkeeper. Often, shame and embarassment are more powerful tools than legislation in Vekllei.
Generally it&amp;rsquo;s pretty traditional stuff supported by columns and fiction, although it varies between pornographers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of &#34;Human Decay&#34;</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-30-human-decay/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.Talking about utopia in landscape is easy — Vekllei is a glittering midcentury paradise that fosters human life as a wonderful dream.
Talking about utopia in character is much harder. How can you find utopia in flawed and sometimes unattractive human beings? By what metric is the vague, intuitive values of a utopia measured against a living person?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Summers in the Arctic (and Newda architecture)</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-18-summers/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.Previous post here.
The Café Resmoiones approaches its hundredth birthday as the girls outside await their fifteenth. The building was once a kindergarten, so they’d been told, but through decades of Vekllei’s irreverent planning it had become a café. It was not a very good café, the food was shit, but the building was nice and it was at the bottom of Lola’s steep residential hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Grotesque</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-13-erotic-grotesque/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.Previous post here.
 Six bodies hung from the Rodney Creek Railroad Bridge, without names. The leftmost corpse, which was a boy, had a sign slung around his neck with tomorrow’s 8am train on it. Besides the swaying boy was his father, and next to him was his mother, and so it went down the railroad bridge, counting off his little sisters and grandmama and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Much love to all of you</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-06-02-hello/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching a steam locomotive to school</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-30-cabforward/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon. Most of the kids pictured here are the cubs of lumberfolk who make a living out of felling hard pines in the mountains in the North of Vekllei. About half have dark hair and rounder faces, as descendants of both inuits and Scandinavians, and others are of mixed ancestry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Tzipora Desmoines, the Eternal Teen-ager and Princess of the Earth</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-27-character/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.This is Tzipora. She goes by two names &amp;ndash; Tzipora, her birth name, and Zelda, a name she mistakenly thought sounded less Jewish. She lives in Lola in the Vekllei city-state.
As an immigrant, she struggles with school but holds her own on in track and field, an inversion of her otherwise quiet and bookish nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The participatory economy of Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.Nestled between the regional tram offices and the pre-war Ferouistet Department Store, the Lola district is not known for much but her department store and good schools. It sits on the slope of the wide Vekllei capital basin, where the Atlantic can be seen from the street. It was Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s first home in Vekllei, and it was where she lived with her father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dad&#39;s Birthday</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-04-birthday/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Littlest Goddess in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-06-palace/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.The Palace Gods live in decadence in an isolated and incestuous land above the mortal planes called the Palace. They do not eat and will live forever, provided they stay within the gardens of the Palace and consummate their industrial godhood occasionally with domen, an opium that they believe purifies blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young and Educated</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-04-02-educated/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.lmao wish I had nice clothes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mineral Lake starts absorbing Grief in Pachinki</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-31-swamp/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.Rena’s little boy was found in the closest town with his guts turned out and his throat cut. They didn’t tell it to Rena like that, but that’s what happened to him. His village and people, the Lehmanen, are descendants of Palace Gods forced out of the heavens some millennia ago over their refusal to smoke Domen, a sort of opium of the Gods and essential practice in the Palace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Celebration of all Women across the World</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-25-parade/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.In Vekllei on the first of each May, the women’s councils and industrial unions wipe clean their banners and flags and join great parades that regale the main streets of the city with song and colour. They carry flags and banners in celebration of womanhood and remembrance of the dead — for those Potter’s Fields and unmarked graves that intern nameless women across the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Palace Gods attempt to retrieve their runaway child</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-11-gods/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.She could feel the wind rising. The horizon beyond was warped, caught in the distortion of a forested planetoid before them. The morning sun cast a honeyed warmth on her wings of black sugar, which sang like wind chimes as she soared high above the gem deserts below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sugarhouse Mountain Fortress</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-03-10-fortress/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.A hundred years ago, the fortress existed as a spectre of the neighbouring villages; a beast of suffering and woe with fingers deep into the mountains around Montre. In the waning days of the military junta, the beast’s creators, the Sugarhouse Fort served as a strategic command centre for Vekllei’s nuclear arsenal and a blacksite to disappear the most prolific and dangerous agitators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Generation</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-02-26-generation/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌸 Archived Post
This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.We best know Vekllei as a dense society of utopia and great infrastructure today, but there was blood in that crucible. It is difficult to imagine that only fifty years ago these streets were unpaved and impassible with the rubble of old society. Shadows on concrete marked the souls lost in the arrogance of the monarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
