<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Essays on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/news/essays/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Essays on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/news/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Ghibli</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/news/essays/ghibli/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/news/essays/ghibli/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Note from the Editor This thesis was completed in partial fulfillment of Bachelor of Media (Honours). It remains a good testament to my love of Ghibli. It was originally submitted in October 2020 and published in December 2020.   Abstract #  This thesis looks to argue for the value of spatiality in several films of the Studio Ghibli franchise in Japan. Literary space, much like the cartography of the real world, helps map meaning and locate the human body in the contemporary, postmodern displacement of old constructions.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>On Moneylessness</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/news/essays/moneylessness/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/news/essays/moneylessness/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Note from the Editor This essay was written in December 2021. Click here to see it as a post.  The Vekllei Person #  What good is more writing about theories and the methodology of country-constructs? More importantly — how is it authentically convincing to the person who has lived their entire lives immersed in their own ways of living? Vekllei does not use money — the purpose of these notes are to demonstrate how such a thing works, immersing Vekllei’s participatory economy in a human lens, and articulate the motivations, biases and assumptions of the average working Vekllei person.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Utopie Concrète</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/news/essays/utopie/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/news/essays/utopie/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Note from the Editor This essay was written in June 2021. Click here to see it as a post.   A New Style of Utopia #  I write introspectively about the project sometimes, as a means by which I consider what I&amp;rsquo;m doing and where my unconscious is leading me with this project. I have the instinct of someone who is over-educated and self-obsessed; someone who went to university, fell for the farce of serious media criticism, and failed to see that all media theorists are basically freaks.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hong Kong</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/news/essays/hongkong/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/news/essays/hongkong/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Note from the Editor This article was originally published in October 2019. This article was written shortly after my return from Hong Kong, where I got caught up in the pro-democracy protests and is a broad response to Australian coverage of the ongoing events.  Hong Kong is a loud, bustling jewel of a city. It is perhaps my favourite city in the world. On sweltering days, what sounds like raindrops smack the pavement as hundreds of air-conditioning units drip liquid into the streets below.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Waugh</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/news/essays/waugh/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/news/essays/waugh/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Note from the Editor This article was originally published in October 2019. It offers an analysis of Evelyn Waugh&amp;rsquo;s Handful of Dust through an anti-utopian prism.  Waugh’s Handful of Dust as Anti-Utopia #  Waugh&amp;rsquo;s A Handful of Dust has remarkable topography. The word can be extrapolated in this case in several ways; for one, the book is occupied by worldly, secular affairs, inextricably bound to a particular cultural landscape and absence of metaphysic.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Cashless Tokyo</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/news/essays/tokyo/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/news/essays/tokyo/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Note from the Editor This article was originally published in December 2018. Yes, it’s painfully self-concerned and a little difficult to read back, but for newcomers to the project you might find some “obvious truths” about Vekllei you have not yet encountered.  I did not come to Tokyo to find a reference for the Petticoat Project, because utopia does not exist there for me. In fact, by nearly every Vekllei metric, Tokyo is positively dystopian — a consumer paradise of the crushing, isolating modernity Vekllei is supposed to escape.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>