<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>uniforms on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/uniforms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in uniforms on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/uniforms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-09-08-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.In Vekllei, uniforms are prevalent across all levels of society. They are perhaps the most obvious example of the opaque contradictions at the heart of Vekllei life, caught between wholly opposing ideas: between tradition and progress; liberty and control; and, most crucially here — between individualism and the burden of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-08-police/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #3 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.There are two regular police organs in Vekllei.
 Fedecenoayan porits (national police, or venopor) Comoisniyan denporitsa (local police, or cosmopor)  A young venopor officer stands on the left, in the full street regalia they’re renowned for. Unlike cosmopor, they often carry machine guns while on patrol and are stationed outside of government buildings, hospitals, train stations, ports, schools and any company managed directly by a bureau, which is a trade organ of national importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Uniforms in Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-16-winter-uniforms/</guid>
      <description>Archived from the original article here🌼 Featured in the Atlantic
This article appeared in Issue #1 of the Atlantic Bulletin. You can read it here.When I paint Vekllei, I usually depict the warmer months. Hems are shorter, days are longer, and the destabilisation of the world’s climate has only benefited these arctic people. At the gift end of the Vekllei low pressure system, Scandinavian misery has become Mediterranean pleasure, with warm summers and a mild Autumn and Spring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
