<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Places</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/places/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Places </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/factbook/world/places/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Comet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/places/comet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/places/comet/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about a location in Vekllei The Comet Administration Assembly is the capital complex of the Commownealth, located on the island of Meteor in the North Atlantic ocean. Originally home to only a few hundred people, Comet was established in 2036 as an administrative centre for the vast Commonwealth, which spans the Atlantic and Caribbean oceans. It was chosen for its centrality and cultural neutrality, and is accessible to Commonwealth staff and emissaries by air or sea.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places"><strong>location</strong></a> in <a href="/vekllei/"><strong>Vekllei</strong></a></div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>The Comet Administration Assembly</strong> is the capital complex of the Commownealth, located on the island of Meteor in the North Atlantic ocean. Originally home to only a few hundred people, Comet was established in 2036 as an administrative centre for the vast Commonwealth, which spans the Atlantic and Caribbean oceans. It was chosen for its centrality and cultural neutrality, and is accessible to Commonwealth staff and emissaries by air or sea.</p>
<p>The complex consists of the Superior Assembly and Chambers, as well as accomodation, recreation facilities and offices for staff.</p>
<p>The island of Meteor makes up part of the Western Azores archipelago, situated West of the Azores Commownealth Republic. Most of the island is a Crown Land outside of the administrative complex and support facilities. The island is served by Port Vekllei and Jetport Vekllei.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Cosmodrome</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/places/astroport/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/places/astroport/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about a place in Vekllei The Vekllei World Astroport is the largest spaceport of Vekllei and the primary link to the Vekllei Lunar Territories. It is a combined civilian, military and research spaceport located on Ascension that launches around eight flights a day to the moon via SSTOs.
The spaceport is serviced by both a Commonwealth Airways shuttle and Commonwealth Starlines, which provides services into space and towards the moon.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about a place in <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The Vekllei World Astroport is the largest spaceport of <a style="color: var(--color-millmint)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> and the primary link to the Vekllei Lunar Territories. It is a combined civilian, military and research spaceport located on <a style="color: rgb(48, 106, 175)" href="/ascension/"><span class="fi fi-ac"></span> Ascension</a> that launches around eight flights a day to the moon via <a href="/stories/lightbulb/">SSTOs</a>.</p>
<p>The spaceport is serviced by both a <a style="color: rgb(245, 60, 89)" href="/air/"><span class="fi fi-min-air fis"></span> Commonwealth Airways</a> shuttle and <a style="color: rgb(44, 81, 177)" href="/starlines/"><span class="fi fi-min-starlines fis"></span> Commonwealth Starlines</a>, which provides services into space and towards the moon.</p>
<p>The cosmodrome has two terminals, one for civilian and one for government use. Two flights leave for the moon per day, CF 1 and 2.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Moshel School</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/places/moshel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/factbook/world/places/moshel/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[߷ This article is about a location in Vekllei The Moshel Street State School, also the Moshel School or Lola 6th, is a Central School in the borough of Lola. It is the second-largest school in Lola, and offers schooling between Prep and Year 12. It is also Tzipora&rsquo;s school, and is where she completes her secondary schooling upon her arrival in Vekllei.
As a Central School, Moshel St occupies a large grounds that are well-equipped with facilities, including a dining hall, multipurpose gymnasium, photographic, photonic computing, and chemical laboratories, and a large school library.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src=""/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">߷ This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places"><strong>location</strong></a> in <a href="/vekllei/"><strong>Vekllei</strong></a></div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>The Moshel Street State School</strong>, also the Moshel School or Lola 6th, is a <a href="/factbook/society/state/education/#state-schools">Central School</a> in the borough of <a href="/lola/">Lola</a>. It is the second-largest school in Lola, and offers schooling between <a href="/factbook/society/state/education/#preparatory-school">Prep</a> and Year 12. It is also Tzipora&rsquo;s school, and is where she completes her secondary schooling upon her arrival in Vekllei.</p>
<p>As a Central School, Moshel St occupies a large grounds that are well-equipped with facilities, including a dining hall, multipurpose gymnasium, photographic, photonic computing, and chemical laboratories, and a large school library. Other school facilties include a multi-faith chapel and school farm. It is considered an average Central school for the Vekllei metropole, but its cricket teams and sports facilities are highly regarded.</p>
<p>Like most Vekllei schools, Moshel St has a house system consisting of Loh, Vosmiosn, Reznor, and Halifasmiosn.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
