<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Places</title>
	<link>/factbook/world/places/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Places </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/world/places/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Comet</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/comet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/comet/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei The Comet Administration Assembly is the capital complex of the Commownealth, located on the island of Meteor in the North Atlantic ocean. Originally home to only a few hundred people, Comet was established in 2036 as an administrative centre for the vast Commonwealth, which spans the Atlantic and Caribbean oceans. It was chosen for its centrality and cultural neutrality, and is accessible to Commonwealth staff and emissaries by air or sea.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places"><strong>location</strong></a> in <a href="/vekllei/"><strong>Vekllei</strong></a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>The Comet Administration Assembly</strong> is the capital complex of the Commownealth, located on the island of Meteor in the North Atlantic ocean. Originally home to only a few hundred people, Comet was established in 2036 as an administrative centre for the vast Commonwealth, which spans the Atlantic and Caribbean oceans. It was chosen for its centrality and cultural neutrality, and is accessible to Commonwealth staff and emissaries by air or sea.</p>
<p>The complex consists of the Superior Assembly and Chambers, as well as accomodation, recreation facilities and offices for staff.</p>
<p>The island of Meteor makes up part of the Western Azores archipelago, situated West of the Azores Commownealth Republic. Most of the island is a Crown Land outside of the administrative complex and support facilities. The island is served by Port Vekllei and Jetport Vekllei.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Cosmodrome</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/astroport/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/astroport/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a place in Vekllei The Vekllei World Astroport is the largest spaceport of Vekllei and the primary link to the Vekllei Lunar Territories. It is a combined civilian, military and research spaceport located on Ascension that launches around eight flights a day to the moon via SSTOs.
The spaceport is serviced by both a Commonwealth Airways shuttle and Commonwealth Starlines, which provides services into space and towards the moon.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a place in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p>The Vekllei World Astroport is the largest spaceport of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> and the primary link to the Vekllei Lunar Territories. It is a combined civilian, military and research spaceport located on <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(48, 106, 175); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(48, 106, 175) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/ascension/"><span class="fi fi-ac"></span> Ascension</a> that launches around eight flights a day to the moon via <a href="/stories/lightbulb/">SSTOs</a>.</p>
<p>The spaceport is serviced by both a <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(245, 60, 89); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(245, 60, 89) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/state/air/"><span class="fi fi-min-air fis"></span> Commonwealth Airways</a> shuttle and <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(44, 81, 177); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(44, 81, 177) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/industry/state/starlines/"><span class="fi fi-min-starlines fis"></span> Commonwealth Starlines</a>, which provides services into space and towards the moon.</p>
<p>The cosmodrome has two terminals, one for civilian and one for government use. Two flights leave for the moon per day, CF 1 and 2.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Moshel School</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/moshel/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/moshel/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei The Moshel Street State School, also the Moshel School or Lola 6th, is a Central School in the borough of Lola. It is the second-largest school in Lola, and offers schooling between Prep and Year 12. It is also Tzipora&rsquo;s school, and is where she completes her secondary schooling upon her arrival in Vekllei.
As a Central School, Moshel St occupies a large grounds that are well-equipped with facilities, including a dining hall, multipurpose gymnasium, photographic, photonic computing, and chemical laboratories, and a large school library.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/school-map.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places"><strong>location</strong></a> in <a href="/vekllei/"><strong>Vekllei</strong></a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>The Moshel Street State School</strong>, also the Moshel School or Lola 6th, is a <a href="/factbook/society/state/education/#state-schools">Central School</a> in the borough of <a href="/lola/">Lola</a>. It is the second-largest school in Lola, and offers schooling between <a href="/factbook/society/state/education/#preparatory-school">Prep</a> and Year 12. It is also Tzipora&rsquo;s school, and is where she completes her secondary schooling upon her arrival in Vekllei.</p>
<p>As a Central School, Moshel St occupies a large grounds that are well-equipped with facilities, including a dining hall, multipurpose gymnasium, photographic, photonic computing, and chemical laboratories, and a large school library. Other school facilties include a multi-faith chapel and school farm. It is considered an average Central school for the Vekllei metropole, but its cricket teams and sports facilities are highly regarded.</p>
<p>Like most Vekllei schools, Moshel St has a house system consisting of Loh, Vosmiosn, Reznor, and Halifasmiosn.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Antigua</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-antigua/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-antigua/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Antigua, situated in the natural harbour of English Harbour on the southern coast of Antigua, is a major maritime facility of the Marine Services of Vekllei. The complex has a long maritime history dating back to the 18th century. Originally established as a Royal Navy base of the United Kingdom, it was a crucial outpost in the Caribbean, serving as a repair dockyard and strategic fort during the height of British colonial power.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Antigua</strong>, situated in the natural harbour of English Harbour on the southern coast of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(133, 122, 187); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(133, 122, 187) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/antigua/"><span class="fi fi-antigua"></span> Antigua</a>, is a major maritime facility of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The complex has a long maritime history dating back to the 18th century. Originally established as a Royal Navy base of the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(200, 16, 47); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(200, 16, 47) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/uk/"><span class="fi fi-gb"></span> United Kingdom</a>, it was a crucial outpost in the Caribbean, serving as a repair dockyard and strategic fort during the height of British colonial power. The station&rsquo;s sheltered position protected naval fleets from hurricanes and served as a defensive stronghold against piracy and European rivals. Much of the original fortifications survive, and are still in use in some capacity in the current station.</p>
<p>Today, Naval Station Antigua is a modern naval base, featuring expanded dry-docks and a radar station. Its unique facilities include a heritage shipyard, which preserves parts of the original 18th-century dockyard, and a civil defence station that specialises in coastal search-and-rescue and disaster response training for the Littoral Service. The facility is also an important base of operations for international anti-drug trafficking operations, and maintains strong ties with neighbouring Caribbean nations. It is the home base of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina Commonwealth</a> Auxiliary Fleet.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Falklands</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-falklands/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-falklands/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Falklands, located in Stanley Harbour on East Falkland Island, is a major Vekllei military facility of the Marine Services in the South Atlantic. Originally established by the British in the mid-19th century, the station served as a coaling and resupply point for whalers, explorers and naval ships patrolling the distant seas around Cape Horn and the Southern Ocean.
In current service, it remains an important military facility for the Vekllei Antarctic and South Atlantic.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Falklands</strong>, located in Stanley Harbour on East Falkland Island, is a major <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> military facility of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> in the South Atlantic. Originally established by the British in the mid-19th century, the station served as a coaling and resupply point for whalers, explorers and naval ships patrolling the distant seas around Cape Horn and the Southern Ocean.</p>
<p>In current service, it remains an important military facility for the Vekllei Antarctic and South Atlantic. It also provides a military basis for the continued Vekllei claim over the sovereignty of the Falklands, which remains in dispute with Argentina. Both the maritime and littoral services frequently encounter Argentina naval vessels in the waters around the islands, and in this sense the station represents a military commitment to their independence and sovereignty.</p>
<p>The station has several unique facilities, including a cold-weather warfare research and training centre (run by the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-defence); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-defence) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/dsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-dsre fis"></span> DSRE</a> and a drydock capable of servicing icebreakers and patrol vessels for Antarctic missions. An extension of the facility hosts the headquarters of the Antarctic Division of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a>. which is focused on marine conservation and environmental monitoring in the surrounding sub-Antarctic waters.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Java</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-java/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-java/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Java, situated on the eastern coast of Java in the Gulf of Guinea, is a major maritime facility of the Vekllei Marine Services. Originally established by Portuguese colonial forces in the early 18th century, the station was strategically located to protect the lucrative cocoa and coffee trade routes, which Java once dominated. Over time, the station expanded its capabilities to serve as a refuelling and resupply point for colonial fleets.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Java</strong>, situated on the eastern coast of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(217, 20, 19); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(217, 20, 19) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/verde/java/"><span class="fi fi-java"></span> Java</a> in the Gulf of Guinea, is a major maritime facility of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a>. Originally established by Portuguese colonial forces in the early 18th century, the station was strategically located to protect the lucrative cocoa and coffee trade routes, which Java once dominated. Over time, the station expanded its capabilities to serve as a refuelling and resupply point for colonial fleets. After accession to <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, the station fell into the control of its naval service, and the facility was rapidly expanded to support a large naval presence in the Gulf of Guinea.</p>
<p>In the modern era, Naval Station Java has become a central hub for the Vekllei navy, providing a headquarters for regional operations off the coast of West and Southern Africa and a major naval dockyard and refuelling station. The station also has large radar arrays capable of detecting surface vessels as small as wooden boats between Java and the African coast.</p>
<p>Anti-piracy and strategic security patrols are the basis of operations from the station, and the station also supports the construction, refitting and maintenance of several classes of naval vessels. These include the <a href="/prosperity-class/"><em>Prosperity</em></a>-class aircraft cruisers, <a href="/hera-class/"><em>Hera</em></a>-class minelayer/minesweepers, and the <a href="/palm-class/"><em>Palm</em></a>-class submarine chasers relocated from the closure of the dry-dock in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/places/ns-morocos/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Naval Station Morocos</a>. It has the third-largest dry-dock in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, capable of receiving <a href="/volcanic-class/"><em>Volcanic</em></a>-class aircraft carriers.</p>
<p>Naval Station Java also plays an important role in historical preservation, housing a museum detailing Java’s colonial maritime history and its evolution into a modern naval power. It is also home to the East Atlantic Naval School, which trains sailors from across the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/"><span class="fi fi-atlantic"></span> Atlantic Commonwealth</a> and <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/verde/"><span class="fi fi-verde"></span> Verde Commonwealth</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Kairi</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-kairi/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-kairi/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Kairi, located on Kairi&rsquo;s northern coast, serves as the primary maritime base for the Kalina Commonwealth and Lucayan Commonwealth regions of the Marine Services. It has its origins in the British colonial period, when the site was used in the early 17th century to protect valuable sugar trade routes. The fort there played a key role during the Napoleonic Wars, acting as a supply and defence point in the strategic Caribbean waters.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Kairi</strong>, located on <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(215, 18, 45); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(215, 18, 45) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/kairi/"><span class="fi fi-kairi"></span> Kairi</a>&rsquo;s northern coast, serves as the primary maritime base for the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/kalina/"><span class="fi fi-kalina"></span> Kalina Commonwealth</a> and <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/lucaya/"><span class="fi fi-lucaya"></span> Lucayan Commonwealth</a> regions of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a>. It has its origins in the British colonial period, when the site was used in the early 17th century to protect valuable sugar trade routes. The fort there played a key role during the Napoleonic Wars, acting as a supply and defence point in the strategic Caribbean waters. Over time, it became a critical hub for British and later U.S. naval operations during World War II, where it was instrumental in securing the Atlantic from enemy submarines.</p>
<p>Today, Naval Station Kairi is a sprawling facility, home to several advanced shipyards, extensive dry-docks, and a state-of-the-art command centre for overseeing regional security. The station includes a tropical warfare training centre, used by different <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-land); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-land) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/territorial/"><span class="fi fi-min-land fis"></span> Territorial Services</a> for joint exercises. Its dockyards are the home station of the <a href="/suffrage-class/"><em>Suffrage</em></a>-class corvettes, many of which were manufactured in the automatic docks at the site.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Mira</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-mira/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-mira/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Mira, located just outside of Fennel on the island of Mira, is a key Vekllei naval facility of the Marine Services in the Atlantic Ocean. Established in the early 20th century by Portugal, then the administrator of the island, the station was initially a strategic outpost for defending Portugal’s colonies and safeguarding maritime routes between Europe, Africa, and South America.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Mira</strong>, located just outside of Fennel on the island of Mira, is a key <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> naval facility of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> in the Atlantic Ocean. Established in the early 20th century by <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(0, 102, 1); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(0, 102, 1) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/portugal/"><span class="fi fi-pt"></span> Portugal</a>, then the administrator of the island, the station was initially a strategic outpost for defending Portugal’s colonies and safeguarding maritime routes between Europe, Africa, and South America.</p>
<p>Today, the station has evolved into a modern naval base, serving the <a href="/baker-class/"><em>Baker</em></a> and <a href="/swordfish-class/"><em>Swordfish</em></a>-class of air escort destroyers. It also serves as a staging facility for Vekllei naval operations, including anti-piracy patrols. Its facilities include automatic ship repair docks, nuclear refuelling stations, and advanced communication systems for monitoring Atlantic shipping lanes.</p>
<p>Naval Station Mira is a lynchpin of Vekllei maritime security in the east Atlantic, often hosting search-and-rescue missions and environmental monitoring in the surrounding waters. It also plays a significant role in the local economy, providing jobs and contributing to Fennel’s naval heritage.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Morocos</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-morocos/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-morocos/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Morocos, located on the Verde island of Morocos, serves as a nuclear refuelling and supply station of the Vekllei Marine Services in the Verde Commonwealth. Established in 2054, the station was originally built to support the increased fuelling demands of Vekllei nuclear naval vessels in the eastern Atlantic. Its strategic position at the crossroads of Atlantic shipping routes also made it a vital position for monitoring regional trade and bolstering the federalisation of the Verde archipelago.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Morocos</strong>, located on the Verde island of Morocos, serves as a nuclear refuelling and supply station of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> in the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/verde/"><span class="fi fi-verde"></span> Verde Commonwealth</a>.
Established in 2054, the station was originally built to support the increased fuelling demands of Vekllei nuclear naval vessels in the eastern Atlantic. Its strategic position at the crossroads of Atlantic shipping routes also made it a vital position for monitoring regional trade and bolstering the federalisation of the Verde archipelago.</p>
<p>The station is equipped with docking, refuelling, and maintenance facilities. It supports regional naval patrols, anti-smuggling operations, and search-and-rescue missions in the expansive Atlantic waters. The station also serves as a training centre for the Verdean component of the maritime service, primarily for coastal defence and maritime surveillance.</p>
<p>The station serves as the home station of <a href="/palm-class/"><em>Palm</em></a>-class submarine-chasers, but they have been serviced at <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/places/ns-java/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Naval Station Java</a> while the renovations of the automatic dry-dock at Morocos are underway.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Oslola</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-oslola/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-oslola/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Oslola, located on the fortified island of Kolumbo off the southern coast of Oslola, is the largest and most advanced naval facility in the Vekllei. The dockyards there date back hundreds of years, and the site has served as a naval fort since at least the 15th Century. Today, it is a densely-developed island complex housing the Oslola Commonwealth Docks, a dozen automatic shipyards, the Commonwealth Naval School and powerful radar arrays.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Oslola</strong>, located on the fortified island of Kolumbo off the southern coast of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(88, 90, 190) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/volcanic/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, is the largest and most advanced naval facility in the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. The dockyards there date back hundreds of years, and the site has served as a naval fort since at least the 15th Century. Today, it is a densely-developed island complex housing the Oslola Commonwealth Docks, a dozen automatic shipyards, the Commonwealth Naval School and powerful radar arrays. It is also home to a warren of forts and coastal fortifications, guarding the inhabited southwest coast of Oslola.</p>
<p>Although federalisation has decentralised much of Vekllei&rsquo;s naval industry, Naval Station Oslola remains the largest and most important of its naval facilities. It contains the King Dock, the only dry-dock capable of manufacturing and maintaining the <em>Veletia</em>-class supercarrier. It also houses the Commonwealth Submersible Plant, a collection of factories building <a href="/capricorn-class/"><em>Capricorn</em></a> and <a href="/mantle-class/"><em>Mantle</em></a>-class submarines. It is also the home station for most of the maritime service&rsquo;s oversized oceangoing vessels, including the <em>Federal</em>-class battleship and most of its battlecruisers.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Santes</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-santes/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-santes/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Santes, located on the remote island of Santes in the South Atlantic, is one of the most isolated naval installations in the world. It is an important maritime facility of the Vekllei Marine Services.
Established by the United Kingdom in the early 20th century, its original purpose was to serve as a monitoring outpost for maritime activity during World War I.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Santes</strong>, located on the remote island of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(211, 45, 71); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(211, 45, 71) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/santes/"><span class="fi fi-santes"></span> Santes</a> in the South Atlantic, is one of the most isolated naval installations in the world. It is an important maritime facility of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a>.</p>
<p>Established by the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(200, 16, 47); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(200, 16, 47) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/uk/"><span class="fi fi-gb"></span> United Kingdom</a> in the early 20th century, its original purpose was to serve as a monitoring outpost for maritime activity during World War I. Given Santes&rsquo;s strategic location along key shipping routes between South America and Africa, the station played a quiet but vital role in monitoring naval traffic and submarine movements during both World Wars.</p>
<p>Today, Naval Station Santes operates as a small yet advanced facility focused on oceanographic research, maritime surveillance, and environmental monitoring. It features a modern weather station and a deep-sea submersible docking area, unique due to its proximity to the South Atlantic’s unexplored depths. The station is also instrumental in supporting scientific expeditions to the island and surrounding waters, making it a hub for both naval and environmental activities of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-landscape);
background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-landscape) 10%, transparent);
" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/landscape/lsre/"><span class="fi fi-min-lsre fis"></span> LSRE</a>.</p>
<p>No class of Vekllei ships call at Santes as a home station, but facilities for docking and replenishing <em>Capricorn</em>-class attack submarines are located at the station.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Sude</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-sude/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-sude/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Sude, located in Godthul in the Sude Islands, is a peripheral Marine Services naval station of Vekllei. Originally established as a whaling station in the early 20th century, Godthul became one of the world’s largest whaling hubs, operating until the mid-1960s when commercial whaling declined. During World War II, the station was briefly fortified by British forces to guard against potential Axis activity in the Southern Ocean.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Sude</strong>, located in Godthul in the <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(60, 122, 184); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(60, 122, 184) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/antarctic/sude/"><span class="fi fi-gs"></span> Sude</a> Islands, is a peripheral <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> naval station of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. Originally established as a whaling station in the early 20th century, Godthul became one of the world’s largest whaling hubs, operating until the mid-1960s when commercial whaling declined. During World War II, the station was briefly fortified by British forces to guard against potential Axis activity in the Southern Ocean.</p>
<p>Naval Station Sude was formally established following the 2015 Antarctic Crisis, and plays a significant role in maintaining <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> sovereignty over the South Hetland islands. It currently supports a small naval garrison, along with a detachment of Littoral Service vessels. The Naval Station also supports general government and civilian shipping as a staging base for Antarctic and South Atlantic expeditions.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Naval Station Verde</title>
	  <link>/factbook/world/places/ns-verde/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/world/places/ns-verde/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[This article is about a location in Vekllei Naval Station Verde, located on the Azores island of Costa Verde, serves as a vital maritime hub of the Vekllei Marine Services in the Atlantic Commonwealth. Established in the late 19th century under the rule of Portugal, the station initially operated as a strategic coaling and resupply point for Portuguese naval vessels. Over the years, it expanded into a modern naval base, equipped with automatic facilities for ship maintenance, refuelling, and training.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">This article is about a <a href="/factbook/landscape/places">location</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Naval Station Verde</strong>, located on the Azores island of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(33, 131, 67); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(33, 131, 67) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/costa-verde/"><span class="fi fi-costa-verde"></span> Costa Verde</a>, serves as a vital maritime hub of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-marine); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-marine) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/ministries/defence/armed-forces/marine/"><span class="fi fi-min-marine fis"></span> Marine Services</a> in the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/atlantic/"><span class="fi fi-atlantic"></span> Atlantic Commonwealth</a>. Established in the late 19th century under the rule of <a class="slink" style="color: rgb(0, 102, 1); background: color-mix(in srgb, rgb(0, 102, 1) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/countries/portugal/"><span class="fi fi-pt"></span> Portugal</a>, the station initially operated as a strategic coaling and resupply point for Portuguese naval vessels. Over the years, it expanded into a modern naval base, equipped with automatic facilities for ship maintenance, refuelling, and training. Today, it serves as the base of <a href="/volcanic-class/"><em>Volcanic</em>-class</a> Fleet Carriers and <a href="/nike-class/"><em>Nike</em>-class</a> Missile Cruisers of the Commonwealth Fleet.</p>
<p>Situated in Ponta Delgada’s natural harbor, the station plays a critical role in monitoring the shipping lanes between Europe, Africa, and the Americas. It also serves as a key base for maritime patrols of the Littoral Service, search-and-rescue missions, and anti-piracy operations. The Naval Station has hosted joint operations with the UN anti-piracy task force, reinforcing its strategic significance.</p>
<p>The station mostly employs locals and has integrated itself into the community through outreach programs and open days, contributing to Costa Verde&rsquo;s ongoing maritime legacy.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
