<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Characters</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/characters/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Characters </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/characters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Picture of Integration</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/integration/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/integration/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Sitting on the concrete sea wall in Lola. Tzipora was a picture of integration, because she wanted badly for people to respect her. She also felt she owed something to the country which had lifted her up and given her a quality of life. She had no prospects before coming to Oslola, so she practiced gratitude in everything she did &ndash; sometimes out loud.
Lin Zhi was not a picture of integration; Lin Zhi was a black box.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/zhi.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Sitting on the concrete sea wall in <a href="/lola/">Lola</a>.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora was a picture of integration, because she wanted badly for people to respect her. She also felt she owed something to the country which had lifted her up and given her a quality of life. She had no prospects before coming to <a style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190)" href="/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>, so she practiced gratitude in everything she did &ndash; sometimes out loud.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi was not a picture of integration; Lin Zhi was a black box. She barely spoke English &ndash; the common language of Vekllei&rsquo;s immigrant society and international schools. A lot of the English she did speak came in short, sharp barks. Her severe disposition was well known at <a href="/moshel/">Moshel St School</a>. They were paired together in gardening class, and Tzipora learned soon enough that Lin Zhi was not so much rude as she was quiet and isolated, and did not trust or like her peers.</p>
<p>Tzipora was terrible at making friends, but not because she was out of tune with people&rsquo;s feelings. She knew Zhi was a private person instinctively, and so she did not ask her questions or force conversation except to plant crops and water ferns. Zhi in turn became used to her and they developed silent routines in class.</p>
<p>When Tzipora broke her arm a few months later, Zhi asked how she broke it, without looking up from the soil.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I was playing tennis and fell on it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>And Lin Zhi laughed once.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Portrait</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/portrait/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/portrait/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Portrait of Tzipora &amp; Cobian finished in a painterly style. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/portrait.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Portrait of Tzipora &amp; Cobian finished in a painterly style.</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Weirdo</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/weirdo/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/weirdo/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Zelda&rsquo;s a weirdo, but she&rsquo;s a friend. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/weirdo.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Zelda&rsquo;s a weirdo, but she&rsquo;s a friend.</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Friends</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/friends-draft/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/friends-draft/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Paint-sketch of the girls together I never ended up finishing. Clockwise:
Cobian is an Algic girl, which means she&rsquo;s indigenous to Iceland in my world, which is called Oslola. She comes from a mixed indigenous Arctic background. Her mother is kind of crazy and Cobian is a bit insecure, but she&rsquo;s very close with Tzipora. They drift between friends and girlfriends, it&rsquo;s complicated.
Coretti is Afro-Russian. Even though she was born in Congo (sometimes called Zaire in my world) she grew up in the USSR and immigrated to Oslola later on.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/draft.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <span class="text">Paint-sketch of the girls together I never ended up finishing.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Clockwise:</p>
<p>Cobian is an Algic girl, which means she&rsquo;s indigenous to Iceland in my world, which is called <a style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190)" href="/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a>. She comes from a mixed indigenous Arctic background. Her mother is kind of crazy and Cobian is a bit insecure, but she&rsquo;s very close with Tzipora. They drift between friends and girlfriends, it&rsquo;s complicated.</p>
<p>Coretti is Afro-Russian. Even though she was born in Congo (sometimes called Zaire in my world) she grew up in the USSR and immigrated to Oslola later on. She&rsquo;s very patient and graceful, and is dating Tzipora&rsquo;s best friend Moise.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi is Chinese and always goes by her full name. She doesn&rsquo;t speak much of their language and she&rsquo;s kind of a hothead so she&rsquo;s a bit of a mystery to them. But Tzipora attracts eccentric characters and Lin Zhi doesn&rsquo;t have any other friends so she hangs out with them.</p>
<p>Finally, Tzipora (being held) is the main character of the story. Her mother was Spanish Roma and her father was Yiddish. She&rsquo;s very friendly but intense and she&rsquo;s sort of the focus point which the friendship group is centred around. She&rsquo;s got more going on with her (she doesn&rsquo;t live with her parents and how she came to Vekllei is ambiguous) but she&rsquo;s just trying her best.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
