<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Ayn on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/ayn/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Ayn on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/ayn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Happy New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-01-new-year/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2022-01-01-new-year/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Welcome to 2022, year of Vekllei. Here&amp;rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love.  Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&amp;rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Generations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-09-generations/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Ayn was a naturally busy person. She worked long, hard hours at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence, or ‘AB/NI,’ as a clerk, or specialist, or whatever they needed her to be that day. Her days off were filled with petty occupations and minor obligations — mostly tending to her plants and cleaning. She enjoyed number puzzles.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei&#39;s New-Age Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-01-woman/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }   A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.
 — Lu Xun, 1927
 Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &amp;lsquo;backward elements.&amp;rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2021-01-5-rocket/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  The New Year in Vekllei rings out during its months of darkness and cold. This calendar runs the regular affairs of the country, like it does the modern world. To Vekllei people, however, it is plain that New Years occurs not in darkness but instead in the summer solstice in June, the way it has for thousands of years in the dramatic cycles of light and dark in the country.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Most Beautiful Woman</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-12-ayn/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”
It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Canal Living</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-03-canal/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin  Atlantic Salmon was the best in the world, and Vekllei had a lot of it. Ocean-going fishing boats brought their haul to Ro, where they cruised wide postwar canals and unloaded tonnes of shiny, bright salmon into processing plants. If a new factory was built, so too was a canal or a railroad.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Introducing Ayn</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-14-ayn/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-14-ayn/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  The daughter of a Soviet expat and Hong Konger deckhand, Ayn Rumouisen has never stepped foot outside of Vekllei. A serious fear of flying and the open ocean has hedged her appetite for travel for all of her thirty-two years. She is well respected as an operations consultant within the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), and is close with the ABNI Operations Director Baron Desmoisnes and Vekllei’s first “Gregori Baby,” Tzipora &amp;ldquo;Zelda&amp;rdquo; Desmoisnes.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Brief Introduction to Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-an-introduction/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-09-03-an-introduction/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  Editor&amp;rsquo;s note: this article, while ready for reading, is still under construction.
Considering both the length and convoluted terminology that embroil this project, there was only so long I could carry on before people started getting lost. The truth of it is that Vekllei is not a particularly complex or difficult project to summarise, despite the snapshot &amp;ldquo;lore in scenes&amp;rdquo; approach that kneecaps a complete understanding.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The participatory economy of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2019-05-07-utopia/</guid>
	  <description>Archived from the original article here   a.book-btn:hover { filter: brightness(85%); }  ❖ This article predates the project, and should be considered non-canon.  Nestled between the regional tram offices and the pre-war Ferouistet Department Store, the Lola district is not known for much but her department store and good schools. It sits on the slope of the wide Vekllei capital basin, where the Atlantic can be seen from the street.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>