<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Ayn</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/ayn/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Ayn </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/ayn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Family</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/family/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/family/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ They may not be related, but they are a family. Visit characters to read more about them. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/family.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">They may not be related, but they are a family. Visit <a href="/characters/">characters</a> to read more about them.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei 2024</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/2024/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/2024/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ The first morning of 2064. Ayn is collecting arctic basil for the eggs. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/2024.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">The first morning of 2064. Ayn is collecting arctic basil for the eggs.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Christmas Lamb</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/christmas-lamb/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/christmas-lamb/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ It is December 28th. Baron is the only one still trying to finish the Christmas lamb. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/lamb.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">It is December 28th. Baron is the only one still trying to finish the Christmas lamb.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Personal Defence</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/pdw/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/pdw/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[A submachine gun equipped with drums for use in corridors and tight spaces, in the event of catastrophe. A HO/NI analyst poses with one of the interior defence weapons hidden in their headquarters.
HO/NI stands for &ldquo;Home Office/National Intelligence,&rdquo; and is the internal intelligence apparatus of Vekllei. It is one of six bureaus: HO/NI, AB/NI, RB/NI EB/NI, OB/NI, and SA/NI.
Although her weapon is obviously inspired by the uzi, it&rsquo;s actually a domestic Vekllei model descended from what the original uzi license.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/pdw.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">A submachine gun equipped with drums for use in corridors and tight spaces, in the event of catastrophe.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>A <a href="/opsec/">HO/NI</a> analyst poses with one of the interior defence weapons hidden in their headquarters.</p>
<p>HO/NI stands for &ldquo;Home Office/National Intelligence,&rdquo; and is the internal intelligence apparatus of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. It is one of six bureaus: HO/NI, AB/NI, RB/NI EB/NI, OB/NI, and SA/NI.</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">Although her weapon is obviously inspired by the uzi, it&rsquo;s actually a domestic Vekllei model descended from what the original uzi license. In this setting, both <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> and <a href="/israel/"><span class="fi fi-il"></span> Israel</a> (along with many others) are part of the <a href="/free-nations/">non-aligned movement</a>, and so a lot of trade flows between its members.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Heatwave</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/heatwave/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/heatwave/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Oslolans when the temperature hits 25°C. Oslola is part of Vekllei, and is known as Iceland in our own world. In this setting, the North Atlantic is a bit more temperate thanks to the Oslolan Low Pole and strong ocean currents. Still, they&rsquo;re acclimatised to cool air, and 25°C (77°F) is hot weather for them.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/heatwave.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">Oslolans when the temperature hits 25°C.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><a style="color: rgb(88, 90, 190)" href="/oslola/"><span class="fi fi-oslola"></span> Oslola</a> is part of <a style="color: var(--color-vekllei)" href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and is known as Iceland in our own world. In this setting, the North Atlantic is a bit more temperate thanks to the Oslolan Low Pole and strong ocean currents. Still, they&rsquo;re acclimatised to cool air, and 25°C (77°F) is hot weather for them.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Analyst</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/analyst/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/analyst/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Ayn is an Intelligence Analyst at HO/NI&rsquo;s Section 3. Intelligence officers in the Commonwealth have ranks, called Grades, and receive awards that can be displayed above their ID tag in formal settings. In civilian clothes, two awards (usually the highest but at the discretion of the officer) are worn in a ribbon bar. In full dress the medals are worn.
From top to bottom, Ayn&rsquo;s accessories are listed:
Ribbon bar featuring the Order of Veletia and the National Service Medal.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/fullres/analyst.jpg"/> <p>Ayn is an Intelligence Analyst at HO/NI&rsquo;s Section 3. Intelligence officers in the Commonwealth have ranks, called Grades, and receive awards that can be displayed above their ID tag in formal settings. In civilian clothes, two awards (usually the highest but at the discretion of the officer) are worn in a ribbon bar. In full dress the medals are worn.</p>
<p>From top to bottom, Ayn&rsquo;s accessories are listed:</p>
<ol>
<li>Ribbon bar featuring the Order of Veletia and the National Service Medal.</li>
<li>ID tag featuring name, photograph, ID number, expiry and department.</li>
<li>The HO/NI Intelligence Pin worn by all officers.</li>
<li>The Order of Veletia, awarded for saving many lives or preventing extraordinary harm as part of service, or for acts of extraordinary courage. Ayn received this for her part in Operation Sea of Reeds.</li>
<li>The National Service Medal, awarded for consistently distinguished and competent service to the directorate. Ayn received this shortly after ten years service for her exemplary work in analysis.</li>
</ol>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ Welcome to 2022, year of Vekllei. Here&rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love. Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/newyear2022.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note ">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>Welcome to 2022,</strong> year of Vekllei. Here&rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Generations</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/cyclical/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/cyclical/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Ayn was a naturally busy person. She worked long, hard hours at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence, or ‘AB/NI,’ as a clerk, or specialist, or whatever they needed her to be that day. Her days off were filled with petty occupations and minor obligations — mostly tending to her plants and cleaning. She enjoyed number puzzles. A couple friends had formed a book club, and she went to that on occasion.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/generations.jpg"/> <p><strong>Ayn was a naturally busy person</strong>. She worked long, hard hours at the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence, or ‘AB/NI,’ as a clerk, or specialist, or whatever they needed her to be that day. Her days off were filled with petty occupations and minor obligations — mostly tending to her plants and cleaning. She enjoyed number puzzles. A couple friends had formed a book club, and she went to that on occasion.</p>
<p>Tzipora’s arrival in June of 2063 saw several disruptions to Ayn’s routines, not least of which was the surfacing of her old unsentimental boyfriend, now ten years older and much different. Tzipora herself emerged into Ayn’s personal life, and they became close — much like it was with Baron, Tzipora was both a daughter and a friend.</p>
<p>It had been Ayn’s recommendation, actually, that Baron should take her.</p>
<p>“At least for a while,” she said, “She talks about you all the time. No one’s talking about adoption — just take her until the system can sort her out. That’s my advice.”</p>
<p>Tzipora met Ayn’s parents later that year, and just like that, Tzipora had forged herself a new family through her force of will and good charm — Baron, the father; Ayn, the mother; and her Hong-Konger/Russian parents. And Ayn’s parents adored her; they showered Tzipora with gifts and baked goods. She was the grandchild they’d wanted so much.</p>
<p>The whole situation aroused an ongoing memory, foggy through shame and discomfort, about her ageing parents and her unmarried lifestyle. It was very difficult for Ayn to discuss her decision not to have children with her parents. She was an only child. How do you tell your parents their ancestors, their bloodline ends with you? It hurt them a lot. It hurt Ayn too, to make that choice and follow her heart.</p>
<p>Ayn lived in the same studio apartment in the Great Coast she had for a decade, though she now owned it from her work. As a childless, unmarried woman it was very difficult to find larger homes, which were usually allocated to couples and families. Real estate in Vekllei was both a reward and a punishment, and informed the social fabric of the country.</p>
<p>Tzipora was good at being a grandchild when she needed to be, and Ayn was very thankful for her presence in their lives. Ayn loved her parents, and found herself thinking back to her own childhood more and more as they grew older. She was still their baby, and it was sometimes difficult to reconcile her own independence as an adult with her desire to make them happy. That desire — the instinct to please — dated back to being a little girl, dumb and full of wonder, navigating her childhood with her mum and dad, much younger then, always loving.</p>
<p>After work, she would sometimes sit and smoke, then put it out and smell the salt on the breeze. She used to come out here to think, often melancholic about her life and decisions. Nowadays, the thoughts were lighter, more straightforward. She was more self-assured. Sometimes, Tzipora sat out there with her.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Vekllei&#39;s New-Age Women</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/women/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/women/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.
— Lu Xun, 1927
Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &lsquo;backward elements.&rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.
— Ding Ling on the long-marcher woman soldiers, 1942
When Tzipora first arrived in Vekllei in 2063, she was traumatised by the foreignness of everything.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/women.jpg"/> <blockquote>
<p><em>A woman has so many parts to her body, life is very hard indeed.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>— <strong>Lu Xun</strong>, 1927</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Even from my point of view, as a woman, there is nothing attractive about such &lsquo;backward elements.&rsquo; Their skin is beginning to wrinkle, their hair is growing thin, and fatigue is robbing them of their last traces of attractiveness.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>— <strong>Ding Ling</strong> on the long-marcher woman soldiers, 1942</p>
<p><strong>When Tzipora first arrived in Vekllei in 2063</strong>, she was traumatised by the foreignness of everything. It was not just that they drove on the wrong side of the road, or that the chocolate was made by someone else, but that her whole understanding of the world — the world she’d been raised in all her life — was unravelled within weeks. It did not matter if you learned the language, or dressed like them, or worked with them — the way a Vekllei person thinks seemed totally alien, as though they were tuned into a frequency that she couldn’t hear. That was very difficult for her.</p>
<p>Her clearest memory, out of all the emotional turmoil in her first few weeks, was the clothes. Tzipora was not fashionable or materialistic, but she’d never had nice things to wear. In Vekllei the things on the rack were simple, and often second-hand, but they were very well made and the department stores had a big variety. She picked out five shirts, nearly identical, and decided that these would be what she would wear from now on — it was her own way of establishing an identity; SHE IS THE GIRL WHO WEARS THIS TYPE OF SHIRT. Little things like that mattered a lot, because Tzipora was treated differently here. She was both ‘young’ and a ‘girl’, which had implications for how overseas people talked to her and how she was regarded. Here, almost no one seemed to notice. She had dignity by default, which was exciting and scary at the same time, so she needed something other than her appearance to claim as ‘hers’. And at that time, it was the shirt with the pleats.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Vekllei is a place that is very much radical</strong> but, either intentionally or as a byproduct of its opaque culture, suppresses the <em>appearance</em> of radicalism in its public affairs (or as they say there, ‘sun-facing space’). This is for a few reasons. First, Vekllei uses its obscurity as a weapon against its continental neighbours, who might pull it into geopolitical tensions it wants no part of. The second is that Vekllei’s failed revolutionary movements of the early 20th Century are buried with the Junta that suppressed them. The third, and most critically, is that Vekllei people themselves are unaware of just how saturated their lives are with the cultural and political ideology of the floral period, which makes “foreign” political thinking difficult and results in a lot of empty rhetoric — for example, “petticoat socialism” describes the Bureau System, which does not have much to do with either petticoats or continental socialism.</p>
<p>This paradigm makes more sense when you consider that there are really two Veklleis — the one that existed before the Atomic War, and the one that exists now, called the “Floral Period” or sometimes “Petticoat Society”. The one that existed before has little resemblance to the one that exists now, and that is the way people have continued to think in the decades of independence — anything prior to 2015 is, simply, history.</p>
<p>Make no mistake — Vekllei is tremendously radical in its culture and politics, which it tempers with conservative names and third-way politicking. Today’s post looks at how the Vekllei woman changed in the years between 2005 and 2020.</p>
<p>Not unlike revolutions of years past, postwar Vekllei had (for the moment, at least) lost many of its structural oppressors of women, since the structure itself had collapsed quickly. The interim government had taken an orthodox, though contrarian, communist position, which ushered a new handbook of rhetoric towards de-objectification of women and their pragmatic and social value in the workforce. The interim government had several key women figures among it, who are credited with its success in this critical, and rapidly changing period.</p>
<p>In the Vekllei socialist (<em>socialisme oa Vekllei</em>) line of thinking, there are two points of attack. There was the suppression of old models of feminine beauty, which argued against women’s independence and dignity in favour of their security with men, who made up Vekllei’s economic and social caste throughout the entirety of the Junta’s rule. But there was also a very real fear that women’s liberation by Western metrics would simply evolve indentured living into a more obtuse, and in some ways more sinister, commodity-woman (<em>cosmavisiousnesh</em>, lit. ‘plastic woman’<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>), who was free to educate herself but found her appearance subjected to permanent scrutiny — a product for a consumer, dependent on shifting fashions and complex social constellations still fundamentally controlled by men. This fear was not unfounded, as many educated women of the interim government (who made up nearly half of its members) had spent significant time in Western Europe and the United States, and were keenly aware of who was “gazing” (<em>lismious</em>) and who was being “gazed at” (<em>visimett</em>).</p>
<p>The solution developed by the interim government was both political and spiritual, designed to demolish the external remnants of Vekllei’s pre-war and highly stratified society, and the looming threats of foreign investment, new wealth, and an import of the modern commodity-woman. Most importantly, it understood that present notions of empowerment or disempowerment were problematic unto themselves — whether it was sexual liberation, modesty, or indeed the economic role of women in abstract — their ability to empower was still fundamentally chained to old society, which was still dominated by the sexist cultural default.</p>
<p>In 2016, Cisma de Diviousmesn, First Secretary of the War Recovery Committee, described the problem as such in The <em>Atlantic</em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We are nearing a precipice that all Vekllei women may fall into, should we follow unblinkingly the Visis Plan [postwar redevelopment plan], and allow foreign investment to replace English colonial governor-generals; we should be wise enough, so to speak, to not trade a king for a master and call it recovery.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In <em>Upen</em>’s discourse on womanhood, the essential virtues of a woman have always included good words, good work and good fortune — emphasising the role of women as both an alias for success/wealth and also as responsible for that fortune themselves, either in the workplace or through their innate spirituality. This has remained true throughout much of Vekllei’s history, but was obfuscated by the economic masculinity of Vekllei’s protectionist mercantile period. After the war, Upen saw a revival that would culminate in the spiritual fever of the late 2010s and early 2020s. The interim government co-opted this surge pragmatically, encouraging a shift in local perceptions of womanhood through spiritual, rather than political or ideological, methods.</p>
<p>“This is a New Age,” the posters said. “So become a New-Age Woman.”<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>Becoming a New Age Woman involved two things — tearing down the external oppressions of the old and interim periods (harassment, domestic violence, and male interference in the affairs of women), and the interrogation of internalised sexisms (empowerment by male opinion [this included styles women found attractive, as inherited from men], abolishment of economic preoccupations, and the reconstruction of womanhood in abstract). This individual struggle was supported by the many social programmes developed by the interim government, with names like “economic feminisation” (abolishment of the male economic burden) and “abolishment of self-beautification for your man” (<em>scisimionze</em>, or “self-adornment/self-beautification”).</p>
<p>The point was not to empower women by simply displacing men from male economic and social constructions — a move that was seen as disempowering because of who was setting those priorities —  but to rebuild Vekllei’s domestic understanding of “the woman” by the terms of women, legitimised by the authority of the interim government and the powerful cultural force Upen continues to have on society. Within such a culture, it was reasoned, women would be free to choose what womanhood meant to them, since it was not simply reactive to a sexist cultural default. The sum of this effort was called ‘sun-facing,’ or <em>semoisnesne</em>, which referred to the progressive attitude of both the individual and the country.</p>
<p>Although Vekllei’s New Age Woman had dramatic effects and benefitted the status of women in Vekllei society tremendously, it was nonetheless fundamentally political and had obscure and surprising cultural artefacts buried within. The idea that a woman would be “free to choose” her own womanhood was a little misleading, since the interim government was rapidly developing its plan for “petticoat society,” in which Sundress Municipalism, the Bureau System and Floral Aestheticism would become such powerful cultural forces that no man nor woman would be able to escape them entirely.</p>
<p>As the wealth of the country grew and then exploded in the transition to Vekllei’s floral society, it was clear how the structure of petticoat society continued to influence women in Vekllei. Women can wear whatever they like — but simplicity and subtle self-decoration are common and encouraged by the uniforms system and floral aesthetics. Women can live however they like — but education is compulsory in childhood and highly valued, and young women are encouraged to fulfil ‘the female inclination for leadership’ inherited from Upen’s mother-metaphysics. And women can date whomever they like — though ideological compatibility, and not appearance, is encouraged in the <em>semoisnesne</em> attitude.</p>
<p>Some of these things are easily argued as good — few would assume there are many feminists in the world who argue against the education of women — but they do betray the notion of truly “free” choice, insofar as Vekllei society is dominated by the economic and spiritual values of its structure. Vekllei considers capitalist economics, exponential growth, and gross historicism to be “masculine” — of course that sort of language trickles down into the social aspects of society. More directly, it prioritises form, colour, and purity in aesthetics — of course that aesthetic ideology affects how people dress, and contributes to its uniformed culture.</p>
<p>It is difficult to place where the state begins and ends in Vekllei, which is how it can be argued for as an unfree and anarchic society simultaneously. So too is it difficult to determine how much of Vekllei culture originates in the centres of power in Vekllei — either political or religious — and subsequently there are problems in clarifying how women are affected by power, especially since women participate and in some cases dominate those hierarchies. Are they externalised, or internalised? Who is gazing at who?</p>
<p>Regardless of Vekllei’s cultural obscurity, which affects much more than politics and many people other than women, it is clear a dramatic and liberating shift occurred in Vekllei’s interim period of independence, and that shift has contributed tremendously to the status of contemporary Vekllei women, who enjoy economic and social freedoms that were unimaginable just decades prior. Even though Vekllei has not embraced political iconography to celebrate their indigenous feminism, we can see just how radical and wide-ranging the changes made were.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The phrase &ldquo;plastic woman&rdquo; was coined by author John Graves, whose work found popularity in postwar Vekllei after its translation.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><em>Cosmatsisosmiosne de Ne</em>, lit. &ldquo;Woman of the New Age&rdquo;&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/rocket/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/rocket/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The New Year in Vekllei rings out during its months of darkness and cold. This calendar runs the regular affairs of the country, like it does the modern world. To Vekllei people, however, it is plain that New Years occurs not in darkness but instead in the summer solstice in June, the way it has for thousands of years in the dramatic cycles of light and dark in the country. In this sense, the end of December resonates among businesses and little else, much like the financial year elsewhere.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/rocket.jpg"/> <p><strong>The New Year in Vekllei rings out during its months of darkness and cold</strong>. This calendar runs the regular affairs of the country, like it does the modern world. To Vekllei people, however, it is plain that New Years occurs not in darkness but instead in the summer solstice in June, the way it has for thousands of years in the dramatic cycles of light and dark in the country. In this sense, the end of December resonates among businesses and little else, much like the financial year elsewhere. An ancient pagan festival, one of twelve each year, takes its place in summer. This event is called <em>Rascismion</em>, or “Rebirth of the Season” in the old Vekllei usage of the word — meaning the complete cycle of seasons.</p>
<p>As a spiritual artefact of <em>Upen</em>, it is no surprise that the Solstice brings good luck and rebirth to Vekllei. It marks good fortune then, that the assembly and launch of the <em>Desg</em> met the Solstice, launching for Jupiter’s Europa just before midnight on June 21st, 2064. Constructed by the <em>Solar Concern of the Vekllei Commonwealth Materials Bureau</em> (or Solaburo) in cooperation with the <em>Rocket Navy of the Vekllei Commonwealth Armed Forces</em> and the <em>Cosmos Office</em> (or Cosmoburo), the <em>Desg</em> will land material on Europa to prepare for human arrival in six years. It is named after the Desg creatures of Vekllei mythology, who passed messages between malicious and benevolent factions of creatures before human settlement.</p>
<p>Although it was nearly midnight, it was the Solstice and the sun would not set tonight. Ayn and Tzipora had spread out plates of Vekllei <em>Kimisosyo</em> stew across a blanket just south of the Lita Cosmodrome to watch the launch. The <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/lita">Royal Borough of Lita</a> was not far from Copette (<a href="https://millmint.net/images/railmap.jpg">map of Vekllei here</a>), one of the Five Crown Boroughs of Vekllei, but this was Vekllei’s glacial interior and it felt a million miles from anywhere. Its geography was ancient and violent, strikingly barren and brutally volcanic. Why visit Europa? It was alien enough here.</p>
<p>Ayn had brought her portable television. Baron was supposed to meet them there, but his train was delayed and he was stuck somewhere in <a href="/factbook/landscape/boroughs/miyatvousi/">Miyatvousi</a> with the beer and fruit spritzers. Tzipora liked a drink, but Ayn liked it too much and had given it up years ago.</p>
<p>“I suppose it’s better than being drunk,” Tzipora said, nursing a fizzy drink.</p>
<p>“Oh, it’s not at all, Zelda… Getting drunk feels great, that’s why I got drunk,” Ayn said. She was watching some teen-agers cuddling further down the hill, and sighed after a moment. “That’s the trouble with it. A warm night like this, tired and with nothing to do? It’s the best feeling in the world. Let’s not kid ourselves.”</p>
<p>“I like wine,” Tzipora said stupidly before erring a moment later, embarrassed at how childish she sounded. “Well, you know. I drink alcohol, but not much. I like sweet things mostly.”</p>
<p>Ayn felt sorry for girl as the awkwardness of the conversation settled on Tzipora. It was worse to be self-aware, sometimes.</p>
<p>“Baron likes a drink,” Tzipora continued. “He drinks a lot. He’s okay though, I don’t think he can get drunk. He’s a cool cucumber, he doesn’t change at all.”</p>
<p>“Is that right? Anyway, what time is it? It’ll be launching soon.”</p>
<p>As the minutes ticked closer to launch, Tzipora began to fret that Baron wouldn’t make it. The New Year was very important to her.</p>
<p>He was out-of-breath and wrestling a crate of beer back under his arm as the distant boom of the atomic thrusters caught the mountaintops. He crested the hill as a dull roar invited the distant glitter of rocket engines that flickered out of the Lita Cosmodrome Launch Basin. He saw Ayn and Tzipora not far away and called to them, but they couldn’t hear him — the <em>Desg</em> had called in the New Year, and all eyes were on it as it shined in the sky, brightest of all the stars. 2064 had became 2065, or Year 59 of the Floral Period.</p>
<p><strong>Happy New Year!</strong></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Most Beautiful Woman</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/beautiful-woman/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/beautiful-woman/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[✿ This article was featured in Issue #2 of the Atlantic Bulletin When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”
It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture. Tzipora was not quite sure how to describe it.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/ayn.jpg"/> <blockquote class="note story">
  <div class="icon">
</div>
  <div class="text">✿ <strong>This article</strong> was featured in <a href="/news/bulletin/2020/2"><strong>Issue #2</strong></a> of the <em>Atlantic Bulletin</em></div>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>When Tzipora first laid eyes on Ayn</strong>, hours after her arrival in the country, she thought, “that’s the most beautiful woman I’ve ever seen.”</p>
<p>It wasn’t just her features or figure that captured Tzipora’s attention — it was also her confident, inconspicuous movements and a quiet self-assuredness that seemed obvious in her gentle expression and posture. Tzipora was not quite sure how to describe it. Her beauty was very alive in the way she inhabited a space, as she walked into the hotel lounge to meet them. Maybe it was grace — maybe it was a little girl-crush — she didn’t know.</p>
<p>As Baron greeted her and they exchanged cheek kisses, it appeared to Tzipora that Ayn and Baron were old friends, and she was further assured in her respect for him — that Baron could know such beautiful women seemed natural! Baron was capable of anything in Tzipora’s eyes, a figure of ultimate power — it only made sense that he knew this woman!</p>
<p>Of course, both Ayn and Baron were mortal, and Tzipora got to know them well during the helter-skelter weeks following her arrival in Vekllei. Baron might have rescued her, but it was Ayn who introduced her to Vekllei, as AB/NI called Baron into office for the first time in a decade. It was Ayn who took her clothes shopping and wrestled with Zelda’s obsessive-compulsive fabric requirements. It was Ayn who taught Tzipora her first Vekllei sentence. And in the end, it was Ayn who convinced Baron that he had to take responsibility for Tzipora.</p>
<p>It was only years later that Tzipora began to realise that Ayn and Baron were, in a sense, married to each other through their work. They worked closely (he as recent head of operations at AB/NI, she as a research analyst in American economics) and their friendship went back decades. She was his “work wife,” which was the closest Baron could ever get to that particular institution, and so her proximity and love towards Tzipora made her a mother.</p>
<p>She was a vision of everything Tzipora wanted for herself — to be capable and respected; beautiful and unassuming; intelligent and productive. And once more, it was Ayn, in the end, who convinced Tzipora that she could these things for herself, regardless of her genetic disability. “Go out there,” is what she said, “and trust in yourself.&quot;</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Introducing Ayn</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ayn/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ayn/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The daughter of a Soviet expat and Hong Konger deckhand, Ayn Rumouisen has never stepped foot outside of Vekllei. A serious fear of flying and the open ocean has hedged her appetite for travel for all of her thirty-two years. She is well respected as an operations consultant within the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), and is close with the ABNI Operations Director Baron Desmoisnes and Vekllei’s first “Gregori Baby,” Tzipora &ldquo;Zelda&rdquo; Desmoisnes.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/introducingayn.jpg"/> <p>The daughter of a Soviet expat and Hong Konger deckhand, <strong>Ayn</strong> <strong>Rumouisen</strong> has never stepped foot outside of Vekllei. A serious fear of flying and the open ocean has hedged her appetite for travel for all of her thirty-two years. She is well respected as an operations consultant within the Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), and is close with the ABNI Operations Director <strong>Baron Desmoisnes</strong> and Vekllei’s first “Gregori Baby,” <strong>Tzipora &ldquo;Zelda&rdquo; Desmoisnes</strong>.</p>
<p>She’s known Baron, Tzipora’s father, for nigh twenty years. They met when she was eighteen, both as cadets in Vekllei’s combat intelligence programme. They dated for a few years before the requirements of intelligence work forced them apart. Baron was sent to South America for nearly a decade, and Ayn stayed behind in the Monitoring &amp; Preparations Department where she published work in the classified journals about events relevant to ABNI. She was also an associate contributor to the “Import Strangle” theoretical model, which has proven successful at plotting the collapse of major U.S. employers (like U.S. Steel in 2065 and Chrysler in 2068) for use in Vekllei foreign policy.</p>
<p>Baron and Ayn exemplify quiet, uncinematic mateship — people satiated by occasional company and mutual respect, satisfied by their intermittent time together. After Tzipora’s adoption, Baron, now approaching his forties, returned to work as a senior director for the Americas Bureau, and soon found himself in Ayn’s professional orbit. In doing so, he introduced a nervous young satellite called Tzipora to her.</p>
<p>Tzipora adores Ayn. Ayn is everything Tzipora wants to be. She is even-tempered but strong-willed, graceful but not girlish, fiercely intelligent but pleasantly social. Where Baron is a product of his years in America and is totally professionalised at home and at work, Ayn has enjoyed life in Vekllei and is well-rounded and sweet. It was a shock for Tzipora to see Baron and Ayn in a photograph from their cadetship. Baron straddled a motorcycle, and did not wear spectacles. He was well-built and rough-looking. Ayn was a slender Asian woman dressed in slacks and a sunhat. Ayn today looked very much similar. Baron, in his beard and white-speckled hair, looked like an entirely different person.</p>
<p>Tzipora and Ayn share a hardship in their infertility despite a desire to have children — Ayn suffered from endometriosis for many decades and is incapable of pregnancy. In all ways, Baron’s reluctant decision to adopt Tzipora was a wonderful blessing — it brought old friends closer together and gave Ayn a daughter. For Tzipora, whose memories of her biological mother were bittersweet and muddied with time, Ayn was a breath of womanhood and light-heartedness in a household that contained only a single hard-working middle-aged man and his teen-age daughter.</p>
<p>Since Baron’s immediate family is dead, Tzipora is close with Ayn’s parents in the North of Vekllei and they’ve taken to her as a granddaughter. Although Ayn and Baron are not married, and may never marry (although Tzipora gauges his response at least once a year), their lives are so thoroughly entwined that it is not uncommon that Baron will return home to Ayn and Tzipora preparing dinner together. In fact, Ayn is the reason Tzipora is such a good cook. Love takes many forms, and Tzipora enjoys several of them.</p>
<p><em>Normal programming will resume presently. Thanks for your patience everyone.</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Brief Introduction to Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/an-introduction/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/an-introduction/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Editor&rsquo;s note: this article, while ready for reading, is still under construction.
Considering both the length and convoluted terminology that embroil this project, there was only so long I could carry on before people started getting lost. The truth of it is that Vekllei is not a particularly complex or difficult project to summarise, despite the snapshot &ldquo;lore in scenes&rdquo; approach that kneecaps a complete understanding. I&rsquo;m just lazy.
In fact, Vekllei is not a particularly challenging idea.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/lola.jpg"/> <p><em>Editor&rsquo;s note: this article, while ready for reading, is still under construction.</em></p>
<p>Considering both the length and convoluted terminology that embroil this project, there was only so long I could carry on before people started getting lost. The truth of it is that Vekllei is not a particularly complex or difficult project to summarise, despite the snapshot &ldquo;lore in scenes&rdquo; approach that kneecaps a complete understanding. I&rsquo;m just lazy.</p>
<p>In fact, Vekllei is not a particularly challenging idea. It is unique, but some days that&rsquo;s about all it has going for it. The word itself — <strong>Vekllei</strong> — refers to both the landscape and the people of an island we know as Iceland. This project looks at that country and its people across a span of about fifty years, mostly between 2070 and 2120. As an alt-history, timelines diverge between our world and theirs in the 1940s, although Vekllei&rsquo;s history is much older.</p>
<p><em>Vekllei is utopia, but Vekllei is not perfect</em>. It is constructed under a framework of <em>utopie concrète</em>, where dreamlike landscapes and characters collide with the dirt and dysfunction of reality. To some people, the contradictions and imperfection of Vekllei society would disqualify it as utopia, especially in an orthodox understanding of the idea, but Western cultural orthodoxy is not the metric used by a Vekllei person.</p>
<p>Vekllei people instead use Vekllei cultural metrics, and to a Vekllei person it is the patina of things — its imperfections and tragedy — that recognise the beauty in life itself, as markers of both existence and usefulness. This cultural intuition is a central tenant of <strong>Upen</strong>, Vekllei&rsquo;s nondenominational animism and universal spirituality.</p>
<p>Simultaneously, Vekllei is undeniably heavenly. It is a gorgeous country of spiritual satisfaction and earnest friendship. Your first day in Vekllei is a dizzying spiritual experience. The weight of the world seems to shift, and then rise off your shoulders. Colour and vitality disentangle themselves from injustice and consumption and pivot to meet you. Food is good and free, strangers are friendly and bursting with lively purposefulness.</p>
<p>Vekllei understands itself as a city-state. This colours a lot of how Vekllei people think of themselves. In practice, there are many distinct &lsquo;cities&rsquo; — the Capital, Little Vekllei, Copette, Ro, Montre and Adouisneh are the largest of them — but they are not recognised as such or federated in Vekllei geographic lexicon. Vekllei is a single continuous neighbourhood, circling nearly the entire coast of their island. Vekllei is also the land on which they sit, which predates the country by millions of years and informs many principles of Upen, which go on to manifest in public policy.</p>
<p>Vekllei cities are almost entirely built according to a single architectural school, <strong>Newda</strong>, which manifests in many different ways but is almost always obviously a flavour of midcentury modernism. Water and concrete define Vekllei cities.</p>
<p>The Vekllei flag is an unornamented purplish red, known as the &lsquo;Domestic Standard&rsquo;. Internationally, they employ a highly decorated flag called the &lsquo;International Standard,&rsquo; which features both the <em>Oa</em> national flower (and omnipresent symbol in every corner of society) and Vekllei logographic script, called <em>Topet</em>.</p>
<p>Vekllei has five language systems, which contribute to the single national language &ndash; also called Vekllei. There is spoken Vekllei,  <strong>Topet</strong> (logographic Vekllei script), <strong>Rapotenne</strong> (name-script), <strong>Vekllei semaphore</strong>, and <strong>Potenne</strong> (hand-talk) or <strong>Upotenne</strong> (spirit-hand-talk). Potenne is a sign language used with or in place of speech, and Upotenne is a way of manifesting physical runes specifically.</p>
<p>Vekllei cities are very colourful, because colour has great meaning. You can construct sentences using only colour and shapes through Vekllei semaphore.</p>
<p>This sort of lifestyle is possible because of Vekllei&rsquo;s abolishment of work, commodity and consumption. In the case of Vekllei, this means that people do not use money and work only for personal benefit, as both ways of actualising themselves and keeping useful or socialising. Not all work is equally difficult or interesting, but everyone must work in fairness. For some, that means as little as a few hours a week copy-editing neighbourhood newsletters. For others, they may work weeks without days off. The consequence of this is that value and products are valueless in any real sense, as post-scarcity relegates the functioning Vekllei economy to autonomous overproduction and waste.</p>
<p>The question of why people work is not an especially difficult one. In Vekllei, where money has not existed for a long time and generations are raised without it, basic premises of motivation have been reconsidered. Life in Vekllei is mostly a largely individual march towards actualisation, through several avenues of pleasure. There is the enjoyment of food and culture, the intimacy of love and marriage, the heritage in family and blood, and the power of work and professional legacy. Only a handful of these contribute to the pleasure of work, but in a society that has mostly done away with menial work through automation and advanced robotics, pleasure is mostly what you make of it. In Vekllei, this is called <strong>Product Socialism</strong>, an inaccurate nominer that describes both the bureau system of work and distribution and Vekllei&rsquo;s fundamental syndicalism. In politics, it is called <strong>Sundress Municipalism</strong>.</p>
<p>The quality of life for almost any other person in today&rsquo;s world, however, has declined slowly by nearly any metric. People are, on average, poorer and hungrier than they were fifty years ago. Various contradictions — in startling contrast to Vekllei&rsquo;s own schisms — have left previously dignified superpowers in disorienting cycles of bloodshed and madness. In the U.S., a large number of confederate states have reasserted their sovereignty following the collapse of the Ford Motor Company and the Northrop corporation. Cultural reforms in Red China have left vast wings of the CCP disatissfied with current leadership, with whispers of a coup. Western Europe has rediscovered her reactionary heritage and indulged in a serious of increasingly authoritarian traditionalist movements, and the export economy of the Soviet Union has collapsed after the shift towards atomic fuels. Vekllei rejects millions of applications for asylum each year.</p>
<p>The circumstance of the world is only made more tragic by the relative peace and stability of Vekllei, and the simplicity and carefree lifestyle of the average Vekllei person. Vekllei has the most flowers per capita of any country in the world. The last fifty years has seen the melting of much of the poles and the the introduction of el nino summers and instant winters that wrack Germany, Austria, Italy, and much of temperate Europe. The Adriatic seems to see more gloom than mediterranean sun these days. The equatorial deserts of the world, Nevada included, are mere degrees away from unsurvivable. With temperatures frequently breaking 50C (125F) throughout the year, it thins the population of Southerners too old or too poor to avoid the heat. North Africa is a husk. There is no water and no food. There is a reason there are mass graves all across the shores of the Black Sea, and why Europe tastes the boot. There is a reason the southern African states are crumbling.</p>
<p>In Vekllei, with her extreme daylight cycles and polar latitude, the weather has improved significantly. Summers are warm enough to host outdoor activities for much of the season and winters are milder than previously, rarely dropping below freezing. Vekllei life, in its insular fashion, has been somewhat improved by the destabilisation of the climate. Lush temperate rainforests cover much of its lowlying basins, and rich volcanic soils spoil agricultural endevour in the warm seasons.</p>
<p>Vekllei&rsquo;s current prosperity has enabled the country to embark on her final project. The benefits of industrialisation and contemporary post-scarcity are employed in a serious effort to reestablish localised, agrarian life built upon the unit of the community.</p>
<p>Vekllei understands the the achievements of industry as a liberationist tool to return to preindustrial, satisfying life. It is not as though the country will abolish three centuries of tremendous progress — quite the contrary, in fact. But understood through petticoat ideology, the marriage of labour and the ordinary person can only occur through self-satisfying, personal work. This is in contrast, one can suppose, to mechanised, industrial labour to which we owe our enormous wealth. To a Vekllei person, work is social, productive, creative and satisfying. The simple pleasures of agriculture; specialised craftsman and tradesman; artistry — these are the fruits only of a society that can afford them, since they necessitate the deindustrialisation of agriculture, factory manufacturing and mass media simultaneously.</p>
<p>So even though Vekllei is by all measures an industrial society; a land of helijets and plenty; the people of this country see automation as the deindustrialisation of society, at least culturally — a return to community employment, decentralised agriculture and tending of the land.</p>
<p>Vekllei is a fundamentally female country. This is what <strong>petticoat society</strong> means. There are plenty of men in it, and quite distinct social constructs for men and women exist in a way that distinguishes the country from traditional progressive projects, but the feminisation of the economy and politics remains. Vekllei economic gender theory understands masculinity as first and foremost a  value to be consumed in industrial society, in a perverse sort of value exchange. Men are first commodified and then broken through work, killed in wars, are suffocated emotionally, and so forth. The very premise of  manhood, as the 1950s understands it (which this world is very much immersed in) is not just a biological or social construct, but an economic one. As Vekllei progresses, and erases these identifiers of masculinity, men will become female first in an economic sense (in a process called economic feminisation), and will eventually become females socially also. These are gender constructs that are essentially still prescribed by traditional Vekllei values, but are tied to the  deindustrialisation of the country. The perfect Vekllei society is one in which the man dies with the machine.</p>
<p>Although Vekllei is not a traditional egalitarian experiment, and is often a land of absurd contradiction in Western political tradition, Vekllei women enjoy a society built for them. Womanhood in the country is not defined by commodity or appearance, but by ideas the culture associates with womanhood — compassion, bravery, intelligence, grace, etc. They are defined not by their relationships or their economic circumstance, but by their friends, political opinions, ability, etc. The decommodification of society has also decommodified womanhood. Vekllei is not simply a good place to be a woman, but is in fact a female country.</p>
<p>Finally, you might have notices a certain set of recurring characters. The girl with short dark hair is Tzipora Desmoines, the character of utopia in this project. Her adoptive father, Baron, is bearded and wears half-framed spectacles. Her friend, Cobian, wears round spectacles and her hair in a ponytail. Their mutual friend, Moise, is heavy-set and has curly hair. Together, they represent a broad demographic of Vekllei people. Baron is descended from Nordic caucasians; vikings from Vekllei&rsquo;s initial settlement. Tzipora and Cobian are descended from both inuits and Scandinavians, in the population explosion that followed Inuit settlement in the Danish territory. Moise is descended from Greek immigrants in the tide of immigration that followed the immediate postwar era. Although there are Vekllei people of colour, they make up a minority of the population.</p>
<p>Hopefully, this guide has helped to introduce you to the world in which Vekllei is situatated. I&rsquo;m likely to expand in the coming days on this section, so stay tuned.</p>
<p>It is a world of nuclear power, gingham and moon colonisation wrapped in the aesthetic of the 50s/60s. There&rsquo;s a lot of poverty and suffering in it, but also tremendous hope. Vekllei is utopia.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The participatory economy of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/participatory-economy/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/participatory-economy/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Nestled between the regional tram offices and the pre-war Ferouistet Department Store, the Lola district is not known for much but her department store and good schools. It sits on the slope of the wide Vekllei capital basin, where the Atlantic can be seen from the street. It was Tzipora&rsquo;s first home in Vekllei, and it was where she lived with her father. The schools were good, the kids were all right, and the trams were a gift from Christ.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://images.millmint.net/square.jpg"/> <p>Nestled between the regional tram offices and the pre-war Ferouistet Department Store, the Lola district is not known for much but her department store and good schools. It sits on the slope of the wide Vekllei capital basin, where the Atlantic can be seen from the street. It was Tzipora&rsquo;s first home in Vekllei, and it was where she lived with her father. The schools were good, the kids were all right, and the trams were a gift from Christ.</p>
<p>Most of Vekllei looks like Lola, marked by her mid-rise streets and public thermal ponds and geyser baths (named after the Vekllei village of Geyser, as it happens). Vekllei people do not generally own cars, and mostly commute via the metro, the exhaustive tram network or on occasion in a loan car from the autopool. The streets are narrow and empty of traffic save for service vehicles, and in the summers they are invaded by neighbourhood children playing baseball or seeking shade under the street trees.</p>
<p>Lola is one of hundreds of neighbourhoods in the vast, densely-populated capital of the country from which it aquires its namesake. It is a city facing its past, now that there is plenty to eat and little to do &ndash; and as a sprawling urban utopia with a fierce nostalgia for preindustrial life, there is no other place like it on Earth. Caught at once between the future of space and helijets, and her collective memories of agriculture and simple labour, Vekllei&rsquo;s petticoat society marks a departure from futurism and a turn to its history, as though the violence and suffering and chaos of the past three centuries were but a chore obstructing utopia.</p>
<h2 id="participatory-economics--property">
  Participatory Economics &amp; Property
  <a class="anchor" href="#participatory-economics--property">#</a>
</h2>
<p>In Vekllei’s feminised parpolity, the revitalisation of <a href="https://vekllei.city/religion/">Upen</a> brought about an ancient understanding of property reborn in the widespread poverty of Vekllei society following <a href="https://vekllei.city/the-forgotten-generation/">the first Atomic War</a>. Widespead social regression and cross-generational nostalgia for preindustrial life took hold in urban Vekllei society almost immediately after the atomic fire, as the ruins of colonial and imperial society lay around the Vekllei people. The monarchy, a tokenistic and fashionable invention of the gilded Mercantile age just three centuries before, evaporated nearly overnight with the death of the king. So, too, did the military junta salivating over the charred remains of the capital find it nearly impossible to consolidate power in a city now without infrastructure. In the ashes of modern industrialisation grew tempered, atomised communities of streets and villages — the common council as we see it today. Food production returned to the city in the ruins of vast factories, wide canals were dug for unmotorised barges, and councils of working people organised self-interest in these communities, which would be understood a century later as <em>Sundress Municipalism</em>. So too did the common understanding of property evaporate.</p>
<p>The old libertarian bugbear of the origins of property was revived — the population had been decimated, Vekllei people were surrounded by vast swaths of useless land of deceased ownership, and the institutions of old society had failed to retake power following the war. The question of ownership was pertinent, as it would clarify the sovereigns of future society. The sovereignty of Vekllei, as it would later be determined, is decentralised and portioned between any land-operating individual, local organisations, municiple councils, and syndicates. This tradition carries on today. In any one apartment building or row-house, you will find the inhabitants, building administrators, local councils and tenant unions exercising types of ownership over a space. In other words; residents of a home will have implied ownership over a home, but a community has implied ownership over the community itself. The intersection of different kinds of ownership result in complex and partially uncoded laws that, although vulnerable to beaurocratic and exhaustive legal disputes, are mostly discarded in place of local opinion.</p>
<p>The foundation of the Vekllei political and economic system is the community; a population larger than a single family and small enough to have valuable social bonds; a group of people bound by common living, work, and recreation. An unruly or criminal tenant is more likely to be run out of town by his neighbours than by the courts. This is not to misrepresent the daily conflicts of Vekllei domestic society — disputes are common and meaningless. But abuse of common ownership is tempered by the fact that it is quite impossible to evict any individual from his home without overwhelming agreement of his neighbours, essentially relegating formal council ownership to irrelevency; the true owners of any single home are, in practice, the community in which it is situated, supervised by protections offered under the local judicial councils.</p>
<p>The ownership of a factory is a lot more straightforward — the old mantra of the democratic workplace is more or less true here. Principally, unautomated (manned) factories recieve production requests from one of the hundreds of different economic bureaus keeping stock of production in the country, which otherwise do not directly supervise production except in circumstance of scarcity. Production requests are voluntary, and usually formalities in the production of items for local consumption. Heavily centralised industries, particularly heavy industries like raw product extraction and refining, usually operate under direct supervision of a bureau. Unions exist independently of the bureau system and usually hold membership from every worker of a factory, including managers. Mirroring nested councils, there are also larger industry unions that generally involve themselves only in general strikes and legal cases without precedent.</p>
<p>The ownership of a grocery store is clear and implied, if not codified. The person who manages and works the shop, either through implied property bonding (so-called ‘folk morality’; a phenomena largely dependent on the person’s social value and local consent) or familial tradition, owns the shop. These are not lawful protections of ownership — indeed, Vekllei common law says very little about senrouive business ownership — but in almost every case, they are validated by a community intuitively. Even antisocial or hostile shop-owners are rarely challenged on their right to the property they manage — the shop is, technically speaking, seen as an extension of the natural landscape (as no more than fired clay and timber), and the live-and-let-live culture in Vekllei is sympathetic to leaving people to their business and shop elsewhere. Legal disputes on the right to live above and manage a store are relatively rare, and usually resolved through ‘blood rights’ ( similar to ‘folk morality’) in the case of an individual or in a more democratic fashion involving multiple relevant complainants, like employees. In both of these examples, the disputed property is considered an entity itself with its own rights and interests extrapolated from its history and surrounding landscape.</p>
<p>Herein remains the distinction between <em>venrouiva</em>/<em>senrouive</em> property, and their implied ownership. <em>Venrouiva</em> usually operate in cooperation with the product bureaus in the case of manufacturing, or other national organisations as their industry requires in education, medicine, power, water, etc. They are ultimately beholden to the direction of the country, as organised by the seats of power and politics. <em>Senrouive</em> exists somewhat independent of the economy entirely, recieving mostly what it asks for and immersing their respective economies in the communities around them. Although all physical material in Vekllei is ultimately property of the country (a vague, naturalistic construct seen as distinct from the government, at least in a Western understanding), <em>senrouive</em>will almost never be managed directly by larger unions or administrative bodies. This distinction does little to articulate public and private ownership, as the very concept of property remains formally unacknowledged in the economy in the country. Instead, all business today is conducted in cooperation with the ideas of community, implied ownership, self-interest and some sort of idea of supply and demand largely usurped by post-scarcity and widespread automation.</p>
<p>Because of this, Vekllei does not actually consider itself classless — Indeed, <em>venrouiva</em> are fundamentally a coordinating class of workers that are atomised from <em>senrouive</em> work through their power and decision-making. They are a class of power in law, education, science, medicine, and politics, and consequently, guide the direction of the country. Although even <em>senrouive</em> business is still fundamentally worker-owned and managed (as part of Sundress Municipalism), this hierarchy remains in principle, even if the quality of life of <em>venrouiva</em> and <em>senrouive</em> workers is in practice identical. This fact is rarely acknowledged outside of technical circles in the country, because it matters very little to the common Vekllei person. Vekllei is not outwardly egalitarian, despite practice, and the problems of power are mitigated by a mess of democratic structures ultimately enslaved to self-interested, independent communities of people. For one of the most centralised countries in the world, with a homogenous ethnic people and culture, Vekllei is better described as hundreds of thousands of hamlets than a single city.</p>
<p><strong>this section is continued on my website:</strong> <a href="https://www.millmint.net"><strong>www.vekllei.city</strong></a><strong>. It&rsquo;s too long for reddit, and so I&rsquo;ll continue work there.</strong></p>
<p><em>you can check my reddit profile (and there&rsquo;s a follow button there now, because reddit is Facebook) for more posts about Vekllei and Tzipora.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.millmint.net/"><em>www.vekllei.city</em></a>  <em>or</em> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/melon.kony/"><em>insta</em></a> <em>fer more. I love questions. tahnk</em></p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
