<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>intro on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/intro/</link>
	<description>Recent content in intro on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>FAQ</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/intro/faq/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/intro/faq/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Hobart&amp;rsquo;s utopia, called Vekllei Why Utopia? # Vekllei is a jumble of very pure, obsessive instincts that are illustrated to make them look and feel real. I want to take purity seriously by considering its implications in the real world. Vekllei does not use money &amp;ndash; a very straightforward and fantastical idea. Of course, moneylessness has extraordinary implications, and to maintain the purity of the idea we have to work very hard.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Characters</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/</guid>
	  <description>߷ This article is about Hobart&amp;rsquo;s characters, who live in Vekllei Tzipora See all stories featuring Tzipora
Tzipora lo Ula de Helette Desmoisnes, often called Zelda by her friends, is the main character of this project. Although born in Vekllei, Tzipora was raised overseas in Colombia and later educated in the United States. Since her arrival in Vekllei, she has formed sincere and long-lasting relationships in her homeland, stabilising the neurotic parts of her personality and blessing her new life with companionship.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Culture</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/</guid>
	  <description> /Utopia/ is the wiki of Vekllei, its Commonwealth, and the features of its society. It also includes articles on the characters I draw regularly. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Essays</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/essays/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/essays/</guid>
	  <description>/Essays/ holds an archive of the things that I (Hobart) have written over the years. I have a background in journalism and media criticism, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t bode well for the quality of the essays linked below. My favourites are Not Long in Hong Kong, an angry reflection on my time in Hong Kong, and A Universal Nostalgia, my honours thesis on utopian spatiality in the films of Studio Ghibli &amp;ndash; mostly used as evidence of my love of Ghibli.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Intro – What is Vekllei?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/intro/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/intro/</guid>
	  <description>This is the Epoch of Rest # ✿ Check out the FAQ These stories are about good places and people. They take place in a fictional state called Vekllei, which is an Atlantic country that does not use money. The point of this project is to take the purity of that idea seriously, and immerse a place of wonder in the real world.
So this is Utopia,
Is it? Well — I beg your pardon;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>MillMint</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/</guid>
	  <description> /News/ is the place for everything going on at Studio MillMint and the Vekllei world-building project. It also includes essays written by author Hobart Phillips relevant to the project, particularly on functional moneylessness and utopie concrète. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Utopia</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/</guid>
	  <description> /Utopia/ is the wiki of Vekllei, its Commonwealth, and the features of its society. It also includes articles on the characters I draw regularly. </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>