<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0">
  <channel>
	<title>intro</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/categories/intro/</link>
	<description>Recent content in intro </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<image>
		<url>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</url>
		<title>intro</title>
		<link>https://millmint.net/stories/</link>
	</image>
	<webfeeds:cover image="https://millmint.net/images/missile.jpg" />
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/categories/intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>FAQ</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/intro/faq/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/intro/faq/</guid>
	  <image>
	  	<url>https://millmint.net/images/drawing.jpg</url>
	  	<title>Illustration</title>
	  </image>
	  <description>
		  <img src="https://millmint.net/images/drawing.jpg"/> 
		  &lt;style&gt;
#article-info .emoji {
    margin-right: 85px;
}
.markdown a {
color: var(--color-red);
}
.markdown a.anchor {
color: var(--color-red);
}
aside nav ul a {
color: var(--color-red);
}
#article-info .emoji {
color: var(--color-red);
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/intro/#three-utopias&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hobart&amp;rsquo;s utopia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-utopia&#34;&gt;
  Why Utopia?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#why-utopia&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is a jumble of very pure, obsessive instincts that are illustrated to make them look and feel real. I want to take purity seriously by considering its implications in the real world. Vekllei does not use money &amp;ndash; a very straightforward and fantastical idea. Of course, moneylessness has extraordinary implications, and to maintain the purity of the idea we have to work very hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplicity is actually very complicated, and so Vekllei is very complicated to justify the simplicity. It&amp;rsquo;s filled with things I value and people I admire. You&amp;rsquo;ll find hundreds of posts and many articles on this site, and all of them are designed to make this place and its people feel real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This place is &lt;strong&gt;iterative&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; canon disappears, people change appearance and the systems of Vekllei twist and turn as I do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This place is &lt;strong&gt;good-spirited&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Vekllei is escapism, and although the dark accompanies the light, this project is supposed to be escapist and fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This place is &lt;strong&gt;constantly expanding&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I try out new styles, mediums and methods of distribution all the time. Some of them work, some of them don&amp;rsquo;t. That&amp;rsquo;s part of the fun of it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei is a utopia&lt;/strong&gt;, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I don&amp;rsquo;t take it seriously or consider its society pragmatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s full of stuff I love&lt;/strong&gt;, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s perfect. Personal growth can come from bad experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I draw in certain styles&lt;/strong&gt;, but Vekllei isn&amp;rsquo;t based off any one country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei is mostly self-contained stories&lt;/strong&gt;, but I experiment with mediums and methods all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;
  F.A.Q.
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#faq&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&#34;who-are-you&#34;&gt;
  Who are you?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#who-are-you&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/about/&#34;&gt;A Tasmanian illustrator.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-is-vekllei-a-utopia&#34;&gt;
  Why is Vekllei a utopia?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#why-is-vekllei-a-utopia&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes me feel better about my life and the world. It’s escapism; it’s a dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;its-a-bit-cringe-to-grandstand-your-political-beliefs-doncha-think&#34;&gt;
  It’s a bit cringe to grandstand your political beliefs, doncha think?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#its-a-bit-cringe-to-grandstand-your-political-beliefs-doncha-think&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is a personal utopia. That’s what I’m selling. At least you’re getting good opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;wheres-the-tension-if-its-perfect&#34;&gt;
  Where’s the tension if it’s perfect?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#wheres-the-tension-if-its-perfect&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei can be cynical and tragic in places. Utopia is more than just idealistic fantasy, and can contain bad things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-there-a-novel-a-story-a-comic&#34;&gt;
  Is there a novel? A story? A comic?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#is-there-a-novel-a-story-a-comic&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m working on a comic right now. I’m pretty much working on Vekllei full-time so I’m hoping to announce it soon. I’ve got a lot of different Vekllei projects going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;where-is-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  Where is Vekllei?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#where-is-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iceland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-your-alt-history-thought-out&#34;&gt;
  Is your alt-history thought out?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#is-your-alt-history-thought-out&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei’s history is whatever I need it to be. I’m always trying to be realistic, but it’s all worked backwards from the setting. I’m not really “world-building” in the way some might understand it. Very little of it is published, most of it is retrieved on request. Just ask if you have questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-does-vekllei-call-itself-petticoat-socialist&#34;&gt;
  Why does Vekllei call itself “petticoat socialist”?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#why-does-vekllei-call-itself-petticoat-socialist&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is set in a culture of Marxist revivalism in the 50s and 60s. A lot of Vekllei’s lexicon is set in that context. Vekllei is a decentralised democracy that doesn’t use money. It’s a sort of participatory economy. It&amp;rsquo;s almost anarchic in that sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-the-petticoat&#34;&gt;
  Why the &amp;ldquo;petticoat&amp;rdquo;?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#why-the-petticoat&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is a female country. Womanhood is decommodified. It&amp;rsquo;s maternal, social and friendly where progressive utopian rhetoric is masculine, technocratic and historicist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;who-is-zelda&#34;&gt;
  Who is Zelda?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#who-is-zelda&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zelda is another name for &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/&#34;&gt;Tzipora&lt;/a&gt;. She has two names specifically to confuse you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/vekllei&#34;&gt;Join the Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dCE6vSU&#34;&gt;Join the Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be &amp;ldquo;petticoat&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;futher-reading&#34;&gt;
  Futher Reading
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#futher-reading&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those curious about what sort of things go into a place like Vekllei, these are some of my favourite books. I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked about them before, so I&amp;rsquo;ve included this section in the hopes you enjoy them as much as I have. There are many more than these, so if you&amp;rsquo;re interested, &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/about/&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll update this list periodically as more occur to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the Origins of Modern Japanese Literature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karatani Kojin&lt;/strong&gt; | 1993&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karatani interrogates the appearance of Western conceptual artefacts (Landscape, The Child, Interiority) during the Meiji period in Japan. This book had a tremendous impact on my assumptions about the world and affected Vekllei tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting Point &lt;em&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/em&gt; Turning Point&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miyazaki Hayao&lt;/strong&gt; | 2009 &amp;amp; 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These books are essentially a compilation of essays from Miyazaki&amp;rsquo;s years as a filmmaker. He&amp;rsquo;s an incredibly smart and insightful creative force whose work &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/news/essays/ghibli&#34;&gt;I have written at length about&lt;/a&gt; before. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s all really powerful, affecting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three Faces of Utopianism Revisited&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lyman Sargent&lt;/strong&gt; | 1994&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the defining taxonomical look at the phenomena of utopianism and how it works. His breakdown of &amp;lsquo;utopia&amp;rsquo; into both dystopian and eutopian elements is also my preffered descriptor and use of &amp;lsquo;utopia&amp;rsquo; as a concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Towards a New Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Le Corbusier&lt;/strong&gt; | 1936&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is a postmodern mess, but also deeply sympathetic to the modernist instinct. I like the utopianism of the 20th Century, and Le Corbusier typifies that &amp;lsquo;utopian&amp;rsquo; futurism we saw in that period. I like how single-minded he is about it. His buildings remain beautiful, many years on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Characters</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/</guid>
	  <image>
	  	<url>https://millmint.net</url>
	  	<title>Illustration</title>
	  </image>
	  <description>
		  <img src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint &#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/intro/#three-utopias&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hobart&amp;rsquo;s characters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who live in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!--&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Although almost all characters&lt;/strong&gt; in this project were born in Vekllei, they are of vastly different heritages and backgrounds. A study of modern Vekllei is a study of immigration. Most characters here have swirling ethnic, religious and cultural histories aiding and obscuring their destinies. This is useful, because if you&amp;rsquo;re following along with this project, you&amp;rsquo;re in some small way an immigrant yourself. It&amp;rsquo;s through the eyes of these people that you see Vekllei, and their lives contribute to the utopian dimensions of this project as utopias-of-living.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
--&gt;




&lt;div class=&#34;tabs&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;toggle&#34; name=&#34;tabs-characters&#34; id=&#34;tabs-characters-0&#34; checked=&#34;checked&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;tabs-characters-0&#34;&gt;Tzipora&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;tabs-content&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;smallimg&#34; alt=&#34;picture of Tzipora&#34; style=&#34;background-color: transparent;&#34; src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/mastheads/characters/archived/zelda.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/tzipora&#34;&gt;See all stories featuring Tzipora&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tzipora lo Ula de Helette Desmoisnes&lt;/strong&gt;, often called &lt;strong&gt;Zelda&lt;/strong&gt; by her friends, is the main character of this project. Although born in Vekllei, Tzipora was raised overseas in Colombia and later educated in the United States. Since her arrival in Vekllei, she has formed sincere and long-lasting relationships in her homeland, stabilising the neurotic parts of her personality and blessing her new life with companionship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;
  Appearance
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#appearance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is blue-eyed and black-haired of mixed Eastern European Jewish and Spanish Romani heritage. She has a round head and a big smile, and is naturally athletic. She parts her short hair in the centre and ornaments it with fountain hairpieces, traditional hair loops and floral assemblies depending on the occasion. She is a victim of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/&#34;&gt;Gregori-Heitzfeld Disease&lt;/a&gt;, which affects her quality of life and contributes to her isolation from other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She dresses in conservative fashions and has maintained a consistent taste throughout her life. She has a preference for loose-fitting clothing, particularly buttoned shirts, slacks and skirts of various styles. She is most commonly seen in a pleated white shirt, modest skirt, folded socks and penny loafers or sandals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;
  Personality
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#personality&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is nonconformist by way of ignorance or obstinance depending on the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is paranoid and conservative, good-natured and austere, with a moral outlook bound by her deepest anxieties and obsessions. She is deeply spiritual and material, fascinated with objects and their history. She has many collections of many things she’s found. She’ll likely die a Catholic, but has a confrontational relationship with God and no longer attends mass. She has Jewish ancestry and struggles to reconcile the fractured parts of her family history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora may be intense and inward-facing, but she can also be disarmingly charming and self-deprecating. She has a good sense of humour. There are not many girls that can so easily reconcile the contradictions between the peculiar and the healthy, the eccentric and the friendly, and the violent and the domestic. That’s part of her character — an essence of being that radiates decency, good taste and a respect for the spirit of all things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;toggle&#34; name=&#34;tabs-characters&#34; id=&#34;tabs-characters-1&#34;  /&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;tabs-characters-1&#34;&gt;Cobian&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;tabs-content&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;smallimg&#34; alt=&#34;picture of Cobian&#34; style=&#34;background-color: transparent;&#34; src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/mastheads/characters/cobian.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/cobian&#34;&gt;See all stories featuring Cobian&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cobian lo Ro de Viviya de Queismesnah&lt;/strong&gt; is Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s longtime friend and occasional girlfriend. Conservative in manner and appearance, Cobian is easily remembered by her circular spectacles and stern fringe, styles maintained since childhood. Tzipora and Cobian met during secondary schooling in Vekllei, and remained close throughout the rest of their lives. She is very close with Tzipora, but has tepid relationships with Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s (mostly male) friendship group out of jealousy and a general distaste for boys. She is rigorously polite in the middle-class sense of the word; formal among strangers, gossipy among friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;
  Appearance
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#appearance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian is green-eyed and black-haired, descended mostly from Inuit-Scandinavian ethnic groups common in Vekllei. She is more Asiatic in appearance than her friend Zelda, and is tall for her age. She styles her long hair in many different ways, most commonly in a bun or braids. She is healthy but inactive, and tans easily without freckling. Cobian is naturally graceful and well-mannered, traits Tzipora is deeply envious of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She dresses in prim, well-maintained clothing courtesy of her despotically hygienic mother, and has a penchant for ironed shirts, pleatless skirts, cute hats, synthetic hosiery and jewellery she considers befitting a maturing young woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;
  Personality
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#personality&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Tzipora meets her, Cobian is a figure of sympathy and irritation. She was deeply insecure after old friendships fell apart in the tumultuous transition between middle and secondary schooling. Once she became comfortable around her new friend and matured out of some old insecurities, Cobian revealed herself to be easy-going and friendly, a person of small pretensions and genuine friendship. In her own skin, she makes an excellent conversationalist, charmingly attentive and ready to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people think she&amp;rsquo;s pretentious; she&amp;rsquo;s not pretentious. She likes good food and is highly fashionable in her interests and styles, but Cobian is also deeply empathetic and finds interest in new things via her friends she&amp;rsquo;d never previously thought about. She makes up most of Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s social life, which leaves plenty of space for Zelda&amp;rsquo;s big personality and obsessions. Zelda has a deeply stablising effect on Cobian, rounding out some of her mother&amp;rsquo;s strict legacy through Zelda&amp;rsquo;s androgynous habits and far-fetched fascinations. But Zelda&amp;rsquo;s big personality does not include much talking or grace, and in these deficiencies Cobian&amp;rsquo;s social talent shines. Together they make a great pair, their neighbouring personalities aiding their best selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;toggle&#34; name=&#34;tabs-characters&#34; id=&#34;tabs-characters-2&#34;  /&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;tabs-characters-2&#34;&gt;Moise&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;tabs-content&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;smallimg&#34; alt=&#34;picture of Moise&#34; style=&#34;background-color: transparent;&#34; src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/mastheads/characters/moise.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/moise&#34;&gt;See all stories featuring Moise&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moise ra Hasapis&lt;/strong&gt; is Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s neighbour and best friend. Like Tzipora, he was born overseas and has only started schooling in Vekllei in late childhood. Imposing in both attitude and posture, Moise is feared and respected among his peers, an unfortunate social situation that enables his renowned temper. An agitator and victim of his troubles, Moise is tempered by Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s inwardness and Coretti&amp;rsquo;s good-naturedness. He lives with his sister and father in Seispri, and deeply despises his mother, who remains in Greece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;
  Appearance
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#appearance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise is brown-eyed and dark-haired, with powerful Greek features inherited from his parents. Well-built and heavy-set, Moise is overweight when he meets Tzipora, and loses some of it through her help in exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is not particularly interested in his own appearance, but by habit or luck is characterised by a wardrobe of shorts, slacks, bright shirts and tennis shoes. In summer, he usually wears Hawaiian shirts, a fact Tzipora finds funny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;
  Personality
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#personality&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise is hot-headed and sensitive, traits that leave him feeling cornered by the world. It is precisely this cycle of passion and anxiety that endears him to Tzipora, who recognises his feelings in herself. Tzipora is dependent on his male perspective and relative straightforwardness, compared to Cobian&amp;rsquo;s more intricate and unspoken social rituals &amp;ndash; the distinction between true mateship and true love, she supposes. Moise, for his part, admires Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s sincerity and plainspokenness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He dislikes his parents and is protective over his younger sister, Penelope. He has some interest in making films, since he is not particularly academic and doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to leave his sister for the army. He is uncomfortable with sharing his emotions, which upsets his girlfriend Coretti. Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s social intimacy with him is largely due to their similar shyness of emotion and stubborn independence, which counterintuitively binds them closely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;toggle&#34; name=&#34;tabs-characters&#34; id=&#34;tabs-characters-3&#34;  /&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;tabs-characters-3&#34;&gt;Coretti&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;tabs-content&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;smallimg&#34; alt=&#34;picture of Coretti&#34; style=&#34;background-color: transparent;&#34; src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/mastheads/characters/coretti.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/coretti&#34;&gt;See all stories featuring Coretti&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coretti lo Rus de Gloria Adoula&lt;/strong&gt; is Moise&amp;rsquo;s girlfriend. Born in the Congo, she lived in Russia before moving to Vekllei at 6 years old, and speaks Vekllei fluently. She is sensitive and diplomatic, and is well-liked for her impartiality. As her relationship with Moise develops, so too does she grow closer with Tzipora and her friends. Although her relative maturity can distance her on occasion, her unprejudiced curiosity and social grace are traits Tzipora loves, and they bond closely over their shared taste in art and music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;
  Appearance
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#appearance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti is Vekllei-Congolese with dark skin and natural, short hair. She is slim, authentically pretty and graceful &amp;ndash; and has many admirers for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is not particularly fashionable and does not need to be. This modesty enhances her natural charisma. Like Tzipora, she has some affection for &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-07-21-fashion/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nuova Grotessco&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; styles and unpretentious blouses and pinafores. She likes patterned clothing and owns many types, which she rotates regularly &amp;ndash; perhaps her only eccentricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;
  Personality
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#personality&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coretti&amp;rsquo;s gentle good-naturedness leaves powerful impressions on all her meet her. She is the oldest of four sisters, and she applies these learned maternal qualities on her boyfriend&amp;rsquo;s volatile friends, who are deeply passionate and opinionated. Her goodness does not preclude her from her own pleasures &amp;ndash; she adores music and good food, and unlike Lin Zhi, is more than willing to share the culture of her home country with her friends. She loves when gestures are reciprocated &amp;ndash; among her favourite memories is Tzipora showing her how to cook her childhood Colombian staples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite her apparent differences in temperament with her boyfriend Moise, Coretti spends more time around vibrant hotheads than she does placid appeasers. Perhaps this is a behaviour legacy of growing up in a large, loud family. Maybe she is just attracted to big personalities. Either way, they appreciate her for it &amp;ndash; her voice of reason brings them all closer together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;radio&#34; class=&#34;toggle&#34; name=&#34;tabs-characters&#34; id=&#34;tabs-characters-4&#34;  /&gt;
  &lt;label for=&#34;tabs-characters-4&#34;&gt;Lin Zhi&lt;/label&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;tabs-content&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;smallimg&#34; alt=&#34;picture of Lin Zhi&#34; style=&#34;background-color: transparent;&#34; src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/mastheads/characters/zhi.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;button href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/zhi&#34;&gt;See all stories featuring Lin Zhi&lt;/button&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lin Zhi&lt;/strong&gt;, who prefers being addressed by her full name, is Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s friend and occasional accomplice. She is the perfect ally of Tzipora, indulging her most passionate (and self-destructive) instincts, and they remain good friends all their lives. Like Tzipora, Zhi is a recent immigrant and terrified of life in Vekllei, from which she has retreated into traditionally Chinese cultural signals and behaviours. Tzipora is fascinated and deeply curious about her. Cobian and Coretti fear her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;
  Appearance
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#appearance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lin Zhi is Chinese and has lived in Vekllei since she was 15. She has a serious face and round spectacles like Cobian, and brushes her long dark hair back. She maintains two unusual hair loops below her ears in braids, a style she has apparently invented herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lin Zhi resents the burden of integration and demonstrates her foreignness through foreign styles, usually with traditional Chinese items or more contemporary Maoist fare. She wears loose Ku-style pants at home and school, which bear close similarity to Vekllei indigenous &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-11-mist/&#34;&gt;rouisha&lt;/a&gt; trousers, usually with Vekllei or Chinese strap slippers. She has a weakness for jackets and cardigans, and never leaves her arms uncovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;
  Personality
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#personality&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lin Zhi is a girl under siege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora first bonds with her over their social isolation as recent immigrants. Like Tzipora, Zhi speaks poor Vekllei and is deeply resentful of having to relocate to a foreign country. These poor language skills and deep anger are evident in her short, sharp speaking style and stern appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is sensitive to being made fun of, and considers many of her problems making friends to be racial in nature. Despite these emotional burdens, or perhaps because of them, Zhi is deeply loyal to her allies as long as they respect her social boundaries. Zhi is never the engine of conversation &amp;ndash; she&amp;rsquo;s just happy to be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
a.article-button {
  margin-top: 0;
  border: 1px solid var(--color-yellow);
  //background-color: rgba(255, 43, 78, 0.25);
  //color: var(--font-color);
  color: var(--color-yellow);
  }
article h5 {
  margin-top: 1rem;
}

.section {
    opacity: 1!important;
  }

.section p {
    opacity: 0.85;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Culture</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/culture/</guid>
	  <image>
	  	<url>https://millmint.net</url>
	  	<title>Illustration</title>
	  </image>
	  <description>
		  <img src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/Utopia/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the wiki of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;, its Commonwealth, and the features of its society. It also includes articles on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/&#34;&gt;characters&lt;/a&gt; I draw regularly.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Essays</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/essays/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/essays/</guid>
	  <image>
	  	<url>https://millmint.net</url>
	  	<title>Illustration</title>
	  </image>
	  <description>
		  <img src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/essays/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/Essays/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; holds an archive of the things that I (&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/about/&#34;&gt;Hobart&lt;/a&gt;) have written over the years. I have a background in journalism and media criticism, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t bode well for the quality of the essays linked below. My favourites are &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/hong-kong/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not Long in Hong Kong&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an angry reflection on my time in Hong Kong, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/ghibli/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Universal Nostalgia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, my honours thesis on utopian spatiality in the films of Studio Ghibli &amp;ndash; mostly used as evidence of my love of Ghibli.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Intro – What is Vekllei?</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/intro/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/intro/</guid>
	  <image>
	  	<url>https://millmint.net</url>
	  	<title>Illustration</title>
	  </image>
	  <description>
		  <img src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;h2 id=&#34;this-is-the-epoch-of-rest&#34;&gt;
  This is the Epoch of Rest
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#this-is-the-epoch-of-rest&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint millmint&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/intro/faq&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These stories are about good places and people&lt;/strong&gt;. They take place in a fictional state called &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;, which is an Atlantic country that does not use money. The point of this project is to take the purity of that idea seriously, and immerse a place of wonder in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is Utopia,&lt;br&gt;
Is it? Well — &lt;br&gt;
I beg your pardon;&lt;br&gt;
I thought it was Hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Max Beerbohm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Immersing&amp;rsquo; something in the real world means things get dirty, break, and fall apart. A utopia doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be perfect, but it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be an authentic &amp;lsquo;social dream&amp;rsquo;. This style of world-building is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/news/essays/utopie/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;utopie concrète&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and is the way Vekllei is built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I define the broad, general phenomenon of utopianism as social dreaming &amp;ndash; the dreams and nightmares that concern the ways in which groups of people arrange their lives and which usually envision a radically different society than the one in which the dreamers live. But not all are radical, for some people at any time dream of something basically familiar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Lyman Sargent &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the gist of it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; is a fictional country that demonstrates good things through drawing and writing about it. It&amp;rsquo;s part-escapism, part-fantasy, and all good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is a comprehensive archive and open notebook for the stories of Vekllei and its people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Studio MillMint&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;millmint.net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/utopia/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an online wiki of Vekllei its people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/millmint/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/millmint/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is for everything outside of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/stories/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is for illustrated snapshots of life in Vekllei&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-vekllei&#34;&gt;
  What is Vekllei?
  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-is-vekllei&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint millmint&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;✿ Main article: &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No differently will the world one day appear, almost unchanged, in its constant feast-day light, when it stands no longer under the law of labour, and when for homecomers duty has the lightness of holiday play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;–Theodor Adorno, &lt;em&gt;Minima Moralia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; (pronounced &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;Veck-lie&lt;/strong&gt;,&amp;rsquo; or &lt;strong&gt;/vƐk.laɪ/&lt;/strong&gt;) is an island country set in what we know as Iceland. Vekllei is its own country, and does not look or feel like Iceland. It has unique cultures, ethnicites, and landscapes. It is an old country, having been settled for thousands of years by native Algic peoples and Scandinavians. It is also a new county, having suffered a nuclear attack at the beginning of the 21st Century which extinguished much of its old civil society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the mid-21st century, Vekllei has become a remarkable place. Quality of life is excellent and living there is unlike living anywhere else on Earth. The country is an ambitious expression of alternate modes of thinking, visible in every aspect of society, from its bizarre moneyless economy to its complicated cultural and religious metaphysics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some quick facts about Vekllei and the state of the world in the mid-21st Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei takes place in a fictional retrofuture, where some technologies have advanced in different ways. Most &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/society/technology/computers/&#34;&gt;computers in Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; are centralised, connected to via terminals. In this sense, they are both more and less advanced than contemporary personal computing. In other technologies, like aerospace, the world is undeniably more advanced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s future retains the cold war from the previous century. The U.S.S.R. stiill exists, as do emerging political divisions across Europe, Africa, South America and Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s future remains heavily influenced by midcentury modernist styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s unique history has influenced its region for thousands of years, most major diversions from our own timeline occur shortly after the Second World War.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/stories/&#34;&gt;So get going&lt;/a&gt;. This website is an open notebook of the thing I love. If you like world-building, art, and strange corners of the web, you&amp;rsquo;ll find something to like here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
/* flags */
.row {
  display: flex;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
}
.column {
  flex: 33.33%;
  padding: 5px;
}
@media (max-width: 1250px) {
  .row {
    display: none;
  }
}
a, body article a {
  color: var(--color-millmint);
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sargent, L.T., 1994. The Three Faces of Utopianism Revisited. &lt;em&gt;Utopian studies&lt;/em&gt;, 5(1), p.3.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>MillMint</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/millmint/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/millmint/</guid>
	  <image>
	  	<url>https://millmint.net</url>
	  	<title>Illustration</title>
	  </image>
	  <description>
		  <img src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/millmint/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/MillMint/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the place for everything going on at Studio MillMint and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; world-building project. It also includes essays written by author Hobart Phillips relevant to the project, particularly on &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/news/essays/moneylessness/&#34;&gt;functional moneylessness&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/news/essays/utopie/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;utopie concrète&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Utopia</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/</guid>
	  <image>
	  	<url>https://millmint.net</url>
	  	<title>Illustration</title>
	  </image>
	  <description>
		  <img src="https://millmint.net"/> 
		  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/Utopia/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the wiki of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;, its Commonwealth, and the features of its society. It also includes articles on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/&#34;&gt;characters&lt;/a&gt; I draw regularly.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	  </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
