<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Society on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Society on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Armed Forces</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;national-intelligence-in-vekllei&#34;&gt;National Intelligence in Vekllei&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;americas-bureau&#34;&gt;Americas Bureau&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/gregori/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/gregori/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gregori-Heitzfeld Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Starred Article&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This article is complete. It was last updated in July 2020.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint yellow&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Under Construction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This page is still under construction, and may be incomplete.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;-the-people-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;📜 The People of Vekllei&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-introduction&#34;&gt;1. Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei language&lt;/strong&gt;, abbreviated to just &lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, has six core sublanguages that are used commonly today. Although they often intersect, these different systems of communication are distinct languages in their own right, used for different purposes in different arenas of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Language Systems in Vekllei&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoken Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, which is everyday spoken language. It draws from two glossaries with different meanings and feelings, called &lt;em&gt;Oa&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Loh&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topet&lt;/strong&gt;, which are logographic characters (occasionally characterised as hieroglyphs). Like other pictographic languages, &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; characters can be broken down into repeating components, called &lt;em&gt;Topotte&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/strong&gt;, is the traditional logographic language of names. It is much older than Topet, and has more in common with spiritual runes than modern logography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potenne&lt;/strong&gt;, lit. “&lt;em&gt;Hand-Talk&lt;/em&gt;”, is a sign language that incorporates gestures and signing to add meaning to emotion to spoken language, and occasionally in place of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upotenne&lt;/strong&gt;, lit. “&lt;em&gt;Spirit-Hand-Talk&lt;/em&gt;”, as the recreation of runes in human form, used limitedly in spiritual ritual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/strong&gt; is the codification of colour and shape. Traditionally limited to colour, shape and pattern are now also included in &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/em&gt;, in which full sentences can be formed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-language&#34;&gt;2. Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look in more detail about how each aspect of the Vekllei language operates in daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;21-spoken-vekllei&#34;&gt;2.1 Spoken Vekllei&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoken Vekllei draws from two glossaries, called &lt;em&gt;Oa&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Loh&lt;/em&gt;. These glossaries date back to the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;221-oa&#34;&gt;2.2.1 Oa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oa&lt;/em&gt; is considered to have &amp;lsquo;permenant&amp;rsquo; traits. It is often characterised abroad as a positive glossary, though this is not true &amp;ndash; it is in fact dedicated to inanimate and unliving organs. It is gendered as masculine, and is associated with Summer and Spring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;222-loh&#34;&gt;2.2.2 Loh&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loh&lt;/em&gt; is considered to have &amp;lsquo;cyclical&amp;rsquo; traits. This includes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;22-topet&#34;&gt;2.2 Topet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;23-rapotenne&#34;&gt;2.3 Rapotenne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;24-potenne&#34;&gt;2.4 Potenne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;25-upotenne&#34;&gt;2.5 Upotenne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;26-vekllei-semaphore&#34;&gt;2.6 Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-history&#34;&gt;3. History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-application&#34;&gt;4. Application&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Currency</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.markdown a {
color: var(--color-orange);
}
.markdown a.anchor {
color: var(--color-orange);
}
aside nav ul a {
color: var(--color-orange);
}
#headerbox .emoji {
color: var(--color-orange);
}
.markdown a:visited {
color: var(--color-orange);
}
/* coins */
.row {
    display: flex;
    margin-left: auto;
    margin-right: auto;
  }

.column {
  flex: 33.33%;
  padding: 5px;
}
@media (max-width: 1250px) {
    .row {
    display: none;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34;&gt;The National Mint of Vekllei&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;-load8&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 span class=&#34;tag orange&#34;&gt; SOCIETY &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6 span class=&#34;sitetag&#34;&gt;Article&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul class=&#34;breadcrumb&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a style = &#34;font-weight: 800;&#34; href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/&#34;&gt;MillMint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utopia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Society&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;color: var(--color-orange);&#34; href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mint/&#34;&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint orange&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; society
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint orange&#34;&gt;
  ❖ This article is &lt;strong&gt;awaiting illustrations&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-overview&#34;&gt;1. Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The National Mint of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; is shrouded in mystery, since its use as a producer of coins in a country without money seems obscure. As is the case in many of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s State Requisites (A.r.), its purpose and structure is both uniquely Vekllei and thoroughly obtuse, two facts addressed here in this article.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he National Mint of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;Mint&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Mint A.r.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; within the country, is sole producer of coins and government bonds in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the sole proprietor of its domestic gold bullion reserve. It is a civilian state requisite responsible for physical money supply of Vekllei, which it continues to mint in the moneyless Floral Period as souvenirs (and, internationally, legal tender). It also serves as the primary printing facility for Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s Government Bank, the country&amp;rsquo;s Central Bank and regulator of money supply in both Vekllei and Government Crowns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mint is among Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s oldest institutions, founded as a successor to the Port of Vekllei Mint in 1386. It is headquartered in the Nation Mint Complex in the Gold District of Vekllei Proper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mint is an executive government agency directly operated by the Vekllei Government, signalling its responsibility to Vekllei society rather than the Land Sovereign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;The National Mint of Vekllei&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Vekllei Government&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Mint of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Royal Mail Press
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the Mail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Materials Manufacturie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Services Bureau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gold Security Bureau
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fraud Investigation Unit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venrouive Gold Sappers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HO/NI Gold Detachment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-coinage&#34;&gt;2. Coinage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint orange&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/&#34;&gt;The Vekllei Crown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The Royal Mail&lt;/strong&gt; maintains a constitutionally-bound monopoly on all postage in the country, leaving it the sole provider of universal postage service in Vekllei. Like most State Requisites (A.r.), however, it has substantial international trade and foreign dealings that provide for its common description as a state-owned for-profit enterprise, or public corporation.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;U&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;niversal service&lt;/strong&gt; is, by the glossary of the Mail, truly universal. As mandated by Vekllei law, the Mail provides delivery for all postage material anywhere in the world, or indeed, beyond it. It maintains 6,424 post offices across Vekllei, including its antarctic and peripheral possessions. The Mail&amp;rsquo;s first Lunar Post Office opened in 2059. In addition to its domestic monopoly, the Mail contributes nearly VK❦2.6 trillion each year towards the Vekllei Government Securities Bureau (the country&amp;rsquo;s sovereign wealth fund) through its international postage and courier services abroad, under the name World Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Mail&amp;rsquo;s Office of Telecommunications is also responsible for all telephones, telegrams and videophones in the country, the Mail&amp;rsquo;s status as a lynchpin of communication is absolute, and heavily protected by the postwar Vekllei constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vekllei-crowns&#34;&gt;Vekllei Crowns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mastheads/coins/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;coin&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mastheads/coins/10.png&#34; alt=&#34;coin&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mastheads/coins/50.png&#34; alt=&#34;coin&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mastheads/coins/100.png&#34; alt=&#34;coin&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mastheads/coins/200.png&#34; alt=&#34;coin&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mastheads/coins/500.png&#34; alt=&#34;coin&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mastheads/coins/1000.png&#34; alt=&#34;coin&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei Crowns minted as of the 21st Century, produced by the Mint as souvenirs | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/&#34;&gt;The Vekllei Crown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail aims to provide next-day delivery during weekdays in zero-code (that is to say, &lt;em&gt;Home Island&lt;/em&gt;) regions. Overnight delivery is also generally available between &lt;em&gt;Home Islands&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Aismious&lt;/em&gt; Islands, &lt;em&gt;Kala&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Azores&lt;/em&gt; during weekdays. Most Lunar territories are available on Mondays and Fridays, and other territories are available according to the Mail&amp;rsquo;s region table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei people do not pay to post items, stamps are affixed with coloured squares called &lt;em&gt;chromacodes&lt;/em&gt; which are used in the automatic sorting machines common in the country. International Mail uses traditional stamps with price listed, and the Vekllei Crown displayed. Franking is used for tracking and identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;gold-bullion&#34;&gt;Gold Bullion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;government-crowns&#34;&gt;Government Crowns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special, commercial and industrial postage is managed within the &lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt; through special sorting facilities and a dedicated postal network. Regular business postage is funnelled through regular daily service, but hazardous, oversized and dangerous goods are accepted by special Post Offices designed to accept them. The Mail does not provide special services for regular residential or courier delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail is best known overseas as the &lt;strong&gt;World Post&lt;/strong&gt;, which offers services for foreign clients and has established itself as one of the Big Four international transnational courier services in the world today. Similar to domestic postal systems in other countries, the World Post offers flat rates for delivery anywhere in the world, priced according to size and weight. In addition, sister company &lt;strong&gt;Universal Express&lt;/strong&gt; offers next-day weekday delivery in certain markets. Most employees of the World Post and Universal Express are foreign workers banking labour-hours for immigration to Vekllei. Unlike domestic service, the World Post and Universal Express use private courier contracts extensively to fulfil orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finance&#34;&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is easily accessible via the Mail&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Financial Services Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;. Although inaccessible within the country, savings can be withdrawn conditionally upon emigration, and the Mail offers easy access and financial counselling for Vekllei people. Through the Financial Services Bureau, the Mail also offers financial management to immigrant populations with wealth transfer (the phrase for banking of savings and prior income) and Overseas Accounting, commonly used to send money to family abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-operations&#34;&gt;3. Operations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/manufacturie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint orange&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/&#34;&gt;Gold Sappers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;As a military organ&lt;/strong&gt;, the Mail A.r. retains military ranks for its staff, commanded by a Postmaster General and aided by a civilian regulator designed to keep its critical service available to Vekllei people. The Mail&amp;rsquo;s fleet includes dedicated jets, automatic trucks, mail trains, intercity pneumatic systems, vehicle automen, and postmen, all wearing the red and gold colours of the organisation. In total, the Mail delivers nearly 50 million pieces of mail during weekdays.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;t is evident&lt;/strong&gt; that the services assigned to the Mail by the postwar constitution are of critical importance to the stability of Vekllei society. In addition to being one of the oldest active postal organisations in the world, the Royal Mail of Vekllei is tremendously busy, since physical post has scarcely been displaced by the telephone in the country. Even without the Mail&amp;rsquo;s international postage, domestic mail each day can exceed 12 million pieces &amp;ndash; enough for 1 in 2 people, though commercial mail and periodicals are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is typical for critical bureaus in Vekllei, the Mail alleviates the stress of daily service through its dense, vertically-integrated infrastructure aided by automatic (automen vehicles) and permanent fixtures (pneumatic systems and automatic sorting/franking machines). It is precisely this commitment to infrastructure that makes the Mail so visible in daily life, and contributes to its ongoing legacy as Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s oldest running government institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;staff&#34;&gt;Staff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/sappers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  Illustration of Gold Sappers, the Venopor police detachment responsible to the Mint | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/&#34;&gt;Gold Sappers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail employs 48,960 people full-time across its various offices, and nearly 200,000 automen in various roles. Although the Mail does retain a staff of postmen and couriers, most urban daily service is now provided by automatic vehicles and sorting, which account for nearly half of the total automen owned by the organisation. Instead, the majority of Mail employees are involved in the running of the organisation &amp;ndash; mostly as clerks, managers, and administrators. Around 10,000 postmen are employed by the Mail in daily delivery, called &amp;ldquo;posties&amp;rdquo;. There are around 8,000 postal routes in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although at first glance the number of automen dramatically exceeds demand, the total count is misleading &amp;ndash; most automen with the Mail are integrated into the infrastructure of its sorting centres and post offices, and very few are traditionally autonomous robots commonly seen in public in Vekllei. Only about 8,000 automen are employed in physical mail delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 16,220 post boxes in Vekllei, which are iconic for their red and gold paint and intricate detailing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleet&#34;&gt;Fleet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint orange&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/&#34;&gt;The Fairie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail retains a large and diverse fleet of vehicles in regular operations, which, due to their diversity and and expense, have become iconic around the world. From bicycles to space planes, the Mail&amp;rsquo;s fleet of vehicles rivals in diversity postal services three times its size, largely benefitted by Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s obfuscated budgeting system and cultural importance afforded to the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table lists company vehicles relevant to regular postal service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;The Royal Mail Fleet&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8,000 delivery automen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5,200 motorcycles &lt;em&gt;(mostly Local Electric Model 15 &amp;amp; Phantoms)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,400 bicycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,000 automatic vans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;400 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;31 mail boats &lt;em&gt;(MBR)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 mail flying boats &lt;em&gt;(Model 54 &amp;ldquo;Fairie&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 mail helijets &lt;em&gt;(Model RM/Gisma &amp;amp; Record types)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 mail trains &lt;em&gt;(RM Series/Series 225 EMU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 mail trams &lt;em&gt;(Series T6)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail space planes &lt;em&gt;(G.A. Type 1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail ships &lt;em&gt;(RMS&lt;/em&gt; Atlantic &lt;em&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/em&gt; Sunburst &lt;em&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overseas Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Post Company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;250 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;52 cargo jets &lt;em&gt;(Model RM/Type 56C)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 flying boats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Express Company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cargo jets &lt;em&gt;(Model ERM/C.A. Type 6 supersonic)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Postmistress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 executive mail train &lt;em&gt;(Series 4000 EMU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A.r.&lt;/em&gt; is a shortening of &lt;em&gt;state requisite&lt;/em&gt; (A.r., or requoisesiasn amourisocietie)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (often called the &lt;em&gt;Government Bank&lt;/em&gt;) is Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s social bank, and each Vekllei person is entitled to an equal share of it.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economy</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.markdown a {
color: var(--color-red);
}
.markdown a.anchor {
color: var(--color-red);
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Economics in Vekllei&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;emoji&#34;&gt;🪙&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 span class=&#34;tag red&#34;&gt; ARTICLE &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6 span class=&#34;sitetag&#34;&gt;Documents&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/momentsinlove.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint yellow&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-overview&#34;&gt;1. Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The economy of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; is a sparkling jewel of its crown of contradictions, and totally unique in the world today.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;V&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ekllei language&lt;/strong&gt;, abbreviated to just &lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, has six core sublanguages that are used commonly today. Although they often intersect, these different systems of communication are distinct languages in their own right, used for different purposes in different arenas of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Systems of Language&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoken Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, which is everyday spoken language. It draws from two glossaries with different meanings and feelings, called &lt;em&gt;Oa&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Loh&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topet&lt;/strong&gt;, which are logographic characters (occasionally characterised as hieroglyphs). Like other pictographic languages, &lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt; characters can be broken down into repeating components, called &lt;em&gt;Topotte&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rapotenne&lt;/strong&gt;, is the traditional logographic language of names. It is much older than Topet, and has more in common with spiritual runes than modern logography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potenne&lt;/strong&gt;, lit. “&lt;em&gt;Hand-Talk&lt;/em&gt;”, is a sign language that incorporates gestures and signing to add meaning to emotion to spoken language, and occasionally in place of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upotenne&lt;/strong&gt;, lit. “&lt;em&gt;Spirit-Hand-Talk&lt;/em&gt;”, as the recreation of runes in human form, used limitedly in spiritual ritual.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/strong&gt; is the codification of colour and shape. Traditionally limited to colour, shape and pattern are now also included in &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Semaphore&lt;/em&gt;, in which full sentences can be formed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an island country, Vekllei is a traditional maritime state dependent on fish stocks and natural resources in its surrounding oceans, primarily the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s fledgling kingdom under rule of Simiyo Kehsmiouz successfully positioned the country as an Atlantic trading port and mercantile hub, bringing new wealth to the country and beginning the Era of Rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6000&lt;/strong&gt; BC - &lt;strong&gt;3500&lt;/strong&gt; BC, &lt;strong&gt;Kalaallisut / Kala&lt;/strong&gt;, Proto-&lt;em&gt;Quutetast&lt;/em&gt; extinct Algic language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3500&lt;/strong&gt; BC - &lt;strong&gt;800&lt;/strong&gt; AD,  &lt;strong&gt;Quutetast&lt;/strong&gt;,  Algic-Aleutian extinct language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1200&lt;/strong&gt; BC - &lt;strong&gt;900&lt;/strong&gt; AD, &lt;strong&gt;Islandi&lt;/strong&gt;,  Indo-European Scandinavian language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;900&lt;/strong&gt; AD - &lt;strong&gt;1600&lt;/strong&gt; AD, &lt;strong&gt;Topyas&lt;/strong&gt; (Old Vekllei),  fusion dialect of &lt;em&gt;Islandi&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Quutetast&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1600&lt;/strong&gt; AD - &lt;strong&gt;present&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Modern Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, evolution of &lt;em&gt;Topyas&lt;/em&gt;. Spoken today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-structure&#34;&gt;2. Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bureau-system&#34;&gt;The Bureau System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is the transliteration of the Vekllei word &lt;em&gt;Boreaul&lt;/em&gt;, meaning a writing desk. In Vekllei it has evolved to infer a singular labour monopoly of the country (in state speak called &amp;ldquo;masthead chapels;&amp;rdquo; trade unions), either as government State Requisites &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or private venrouive monopolies &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bureaus can consist of a single company, as is often the case in government departments, or several hundred. In this sense, a private Bureau resembles a central federation trade union, organising companies into industry monopolies that, while legally independent from government affairs, are traditionally expected to cooperate with the democratic processes of the country. Bureaus, as administrators of work in Vekllei, are fundamentally political organs, and the Bureau Secretariat, the legal congress of all bureaus, reports directly to the Prime Ministers of Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk about a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, it refers to a &lt;em&gt;Bureau Proper&lt;/em&gt; unless otherwise stated. Bureaux Proper are the formal trade organisations of the country, bound to its direction and intention. They coexist with &lt;em&gt;Bureau Minor&lt;/em&gt; or &amp;ldquo;Petty Bureaux,&amp;rdquo; which are informal, often provincial or regional, independent from Proper Bureaux, and better resemble free trade unions. The following infosheets describe their differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Bureau Proper&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Bureau Minor&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Senrouive&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Venrouive&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bureaus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s international standing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extraterritorial influence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social benefit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;informal-markets&#34;&gt;Informal Markets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-floral-society&#34;&gt;3. Floral Society&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moneylessness&#34;&gt;Moneylessness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bureau-system-1&#34;&gt;The Bureau System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;property-ownership&#34;&gt;Property Ownership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;place-metaphysics&#34;&gt;Place-Metaphysics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sundress-municipalism&#34;&gt;Sundress Municipalism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-currency-and-markets&#34;&gt;4. Currency and Markets&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/crown.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he Vekllei Kroner&lt;/strong&gt;, or “&lt;strong&gt;Crown&lt;/strong&gt;,” is hundreds of years old, and Vekllei still operates a mint for currency. At any time, a Vekllei person can write to the National Mint and order a set of coins, like the ones pictured above. So what is going on here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the Kroner has not been used since 2022, after the last village in Stochi returned coinage to the Mint, it continues to exist to this day as a gold-backed currency in the International Market, through which Vekllei trades with other countries. The physical coins, produced mostly as a novelty in the tradition of &lt;em&gt;mayaesdiou&lt;/em&gt; (medallions, or small metal pieces commonly collected and given in Vekllei), are a physical coinage of the International Market. The coins also operate as a form of bullion, or wealth reserve, since each coin is worth exactly its face value in gold. Since the International Market is completely closed and independent of the domestic economy, its value is controlled directly by the so-called Government Bank. It is one of the few gold-backed currencies in a developed nation today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further complicate things, there are actually two different Kroner in Vekllei. There is the &lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Kroner&lt;/strong&gt;, which represents the International Market, but there is also a seperate &lt;strong&gt;Government/State Kroner&lt;/strong&gt;, which is not minted and used only as an investment mechanism, backed by government &amp;ldquo;white bonds&amp;rdquo; which are usually measures of labour-hours or refined materials. It is, in a sense, a fiat currency alongside a gold-backed currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They exist independently because they are used for two seperate purposes. The Vekllei Kroner is used a wealth reserve and bullion, and also represents the collective wealth of the Vekllei people. Each citizen, in theory, is entitled to an equal share of the Government Bank, although it can only be withdrawn as currency in specific circumstances. Vekllei also holds substantial amounts of foreign currency in the Government Bank and Vekllei Kroner, which is used to invest and stabilise holdings and capital in foreign countries. The Government Kroner, on the other hand, is used as an investment mechanism abroad, usually in support of infrastructure. It is also used to acquire foreign currencies through investment in foreign capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having two currencies, neither the &amp;ldquo;Vekllei Crown&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Government Crown&amp;rdquo; are used in the domestic economy in Vekllei, which is autonomous and not subject to a central bank. So it is that Vekllei’s currency is both little more than a novelty and essential to the function of the country in a world still ruled by money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the coinage depicted above — 8 coins are minted in Vekllei today.&lt;/strong&gt; They were designed in 2015, in the year of independence. They represent eight core values in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “small crowns,” worth 1VK and 10VK respectively, represent fraternity and liberty, two founding elements of the Vekllei constitution. The 50VK coin is plated in silver and has a small ruby inset. Rubies are used to represent energy, in this case, the vitality of the spirits, which dominate Upen and the Vekllei landscape. The 100, 200, 500 and 1,000VK coins represent different landscapes of the country. As a volcanic island nation, the ocean (100) and landscape (200) coins are fairly straightforward. The humanity coin (500) represents the Vekllei people and ancestry — note how humans are placed alongside other natural forces. The flower coin (1,000VK) represents the flowers of the country, which are important spiritually and have formed part of the Vekllei identity. Vekllei has the most flowers per capita in the world. The final, larger 10,000VK coin represents the previous seven together, as a total sum of Vekllei landscape and identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Requisites, or &lt;em&gt;requoisesiasn amourisocietie&lt;/em&gt; (A.r.), for example the &lt;em&gt;Thunderburo&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Industries, or &lt;em&gt;societie indastrie&lt;/em&gt; (S.A.), like the historic &lt;em&gt;General Reactor&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mail</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.gt-container {
  display: none;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mailtrain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  A Series 225 EMU RM train used as a rail post office in rural Vekllei | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/&#34;&gt;Racing the Post Office to the Station&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint mail&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; society
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; is perhaps the country&amp;rsquo;s most visible organisation overseas. For many foreigners, Royal Mail aircraft may be the closest they ever come to seeing for themselves the mysterious Atlantic country. For Vekllei residents, the ancient organisation is a living relic of the country&amp;rsquo;s ancient history, and an ongoing testament to the longevity of their people.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;Mail&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Mail A.r.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; within the country, is the national postal carrier of &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;. It is a military state requisite reponsible for all postage in the country, and delivers nearly 50 million mail pieces domestically and abroad each day. One of the oldest institutions of its kind in Vekllei, it was founded in 1422 as a courier system between the Vekllei Kingdom and its largely mercenary military force. In 1742, it was formalised as a modern postal system available to the civilian public, and today offers a variety of services available to all Vekllei residents, including external territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is also home to the U.N. Universal Postal Union, the body responsible for coordinating international postage, of which Vekllei is a signatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/fairie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  An MS Model 54-2 &amp;ldquo;Fairie,&amp;rdquo; used to deliver mail to Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s islands and islets | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/&#34;&gt;The Fairie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint mail&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/&#34;&gt;Post is for People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail is old enough to have its own hieroglyph in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/language/#3-topet&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which has resulted in the somewhat misleading transliteration of its name. In Vekllei, it is simply called the &amp;lsquo;Mail&amp;rsquo;, since its written name includes both its royal and national meanings intrinsically. Abroad, this is usually translated as the Royal Mail of Vekllei, but this is in fact more of a description of the organisation than its proper name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Vekllei refers to its territory as its sovereign (expressed commonly as the &amp;lsquo;Landscape Sovereign&amp;rsquo;), the Mail remains Royal even today, centuries after the collapse of the monarchy that founded it. Despite its regular function as a postal service, it is nonetheless considered a resource of landscape, not a government department, and so it remains &amp;ldquo;the Royal Mail of Vekllei&amp;rdquo; in the 21st Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most Royal Bureaus, the Mail is headquartered in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s capital across a dozen or so city blocks dedicated to administration, manufacturing, vehicle storage and maintenance, and Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s General Post Office. There are over 6,400 post offices in Vekllei today, connecting the dense Home Islands to its far-flung peripheral territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint mail&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/&#34;&gt;The Men and Women of the Royal Mail in Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei has maintained courier systems for at least a thousand years, the Mail as a contiguous instituion was founded in 1422 by the Desimou VII, King of Vekllei, in the late Period of Rest. During this time, the lords of Vekllei had established significant mercantile holdings across the North Atlantic, and had developed reliable systems of trade throughout Ireland and Denmark. The Royal Mail of Vekllei was first established as a royal communications organ that sought to ensure stability of the Desimou rule across the incresingly autonomous Vekllei empire. In this period, the Mail consisted of a handful of messengers attached to the feudal military apparatus of the Vekllei monarchy, which transferred to the incoming Junta upon collapse of the monarchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/pond.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail would not come to resemble conventional civilian Mail until 1652, when the Junta expanded postal contracts to the privy councils of the Faroe and Greenland territories, and later broke apart the Mail monopoly to benefit then-Secretary of State Kism Sismiosnah, who established the New Parliament Postal Service. It was not until nearly a century later, in 1742, that company services were opened to all land-owning Vekllei people, and the Mail came to resemble its contemporary mandate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail was reestablished in 2015, during Vekllei independence. It was afforded a mandate protected by the postwar &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#floral-society&#34;&gt;Petticoat Constitution&lt;/a&gt;, and all existing private mail services established in occupation were folded directly into the new state monopoly. In 2016, a year after reestablishment, Mi Miou was elected as the world&amp;rsquo;s first female Postmistress General. The Floral Period of the Royal Mail has been marked by a rapid expansion of both infrastructure and services in Vekllei and abroad. World Post, the international for-profit arm of the Mail, was established in 2034.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint mail&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/&#34;&gt;The Postmistress of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail is organised horizontally as an independent branch of the Royal Vekllei Armed Forces, and so, unlike other State Requisites, reports directly to the Prime Ministers of the Vekllei Government, as representatives of the Landscape Sovereign. As is common with most large-scale industry in Vekllei, the Mail is vertically integrated, and the majority of its contract work is consolidated directly into the bureau structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail has two offices of administration: the General Office and the Office of the Postmistress, which are responsible for daily operations and interdepartmental administration respectively. The following table outlines the Mail&amp;rsquo;s structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;The Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Office&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Royal Mail Press
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the Mail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Materials Manufacturie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Services Bureau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special Services Office
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postal Inspection Offices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joint HO/NI Postal Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overseas Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Post Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Express Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Mail&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VK Mail Chapel (VKC 1st Mail Workers Unite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service Assurance Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Telecommunications&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma Vekllei&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma Overseas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial Telecommunications Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Company Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Post Boxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Postmistress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Commission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Democracy Office&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/stamps.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/characters/#tzipora-zelda-desmoisnes&#34;&gt;Tzipora&lt;/a&gt; arranges some of her favourite Vekllei stamps | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/&#34;&gt;Philately Foolery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint mail&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/&#34;&gt;Philately Foolery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The Royal Mail&lt;/strong&gt; maintains a constitutionally-bound monopoly on all postage in the country, leaving it the sole provider of universal postage service in Vekllei. Like most State Requisites (A.r.), however, it has substantial international trade and foreign dealings that provide for its common description as a state-owned for-profit enterprise, or public corporation.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal service is&lt;/strong&gt;, by the glossary of the Mail, truly universal. As mandated by Vekllei law, the Mail provides delivery for all postage material anywhere in the world, or indeed, beyond it. It maintains 6,424 post offices across Vekllei, including its antarctic and peripheral possessions. The Mail&amp;rsquo;s first Lunar Post Office opened in 2059. In addition to its domestic monopoly, the Mail contributes nearly VK❦2.6 trillion each year towards the Vekllei Government Securities Bureau (the country&amp;rsquo;s sovereign wealth fund) through its international postage and courier services abroad, under the name World Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Mail&amp;rsquo;s Office of Telecommunications is also responsible for all telephones, telegrams and videophones in the country, the Mail&amp;rsquo;s status as a lynchpin of communication is absolute, and heavily protected by the postwar Vekllei constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;daily-service&#34;&gt;Daily Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint mail&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/&#34;&gt;Racing the Post Office to the Station&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail aims to provide next-day delivery during weekdays in zero-code (that is to say, &lt;em&gt;Home Island&lt;/em&gt;) regions. Overnight delivery is also generally available between &lt;em&gt;Home Islands&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Aismious&lt;/em&gt; Islands, &lt;em&gt;Kala&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Azores&lt;/em&gt; during weekdays. Most Lunar territories are available on Mondays and Fridays, and other territories are available according to the Mail&amp;rsquo;s region table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei people do not pay to post items, stamps are affixed with coloured squares called &lt;em&gt;chromacodes&lt;/em&gt; which are used in the automatic sorting machines common in the country. International Mail uses traditional stamps with price listed, and the Vekllei Crown displayed. Franking is used for tracking and identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;special-delivery&#34;&gt;Special Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special, commercial and industrial postage is managed within the &lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt; through special sorting facilities and a dedicated postal network. Regular business postage is funnelled through regular daily service, but hazardous, oversized and dangerous goods are accepted by special Post Offices designed to accept them. The Mail does not provide special services for regular residential or courier delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;international-service&#34;&gt;International Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail is best known overseas as the &lt;strong&gt;World Post&lt;/strong&gt;, which offers services for foreign clients and has established itself as one of the Big Four international transnational courier services in the world today. Similar to domestic postal systems in other countries, the World Post offers flat rates for delivery anywhere in the world, priced according to size and weight. In addition, sister company &lt;strong&gt;Universal Express&lt;/strong&gt; offers next-day weekday delivery in certain markets. Most employees of the World Post and Universal Express are foreign workers banking labour-hours for immigration to Vekllei. Unlike domestic service, the World Post and Universal Express use private courier contracts extensively to fulfil orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finance&#34;&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is easily accessible via the Mail&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Financial Services Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;. Although inaccessible within the country, savings can be withdrawn conditionally upon emigration, and the Mail offers easy access and financial counselling for Vekllei people. Through the Financial Services Bureau, the Mail also offers financial management to immigrant populations with wealth transfer (the phrase for banking of savings and prior income) and Overseas Accounting, commonly used to send money to family abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;telecommunications&#34;&gt;Telecommunications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosma&lt;/strong&gt; (a portmanteau of &lt;em&gt;communicasia matismion&lt;/em&gt;) is Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s state communications company, responsible for all residential and public telephones in the country. This includes videophones, public phone booths, and residential networks. Cosma also maintains telecommunications infrastructure networks internationally through &lt;strong&gt;Cosma Overseas&lt;/strong&gt;, primarily the Vekllei-Europe undersea cables and their sister sets between Vekllei and North America. Much of the network dates back over a hundred years, since a shortage of modern personal telephones in Vekllei requires Cosma to maintain a wide variety of voltage and cable standards. Commercial, industrial and government telecommunications is managed by a seperate internal department called the &lt;strong&gt;Industrial Telecommunications Office&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operations&#34;&gt;Operations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/manufacturie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  Outdoor view of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/&#34;&gt;Royal Mail&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; stamp printing complex. | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/&#34;&gt;The Stamp Manufacturie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint mail&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/&#34;&gt;The Stamp Manufacturie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;As a military organ&lt;/strong&gt;, the Mail A.r. retains military ranks for its staff, commanded by a Postmaster General and aided by a civilian regulator designed to keep its critical service available to Vekllei people. The Mail&amp;rsquo;s fleet includes dedicated jets, automatic trucks, mail trains, intercity pneumatic systems, vehicle automen, and postmen, all wearing the red and gold colours of the organisation. In total, the Mail delivers nearly 50 million pieces of mail during weekdays.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is evident&lt;/strong&gt; that the services assigned to the Mail by the postwar constitution are of critical importance to the stability of Vekllei society. In addition to being one of the oldest active postal organisations in the world, the Royal Mail of Vekllei is tremendously busy, since physical post has scarcely been displaced by the telephone in the country. Even without the Mail&amp;rsquo;s international postage, domestic mail each day can exceed 12 million pieces &amp;ndash; enough for 1 in 2 people, though commercial mail and periodicals are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is typical for critical bureaus in Vekllei, the Mail alleviates the stress of daily service through its dense, vertically-integrated infrastructure aided by automatic (automen vehicles) and permanent fixtures (pneumatic systems and automatic sorting/franking machines). It is precisely this commitment to infrastructure that makes the Mail so visible in daily life, and contributes to its ongoing legacy as Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s oldest running government institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;staff&#34;&gt;Staff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/postmistress.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail employs 48,960 people full-time across its various offices, and nearly 200,000 automen in various roles. Although the Mail does retain a staff of postmen and couriers, most urban daily service is now provided by automatic vehicles and sorting, which account for nearly half of the total automen owned by the organisation. Instead, the majority of Mail employees are involved in the running of the organisation &amp;ndash; mostly as clerks, managers, and administrators. Around 10,000 postmen are employed by the Mail in daily delivery, called &amp;ldquo;posties&amp;rdquo;. There are around 8,000 postal routes in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although at first glance the number of automen dramatically exceeds demand, the total count is misleading &amp;ndash; most automen with the Mail are integrated into the infrastructure of its sorting centres and post offices, and very few are traditionally autonomous robots commonly seen in public in Vekllei. Only about 8,000 automen are employed in physical mail delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 16,220 post boxes in Vekllei, which are iconic for their red and gold paint and intricate detailing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleet&#34;&gt;Fleet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint mail&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/&#34;&gt;The Fairie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail retains a large and diverse fleet of vehicles in regular operations, which, due to their diversity and and expense, have become iconic around the world. From bicycles to space planes, the Mail&amp;rsquo;s fleet of vehicles rivals in diversity postal services three times its size, largely benefitted by Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s obfuscated budgeting system and cultural importance afforded to the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table lists company vehicles relevant to regular postal service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;The Royal Mail Fleet&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8,000 delivery automen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5,200 motorcycles &lt;em&gt;(mostly Local Electric Model 15 &amp;amp; Phantoms)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,400 bicycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,000 automatic vans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;400 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;31 mail boats &lt;em&gt;(MBR)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 mail flying boats &lt;em&gt;(Model 54 &amp;ldquo;Fairie&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 mail helijets &lt;em&gt;(Model RM/Gisma &amp;amp; Record types)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 mail trains &lt;em&gt;(RM Series/Series 225 EMU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 mail trams &lt;em&gt;(Series T6)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail space planes &lt;em&gt;(G.A. Type 1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail ships &lt;em&gt;(RMS&lt;/em&gt; Atlantic &lt;em&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/em&gt; Sunburst &lt;em&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overseas Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Post Company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;250 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;52 cargo jets &lt;em&gt;(Model RM/Type 56C)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 flying boats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Express Company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cargo jets &lt;em&gt;(Model ERM/C.A. Type 6 supersonic)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Postmistress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 executive mail train &lt;em&gt;(Series 4000 EMU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A.r.&lt;/em&gt; is a shortening of &lt;em&gt;state requisite&lt;/em&gt; (A.r., or requoisesiasn amourisocietie)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (often called the &lt;em&gt;Government Bank&lt;/em&gt;) is Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s social bank, and each Vekllei person is entitled to an equal share of it.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navy</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/navy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/navy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.markdown a {
color: var(--color-red);
}
.markdown a.anchor {
color: var(--color-red);
}
aside nav ul a {
color: var(--color-red);
}
#headerbox .emoji {
color: var(--color-red);
}
.markdown a:visited {
color: var(--color-orange);
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Navies of Vekllei&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;s&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5 span class=&#34;tag red&#34;&gt; ARTICLE &lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6 span class=&#34;sitetag&#34;&gt;Documents&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mailtrain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; society
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-overview&#34;&gt;1. Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;All Bureau and military vessels&lt;/strong&gt; in Vekllei belong to a navy. There is, of course, the traditional Royal Navy of Vekllei, the military branch responsible for armed naval operations, but also includes the Vekllei Merchant Navy and
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;Mail&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Mail A.r.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; within the country, is the national postal carrier of &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;. It is a military state requisite reponsible for all postage in the country, and delivers nearly 50 million mail pieces domestically and abroad each day. One of the oldest institutions of its kind in Vekllei, it was founded in 1422 as a courier system between the Vekllei Kingdom and its largely mercenary military force. In 1742, it was formalised as a modern postal system available to the civilian public, and today offers a variety of services available to all Vekllei residents, including external territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is also home to the U.N. Universal Postal Union, the body responsible for coordinating international postage, of which Vekllei is a signatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/fairie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/&#34;&gt;Post is for People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail is old enough to have its own hieroglyph in &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/language/#3-topet&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which has resulted in the somewhat misleading transliteration of its name. In Vekllei, it is simply called the &amp;lsquo;Mail&amp;rsquo;, since its written name includes both its royal and national meanings intrinsically. Abroad, this is usually translated as the Royal Mail of Vekllei, but this is in fact more of a description of the organisation than its proper name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Vekllei refers to its territory as its sovereign (expressed commonly as the &amp;lsquo;Landscape Sovereign&amp;rsquo;), the Mail remains Royal even today, centuries after the collapse of the monarchy that founded it. Despite its regular function as a postal service, it is nonetheless considered a resource of landscape, not a government department, and so it remains &amp;ldquo;the Royal Mail of Vekllei&amp;rdquo; in the 21st Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most Royal Bureaus, the Mail is headquartered in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s capital across a dozen or so city blocks dedicated to administration, manufacturing, vehicle storage and maintenance, and Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s General Post Office. There are over 6,400 post offices in Vekllei today, connecting the dense Home Islands to its far-flung peripheral territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/&#34;&gt;The Men and Women of the Royal Mail in Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    Although Vekllei has maintained courier systems for at least a thousand years, the Mail as a contiguous instituion was founded in 1422 by the Desimou VII, King of Vekllei, in the late Period of Rest. During this time, the lords of Vekllei had established significant mercantile holdings across the North Atlantic, and had developed reliable systems of trade throughout Ireland and Denmark. The Royal Mail of Vekllei was first established as a royal communications organ that sought to ensure stability of the Desimou rule across the incresingly autonomous Vekllei empire. In this period, the Mail consisted of a handful of messengers attached to the feudal military apparatus of the Vekllei monarchy, which transferred to the incoming Junta upon collapse of the monarchy.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/pond.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

The Mail would not come to resemble conventional civilian Mail until 1652, when the Junta expanded postal contracts to the privy councils of the Faroe and Greenland territories, and later broke apart the Mail monopoly to benefit then-Secretary of State Kism Sismiosnah, who established the New Parliament Postal Service. It was not until nearly a century later, in 1742, that company services were opened to all land-owning Vekllei people, and the Mail came to resemble its contemporary mandate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail was reestablished in 2015, during Vekllei independence. It was afforded a mandate protected by the postwar &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#floral-society&#34;&gt;Petticoat Constitution&lt;/a&gt;, and all existing private mail services established in occupation were folded directly into the new state monopoly. In 2016, a year after reestablishment, Mi Miou was elected as the world&amp;rsquo;s first female Postmistress General. The Floral Period of the Royal Mail has been marked by a rapid expansion of both infrastructure and services in Vekllei and abroad. World Post, the international for-profit arm of the Mail, was established in 2034.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/&#34;&gt;The Postmistress of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail is organised horizontally as an independent branch of the Royal Vekllei Armed Forces, and so, unlike other State Requisites, reports directly to the Prime Ministers of the Vekllei Government, as representatives of the Landscape Sovereign. As is common with most large-scale industry in Vekllei, the Mail is vertically integrated, and the majority of its contract work is consolidated directly into the bureau structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail has two offices of administration: the General Office and the Office of the Postmistress, which are responsible for daily operations and interdepartmental administration respectively. The following table outlines the Mail&amp;rsquo;s structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;The Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Office&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Royal Mail Press
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the Mail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Materials Manufacturie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Services Bureau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special Services Office
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postal Inspection Offices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joint HO/NI Postal Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overseas Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Post Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Express Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Mail&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VK Mail Chapel (VKC 1st Mail Workers Unite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service Assurance Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Telecommunications&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma Vekllei&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma Overseas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial Telecommunications Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Company Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Post Boxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Postmistress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Commission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Democracy Office&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-services&#34;&gt;2. Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/stamps.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/&#34;&gt;Philately Foolery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The Royal Mail&lt;/strong&gt; maintains a constitutionally-bound monopoly on all postage in the country, leaving it the sole provider of universal postage service in Vekllei. Like most State Requisites (A.r.), however, it has substantial international trade and foreign dealings that provide for its common description as a state-owned for-profit enterprise, or public corporation.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;U&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;niversal service&lt;/strong&gt; is, by the glossary of the Mail, truly universal. As mandated by Vekllei law, the Mail provides delivery for all postage material anywhere in the world, or indeed, beyond it. It maintains 6,424 post offices across Vekllei, including its antarctic and peripheral possessions. The Mail&amp;rsquo;s first Lunar Post Office opened in 2059. In addition to its domestic monopoly, the Mail contributes nearly VK❦2.6 trillion each year towards the Vekllei Government Securities Bureau (the country&amp;rsquo;s sovereign wealth fund) through its international postage and courier services abroad, under the name World Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Mail&amp;rsquo;s Office of Telecommunications is also responsible for all telephones, telegrams and videophones in the country, the Mail&amp;rsquo;s status as a lynchpin of communication is absolute, and heavily protected by the postwar Vekllei constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;daily-service&#34;&gt;Daily Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/&#34;&gt;Racing the Post Office to the Station&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail aims to provide next-day delivery during weekdays in zero-code (that is to say, &lt;em&gt;Home Island&lt;/em&gt;) regions. Overnight delivery is also generally available between &lt;em&gt;Home Islands&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Aismious&lt;/em&gt; Islands, &lt;em&gt;Kala&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Azores&lt;/em&gt; during weekdays. Most Lunar territories are available on Mondays and Fridays, and other territories are available according to the Mail&amp;rsquo;s region table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei people do not pay to post items, stamps are affixed with coloured squares called &lt;em&gt;chromacodes&lt;/em&gt; which are used in the automatic sorting machines common in the country. International Mail uses traditional stamps with price listed, and the Vekllei Crown displayed. Franking is used for tracking and identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;special-delivery&#34;&gt;Special Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special, commercial and industrial postage is managed within the &lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt; through special sorting facilities and a dedicated postal network. Regular business postage is funnelled through regular daily service, but hazardous, oversized and dangerous goods are accepted by special Post Offices designed to accept them. The Mail does not provide special services for regular residential or courier delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;international-service&#34;&gt;International Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail is best known overseas as the &lt;strong&gt;World Post&lt;/strong&gt;, which offers services for foreign clients and has established itself as one of the Big Four international transnational courier services in the world today. Similar to domestic postal systems in other countries, the World Post offers flat rates for delivery anywhere in the world, priced according to size and weight. In addition, sister company &lt;strong&gt;Universal Express&lt;/strong&gt; offers next-day weekday delivery in certain markets. Most employees of the World Post and Universal Express are foreign workers banking labour-hours for immigration to Vekllei. Unlike domestic service, the World Post and Universal Express use private courier contracts extensively to fulfil orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finance&#34;&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is easily accessible via the Mail&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Financial Services Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;. Although inaccessible within the country, savings can be withdrawn conditionally upon emigration, and the Mail offers easy access and financial counselling for Vekllei people. Through the Financial Services Bureau, the Mail also offers financial management to immigrant populations with wealth transfer (the phrase for banking of savings and prior income) and Overseas Accounting, commonly used to send money to family abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;telecommunications&#34;&gt;Telecommunications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosma&lt;/strong&gt; (a portmanteau of &lt;em&gt;communicasia matismion&lt;/em&gt;) is Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s state communications company, responsible for all residential and public telephones in the country. This includes videophones, public phone booths, and residential networks. Cosma also maintains telecommunications infrastructure networks internationally through &lt;strong&gt;Cosma Overseas&lt;/strong&gt;, primarily the Vekllei-Europe undersea cables and their sister sets between Vekllei and North America. Much of the network dates back over a hundred years, since a shortage of modern personal telephones in Vekllei requires Cosma to maintain a wide variety of voltage and cable standards. Commercial, industrial and government telecommunications is managed by a seperate internal department called the &lt;strong&gt;Industrial Telecommunications Office&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-operations&#34;&gt;3. Operations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/manufacturie.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/&#34;&gt;The Stamp Manufacturie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;As a military organ&lt;/strong&gt;, the Mail A.r. retains military ranks for its staff, commanded by a Postmaster General and aided by a civilian regulator designed to keep its critical service available to Vekllei people. The Mail&amp;rsquo;s fleet includes dedicated jets, automatic trucks, mail trains, intercity pneumatic systems, vehicle automen, and postmen, all wearing the red and gold colours of the organisation. In total, the Mail delivers nearly 50 million pieces of mail during weekdays.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;t is evident&lt;/strong&gt; that the services assigned to the Mail by the postwar constitution are of critical importance to the stability of Vekllei society. In addition to being one of the oldest active postal organisations in the world, the Royal Mail of Vekllei is tremendously busy, since physical post has scarcely been displaced by the telephone in the country. Even without the Mail&amp;rsquo;s international postage, domestic mail each day can exceed 12 million pieces &amp;ndash; enough for 1 in 2 people, though commercial mail and periodicals are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is typical for critical bureaus in Vekllei, the Mail alleviates the stress of daily service through its dense, vertically-integrated infrastructure aided by automatic (automen vehicles) and permanent fixtures (pneumatic systems and automatic sorting/franking machines). It is precisely this commitment to infrastructure that makes the Mail so visible in daily life, and contributes to its ongoing legacy as Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s oldest running government institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;staff&#34;&gt;Staff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/mail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/postmistress.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail employs 48,960 people full-time across its various offices, and nearly 200,000 automen in various roles. Although the Mail does retain a staff of postmen and couriers, most urban daily service is now provided by automatic vehicles and sorting, which account for nearly half of the total automen owned by the organisation. Instead, the majority of Mail employees are involved in the running of the organisation &amp;ndash; mostly as clerks, managers, and administrators. Around 10,000 postmen are employed by the Mail in daily delivery, called &amp;ldquo;posties&amp;rdquo;. There are around 8,000 postal routes in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although at first glance the number of automen dramatically exceeds demand, the total count is misleading &amp;ndash; most automen with the Mail are integrated into the infrastructure of its sorting centres and post offices, and very few are traditionally autonomous robots commonly seen in public in Vekllei. Only about 8,000 automen are employed in physical mail delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 16,220 post boxes in Vekllei, which are iconic for their red and gold paint and intricate detailing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleet&#34;&gt;Fleet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint red&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/&#34;&gt;The Fairie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail retains a large and diverse fleet of vehicles in regular operations, which, due to their diversity and and expense, have become iconic around the world. From bicycles to space planes, the Mail&amp;rsquo;s fleet of vehicles rivals in diversity postal services three times its size, largely benefitted by Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s obfuscated budgeting system and cultural importance afforded to the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table lists company vehicles relevant to regular postal service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;The Royal Mail Fleet&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8,000 delivery automen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5,200 motorcycles &lt;em&gt;(mostly Local Electric Model 15 &amp;amp; Phantoms)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,400 bicycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,000 automatic vans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;400 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;31 mail boats &lt;em&gt;(MBR)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 mail flying boats &lt;em&gt;(Model 54 &amp;ldquo;Fairie&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 mail helijets &lt;em&gt;(Model RM/Gisma &amp;amp; Record types)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 mail trains &lt;em&gt;(RM Series/Series 225 EMU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 mail trams &lt;em&gt;(Series T6)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail space planes &lt;em&gt;(G.A. Type 1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail ships &lt;em&gt;(RMS&lt;/em&gt; Atlantic &lt;em&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/em&gt; Sunburst &lt;em&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overseas Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Post Company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;250 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;52 cargo jets &lt;em&gt;(Model RM/Type 56C)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 flying boats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Express Company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cargo jets &lt;em&gt;(Model ERM/C.A. Type 6 supersonic)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Postmistress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 executive mail train &lt;em&gt;(Series 4000 EMU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A.r.&lt;/em&gt; is a shortening of &lt;em&gt;state requisite&lt;/em&gt; (A.r., or requoisesiasn amourisocietie)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (often called the &lt;em&gt;Government Bank&lt;/em&gt;) is Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s social bank, and each Vekllei person is entitled to an equal share of it.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rail</title>
      <link>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/rail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.gt-container {
  display: none;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/orange.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  A Mustard 56-Series EMU passes through the borough of &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/troll/&#34;&gt;Troll&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-03-orange/&#34;&gt;VNR Orange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint vnr&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; society
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; discusses one of the most important and visible organisations in everyday Vekllei life: Vekllei National Rail. Vekllei is criss-crossed by hundreds of different rail lines of various gauges, grades, and purposes. In fact, it runs many lines at a total loss, often undercapacity. To understand these inefficiencies is to understand why the National Rail exists, and to some extent, how Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s state assets and powerful bureaus shape life in the country today.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he National Rail of Vekllei (VNR)&lt;/strong&gt; is a catch-all term for bureau-backed, state-owned rail operators of Vekllei. In casual use, it refers to the Vekllei National Railway A.r.R. and its sister companies, like Vekllei Metro, which are structured within the service-oriented Railways Bureau. More precisely, Vekllei National Rail encompasses several different bureaus that operate, design, maintain and communicate rail service in the country, which itself is further included under the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most critical organisations of Vekllei, the structure and directorship of Vekllei National Rail is complex, but can be simplified by understanding that all rail transport in the country is ultimately the responsibility of an organisation called Vekllei National Rail, and it is towards this organ that this article is addressed. Today, the National Rail operates nearly 20,000km of track, indicating the density of the rail service it provides, and services nearly 20 million people each day through its network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/railmap.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  A map of the rail network and boroughs of Vekllei, showcasing maglev (red), high-speed (yellow), regional (orange) and local (brown) lines | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/&#34;&gt;100 Boroughs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since nationalisation of the private Vekllei rail companies in 1925, the structure and reach of Vekllei National Rail has changed several times. Operated as a for-profit enterprise at a historical loss, the National Rail&amp;rsquo;s history of service is reflected in the variety of trains and track gauges it maintains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is unique in the density of its rail, a feature of deliberate postwar city planning and the Home Island&amp;rsquo;s history as an industrial port city-state. Very few Vekllei people own automobiles, and trains remain by far the most common method of travel in the country. Because of this, the rail network in metropolitan areas is extraordinarily dense, and is designed to offer access to nearly every residence in urban areas. This fact also explains the presence of dedicated rail lines to small towns and villages that would otherwise not justify their maintenance. As visible on the map above, the passenger rail network in Vekllei is unsurpassed in its density, which contributes to the dependence Vekllei people have on their trains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, almost all freight is run along rails of varying gauges. These range from conventional freight trains at standard gauge, to municipal delivery trains at metre guage, and even narrow gauges for moving freight and equipment within large factory complexes. Most major stores and grocers are arranged along freight lines with dedicated sidings, or have their own narrow-gauge tracks dedicated to their use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unusually, Vekllei National Rail is legally absolved of all non-rail transport, and possesses no busses or ferries for public use, which are operated and maintained by dedicated adjacent bureaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/shrine-minded.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  A Lesvesn 59-Series EMU arrives in the village of Cult | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/&#34;&gt;Shrine-Minded Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei has used wagonways since the 18th Century and developed horse-drawn railways for industrial transport in its ports, the first passenger rail line in Vekllei was founded in 1855 by the Pharos Rail Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of rail in Vekllei can be summarised in three key eras of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Development and expansion&lt;/strong&gt;, from early service in 1855.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late Junta/Prewar nationalisation&lt;/strong&gt;, from nationalisation in 1925.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postwar refounding and development&lt;/strong&gt;, since independence in 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the foundation of VNR after nationalisation, rail in Vekllei has seen the scale of its passenger rail networks quadruple in size. It is internationally regarded for its safety and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;early-development&#34;&gt;Early Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first railways in Vekllei developed alongside its ports, as Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s position as an intermediary free port between Europe and the Americas rapidly developed Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s industrial base. Although the earliest internal rail wagons were pulled by horses, primitive steam locomotives had modernised most ports by the early 19th Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first passenger rail line opened in 1855 between Pharos and the present-day borough of Little Vekllei to alleviate the expense of moving goods from the Pharos Port to established settlement further inland. The original line was only a few kilometres long, but was extended in 1858 and again in 1872. By this time, several other lines had been established under private rail companies, including passenger services between Vekllei Proper and Little Vekllei, as well as the beginnings of the Montre-Vekllei Railroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the beginning of the 20th Century, Vekllei had a half-dozen major railroad companies, and dozens other limited/local services provided by private operators or their municipality. This saw a massive increase in both the movement of freight and ridership, and helped entrench Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s position as a stopover port city for transatlantic freight and passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nationalisation&#34;&gt;Nationalisation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early 20th Century was marked by an exponential increase in ridership, which saw a proliferation of new railroads across the Home Islands. Metropolitan and suburban lines during this period were characterised by overcrowding, poor reliability and irregular service. These factors, in addition to the growing economic power of rail barons in the country, saw the Atlantic Junta (known as the Crown) move to nationalise all metropolitan and intercity passenger rail service in 1925 as the Vekllei National Rail Company (VNC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centralisation of Vekllei rail accompanied standardisation of its commuter track gauge, which improved travel times across the country. The VNC period was characterised by reliable investment and a commitment to modernisation of rail in the country. By the late 20th Century, the Vekllei Metropolitan Underground was widely regarded as one of the most beautiful subway systems in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 1980s, VNC started work on what would eventually become the Vekllei-Montre bullet train. The programme overran its cost estimates and was delayed several times, and was not completed until 2004, shortly before the Atomic War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;postwar-development&#34;&gt;Postwar Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Rail Company assets that had been operated by the occupation Vekllei Provisional Government were transferred to the Vekllei Interim Government in 2015 and reestablished as Vekllei National Rail (VNR) in 2018. The Floral Period has been marked by steady growth in ridership and the scale of its network. The organisation also invests heavily into the development of new locomotives and EMUs, culminating in 2047 with the announcement of the Vekllei East Coast Maglev Scheme, which are the fastest commuter trains in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2055, VNR celebrated &amp;ldquo;250 years of rail,&amp;rdquo; and its livery and staff uniforms were overhauled to mark the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, VNR represents the sole means of medium/long-distance transport for over 80% of Vekllei commuters, indicating its continuous status as a monopoly of travel, not just rail, in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei National Rail is an organ of the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government (A.r.R., or &lt;em&gt;requoisesiasn amourisocietie resmesnghet&lt;/em&gt;) as several individual state requisite bureaus, which in turn are charged with different transport companies. Although its structure in Vekllei might be analogous to a government ministry abroad, it functions in practice more like a state-owned enterprise with private subsidiaries. It is not a state-run corporation, and maintains seperate accounting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei National Rail is administered through three State Requisites: the Vekllei National Rail itself including all regular operations and rail service, the National Rail Insurance Scheme which finances construction through Government White Bonds, and the Rail Safety Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Vekllei National Rail&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Railways Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palace of Rail
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei National Railway A.r.R.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VNR Atlantic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VNR Kala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VNR Overseas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei National Magway A.r.R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei Metro A.r.R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government Railroad R.S.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei Freight S.A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Railroad Police Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office of Steam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office of Electrification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuclear-Electric Rail Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private Railcar Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Industrial Rail&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National Freight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/&#34;&gt;Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; Railway Holdings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Railroad Democracy Hall&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VK Rail Chapel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Rail Chapel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail Press Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Rail Press&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vekllei Rail Transport Journal&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Locomotive&lt;/em&gt; Magazine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rail Periodicals Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friends of Rail Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Relations Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial Relations Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail Municipal Land Company S.A.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail Construction House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Railway Laboratories of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senrouive House Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company House Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Rail Insurance Scheme A.r.R.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passenger Accounting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rail Democracy Office&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rail Safety Commission&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track Safety Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passenger Safety Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platform Investigation Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carriage Investigation Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incident Investigation Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;service&#34;&gt;Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/hollywood.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  A Mustard 56-Series EMU arrives in the village of Cult | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/&#34;&gt;Shrine-Minded Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Since most Vekllei people&lt;/strong&gt; catch a train each day, VNR is a uniquely intimate and treasured organ of the Vekllei state. It is somehow exempted from the public apathy and resentment of bureaucracy that targets other monopolies of the Vekllei state, and is routinely regarded as among the most beloved and appreciated &amp;ldquo;companies&amp;rdquo; in Vekllei.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to public transport is considered a &amp;ldquo;critical luxury&amp;rdquo; of the Vekllei state (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for essential state services) and, by extension, the functioning of its society. By design, it makes no profit, and is subsidised entirely by the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government and various independent transport bureaus for the benefit of any Vekllei person. Even prior to the war and investment of the Floral Period, Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s public transport was widely regarded as among the finest of any network in the world thanks to its impeccable safety record, timeliness, and comprehensive coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rail transport contributes tremendously to the national culture and common affection for Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s public institutions. It is also commonly percieved as a triumph of the postwar floral Period, despite rail history in Vekllei dating back hundreds of years prior. The ongoing expansion of the VNR network and renovation of stations and railhubs commands attention internationally, which is watching Vekllei celebrate its golden age of rail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;national-rail&#34;&gt;National Rail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National rail access is generally provided directly by Vekllei National Railway A.r.R. through a branch office dependent on the location. The Home Islands are served by VNR Atlantic, whereas Kala is served by VNR Overseas. The Home Islands house thousands of rural villages outside of urban metropolitan service, and Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s dependence on rail transportatiion demands their inclusion in the VNR network. As such, almost every village in Vekllei has a rail line or interurban tramway, and villages as small as 20 persons see daily service to the capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;metropolitan-service--subways&#34;&gt;Metropolitan Service &amp;amp; Subways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of VNR&amp;rsquo;s ~10,000 trains per day run in metro or subway services throughout Vekllei urban and interurban routes. These lines are primarily serviced by the EMU workhorses of the VNR fleet, particularly 56 and 59-Series trainsets. In urban centers, VNR service is frequent enough to be unscheduled, with trains arriving every other minute or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s underground metro network has been automated by Automatic Train Control, an industrial automan system that allows for driverless trains. Although still serviced by VNR platform staff with training to stop the train in emergencies, Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s automatic metros are otherwise entirely driverless. VNR Overseas metros in Kala and the Kalina Isles retain drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tramways&#34;&gt;Tramways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei operates a variety of trams and streetcars, including double-decker street-level units in the capital region and so-called &amp;ldquo;fast trams&amp;rdquo; (inter-urban cars) outside of the cities. Depending on the make and route of the tramway, they may be grade-seperated or integrated into streets. Their ubuquity in urban areas has caused observers to regard them as the principle method of transport in the country, second only to the bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;freight&#34;&gt;Freight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR&amp;rsquo;s main freight lines run mostly on a seperate gauge and network, and are composed of several companies that operate regionally across a variety of locomotive types and industries. These include traditional freight locomotives and long/short cars, as well as freight trams and wagons used to transport goods around and between factories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operations&#34;&gt;Operations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/stationlogic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint vnr&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/&#34;&gt;Station Logic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;VNR&lt;/strong&gt; is typical of a &amp;lsquo;great Vekllei bureau&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; it instills national pride, is well-run and maintained, and loses tremendous amounts of money. It is the crown jewel of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s insolvent organs, whose thin profit margins and charming inefficiencies are tolerated and even encouraged in this society which subsidises social benefit above all else.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 17 million people per day commute via VNR&amp;rsquo;s networks each day, making up a majority of the Vekllei population. In this sense, VNR&amp;rsquo;s quality of operations affects the Vekllei person more than the quality of their government. In addition to commuter service, VNR automatic freight transit systems are the lifeblood of all industry and commerce in the country, and are regulated directly as a state requisite for their critical importance to the functioning of Vekllei society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR operates 2,114 stations across the Home Islands, which vary from uncovered concrete platforms to tremendous terminus complexes that cover multiple city blocks. The largest station in the country, Vekllei Central, sees over 1 million people per day pass through its gates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s stations are well-regarded for the beauty and decoration overseas. As part of the Millenia Rail campaign in the mid-21st Century, VNR initiated a dramatic overhaul of its passenger infrastructure, restoring heritage-listed station interiors and renovating much of the early postwar metro construction with murals, new lighting, enlarged caverns and shafts, and improved safety features. The cleanliness and safety of Vekllei National Railway is a great point of pride in the country, and in part justifies VNR&amp;rsquo;s tremendous fiscal losses in daily operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR services are mostly unticketed, and as a Vekllei industry, are free to ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;staff&#34;&gt;Staff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/images/vnr.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint vnr&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/posts/2021-04-25-rail/&#34;&gt;The People of Vekllei National Rail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VNR employs 65,240 people, which include roles ranging from locomotive engineers and platform staff to editors of rail enthusiast periodicals. It is also one of the largest employers of 12-16 year olds in the country, via its Station Apprentice programme, unique among organisations of its size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organisation is administered by the President of the Rail Central Office, which is responsible to the Transport Requisite and the Palace of Rail. VNR has a close relationship with bureau and petty-bureau coachbuilders, and wields considerable power in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s heavy industries as a major manufacturing partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleet&#34;&gt;Fleet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint vnr&#34;&gt;
  ❖ Download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.millmint.net/files/factbook/VNR-Rolling-Stock-Bulletin.pdf&#34;&gt;VNR Rolling Stock List (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vekllei National Rail is perhaps unsurpassed in its variety of trainsets and their length of service. An unofficial policy of preservation has ensured that every unit type since the 1980s has seen an ongoing minor presence in current service. VNR rarely retires a trainset completely &amp;ndash; in keeping with the contemporary cultural-political valuation of machines, a few units of each model are retained on various lines for their historical and technical significance. This includes steam locomotives, which continue to operate regular passengers service on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backbone of the contemporary Vekllei rail fleet is the Electric Multiple Units (EMUs), which are designated by their year of manufacture.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In particular, the 56 and 59-Series trainsets make up the majority of EMUs in service today, as they exclusively populate primary commuter lines in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s southwest. VNR also retains Diesel Multiple Units (DMUs) in its long-haul cold-weather routes, particularly in the Afouisneh region and Kala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR pioneered super-conductive maglev transport for mass consumption, and its SC3 trainsets are the fastest in regular service in the world today, reaching nearly 750km/h in places. Its slowest locomotive, the T400 2-6-2 steam locomotive &lt;em&gt;Small Movements&lt;/em&gt; built in 1928, averages just 30km/h on its tourist route in rural Krafla. VNR is also experimenting with nuclear-powered trainsets, but none have so far entered public testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;war&amp;rsquo; prefix is used as a designation for pre-war railcars and locomotives, transliterated from the native word for the Junta&amp;rsquo;s society.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>