<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Society on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Society on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Government</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.gt-container {
  display: none;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint pink&#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; society
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; is positioned uniquely between the anarchy and control. This article looks at its government, which facilitates and manages these competing instincts. As the representative of the Vekllei state, and the body of its human interests, the Vekllei Government is second only to the Sovereign in its authority over Vekllei society.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he Government of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; refers to both the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#administration-of-the-interior&#34;&gt;Administration of the Interior&lt;/a&gt; of the Vekllei &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Home Islands&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#administration-of-the-commonwealth&#34;&gt;international governing body&lt;/a&gt; of the Vekllei Commonwealth. This article serves as a handbook to all departments of the Vekllei Government, and will help clarify the structure and responsibilities of its subordinate ministries and secretariats. These centralised features guide the busy and anarchic Vekllei economies to produce a standard of living unlike anywhere else in the world, celebrating local, departmentalised and democratic government in the 21st Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be damned if some jumped-up Municipal leech is going to tell me where I can and can&amp;rsquo;t make friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Tzipora Desmoisnes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we know as the &amp;lsquo;Vekllei Government&amp;rsquo; is portioned between several powerful state bodies, each representing the natural political concerns of the modern Vekllei state. These bodies are both autonomous and codependent, carving the sovereignty and authority of the state across several governing organs of varying size and scope. These are, in order of sovereignty:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Palace of the Vekllei Sovereign&lt;/strong&gt;, the metaphysical manifestation of all Vekllei territory and its collective geographic, cultural and religious features. It represents the cumulative historical essence of the physical place of Vekllei, and bridges relationships between humans, nature and spirits. The Palace, as representative of the land itself, is the true sovereign of Vekllei and as such retains control over the armed forces of the Commonwealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Governments of the Vekllei Commonwealth&lt;/strong&gt; including, in order of authority:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Crown of Vekllei (also the &lt;em&gt;Crown Sovereign&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Parliament of Spirits&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Administration of the Crown&lt;/em&gt; interchangeably), representing the rule of the Land Sovereign and its presence in the state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Commonwealth Government (also the &lt;em&gt;Parliament of the Commonwealth&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Administration of the Commonwealth&lt;/em&gt; interchangeably), responsible for the maintenance, development and security of the Vekllei Commonwealth, including its territories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Interior Governments (also the &lt;em&gt;Parliaments of the Interior&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Administrations of the Interior&lt;/em&gt; interchangeably), responsible for the internal governance of the Vekllei member-states, primarily used in reference to the interior parliaments of the Vekllei Home Islands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under this arrangement, it is clear that the sovereignty of Vekllei and its Commonwealth members is somewhat obfuscated &amp;ndash; the Crown, Commonwealth and Interior administrations all share overlapping &lt;em&gt;de jure&lt;/em&gt; control over the affairs of Vekllei territories. In addition, the word &amp;lsquo;Vekllei,&amp;rsquo; commonly used to refer to the Vekllei Home Islands, is also used interchangeably to describe states beyond its geography. For example, the &amp;lsquo;Vekllei Commonwealth&amp;rsquo; in fact refers to membership in the Crown, of which Vekllei is an equal member but does not otherwise, in principle, control as a legal metropole. The Kalina Islands, Kala, Demon and other full members of the Commonwealth are equal autonomous members, but nonetheless inherit the Vekllei name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this state of affairs, Vekllei can refer to the powerful member-state in the North Atlantic, the Commonwealth it belongs to, or, indeed, the Crown Sovereign itself. Unfortunately for foreigners, its use is generally dependent on context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34; style=&#34;margin-top: 2rem;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1.2; font-size: 1.5rem; font-weight: 700; filter: brightness(35%);&#34;&gt;Government of the Vekllei Commonwealth&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 100%;&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;-millmint&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Since most Vekllei people&lt;/strong&gt; catch a train each day, VNR is a uniquely intimate and treasured organ of the Vekllei state. It is somehow exempted from the public apathy and resentment of bureaucracy that targets other monopolies of the Vekllei state, and is routinely regarded as among the most beloved and appreciated &amp;ldquo;companies&amp;rdquo; in Vekllei.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government of Vekllei is made up of Ministries, Offices, Departments, Bureaus, Commissions, Directorates and Secretariats depending on the size, purpose and organisation of the organ. This is the government that people living in the Vekllei Home Islands vote for, via the nonpartisan representatives system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;administration-of-the-interior&#34;&gt;Administration of the Interior&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mastheads/flags/vekllei-international.png?q=100&amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;flag&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; padding: 0; background-color: transparent;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mastheads/flags/vekllei-domestic.png?q=100&amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;flag&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; padding: 0; background-color: transparent;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s International and Domestic Standards
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Administration of the Interior of the Government of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (also known as the &lt;em&gt;Interior Government&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Interior Parliament&lt;/em&gt;) represents the human state of the Vekllei Home Islands, as well as its dependent possessions. It includes all 100 &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/&#34;&gt;boroughs&lt;/a&gt; of the Home Islands and its peripheral island possessions. Independent Commonwealth member-states Demon and Aismious lack the population to govern themselves independently, and so are dependent on the Interior Government. Other members of the Commonwealth, including Kalina, Kala and Mira, have parliaments (also called Interior Administrations) similar to the Vekllei Administration of the Interior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Interior Government is made up of 10 ministries which retain total authority over the state in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-commerce&#34;&gt;Ministry of Commerce&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOSOL
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Ministry of Commerce&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOSOL) regulates and initiates trade in the country. Despite the functional moneylessness of the Commonwealth, COSMOSOL remains among the busiest ministries of the Interior Government, since all economic policy, international trade and entitled renumeration (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for withdrawing from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Labour Bank&lt;/a&gt;) occurs through its subordinate commissions. Common responsibilities of COSMOSOL include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulation and taxation of international trade, particularly through Government &amp;lsquo;White Bonds&amp;rsquo; and Labour Bank &amp;lsquo;Blue Bonds&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banking the Commonwealth state apparatus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advising the Parliament on economic policy and foreign trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitoring and reporting on the health of foreign markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Printing and transporting currency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei has a reputation as a financial capital for its political neutrality and location between Europe and the Americas, and is among the largest facilitators of international commerce and exchange in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Bank of Vekllei&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (commonly &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;) is the central bank and currency store of Vekllei. It is operated by the Ministry of Commerce and maintains branches in most major borough capitals in the Home Islands, as well as across all member states of the Vekllei Commonwealth. It is not autonomous and is beholden to the policy decisions of COSMOSOL and, in certain cases, the Interior and Commonwealth Parliaments. Its sworn purpose, as instructed by the Floral Constitution, is to advocate for Floral Economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bank of Vekllei was founded 1642 as the Royal Bank in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/boroughs/lola/&#34;&gt;Lola&lt;/a&gt;, and is the fifth oldest bank in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most banks in Vekllei are institutional or industrial, since the average Vekllei person is unmoneyed and, in a conventional definition, unbanked. Nonetheless, Vekllei maintains several commercial banks under the Bank of Vekllei umbrella, tasked primarily with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cashing and underwriting White and Blue bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling government and financial (bureau) bonds internationally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International placement and borrowing services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading, settling and selling foreign currencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei citizens are entitled to an equal share of the money stored in the Labour Bank, and in certain circumstances may withdraw their balance to emigrate or travel abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite foreign perception of Vekllei economics, the liquid and asset holdings of the Bank of Vekllei make it the second-largest bank in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;commonwealth-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Bank of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Commonwealth Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (COMMBANK) is an international investment subsidiary of the Bank of Vekllei, tasked primarily with banking in Commonwealth members and international markets. It has branches across every Commonwealth member-state and in most major economic hubs around the world, including throughout Europe, the Americas, and Asia. It also serves as the Central Bank of the Kalina Isles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;import-export-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Import-Export Bank of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Import-Export Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (VEKEXIM) is a state policy investment bank used to fund projects outside of the Commonwealth, particularly in developing countries. It is the primary investment mechanism of Vekllei foreign aid system, which uses export credits and low-interest bureau loans to build infrastructure overseas. It is among the most influential export banks in the world, and contributed to the Pan-African Railway and Hundred Dams projects as part of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s ongoing Trade Democracy economic scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;development-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Development Bank of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Development Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (DEVBANK) is a policy bank designed to organise and allocate funding for large-scale political projects, particularly in infrastructure. The Development Bank works as the engine of the Interior Government&amp;rsquo;s policies, funded mostly with White Bonds issued internationally and labour-guaranteed certificates (a type of Blue Bond). It also creates loan arrangements, evaluates, and underwrites national government projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;petty-bureau-labour-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Petty Bureau Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Petty Bureau Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (SISTERBANK) is the commercial lending bank of &amp;lsquo;petty bureau&amp;rsquo; company syndicates and their workers. Its primary function is bureau negotiation and lending in order to facilitate the economic development of private business in Vekllei. It also acts as an intermediary between petty bureau companies and other banks or government financial apparatuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;bureau-proper-labour-bank-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Bureau Proper Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Bureau Proper Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (MOTHERBANK) is the commercial lending bank of &amp;lsquo;bureau proper&amp;rsquo; company syndicates and their workers. Similar to the &lt;em&gt;Petty Bureau Labour Bank&lt;/em&gt;, it facilitates economic activity of bureaus and private industry primarily through asset management and mediation with the government and Bank of Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;national-mint-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;National Mint of Vekllei&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-24-crown/&#34;&gt;The Vekllei Crown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;National Mint of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (also the &lt;em&gt;Mint&lt;/em&gt;) is the sole producer of currency in Vekllei, tasked with minting and melting the Vekllei Crown. It also regulates gold bullion in the country, and manufactures bullion for use in the International Market. It is headquartered in Vekllei Proper, in the Home Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mint is the custodian of the Commonwealth Bullion Depository, which holds reserves of over 6,000 tonnes of gold bullion belonging to the Commonwealth and over 60 other countries, and is among the largest such reserves in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mint is well-regarded internationally for the purity of its metals and intricate commemorative coins, leading international numismatics in colour and variety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-securities-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Securities Commission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Securities Commission&lt;/em&gt; (VECSEC) regulates securities in the Vekllei International Market. It advises fiscal decision-making to the Interior Parliament and legislates trade practices in the country, including the issuing and ownership of government bonds and bureau securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Vekllei citizens do not usually participate in the domestic securities markets, VECSEC lacks traditional legal authority over many of the foreign participants in its supervised markets, but does extradite and prosecute financial crime through the EUROVEK and USVEK extradition treaties. It includes the following departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Council&lt;/strong&gt;: Advisory board to the Commonwealth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Procuratorate&lt;/strong&gt;: Enforcement of penalties and prosecution of financial crimes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Financing and Stock Exchange&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulation and monitoring of the Vekllei Stock Exchange and miscellaneous securities within the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of International Markets&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulation and monitoring of the Vekllei International Market and government bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Investments and Trusts&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulation and monitoring of the investments, securities and financial contracts of Vekllei citizens and companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-trade-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Trade Commission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Trade Commission&lt;/em&gt; regulates consumer protections and antitrust law, and organises trade information from other ministries and supervisory bureaus into policy recommendations and legislation. The Trade Commission also monitors and reports the health of foreign markets, and conducts research into broader geopolitical financial interests, particularly as they compete with domestic interests. It includes the following departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Consumer Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulation of the consumer rights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Market Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Protection of fair markets and regulation of Bureau and Petty Bureau companies, including state monopolies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Market Research&lt;/strong&gt;: Analysis and research of domestic and international markets, compiled and forwarded to other Interior Ministries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bureau of Economics&lt;/strong&gt;: Macroeconomic research relevant to international trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-the-commonwealth&#34;&gt;Ministry of the Commonwealth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOCOM
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Ministry of the Commonwealth&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOCOM) is the organ through which the Interior Government communicates and cooperates with the Commonwealth Administration and its Secretariats. Its primary responsibility is cooperation between member states and standardisation, and publishes reports and manuals towards this goal. It is also the primary ministry through which the parliaments and secretariats of the Commonwealth communicate with the Interior Government. COSMOCOM is also responsible for ensuring changes made to the Floral Constitution are implemented domestically. Common responsibilities of COSMOCOM include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advising, training and auditing local accreditation and qualifications in line with Commonwealth standards and directives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensuring that the Vekllei interior state meets standards determined by the Commonwealth parliaments and international commitments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing and enforcing standards in technical, industrial and brand features of the Vekllei Interior Government and its responsible state assets and bureau partners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training and maintaining the workforce for the Interior civil service and Interior state assets in line with Commonwealth standards and directives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COSMOCOM&amp;rsquo;s commitments to the transnational Commonwealth Parliaments go both ways &amp;ndash; the ministry ensures domestic compliance and also advises Commonwealth policy and standards, since the Vekllei Interior Government is the largest and most industrious member-state of the Commonwealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;accreditation-directorate&#34;&gt;Accreditation Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Accreditation Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;Qualifications Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; or VAD) is a transnational auditor of industrial, commercial and academic qualifications in Vekllei. VAD also develops technical and procedural standards for its responsible commercial and industrial partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standards in education for teachers and staff are generally developed and enforced by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#commonwealth-education-secretariat&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Education Secretariat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VDA also maintains a catalogue of products and technical manuals available to industry partners, and enforces compliance to industrial and commercial standards through its subordinate inspectorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-qualifications-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Qualifications Commission&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei Qualifications Commission (VQC) is the primary research organ of the VAD, and develops most of the qualifications standards and procedure policies of government ministries and state assets. Its research is primarily civil, and industrial and commercial qualifications are generally developed by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#standardisations-directorate&#34;&gt;Standardisations Directorate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-industrial-audit-committee&#34;&gt;Vekllei Industrial Audit Committee&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-commons-audit-committee&#34;&gt;Vekllei Commons Audit Committee&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Commons Audit Committee&lt;/em&gt; is the primary audit and survey body of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;inspectorate-vekllei&#34;&gt;Inspectorate Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Inspectorate&lt;/em&gt; surveys and audits technical standards in business, research and industry as the law-enforcement arm of the Accreditation Directorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey and Testing Group&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Market Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Protection of fair markets and regulation of Bureau and Petty Bureau companies, including state monopolies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Market Research&lt;/strong&gt;: Analysis and research of domestic and international markets, compiled and forwarded to other Interior Ministries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bureau of Economics&lt;/strong&gt;: Macroeconomic research relevant to international trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;civil-service-academy-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Civil Service Academy of Vekllei&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Civil Service Academy&lt;/em&gt; (VCSA) is a training school for middle and senior civil servants and interior policy researchers. Located in the borough of Callaisn in the Home Islands, it primarily trains servants of the domestic government apparatuses, and provides tertiary courses in governance and management related to its primary disciplines. The VCSA also trains directors of key state assets, and provides education resources for bureau industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Vekllei nationals in Commonwealth offices are also trained at the VCSA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;research-directorate&#34;&gt;Research Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Research Directorate&lt;/em&gt; conducts research and prepares policy objectives for use in Commonwealth governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of General Research&lt;/strong&gt;: Flexible, reactive policy and long-term research objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Stability&lt;/strong&gt;: Reactive and timely analysis of current affairs and events threatening the mandate and stability of the Commonwealth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Democracy&lt;/strong&gt;: Research that contributes to floral democracy, particularly as it operates at the borough and canton levels of government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Civil Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Research related to civil rights, demography and culture policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Commonwealth Economics and Trade&lt;/strong&gt;: Macroeconomic research in Commonwealth trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Reform&lt;/strong&gt;: Research related to Vekllei bureaucracy and the efficiency of its government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;standardisations-directorate&#34;&gt;Standardisations Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Standardisations Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (SSD, also Standards Vekllei) works to unify management and supervision of state bodies and assets in Vekllei. It also mandates the responsibilities and visual identity of all departments of the Government and boroughs of the Commonwealth, including the appearance and manuals of style of Commonwealth infrastructure and publications. Its work includes both operating procedures and major brand elements like flags and logos, and specific linguistic and typographic features including typefaces, preferred punctuation and symbols. It has considerable authority over other departments, which usually lack autonomy to enforce their own visual identity independently. Most visual work for the Standardisations Directorate is performed by in-house designers and artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Standardisations Directorate also represents Vekllei in the International Organisation for Standardisation and other industrial standards bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;standards-vekllei&#34;&gt;Standards Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;General Office of the Standardisations Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (GOSED), commonly &lt;em&gt;Standards Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;, administrates the directorate, and determines its operations through direct liaison with the Interior and Commonwealth Administrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;standards-press-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Standards Press of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publishing House organised vertically in the SSD to prepare and publish materials including technical manuals, standard compilation books, and industrial bulletins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;industrial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Industrial Standards of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Industrial Standards of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (INSTA) regulates industrial regulatory and safety standards of industrial and manufacturing work. It also advises industry groups on product certification, and acts as a Commonwealth prosecutor in criminal breaches or oversight of industrial standards. Insta is divided into sixteen technical committees that oversee particular industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;commercial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Commercial Standards of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Commercial Standards of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (COMSTA) regulates standards of small and medium-sized commercial businesses that are otherwise unaffiliated with bureaus proper. It also advises &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#standards-vekllei&#34;&gt;GOSED&lt;/a&gt; on changes to its technical, safety and design committees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since private commerce in Vekllei exists outside of the bureau framework, the license of COMSTA are broader and flexible, and regularly relies upon contracted industry contacts to fill places on its less defined technical committees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;state-assets-directorate&#34;&gt;State Assets Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;State Assets Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (SAD) manages state-owned companies across the Commonwealth, particularly those with considerable international trade. These include several major industrial companies in Vekllei, like General Reactor S.A.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;statistics-directorate&#34;&gt;Statistics Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Statistics Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (STD, also Statistics Vekllei) collects and publishes statistics concerning the economy, country and people of Vekllei. Along with other COSMOCOM directorates, the Statistics Directorate organises research into trends of Vekllei demography and geography. The STD also coordinates the Vekllei Census.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;statistics-press-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Statistics Press of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-electoral-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Electoral Commission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Electoral Commission&lt;/em&gt; conducts elections, by-elections and referendums in Vekllei. It also maintains the Vekllei Electoral Roll, and designs electorates, apportionments and redistributions in the Home Islands.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-defence&#34;&gt;Ministry of Defence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOKOS
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Ministry of Defence&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOKOS) represents the Sovereign Armed Forces of the Vekllei Commonwealth in the Vekllei Government, which are consolidated under the Commonwealth Military Command. COSMOKOS does not exercise command authority over the armed forces of Vekllei, and serves instead as the ministerial liaison between the Commonwealth Military Command and the Interior Government. Common responsibilities of COSMOKOS include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recruitment of citizens and foreigners into the Commonwealth armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procuring equipment to meet the Vekllei obligation towards the Commonwealth armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training citizens and foreigners for the branches of the Commonwealth armed forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducting scientific military research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Policing and security of Vekllei territories and waters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;armed-forces-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Armed Forces of Vekllei&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Armed Forces of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt;, arranged under the COSMOKOS ministry, are unusual in that they do not have control directly over troops or equipment. The actual armed forces of Vekllei, known as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#royal-armed-forces-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Royal&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#royal-armed-forces-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Crown Armed Forces&lt;/a&gt;, are a sovereign feature of the country and as such are placed under direct supervision of the Sovereign Administration &amp;ndash; seperate from the Vekllei and Commonwealth governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the Armed Forces of Vekllei, an agency-level body under control of COSMOKOS, is to integrate the Crown Armed Forces with the interior government, and facilitate the employ of Vekllei people in the Armed Forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;communications-bureau&#34;&gt;Communications Bureau&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Communications Bureau&lt;/em&gt; is a bureau-level organisation of the Armed Forces responsible for coordinating public information about military activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-compulsory-service&#34;&gt;Department of Compulsory Service&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Compulsory Service&lt;/em&gt; (DoCS, also CS) oversees the Vekllei Compulsory Service Scheme, a hybrid civilian/military conscription law that requires four years from each citizen between the ages of 18 and 32. Despite reporting to the Armed Forces of COSMOKOS, the DoCS does not facilitate widespread conscription and mobilisation of the civilian population, a role served by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#department-of-mobilisation&#34;&gt;DoM&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, it is responsible primarily for supervising the fulfilment of the Compulsory Service Scheme, and administrating the conscription and training of Vekllei citizens, including in civilian and industrial roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-foreign-affairs&#34;&gt;Department of Foreign Affairs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Foreign Affairs&lt;/em&gt; (DoFA) coordinates military affairs with states overseas, including members of the Commonwealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Public&lt;/strong&gt;: Press office that prepares public announcements and controls information to the press.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Overseas Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Flexible, reactive policy and long-term research objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Strategic Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;: Research that contributes to floral democracy, particularly as it operates at the borough and canton levels of government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-mobilisation&#34;&gt;Department of Mobilisation&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Mobilisation&lt;/em&gt; (DoM) is responsible for recruitment in peacetime, and conscription in the outbreak of war. In the Floral Period, Vekllei defensive doctrine aims to make the country &amp;ldquo;ungovernable,&amp;rdquo; requiring widespread mobilisation and training of the civilian population. Unlike the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#department-of-compulsory-service&#34;&gt;DoCS&lt;/a&gt;, the DoM is concerned primarily with the combat effectiveness of the mobilised population, and is generally distinguished in its strategic military thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-peacekeeping&#34;&gt;Department of Peacekeeping&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Department of Peacekeeping&lt;/em&gt; (DoP) coordinates Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s overseas peacekeeping operations. Vekllei is among the largest contributors of men and equipment towards United Nations Peacekeeping Forces, which&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;intelligence-liaison&#34;&gt;Intelligence Liaison&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Intelligence Liaison&lt;/em&gt; is a specialised office that coordinates military intelligence between Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s security apparatuses, particularly those of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#national-intelligence-directorate&#34;&gt;National Intelligence Directorate&lt;/a&gt;. Intelligence gathering in Vekllei is performed by a variety of mostly autonomous espionage organs, and the purpose of the Liaison is to authenticate and prepare intelligence for military use. It includes the following branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Intelligence Branch&lt;/strong&gt;: Coordination of intelligence gathered by security apparatuses with Armed Forces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civilian Intelligence Branch&lt;/strong&gt;: Coordination of intelligence gathered by industrial and civilian sectors (in occupied territories, for example) with Armed Forces and security apparatuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic Intelligence Branch&lt;/strong&gt;: Coordination of intelligence gathered by the Armed Forces with security apparatuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;sovereign-liaison&#34;&gt;Sovereign Liaison&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Sovereign Liaison&lt;/em&gt; is a specialised office intended to link the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#royal-armed-forces-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Royal Armed Forces of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; with COSMOKOS, an interior ministry with no direct control over troops of the Crown. Although it is the &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; office of communication with the Crown forces, in practice communication generally occurs directly with the relevant COSMOKOS department. The purpose of the Sovereign Liaison is mostly as a democracy-advocate, supervising the COSMOKOS departments as an anti-corruption watchdog similar to other democracy-advocates. It also ensures COSMOKOS operations do not affect sovereign operations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;police-of-the-parliament&#34;&gt;Police of the Parliament&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Police of the Parliament&lt;/em&gt; (VENOPOR) are the national and paramilitary police of Vekllei, responsible for internal security, riot control, counter-terrorism, disaster response, law enforcement and maritime rights protection. The VENOPOR is made up of a variety of organisations dedicated to specialised and tactical forms of policing unavailable to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#police-of-the-public&#34;&gt;Police of the Public&lt;/a&gt;. As a paramilitary force, the VENOPOR are also trained to support the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#royal-armed-forces-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Crown Armed Forces&lt;/a&gt; in wartime, and coordinate broad mobilisation in the event of a defensive war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VENOPOR is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;coast-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;Coast Guard of the Parliament Police&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-11-14-coastguard/&#34;&gt;The Vekllei Coast Guard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Coast Guard&lt;/em&gt; (also the &lt;em&gt;Navy of the Parliament&lt;/em&gt; or the &lt;em&gt;Coast Guard of the Parliament Police&lt;/em&gt;) is the maritime naval police of Vekllei responsible for search and rescue and law enforcement in the territorial waters of Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the Commonwealth Security Concordat, the Vekllei Coast Guard also provides maritime policing services to members of the Commonwealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;customs-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;Customs of the Parliament Police&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Customs of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (also the &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Customs&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Customs of the Parliament Police&lt;/em&gt;) are responsible for customs and excise duties in Vekllei (and, largely, the Commonwealth). It is also the law enforcement agency responsible for the import and export of goods in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;mint-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;Mint Guard of the Parliament Police&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-09-sappers/&#34;&gt;Gold Sappers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Mint Guard&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;Gold Sappers&lt;/em&gt;) are responsible for the security of financial assets in Vekllei, particularly currency and gold reserves minted and held by the Vekllei National Mint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;judicial-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;Judicial Guard of the Parliament Police&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;special-guard-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;Special Guard of the Parliament Police&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;militia-of-the-parliament-police&#34;&gt;Militia of the Parliament Police&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;police-of-the-public&#34;&gt;Police of the Public&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Police of the Public&lt;/em&gt; (COSMOPOR) are the local police in Vekllei, mostly constabulary responsible for local policing.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-foreign-affairs&#34;&gt;Ministry of Foreign Affairs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOSEA
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;communications-bureau&#34;&gt;Communications Bureau&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;international-affairs-directorate&#34;&gt;International Affairs Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-african-affairs&#34;&gt;Department of African Affairs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-american-affairs&#34;&gt;Department of American Affairs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-asian-affairs&#34;&gt;Department of Asian Affairs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-european-affairs&#34;&gt;Department of European Affairs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-west-asian-affairs&#34;&gt;Department of West Asian Affairs&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;domestic-affairs-directorate&#34;&gt;Domestic Affairs Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;department-of-consular-affairs&#34;&gt;Department of Consular Affairs&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;department-of-protocol-and-culture&#34;&gt;Department of Protocol and Culture&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;department-of-press-and-news-media&#34;&gt;Department of Press and News Media&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;world-missions-directorate&#34;&gt;World Missions Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;World Missions Directorate&lt;/em&gt; is the formal foreign policymaking apparatus of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare bulletins from Parliamentary and Secretarial notes on foreign affairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formulate cohesive positions on events of domestic concern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outline a consistent Commonwealth foreign policy to determine and advise decision-making in future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-industry&#34;&gt;Ministry of Industry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOSEC
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;bureaus-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Bureaus of Vekllei&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;production-surveillance-bureau&#34;&gt;Production Surveillance Bureau&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;workers-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Workers of Vekllei&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;workplace-safety-commission&#34;&gt;Workplace Safety Commission&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;labour-democracy-commission&#34;&gt;Labour Democracy Commission&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-infrastructure&#34;&gt;Ministry of Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOTRAN
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-social-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Social Commission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-housing-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Housing Commission&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Housing Commission&lt;/em&gt; is a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-gardens-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Gardens Commission&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-media-authority&#34;&gt;Vekllei Media Authority&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-nature-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Nature Commission&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&#34;crown-lands-protectorate&#34;&gt;Crown Lands Protectorate&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-landscape&#34;&gt;Ministry of Landscape&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOGOS
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-agriculture-directorate&#34;&gt;Vekllei Agriculture Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-materials-directorate&#34;&gt;Vekllei Materials Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-conservation-directorate&#34;&gt;Vekllei Conservation Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;commercial-standards-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Commercial Standards of Vekllei&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-light-and-water&#34;&gt;Ministry of Light and Water&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOLA
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-electric-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Electric Commission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (VEC, also Thunderburo) is responsible for the state monopoly on electricity generation in Vekllei. Although the VEC is structured as a bureau company, its subsidiaries are state-owned and consequently operates similarly to other agency-level departments of the Interior Government. The VEC consists of multiple subcommissions dedicated to unique types of electricity generation in Vekllei, primarily through hydro-electric, geothermal and nuclear methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;magma-electric-commission&#34;&gt;Magma-Electric Commission&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Magma-Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (colloquially &lt;em&gt;The Magma&lt;/em&gt;) oversees geothermal electricity production in Vekllei. Because of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s location over the rift of the European and American continental plates, widespread geothermal electricity production is widespread and makes up the majority of commercial and domestic electricity consumption in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;hydro-electric-commission&#34;&gt;Hydro-Electric Commission&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Hydro-Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (colloquially &lt;em&gt;The Hydro&lt;/em&gt;, not to be confused with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#vekllei-water-commission&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hydroburo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) oversees hydro-electric electricity generation in Vekllei, particularly in the glacial regions of the Home Islands and Kala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;nuclear-electric-commission&#34;&gt;Nuclear-Electric Commission&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei &lt;em&gt;Nuclear-Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;Atomic Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; or NEC) oversees nuclear electricity generation in Vekllei.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-water-commission&#34;&gt;Vekllei Water Commission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vekllei Electric Commission&lt;/em&gt; (Hydroburo)
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;emergency-light-and-water-authority&#34;&gt;Emergency Light and Water Authority&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Emergency Light and Water Authority&lt;/em&gt; (EVA) is a specialised department of the Ministry of Light and Water designed to mitigate interruption to electricity and water supply. Its mandate includes the security of utility infrastructure and disaster preparation. In the event of major interruption to the utilities supervised by the Ministry, the EVA would assume direct control of the Hydro and Thunderburos and coordinate their recovery. Threats include both natural disasters like volcanic eruptions and earthquakes, as well as damage from conventional or nuclear war.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-transport&#34;&gt;Ministry of Transport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOPOS
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-national-rail-bureau&#34;&gt;Vekllei National Rail Bureau&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/rail/&#34;&gt;Railways in Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vekllei National Rail Bureau is the parent bureau for all rail transport in Vekllei. Its subordinate organisations hold a monopoly on rail transport in the country and its maintenance, including manufacturing, research and administration.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-national-roads-and-pathways-bureau&#34;&gt;Vekllei National Roads and Pathways Bureau&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-national-skies-bureau&#34;&gt;Vekllei National Skies Bureau&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-national-seas-bureau&#34;&gt;Vekllei National Seas Bureau&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;national-transport-laboratories&#34;&gt;National Transport Laboratories&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ministry-of-syndicates-and-chapels&#34;&gt;Ministry of Syndicates and Chapels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COSMOLAB
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;office-of-the-syndicate-general&#34;&gt;Office of the Syndicate-General&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;office-of-the-chapel-general&#34;&gt;Office of the Chapel-General&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;administration-of-the-commonwealth&#34;&gt;Administration of the Commonwealth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mastheads/flags/aismious.png?q=100&amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;flag&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; padding: 0; background-color: transparent;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mastheads/flags/azores.png?q=100&amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;flag&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; padding: 0; background-color: transparent;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mastheads/flags/demon.png?q=100&amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;flag&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; padding: 0; background-color: transparent;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mastheads/flags/kala.png?q=100&amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;flag&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; padding: 0; background-color: transparent;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mastheads/flags/kalina.png?q=100&amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;flag&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; padding: 0; background-color: transparent;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mastheads/flags/mira.png?q=100&amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;flag&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; padding: 0; background-color: transparent;&#34; &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although each member of the Atlantic Commonwealth is considered a full participant of equal importance, administration in practice occurs in the Vekllei &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/&#34;&gt;Home Islands&lt;/a&gt;, its most populous and industrious member state. Many features of Floral Society are universal among Commonwealth members, and the Administration of the Commonwealth serves, maintains and standardises the values of Floral Society across the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;commonwealth-culture-secretariat&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Culture Secretariat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  COLSEC
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Commonwealth Culture Secretariat&lt;/em&gt; (COLSEC) is concerned primarily with &amp;lsquo;cultural values and beliefs&amp;rsquo; of the Commonwealth, their protection, and foreign relations. Its subordinate offices are dedicated to key areas of concern designed to assist its smaller member-states which may lack the political infrastructure to facilitate their own offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;commonwealth-affairs-office&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Affairs Office&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COLSEC &lt;em&gt;Commonwealth Affairs Office&lt;/em&gt; (COLSA) is responsible for the documentation of the general disposition, welfare, culture and demography of the people of the Commonwealth. This includes political attitudes towards the Commonwealth itself, as well as how decisions made by other Secretariats impact public opinion. It is also the body-advocate of the public of member states who are unable to appeal to their local government directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;religious-affairs-office&#34;&gt;Religious Affairs Office&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COLSEC &lt;em&gt;Religious Affairs Office&lt;/em&gt; (COLSERE) is responsible for reporting religious trends across the Commonwealth, particularly as they intersect with religious infrastructure (places of worship and natural shrines) and organised religion. Its focus is mostly external, since the &lt;em&gt;Upen&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s animism in the Home Islands lacks conventional religious hierarchies. COLSERE also serves as an advisory body to COLSEC command and as reporting agency for discrimination and concerns of faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;veteran-affairs-office&#34;&gt;Veteran Affairs Office&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COLSEC &lt;em&gt;Veteran Affairs Office&lt;/em&gt; (COLVET) is responsible for organising healthcare, housing and support for all former members of the Commonwealth Armed Forces. It also serves as an advocacy body for veterans themselves, especially in arguing for material support from other departments within the government. COLVET is also responsible for formulating and advising policy on veteran affairs to Commonwealth and Interior Parliaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;civil-affairs-office&#34;&gt;Civil Affairs Office&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COLSEC &lt;em&gt;Civil Affairs Office&lt;/em&gt; (COLSECA) is responsible for the health of the government of its member states and the maintenance of COLSEC guidelines on Floral Society. It serves as a political school for Floral politics and as the support mechanism for natural disasters, public unrest and other threats to the stability of its member states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;cultural-heritage-affairs-office&#34;&gt;Cultural Heritage Affairs Office&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COLSEC Cultural Heritage Affairs Office (COLSEHE)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;overseas-affairs-office&#34;&gt;Overseas Affairs Office&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The COLSEC Overseas Affairs Office (COLSESEA) coordinates the foreign offices of the Commonwealth, particularly for states that lack their own foreign affairs offices in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/territories/kalina&#34;&gt;Kalina&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/landscape/territories/west&#34;&gt;West Antilles&lt;/a&gt;. It also serves as an advisory board for policy and trade with other countries, particularly as they interact with autonomous states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;commonwealth-records-and-telegraph-directorate&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Records and Telegraph Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-press-bureau&#34;&gt;Vekllei Press Bureau&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;commonwealth-sports-directorate&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Sports Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;commonwealth-telecommunications-directorate&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Telecommunications Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;commonwealth-tourism-directorate&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Tourism Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&#34;commonwealth-security-secretariat&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Security Secretariat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  OPSEC
&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Commonwealth Security Secretariat&lt;/em&gt; (OPSEC) is the mother organisation of the internal and external security organs of the Vekllei government. These include intelligence gathering, espionage, special policing, and state security apparatuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most features of the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;national-intelligence-directorate&#34;&gt;National Intelligence Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;National Intelligence Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (N.I.) the secret service of the Commonwealth and Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s primary covert intelligence apparatus abroad. It is concerned with intelligence-gathering, surveillance and operations external to the Commonwealth. It comprises of 40 semiautonomous outlines, which each may operate several offices. This complex and comprehensive intelligence organisation contributes to its legendary reputation abroad, and conspiracies of its presence in almost every country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The N.I. is unique in its broad recruitment of foreigners, many of whom are promised citizenship and residency in Vekllei. Many N.I. outlines recruit locally, and manage foreign assets through Vekllei-born supervisors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;home-office-honi&#34;&gt;Home Office (HO/NI)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Home Office&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;em&gt;National Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (HO/NI) is the domestic intelligence organisation of the Vekllei Commonwealth, including the Home Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It includes the following departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 1 &lt;em&gt;Atlantique&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Administration and recruitment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 2 &lt;em&gt;Bohs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Organisation security and democracy-advocate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 3 &lt;em&gt;Cosette&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Politics and domestic affairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 4 &lt;em&gt;Devon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Democracy-Advocate command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 5 &lt;em&gt;Eusea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Logistics and training command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 6 &lt;em&gt;Familia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in South Vekllei.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 7 &lt;em&gt;Gem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in East Vekllei.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 8 &lt;em&gt;Helette&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in West Vekllei.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 9 &lt;em&gt;Ioviosn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in North Vekllei.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 10 &lt;em&gt;Jasvere&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in the Commonwealth member states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 11 &lt;em&gt;Kosmo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Senior reporting body and command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 12 &lt;em&gt;Los&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Internal regulation and operations command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;africa-bureau-rbni&#34;&gt;Africa Bureau (RB/NI)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Africa Bureau&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;em&gt;National Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (RB/NI) reports information and conducts operations in the African continent. Headquartered in Casablanca, Morocco, RB/NI is particularly concerned with decolonisation and influencing new democratic states under Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Trade Democracy&amp;rdquo; policy. It also historically seeks to destabilising American and Eastern Bloc influence in the continent, as well as ferment unrest against current colonial governments and the Apartheid regime in South Africa. It includes the following departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 13 &lt;em&gt;Abosasme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in postcolonial Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 14 &lt;em&gt;Bulga&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in colonial Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 15 &lt;em&gt;Cobian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Regional tactical operations command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 16 &lt;em&gt;Domo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Democracy-Advocate command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 17 &lt;em&gt;Ende&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Directorate organisation and localisation command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;americas-bureau-abni&#34;&gt;Americas Bureau (AB/NI)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Americas Bureau&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;em&gt;National Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (AB/NI) reports information and conducts operations across North and South America, including overseas possessions of the United States and regional claims in the Arctic and Antarctic. AB/NI maintains major offices in Washington D.C. in the U.S., Dallas in Dallas America, and Bogotá in Colombia. It is the largest of the N.I. Bureaus, with nearly a hundred satellite offices across the Americas. Its operations are classified, but are implicated in a variety of work including regime change and guerrilla training. AB/NI also fosters positive relations with the regional neighbours of the Commonwealth, particularly in Mexico, British Belize, Venezuela and Colombia. It includes the following departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 18 &lt;em&gt;Anatole&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in the United States and Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 19 &lt;em&gt;Bosme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in Mexico and Central America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 20 &lt;em&gt;Célestine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in South America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 21 &lt;em&gt;Désiré&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Regional tactical operations command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 22 &lt;em&gt;Eudea&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Regional logistics and training command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 23 &lt;em&gt;François&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Antifascist and separatist affairs intelligence command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 24 &lt;em&gt;Gosme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Directorate organisation command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;euro-bureau-ebni&#34;&gt;Euro Bureau (EB/NI)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;European Bureau&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;em&gt;National Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (EB/NI) reports information and conducts operations across Europe and Eurasia, particularly in the UK, France, and the Eastern Bloc. It is second-largest of the regional N.I. bureaus, with offices in London, Paris, Prague, Moscow, and Genoa, and dozens more satellite installations throughout Europe. Its intelligence doctrine is particularly defensive, since most foreign espionage in the Commonwealth originates from Western and Communist Europe, and operates special counter-espionage units for this purpose. It includes the following departments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 25 &lt;em&gt;Ana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in Western Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 26 &lt;em&gt;Basa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in Minor Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 27 &lt;em&gt;Cofa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in states signatory to the Treaty of Friendship, Cooperation and Mutual Assistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 28 &lt;em&gt;Demon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Special counter-espionage command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 29 &lt;em&gt;Eiga&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Directorate organisation and localisation command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;oriental-bureau-obni&#34;&gt;Oriental Bureau (OB/NI)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Oriental Bureau&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;em&gt;National Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (OB/NI) reports information and conducts operations across the Orient and West Asia, Vekllei phrases spanning from the Middle East to the Pacific Islands, including South and East Asia. It maintains offices in Tokyo, Peking, Bangkok, Delhi, and Tehran. Without vested strategic interests in the area, OB/NI&amp;rsquo;s primary mission is nation-building and observation in its region and the support of actions in its neighbouring N.I. regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 30 &lt;em&gt;Asosnia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in Communist China and Taiwan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 31 &lt;em&gt;Bouismiosn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in Japan and South-East Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 32 &lt;em&gt;Cismi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 33 &lt;em&gt;Drosviousn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in the Middle East.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 34 &lt;em&gt;Erswin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Directorate organisation and localisation command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 35 &lt;em&gt;Fennet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Counter-espionage and political command.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;special-protectorate-bureau-spni&#34;&gt;Special Protectorate Bureau (SP/NI)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Special Protectorate Bureau&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;em&gt;National Intelligence&lt;/em&gt; (SP/NI) reports information and conducts operations across special territories and possessions of the Commonwealth, including military sites, the Vekllei Antarctic Claims, and the Lunar Territories. Although its home office is in Vekllei Proper at N.I.,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 36 &lt;em&gt;Arcos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in postcolonial Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 37 &lt;em&gt;Boris&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in colonial Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 38 &lt;em&gt;Codesta&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in colonial Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 39 &lt;em&gt;Decrest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in colonial Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section 40 &lt;em&gt;Endoria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Offices and staff in colonial Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;public-security-directorate&#34;&gt;Public Security Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;state-security-directorate&#34;&gt;State Security Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;state-secrets-office&#34;&gt;State Secrets Office&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;commonwealth-education-secretariat&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Education Secretariat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  CHICOM
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Commonwealth Education Secretariat&lt;/em&gt; (CHICOM) is the commonwealth body responsible for all state education across the Commonwealth, including compulsory primary, vocational and tertiary schooling. Alongside the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#accreditation-directorate&#34;&gt;COSMOCOM Accreditation Directorate&lt;/a&gt;, CHICOM certifies teachers and the Commonwealth curriculum, and publishes textbooks and learning materials via the Children&amp;rsquo;s and Tertiary Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stated mission of CHICOM is the celebration of knowledge and the development of technical skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHICOM also overseas Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s four learned societies, called academies, which offer immortal membership to remarkable contributors to learning in Vekllei. The Academies of the Commonwealth are funded by a bureau tithe, mandated but otherwise seperate from Commonwealth government apparatuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-public-education-directorate&#34;&gt;Vekllei Public Education Directorate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Public Education Directorate&lt;/em&gt; oversees all compulsory education across the Commonwealth, including both government and vocational schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-primary-education-directorate&#34;&gt;Vekllei Primary Education Directorate&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;vekllei-higher-education-directorate&#34;&gt;Vekllei Higher Education Directorate&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;all-commonwealth-school-directorate&#34;&gt;All-Commonwealth School Directorate&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;All-Commonwealth School Directorate&lt;/em&gt; (ACC) manages the local production of school materials, particularly uniforms and textbooks, and ensures their availability and quality for students. The ACC is not involved in teaching or study itself, and instead serves learning infrastructure, including the maintenance and renewal of existing school buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;common-childrens-press&#34;&gt;Common Children&amp;rsquo;s Press&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;common-tertiary-press&#34;&gt;Common Tertiary Press&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;vekllei-national-laboratories&#34;&gt;Vekllei National Laboratories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vekllei National Laboratories&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;National Labs&lt;/em&gt;) is the administrator of the National Laboratory Complex in Amenmer, Coyenstisn, and the National Laboratory System across Commonwealth-level universities and academies in Vekllei.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;academy-of-natural-sciences&#34;&gt;Academy of Natural Sciences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Crown Academy of Natural Sciences&lt;/em&gt; is the sovereign (commonwealth-level) academy of natural sciences in the Commonwealth. It functions primarily as a research institute of distinguished academicians and scientific body that advises policy. Headquartered in the Home Islands, it has hundreds of branch institutes across the Commonwealth and in Rome, London and Beijing. These branches are organised along 7 academic divisions, each subdivided into hundreds of individual departments. It is the oldest of the academies, founded by the Crown Sovereign in 1527.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Chemistry&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of atomic and molecular matter and chemical processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Medicine&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of anatomy, physiology and healthcare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Mathematics and Physics&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of the constituents of the universe, natural forces, and mathematics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Technology and Materials&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of matter, its properties, machines and technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Astronomy&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of celestial phenomena.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Geography&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of geography, geology and oceanography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Biology&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of living organisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;academy-of-engineering-sciences&#34;&gt;Academy of Engineering Sciences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Crown Academy of Engineering Sciences&lt;/em&gt; is the sovereign (commonwealth-level) academy of engineering in the Commonwealth. Its membership of nearly 1,000 academicians are considered to have made invaluable contributions to engineering sciences, and hold lifelong tenure at the academy. It includes six schools, which conduct research and consultancy with the Commonwealth and Interior Administrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Mechanical and Vehicle Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of atomic and molecular matter and chemical processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Electrical Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of anatomy, physiology and healthcare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Chemical Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of the constituents of the universe, natural forces, and mathematics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Civil Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of matter, its properties, machines and technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Agricultural Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies of celestial phenomena.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;academy-of-philosophy&#34;&gt;Academy of Philosophy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Philosophy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School Sociology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Theology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;academy-of-political-sciences&#34;&gt;Academy of Political Sciences&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Law&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of Political Economics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School of History and Geography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;commonwealth-construction-secretariat&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Construction Secretariat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  CONSEC
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;commonwealth-labour-secretariat&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Labour Secretariat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  LABSEC
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;commonwealth-health-secretariat&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Health Secretariat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  HELSEC
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;administration-of-the-crown&#34;&gt;Administration of the Crown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  SOVA
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Commonwealth Administration of the Crown&lt;/em&gt;, not to be confused with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#palace-of-the-vekllei-sovereign&#34;&gt;Palace of the Vekllei Sovereign&lt;/a&gt;, is the administration-level apparatus of the Commonwealth to coordinate policy with the Palace. Since the Commonwealth does not have direct authority of the features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vekllei-democracy-commissariat&#34;&gt;Vekllei Democracy Commissariat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  DEMCOM
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fair-work-authority&#34;&gt;Fair Work Authority&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;b class=&#34;boxtag pink&#34;&gt;
  FAIRWORK
&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Fair Work Authority&lt;/em&gt; (FWA) is the Commonwealth industrial relations tribunal and regulator of industrial awards, a type of standard protected by the rulings of the FWA. It is let by a Chief Justice appointed by the Commonwealth Procuratorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;quality-of-life-surveillance-commission&#34;&gt;Quality of Life Surveillance Commission&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-29-qlc/&#34;&gt;The Quality of Life Surveillance Commission&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;office-of-the-auditor-general&#34;&gt;Office of the Auditor-General&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;office-of-the-secretary-general&#34;&gt;Office of the Secretary-General&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;petitions-office&#34;&gt;Petitions Office&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;courts-of-the-commonwealth&#34;&gt;Courts of the Commonwealth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;procuratorate-of-the-commonwealth&#34;&gt;Procuratorate of the Commonwealth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;high-courts-of-the-vekllei-commonwealth&#34;&gt;High Courts of the Vekllei Commonwealth&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;High Courts&lt;/em&gt; of Vekllei are the superior courts of record with inherent procedural and contempt power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also has appellate jurisdiction from Lower Courts where appropriate, particularly regarding civil matters of significant compensation. Historically, High Courts have jurisdiction over monopoly bureaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have unlimited jurisdiction in law and equity, or at least are not subject to jurisdictional limits as to the remedies they may grant;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;determine appeals, at least as part of their jurisdiction;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are composed of judges whose individual decisions are not subject to judicial review or appeal to a single judge;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are composed of judges entitled to the The Honourable Justice; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regularly publish their decisions in written form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei &lt;em&gt;High Courts&lt;/em&gt; are also&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;supreme-censorate&#34;&gt;Supreme Censorate&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Supreme Censorate&lt;/em&gt; is a an administrative court and anti-corruption agency tasked with combatting corruption and malfeasance in the state and its economic organs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;high-courts-of-the-justiciary&#34;&gt;High Courts of the Justiciary&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;high-courts-of-the-sovereign&#34;&gt;High Courts of the Sovereign&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Courts of the Sovereign&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;Sovereign Magistrates&lt;/em&gt; are Vekllei superior courts with jurisdiction over land and architecture, and serve an inquisitorial role in determining ownership via the Vekllei Delicture system. Land in Vekllei &amp;lsquo;owns itself&amp;rsquo; under this system, and relationships with land are brokered via the Borough Municipal Agent. Ownership is proven to the Sovereign Magistrates via the history of residency, use of the land and self-interest of property as determined by teams of Court Inquisitors, who determine the history and intent of land. The appellate justice of the Sovereign Courts are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/government/#procuratorate-of-the-commonwealth&#34;&gt;Commonwealth Procuratorates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;lower-courts-of-the-vekllei-commonwealth&#34;&gt;Lower Courts of the Vekllei Commonwealth&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Commonwealth, Lower Courts refer to Magistratures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;courts-of-the-magistrate&#34;&gt;Courts of the Magistrate&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Courts of the Magistrate&lt;/em&gt; (also &lt;em&gt;Borough Magistrates&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Petty Courts&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Local Courts&lt;/em&gt;) refer to lower courts attached to civil cases in borough jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;courts-of-the-people&#34;&gt;Courts of the People&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;extensive social warrants of the state (the rights to a job, free education, free healthcare, retirement at 60 for men and 55 for women, maternity leave, free disability benefits and sick leave compensation, subsidies to multichildren families, &amp;hellip;) in return for a high degree of social mobilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the judicial process lacks an [[adversarial system|adversarial]] character; public prosecution is considered as &amp;ldquo;provider of justice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;partial or total expulsion of the former [[ruling classes]] from the public life at early stages of existence of each socialist state; however, in all socialist states this policy gradually changed into the policy of &amp;ldquo;one socialist nation without classes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diversity of political views directly discouraged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the ruling Communist party was eventually subject to prosecution through party committees in first place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abolition of [[Private property#Socialist perspectives|private property]], thus near total collectivization and nationalization of the means of production;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subordination of the judiciary to the Communist Party&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low respect for [[privacy]], extensive control of the party over private life;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;low respect for [[intellectual property]] as knowledge and culture was considered a right for human kind, and not a privilege as in the free market economies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;office-of-the-attorney-general&#34;&gt;Office of the Attorney-General&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;office-of-the-democracy-advocate&#34;&gt;Office of the Democracy-Advocate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Office of the Democracy-Advocate&lt;/em&gt; (also the &lt;em&gt;Democracy Magistrate&lt;/em&gt;) is a unique judicial office of Vekllei law, acting in practice as a sort of superior appellate procurator to hear and advise judicial grievances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 1.2; font-size: 1.5rem; font-weight: 700; filter: brightness(35%);&#34;&gt;Palace of the Vekllei Sovereign&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 100%;&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;Ζ&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Since most Vekllei people&lt;/strong&gt; catch a train each day, VNR is a uniquely intimate and treasured organ of the Vekllei state. It is somehow exempted from the public apathy and resentment of bureaucracy that targets other monopolies of the Vekllei state, and is routinely regarded as among the most beloved and appreciated &amp;ldquo;companies&amp;rdquo; in Vekllei.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government of Vekllei is made up of Ministries, Offices, Bureaus, Commissions, Directorates and Secretariats depending on the size, purpose and organisation of the organ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;royal-armed-forces-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Royal Armed Forces of Vekllei&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crown-army-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Crown Army of Vekllei&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crown-navy-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Crown Navy of Vekllei&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crown-air-service-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Crown Air Service of Vekllei&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crown-rocket-navy-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Crown Rocket Navy of Vekllei&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crown-mail-of-vekllei&#34;&gt;Crown Mail of Vekllei&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Main article: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail&#34;&gt;The Crown Mail of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;general-office&#34;&gt;General Office&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;outline &#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&#34;office-of-the-postmistress&#34;&gt;Office of the Postmistress&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;protectorate-of-the-land-sovereign&#34;&gt;Protectorate of the Land Sovereign&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-police-of-the-crown&#34;&gt;The Police of the Crown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advocate-of-the-parliament&#34;&gt;Advocate of the Parliament&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;office-of-the-prime-minister&#34;&gt;Office of the Prime Minister&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
/* flags */
.row {
  display: flex;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
}
.column {
  flex: 33.33%;
  padding: 10px;
}
@media (max-width: 1250px) {
  .row {
    display: none;
  }
}
&lt;/style&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mail</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.gt-container {
  display: none;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; society
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt; is perhaps the country&amp;rsquo;s most visible organisation overseas. For many foreigners, Royal Mail aircraft may be the closest they ever come to seeing for themselves the mysterious Atlantic country. For Vekllei residents, the ancient organisation is a living relic of the country&amp;rsquo;s ancient history, and an ongoing testament to the longevity of their people.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;, referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;Mail&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Mail A.r.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; within the country, is the national postal carrier of &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;. It is a military state requisite reponsible for all postage in the country, and delivers nearly 50 million mail pieces domestically and abroad each day. One of the oldest institutions of its kind in Vekllei, it was founded in 1422 as a courier system between the Vekllei Kingdom and its largely mercenary military force. In 1742, it was formalised as a modern postal system available to the civilian public, and today offers a variety of services available to all Vekllei residents, including external territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is also home to the U.N. Universal Postal Union, the body responsible for coordinating international postage, of which Vekllei is a signatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-22-pond/&#34;&gt;Post is for People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail is old enough to have its own hieroglyph in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/language/#3-topet&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Topet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which has resulted in the somewhat misleading transliteration of its name. In Vekllei, it is simply called the &amp;lsquo;Mail&amp;rsquo;, since its written name includes both its royal and national meanings intrinsically. Abroad, this is usually translated as the Royal Mail of Vekllei, but this is in fact more of a description of the organisation than its proper name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Vekllei refers to its territory as its sovereign (expressed commonly as the &amp;lsquo;Landscape Sovereign&amp;rsquo;), the Mail remains Royal even today, centuries after the collapse of the monarchy that founded it. Despite its regular function as a postal service, it is nonetheless considered a resource of landscape, not a government department, and so it remains &amp;ldquo;the Royal Mail of Vekllei&amp;rdquo; in the 21st Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/fairie.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  An MS Model 54-2 &amp;ldquo;Fairie,&amp;rdquo; used to deliver mail to Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s islands and islets | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/&#34;&gt;The Fairie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most Royal Bureaus, the Mail is headquartered in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s capital across a dozen or so city blocks dedicated to administration, manufacturing, vehicle storage and maintenance, and Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s General Post Office. There are over 6,400 post offices in Vekllei today, connecting the dense Home Islands to its far-flung peripheral territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-01-mail/&#34;&gt;The Men and Women of the Royal Mail in Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei has maintained courier systems for at least a thousand years, the Mail as a contiguous instituion was founded in 1422 by the Desimou VII, King of Vekllei, in the late Period of Rest. During this time, the lords of Vekllei had established significant mercantile holdings across the North Atlantic, and had developed reliable systems of trade throughout Ireland and Denmark. The Royal Mail of Vekllei was first established as a royal communications organ that sought to ensure stability of the Desimou rule across the incresingly autonomous Vekllei empire. In this period, the Mail consisted of a handful of messengers attached to the feudal military apparatus of the Vekllei monarchy, which transferred to the incoming Junta upon collapse of the monarchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/pond.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail would not come to resemble conventional civilian Mail until 1652, when the Junta expanded postal contracts to the privy councils of the Faroe and Greenland territories, and later broke apart the Mail monopoly to benefit then-Secretary of State Kism Sismiosnah, who established the New Parliament Postal Service. It was not until nearly a century later, in 1742, that company services were opened to all land-owning Vekllei people, and the Mail came to resemble its contemporary mandate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail was reestablished in 2015, during Vekllei independence. It was afforded a mandate protected by the postwar &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/#floral-society&#34;&gt;Petticoat Constitution&lt;/a&gt;, and all existing private mail services established in occupation were folded directly into the new state monopoly. In 2016, a year after reestablishment, Mi Miou was elected as the world&amp;rsquo;s first female Postmistress General. The Floral Period of the Royal Mail has been marked by a rapid expansion of both infrastructure and services in Vekllei and abroad. World Post, the international for-profit arm of the Mail, was established in 2034.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-02-postmistress/&#34;&gt;The Postmistress of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail is organised horizontally as an independent branch of the Royal Vekllei Armed Forces, and so, unlike other State Requisites, reports directly to the Prime Ministers of the Vekllei Government, as representatives of the Landscape Sovereign. As is common with most large-scale industry in Vekllei, the Mail is vertically integrated, and the majority of its contract work is consolidated directly into the bureau structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail has two offices of administration: the General Office and the Office of the Postmistress, which are responsible for daily operations and interdepartmental administration respectively. The following table outlines the Mail&amp;rsquo;s structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;The Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Office&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Royal Mail Press
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bulletin of the Mail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Materials Manufacturie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Services Bureau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special Services Office
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postal Inspection Offices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joint HO/NI Postal Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overseas Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Post Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Express Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Mail&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VK Mail Chapel (VKC 1st Mail Workers Unite)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service Assurance Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Telecommunications&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma Vekllei&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosma Overseas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial Telecommunications Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of Company Infrastructure&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Post Boxes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Vehicles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Postmistress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Commission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Democracy Office&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;services&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/&#34;&gt;Philately Foolery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The Royal Mail&lt;/strong&gt; maintains a constitutionally-bound monopoly on all postage in the country, leaving it the sole provider of universal postage service in Vekllei. Like most State Requisites (A.r.), however, it has substantial international trade and foreign dealings that provide for its common description as a state-owned for-profit enterprise, or public corporation.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal service is&lt;/strong&gt;, by the glossary of the Mail, truly universal. As mandated by Vekllei law, the Mail provides delivery for all postage material anywhere in the world, or indeed, beyond it. It maintains 6,424 post offices across Vekllei, including its antarctic and peripheral possessions. The Mail&amp;rsquo;s first Lunar Post Office opened in 2059. In addition to its domestic monopoly, the Mail contributes nearly VK❦2.6 trillion each year towards the Vekllei Government Securities Bureau (the country&amp;rsquo;s sovereign wealth fund) through its international postage and courier services abroad, under the name World Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/stamps.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/#tzipora-zelda-desmoisnes&#34;&gt;Tzipora&lt;/a&gt; arranges some of her favourite Vekllei stamps | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-16-stamps/&#34;&gt;Philately Foolery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the Mail&amp;rsquo;s Office of Telecommunications is also responsible for all telephones, telegrams and videophones in the country, the Mail&amp;rsquo;s status as a lynchpin of communication is absolute, and heavily protected by the postwar Vekllei constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;daily-service&#34;&gt;Daily Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-05-mailtrain/&#34;&gt;Racing the Post Office to the Station&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail aims to provide next-day delivery during weekdays in zero-code (that is to say, &lt;em&gt;Home Island&lt;/em&gt;) regions. Overnight delivery is also generally available between &lt;em&gt;Home Islands&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Aismious&lt;/em&gt; Islands, &lt;em&gt;Kala&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Azores&lt;/em&gt; during weekdays. Most Lunar territories are available on Mondays and Fridays, and other territories are available according to the Mail&amp;rsquo;s region table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei people do not pay to post items, stamps are affixed with coloured squares called &lt;em&gt;chromacodes&lt;/em&gt; which are used in the automatic sorting machines common in the country. International Mail uses traditional stamps with price listed, and the Vekllei Crown displayed. Franking is used for tracking and identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;special-delivery&#34;&gt;Special Delivery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special, commercial and industrial postage is managed within the &lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt; through special sorting facilities and a dedicated postal network. Regular business postage is funnelled through regular daily service, but hazardous, oversized and dangerous goods are accepted by special Post Offices designed to accept them. The Mail does not provide special services for regular residential or courier delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;international-service&#34;&gt;International Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mail is best known overseas as the &lt;strong&gt;World Post&lt;/strong&gt;, which offers services for foreign clients and has established itself as one of the Big Four international transnational courier services in the world today. Similar to domestic postal systems in other countries, the World Post offers flat rates for delivery anywhere in the world, priced according to size and weight. In addition, sister company &lt;strong&gt;Universal Express&lt;/strong&gt; offers next-day weekday delivery in certain markets. Most employees of the World Post and Universal Express are foreign workers banking labour-hours for immigration to Vekllei. Unlike domestic service, the World Post and Universal Express use private courier contracts extensively to fulfil orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finance&#34;&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is easily accessible via the Mail&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Financial Services Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;. Although inaccessible within the country, savings can be withdrawn conditionally upon emigration, and the Mail offers easy access and financial counselling for Vekllei people. Through the Financial Services Bureau, the Mail also offers financial management to immigrant populations with wealth transfer (the phrase for banking of savings and prior income) and Overseas Accounting, commonly used to send money to family abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;telecommunications&#34;&gt;Telecommunications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosma&lt;/strong&gt; (a portmanteau of &lt;em&gt;communicasia matismion&lt;/em&gt;) is Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s state communications company, responsible for all residential and public telephones in the country. This includes videophones, public phone booths, and residential networks. Cosma also maintains telecommunications infrastructure networks internationally through &lt;strong&gt;Cosma Overseas&lt;/strong&gt;, primarily the Vekllei-Europe undersea cables and their sister sets between Vekllei and North America. Much of the network dates back over a hundred years, since a shortage of modern personal telephones in Vekllei requires Cosma to maintain a wide variety of voltage and cable standards. Commercial, industrial and government telecommunications is managed by a seperate internal department called the &lt;strong&gt;Industrial Telecommunications Office&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operations&#34;&gt;Operations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/&#34;&gt;The Stamp Manufacturie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;As a military organ&lt;/strong&gt;, the Mail A.r. retains military ranks for its staff, commanded by a Postmaster General and aided by a civilian regulator designed to keep its critical service available to Vekllei people. The Mail&amp;rsquo;s fleet includes dedicated jets, automatic trucks, mail trains, intercity pneumatic systems, vehicle automen, and postmen, all wearing the red and gold colours of the organisation. In total, the Mail delivers nearly 50 million pieces of mail during weekdays.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is evident&lt;/strong&gt; that the services assigned to the Mail by the postwar constitution are of critical importance to the stability of Vekllei society. In addition to being one of the oldest active postal organisations in the world, the Royal Mail of Vekllei is tremendously busy, since physical post has scarcely been displaced by the telephone in the country. Even without the Mail&amp;rsquo;s international postage, domestic mail each day can exceed 12 million pieces &amp;ndash; enough for 1 in 2 people, though commercial mail and periodicals are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/manufacturie.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  Outdoor view of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/&#34;&gt;Royal Mail&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; stamp printing complex. | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-11-manufacturie/&#34;&gt;The Stamp Manufacturie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is typical for critical bureaus in Vekllei, the Mail alleviates the stress of daily service through its dense, vertically-integrated infrastructure aided by automatic (automen vehicles) and permanent fixtures (pneumatic systems and automatic sorting/franking machines). It is precisely this commitment to infrastructure that makes the Mail so visible in daily life, and contributes to its ongoing legacy as Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s oldest running government institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;staff&#34;&gt;Staff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;book-columns flex flex-wrap&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/mail.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex-even markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/postmistress.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail employs 48,960 people full-time across its various offices, and nearly 200,000 automen in various roles. Although the Mail does retain a staff of postmen and couriers, most urban daily service is now provided by automatic vehicles and sorting, which account for nearly half of the total automen owned by the organisation. Instead, the majority of Mail employees are involved in the running of the organisation &amp;ndash; mostly as clerks, managers, and administrators. Around 10,000 postmen are employed by the Mail in daily delivery, called &amp;ldquo;posties&amp;rdquo;. There are around 8,000 postal routes in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although at first glance the number of automen dramatically exceeds demand, the total count is misleading &amp;ndash; most automen with the Mail are integrated into the infrastructure of its sorting centres and post offices, and very few are traditionally autonomous robots commonly seen in public in Vekllei. Only about 8,000 automen are employed in physical mail delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 16,220 post boxes in Vekllei, which are iconic for their red and gold paint and intricate detailing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleet&#34;&gt;Fleet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-02-03-fairie/&#34;&gt;The Fairie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mail retains a large and diverse fleet of vehicles in regular operations, which, due to their diversity and and expense, have become iconic around the world. From bicycles to space planes, the Mail&amp;rsquo;s fleet of vehicles rivals in diversity postal services three times its size, largely benefitted by Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s obfuscated budgeting system and cultural importance afforded to the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table lists company vehicles relevant to regular postal service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;The Royal Mail Fleet&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postal Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8,000 delivery automen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5,200 motorcycles &lt;em&gt;(mostly Local Electric Model 15 &amp;amp; Phantoms)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,400 bicycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2,000 automatic vans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;400 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;31 mail boats &lt;em&gt;(MBR)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 mail flying boats &lt;em&gt;(Model 54 &amp;ldquo;Fairie&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 mail helijets &lt;em&gt;(Model RM/Gisma &amp;amp; Record types)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 mail trains &lt;em&gt;(RM Series/Series 225 EMU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 mail trams &lt;em&gt;(Series T6)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail space planes &lt;em&gt;(G.A. Type 1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail ships &lt;em&gt;(RMS&lt;/em&gt; Atlantic &lt;em&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/em&gt; Sunburst &lt;em&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overseas Service Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Post Company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;250 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;52 cargo jets &lt;em&gt;(Model RM/Type 56C)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 flying boats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Express Company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 cargo jets &lt;em&gt;(Model ERM/C.A. Type 6 supersonic)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 mail trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Postmistress&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 executive mail train &lt;em&gt;(Series 4000 EMU)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A.r.&lt;/em&gt; is a shortening of &lt;em&gt;state requisite&lt;/em&gt; (A.r., or requoisesiasn amourisocietie)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Labour Bank of Vekllei&lt;/em&gt; (often called the &lt;em&gt;Government Bank&lt;/em&gt;) is Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s social bank, and each Vekllei person is entitled to an equal share of it.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rail</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/rail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/rail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.gt-container {
  display: none;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; society
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;This article&lt;/strong&gt; discusses one of the most important and visible organisations in everyday Vekllei life: Vekllei National Rail. Vekllei is criss-crossed by hundreds of different rail lines of various gauges, grades, and purposes. In fact, it runs many lines at a total loss, often under capacity. To understand these inefficiencies is to understand why the National Rail exists, and to some extent, how Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s state assets and powerful bureaus shape life in the country today.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;he National Rail of Vekllei (VNR)&lt;/strong&gt; is a catch-all term for bureau-backed, state-owned rail operators of Vekllei. In casual use, it refers to the Vekllei National Railway A.r.R. and its sister companies, like Vekllei Metro, which are structured within the service-oriented Railways Bureau. More precisely, Vekllei National Rail encompasses several different bureaus that operate, design, maintain and communicate rail service in the country, which itself is further included under the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most critical organisations of Vekllei, the structure and directorship of Vekllei National Rail is complex, but can be simplified by understanding that all rail transport in the country is ultimately the responsibility of an organisation called Vekllei National Rail, and it is towards this organ that this article is addressed. Today, the National Rail operates nearly 20,000km of track, indicating the density of the rail service it provides, and services nearly 20 million people each day through its network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since nationalisation of the private Vekllei rail companies in 1925, the structure and reach of Vekllei National Rail has changed several times. Operated as a for-profit enterprise at a historical loss, the National Rail&amp;rsquo;s history of service is reflected in the variety of trains and track gauges it maintains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei is unique in the density of its rail, a feature of deliberate postwar city planning and the Home Island&amp;rsquo;s history as an industrial port city-state. Very few Vekllei people own automobiles, and trains remain by far the most common method of travel in the country. Because of this, the rail network in metropolitan areas is extraordinarily dense, and is designed to offer access to nearly every residence in urban areas. This fact also explains the presence of dedicated rail lines to small towns and villages that would otherwise not justify their maintenance. As visible on the map above, the passenger rail network in Vekllei is unsurpassed in its density, which contributes to the dependence Vekllei people have on their trains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/railmap.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  A map of the rail network and boroughs of Vekllei, showcasing maglev (red), high-speed (yellow), regional (orange) and local (brown) lines | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2020-06-14-map/&#34;&gt;100 Boroughs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, almost all freight is run along rails of varying gauges. These range from conventional freight trains at standard gauge, to municipal delivery trains at metre guage, and even narrow gauges for moving freight and equipment within large factory complexes. Most major stores and grocers are arranged along freight lines with dedicated sidings, or have their own narrow-gauge tracks dedicated to their use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unusually, Vekllei National Rail is legally absolved of all non-rail transport, and possesses no busses or ferries for public use, which are operated and maintained by dedicated adjacent bureaus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Vekllei has used wagonways since the 18th Century and developed horse-drawn railways for industrial transport in its ports, the first passenger rail line in Vekllei was founded in 1855 by the Pharos Rail Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The history of rail in Vekllei can be summarised in three key eras of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Development and expansion&lt;/strong&gt;, from early service in 1855.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late Junta/Prewar nationalisation&lt;/strong&gt;, from nationalisation in 1925.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postwar refounding and development&lt;/strong&gt;, since independence in 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the foundation of VNR after nationalisation, rail in Vekllei has seen the scale of its passenger rail networks quadruple in size. It is internationally regarded for its safety and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;early-development&#34;&gt;Early Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first railways in Vekllei developed alongside its ports, as Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s position as an intermediary free port between Europe and the Americas rapidly developed Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s industrial base. Although the earliest internal rail wagons were pulled by horses, primitive steam locomotives had modernised most ports by the early 19th Century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first passenger rail line opened in 1855 between Pharos and the present-day borough of Little Vekllei to alleviate the expense of moving goods from the Pharos Port to established settlement further inland. The original line was only a few kilometres long, but was extended in 1858 and again in 1872. By this time, several other lines had been established under private rail companies, including passenger services between Vekllei Proper and Little Vekllei, as well as the beginnings of the Montre-Vekllei Railroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the beginning of the 20th Century, Vekllei had a half-dozen major railroad companies, and dozens other limited/local services provided by private operators or their municipality. This saw a massive increase in both the movement of freight and ridership, and helped entrench Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s position as a stopover port city for transatlantic freight and passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nationalisation&#34;&gt;Nationalisation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early 20th Century was marked by an exponential increase in ridership, which saw a proliferation of new railroads across the Home Islands. Metropolitan and suburban lines during this period were characterised by overcrowding, poor reliability and irregular service. These factors, in addition to the growing economic power of rail barons in the country, saw the Atlantic Junta (known as the Crown) move to nationalise all metropolitan and intercity passenger rail service in 1925 as the Vekllei National Rail Company (VNC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centralisation of Vekllei rail accompanied standardisation of its commuter track gauge, which improved travel times across the country. The VNC period was characterised by reliable investment and a commitment to modernisation of rail in the country. By the late 20th Century, the Vekllei Metropolitan Underground was widely regarded as one of the most beautiful subway systems in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 1980s, VNC started work on what would eventually become the Vekllei-Montre bullet train. The programme overran its cost estimates and was delayed several times, and was not completed until 2004, shortly before the Atomic War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;postwar-development&#34;&gt;Postwar Development&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Rail Company assets that had been operated by the occupation Vekllei Provisional Government were transferred to the Vekllei Interim Government in 2015 and reestablished as Vekllei National Rail (VNR) in 2018. The Floral Period has been marked by steady growth in ridership and the scale of its network. The organisation also invests heavily into the development of new locomotives and EMUs, culminating in 2047 with the announcement of the Vekllei East Coast Maglev Scheme, which are the fastest commuter trains in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/shrine-minded.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  A Lesvesn 59-Series EMU arrives in the village of Cult | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/&#34;&gt;Shrine-Minded Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2055, VNR celebrated &amp;ldquo;250 years of rail,&amp;rdquo; and its livery and staff uniforms were overhauled to mark the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, VNR represents the sole means of medium/long-distance transport for over 80% of Vekllei commuters, indicating its continuous status as a monopoly of travel, not just rail, in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei National Rail is an organ of the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government (A.r.R., or &lt;em&gt;requoisesiasn amourisocietie resmesnghet&lt;/em&gt;) as several individual state requisite bureaus, which in turn are charged with different transport companies. Although its structure in Vekllei might be analogous to a government ministry abroad, it functions in practice more like a state-owned enterprise with private subsidiaries. It is not a state-run corporation, and maintains seperate accounting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei National Rail is administered through three State Requisites: the Vekllei National Rail itself including all regular operations and rail service, the National Rail Insurance Scheme which finances construction through Government White Bonds, and the Rail Safety Commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Vekllei National Rail&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Railways Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palace of Rail
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei National Railway A.r.R.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VNR Atlantic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VNR Kala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VNR Overseas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei National Magway A.r.R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei Metro A.r.R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government Railroad R.S.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vekllei Freight S.A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Railroad Police Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office of Steam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office of Electrification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nuclear-Electric Rail Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private Railcar Commission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Industrial Rail&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National Freight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei/society/mail/&#34;&gt;Royal Mail of Vekllei&lt;/a&gt; Railway Holdings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Railroad Democracy Hall&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VK Rail Chapel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Rail Chapel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail Press Bureau&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei Rail Press&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vekllei Rail Transport Journal&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Locomotive&lt;/em&gt; Magazine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rail Periodicals Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friends of Rail Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Relations Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industrial Relations Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail Municipal Land Company S.A.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei National Rail Construction House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Railway Laboratories of Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senrouive House Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company House Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Rail Insurance Scheme A.r.R.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passenger Accounting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rail Democracy Office&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rail Safety Commission&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Track Safety Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passenger Safety Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Platform Investigation Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carriage Investigation Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incident Investigation Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;service&#34;&gt;Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Since most Vekllei people&lt;/strong&gt; catch a train each day, VNR is a uniquely intimate and treasured organ of the Vekllei state. It is somehow exempted from the public apathy and resentment of bureaucracy that targets other monopolies of the Vekllei state, and is routinely regarded as among the most beloved and appreciated &amp;ldquo;companies&amp;rdquo; in Vekllei.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to public transport is considered a &amp;ldquo;critical luxury&amp;rdquo; of the Vekllei state (the Vekllei turn-of-phrase for essential state services) and, by extension, the functioning of its society. By design, it makes no profit, and is subsidised entirely by the Transport Requisite of the Vekllei Government and various independent transport bureaus for the benefit of any Vekllei person. Even prior to the war and investment of the Floral Period, Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s public transport was widely regarded as among the finest of any network in the world thanks to its impeccable safety record, timeliness, and comprehensive coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/hollywood.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint caption&#34;&gt;
  A Mustard 56-Series EMU arrives in the village of Cult | &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-06-shrine-minded/&#34;&gt;Shrine-Minded Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rail transport contributes tremendously to the national culture and common affection for Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s public institutions. It is also commonly percieved as a triumph of the postwar floral Period, despite rail history in Vekllei dating back hundreds of years prior. The ongoing expansion of the VNR network and renovation of stations and railhubs commands attention internationally, which is watching Vekllei celebrate its golden age of rail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;national-rail&#34;&gt;National Rail&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National rail access is generally provided directly by Vekllei National Railway A.r.R. through a branch office dependent on the location. The Home Islands are served by VNR Atlantic, whereas Kala is served by VNR Overseas. The Home Islands house thousands of rural villages outside of urban metropolitan service, and Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s dependence on rail transportatiion demands their inclusion in the VNR network. As such, almost every village in Vekllei has a rail line or interurban tramway, and villages as small as 20 persons see daily service to the capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;metropolitan-service--subways&#34;&gt;Metropolitan Service &amp;amp; Subways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of VNR&amp;rsquo;s ~10,000 trains per day run in metro or subway services throughout Vekllei urban and interurban routes. These lines are primarily serviced by the EMU workhorses of the VNR fleet, particularly 56 and 59-Series trainsets. In urban centers, VNR service is frequent enough to be unscheduled, with trains arriving every other minute or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s underground metro network has been automated by Automatic Train Control, an industrial automan system that allows for driverless trains. Although still serviced by VNR platform staff with training to stop the train in emergencies, Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s automatic metros are otherwise entirely driverless. VNR Overseas metros in Kala and the Kalina Isles retain drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tramways&#34;&gt;Tramways&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei operates a variety of trams and streetcars, including double-decker street-level units in the capital region and so-called &amp;ldquo;fast trams&amp;rdquo; (inter-urban cars) outside of the cities. Depending on the make and route of the tramway, they may be grade-seperated or integrated into streets. Their ubuquity in urban areas has caused observers to regard them as the principle method of transport in the country, second only to the bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;freight&#34;&gt;Freight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR&amp;rsquo;s main freight lines run mostly on a seperate gauge and network, and are composed of several companies that operate regionally across a variety of locomotive types and industries. These include traditional freight locomotives and long/short cars, as well as freight trams and wagons used to transport goods around and between factories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operations&#34;&gt;Operations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-06-01-station-logic/&#34;&gt;Station Logic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint panel&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;VNR&lt;/strong&gt; is typical of a &amp;lsquo;great Vekllei bureau&amp;rsquo; &amp;ndash; it instills national pride, is well-run and maintained, and loses tremendous amounts of money. It is the crown jewel of Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s insolvent organs, whose thin profit margins and charming inefficiencies are tolerated and even encouraged in this society which subsidises social benefit above all else.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly 17 million people per day commute via VNR&amp;rsquo;s networks each day, making up a majority of the Vekllei population. In this sense, VNR&amp;rsquo;s quality of operations affects the Vekllei person more than the quality of their government. In addition to commuter service, VNR automatic freight transit systems are the lifeblood of all industry and commerce in the country, and are regulated directly as a state requisite for their critical importance to the functioning of Vekllei society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/stationlogic.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR operates 2,114 stations across the Home Islands, which vary from uncovered concrete platforms to tremendous terminus complexes that cover multiple city blocks. The largest station in the country, Vekllei Central, sees over 1 million people per day pass through its gates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s stations are well-regarded for the beauty and decoration overseas. As part of the Millenia Rail campaign in the mid-21st Century, VNR initiated a dramatic overhaul of its passenger infrastructure, restoring heritage-listed station interiors and renovating much of the early postwar metro construction with murals, new lighting, enlarged caverns and shafts, and improved safety features. The cleanliness and safety of Vekllei National Railway is a great point of pride in the country, and in part justifies VNR&amp;rsquo;s tremendous fiscal losses in daily operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR services are mostly unticketed, and as a Vekllei industry, are free to ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;staff&#34;&gt;Staff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://millmint.imgix.net/images/vnr.jpg?q=100&amp;amp;auto=format&#34; alt=&#34;smallimg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Read more: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-04-25-rail/&#34;&gt;The People of Vekllei National Rail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VNR employs 65,240 people, which include roles ranging from locomotive engineers and platform staff to editors of rail enthusiast periodicals. It is also one of the largest employers of 12-16 year olds in the country, via its Station Apprentice programme, unique among organisations of its size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organisation is administered by the President of the Rail Central Office, which is responsible to the Transport Requisite and the Palace of Rail. VNR has a close relationship with bureau and petty-bureau coachbuilders, and wields considerable power in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s heavy industries as a major manufacturing partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleet&#34;&gt;Fleet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ❖ Download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/files/factbook/VNR-Rolling-Stock-Bulletin.pdf&#34;&gt;VNR Rolling Stock List (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vekllei National Rail is perhaps unsurpassed in its variety of trainsets and their length of service. An unofficial policy of preservation has ensured that every unit type since the 1980s has seen an ongoing minor presence in current service. VNR rarely retires a trainset completely &amp;ndash; in keeping with the contemporary cultural-political valuation of machines, a few units of each model are retained on various lines for their historical and technical significance. This includes steam locomotives, which continue to operate regular passengers service on some routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backbone of the contemporary Vekllei rail fleet is the Electric Multiple Units (EMUs), which are designated by their year of manufacture.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In particular, the 56 and 59-Series trainsets make up the majority of EMUs in service today, as they exclusively populate primary commuter lines in Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s southwest. VNR also retains Diesel Multiple Units (DMUs) in its long-haul cold-weather routes, particularly in the Afouisneh region and Kala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VNR pioneered super-conductive maglev transport for mass consumption, and its SC3 trainsets are the fastest in regular service in the world today, reaching nearly 750km/h in places. Its slowest locomotive, the T400 2-6-2 steam locomotive &lt;em&gt;Small Movements&lt;/em&gt; built in 1928, averages just 30km/h on its tourist route in rural Krafla. VNR is also experimenting with nuclear-powered trainsets, but none have so far entered public testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;war&amp;rsquo; prefix is used as a designation for pre-war railcars and locomotives, transliterated from the native word for the Junta&amp;rsquo;s society.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>