<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Baron on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/baron/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Baron on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/baron/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Private Fantasy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/drawing/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/drawing/</guid>
	  <description>&#34;And who is this lady?&#34; &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s Tora, a Palace God who comes to Pachinki,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, stumbling over her words. &amp;ldquo;The other Goddesses don&amp;rsquo;t like her much, um, and she&amp;rsquo;s quite powerful. She goes to Pachinki to unite mortals against the Palace.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I see,&amp;rdquo; Baron said, not following but nodding politely. &amp;ldquo;She looks a lot like you, doesn&amp;rsquo;t she?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Oh, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; Tzipora said, brushing away the question with another piece of paper pulled from her schoolbag.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Happy New Year</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/2022/</guid>
	  <description>❖ Welcome to 2022, year of Vekllei. Here&amp;rsquo;s to a great year of art, dreams and love. Tzipora spent the lunar solstice of 2067 with Ayn and Baron on one of the warm steam lakes of Flous. The lake was near where Ayn&amp;rsquo;s parents lived, and they sailed across it on a wooden boat her father had made nearly 50 years before. Time was cyclical out here; it folded in on itself.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Best Years of Our Lives</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/years/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/years/</guid>
	  <description>Kaohsiung changed hands maybe four or five times. Each time the city fell, another company of Chinese burrowed themselves into the city, and each time it took about two months to drive them back into the sea. This was mostly done by the KMT and the Americans, who had heavy equipment. In Taiwan’s mountainous interior, a rainbow coalition of former colonies, indentured states and free-world ideologues fought brutally against the invasion of 2045.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Roadside Picnic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/picnic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/picnic/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This post is an animated PNG without sound. Download the video with sound here. Such was spring. The breeze was cool, but the sun was warm on the skin and everywhere. They’d been driving for a couple hours, Tzipora and Baron. They’d crossed the big glacier and come down the other side into Troll, where there was nothing much for miles around. It was about then that their tyre blew and the little Cosme M40 limped over to the side of the road.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Gun</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/gun/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/gun/</guid>
	  <description>Baron had been working in the twilight of violence for over twenty years. In that time he had not given much thought to children or family, except for those that lingered as ghosts from long ago. Despite popular misconception, Baron did on occasion daydream, and in those daydreams was an abstract picture of his heir — a dark-haired son not unlike himself.
Tzipora was not a son but she was not unlike him.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Shabbat Shalom</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/shalom/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/shalom/</guid>
	  <description>When they met, Tzipora told Baron she was Catholic. He thought that was hilarious — it was one of the few times she saw him laugh. Her name was “Tzipora”, and she gave herself the name “Zelda” — who did she think she was kidding? But that’s just how she was; Tzipora was an intricate person of many backgrounds and instincts.
Baron was Jewish, but he didn’t practice much. He did, however, observe shabbas as a cultural legacy of his childhood.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Baron, the Father</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/father/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/father/</guid>
	  <description>❖ This article was featured in Issue #5 of the Atlantic Bulletin People are not sure what to make of Baron. They are not sure what to make of his daughter, Tzipora, either. To that end, they are lucky to have found each other.
His obscurity is part of a severe disposition, made obvious by his astonishing disinterest in friends and hobbies. When he finishes work, he listens to the radio, prepares supper, and goes to bed.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>AB/NI’s Spectres of Violence</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/spectre/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/spectre/</guid>
	  <description>The Americas Bureau at National Intelligence (AB/NI), a semiautonomous organ of the covert operations council of the War Department, is recognised as the busiest of the continental bureaus. There is a lot to be busy with — the Dallas Secession, the Brazilian invasion of Bolivia, the Dallas nuclear lend-lease, and the reliability of Venezuelan oil production are all of some concern to Vekllei, and so AB/NI proactively has fingers in those pies.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sneak Sneak</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sneak/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sneak/</guid>
	  <description>He kept bad hours. Sometimes he worked so hard he came home in the early morning and fell asleep to the television with the subtitles on. Like a guerrilla sighting a commanding officer, she would approach discreetly, wearing her blanket like a cape and bouncing on her toes. With a gentle movement she&amp;rsquo;d drape it over him and listen for a break in his snoring. If he didn&amp;rsquo;t stir, she&amp;rsquo;d find a nook in his shoulder and would stay there till the sunrays woke him in the morning.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Like Father, Like Daughter</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/beach/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/beach/</guid>
	  <description>The main beach in Mumen, the nicest of the seaside districts, is constructed out of sand imported from the dunes of Africa. Where the rest of the country has black sand, a symptom of its volcanic turbulence, Mumen has nice yellow sand.
Baron doesn’t like the water, and getting him down to the sea at all was a trial. Zelda, for her part, sinks faster than lead in water and only ventures into the shallows with Ayn, who herself is afraid of the deeper ocean.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tattoos of Violence on Quiet Men</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/tattoos/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/tattoos/</guid>
	  <description>Where tattoos had once been an indication of class and work, they were now uncommon. Both class and work had been abolished. Tattoos were almost never seen in the prism of ordinary Vekllei life, but in less savoury occupations they were found where utopian concessions collide with violence and memory.
Baron rolled up his sleeves and laid them out for her. You could accuse him of many things — he was a reticent bloke — but he was never dishonest with Tzipora.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Big Mouth, Fat Lip</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/fat-lip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/fat-lip/</guid>
	  <description>For the first six months Baron had known her, Zelda was a serious and wisened young woman who carried symptoms of her troubled past as gracefully as anyone ever could. Poverty ages a person, and she’d nurtured a calm and dispirited disposition. She did not like war films or books with unhappy endings, or loud noises or arguments. She dressed conservatively and spoke quietly and uncontroversially. She had lived a lifetime already, working in exploitation in motels and supermarkets, watching as Utah unraveled around her.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Cherry Car</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/cherry/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/cherry/</guid>
	  <description>A road trip around Vekllei in the summer is an experience that makes life worth living. In some ways, it is a spiritual detox than reinvigorates a person with the intimate, elusive premise of the Vekllei spiritual enlightenment. In others, it is a way of returning to the earth, and understanding the human place in the principles of Upen.
No matter your intention, be it holiday or rediscovery, the very best of Vekllei is on display.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Dad&#39;s Birthday</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/birthday/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/birthday/</guid>
	  <description>Dad&amp;rsquo;s Birthday.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Forgotten Generation</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/generations/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/generations/</guid>
	  <description>We best know Vekllei as a dense society of utopia and great infrastructure today, but there was blood in that crucible. It is difficult to imagine that only fifty years ago these streets were unpaved and impassible with the rubble of old society. Shadows on concrete marked the souls lost in the arrogance of the monarchy. The nuclear fire was pregnant with a new generation of people, who, in the principles of upen, would forge a new society out of the ruins of the old.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Merry Christmas everyone (plus a little Christmas story)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/christmas-2018/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/christmas-2018/</guid>
	  <description>She had always been a very serious girl, from the first time he’d met her. It was more than a reflection of character; it was how she talked, how she carried herself. Her clothes were plain, her nervous tics were not that funny, and she was afflicted with all sorts of fears and anxieties. She opens her mouth in public and what comes out is usually of serious opinion — a judgement of something or a political remark.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Blood Names</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/blood-names/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/blood-names/</guid>
	  <description>Each person in Vekllei has three names — a given name (Tzipora), a surname (Desmoines), and an alternative given name as part of rapotenne (potenne is ‘handtalk’, upotenne is ‘spirit-talk’, and so it follows that rapotenne is the language system of names). This alternative name is a ‘key’ to the full blood name of an individual, which are given in secret by the mother traditionally, but can be gifted by any mother-figure.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Two Spies and a Vekllei Girl</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/spies/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/spies/</guid>
	  <description>In Nevada about this time of year, the temperature stays steady at 45 degrees (~115 in yank). The asphalt sticks to shoes. On the far right is Lenny the Jew. The moniker is his own; he’s a Jew from New York who ended up working for the Vekllei Rocketry Corps, the Vekllei espionage agency responsible for operations in the southern United States. Lenny the Jew is good with women, and violence.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>