<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vekllei on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/docs/millmint/vekllei/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vekllei on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/docs/millmint/vekllei/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/docs/millmint/vekllei/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/docs/millmint/vekllei/religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion in Vekllei 🌋   ARTICLE  Documents 🚚 Under Construction
This page is still under construction, and may be incomplete.  Upen is the animistic, nondenominational dominant and historical religion of Vekllei.
This article is currently under construction, and will soon feature more information about Vekllei&amp;rsquo;s spiritualism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/docs/millmint/vekllei/language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/docs/millmint/vekllei/language/</guid>
      <description>Language in Vekllei 📑   ARTICLE  Documents 🌺 Note from the Editor
Ever wondered how Vekllei people sound and talk? As it turns out, it&amp;rsquo;s something like Inuktitut blended with French, pronounced by an Australian. This article introduces key Vekllei languages.  ⭐ Starred Article
This article is complete. It was last updated in November 2020.   1. Introduction #  Vekllei language, abbreviated to just Vekllei, has six core sublanguages that are used commonly today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vekllei Back Up</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/docs/millmint/vekllei/_indexBU/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/docs/millmint/vekllei/_indexBU/</guid>
      <description>Under Construction
This page is still under construction, and may be incomplete.  Vekllei #  1. Overview #  1.1 Introduction #   Vekllei (also The Kingdom of Vekllei, The Vekllei Commonwealth, Islanda, Iceland) is a sovereign island country situated in the northern Atlantic, between Greenland and the Faroe Islands. It consists of the Vekllei city-state (referred to as the Home Island or Crown Metropole), two autonomous territories, six crown territories and various possessions including over a hundred satellite islands and islets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
