<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nature on 🌺 MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/tags/nature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nature on 🌺 MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 03:27:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/nature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Absolute Quiet</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 03:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-24-missile/</guid>
      <description>There were plumes in the sky, sent from bunkers buried deep in the well of the Earth, killing with switches. Vekllei went to war, and so Tzipora went to war with it.
The throbbing machinery of another world began turning, and anyone who saw the bomb would hear it. Passing seconds dislocated and caught heartbeats. The plumes were pretty. It was such a shame, those plumes. It was a quiet afternoon in the flower-tundras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Newda in Rural Vekllei</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 03:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-08-17-house/</guid>
      <description>Newda is Vekllei’s national architectural ideology, applied flexibly in a range of modernist styles developed domestically in her architecture schools. Broadly, Newda buildings emphasise distinction from the surrounding landscape (called Dumousiantopet, or ‘beautiful and seperate’), natural decay, and honesty in material and construction. Vekllei’s great Parliament House is Newda; as are the little rural homes found in the mountains inland in Vekllei.
Tzipora’s house in the village of Montre-Lola (as depicted on the map here) is built in what Vekllei calls “Azores revivalism”, a Newda style heavily influenced by the stripped deco and streamline moderne buildings of a century prior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Camp</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 03:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-07-21-base-camp/</guid>
      <description>Just a paint-sketch.
The puffin scouts set up camp not far from the rest, just outside of Krafla in the Lava region. When they moved south tomorrow, thick native grasses and trees would give way to flower-tundras and bare hills, and by Tuesday they’d be in the heart of Lava — empty and extraterrestrial and volcanic.
The Krafla high-energy communications tower was visible from all over the region. It provided uninterrupted radio to most of North Lava, and could relay signals through satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Train Out of Ada</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 01:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-21-missed-train/</guid>
      <description>They both watched as train 416 pulled away from the platform. And that was that — there would be no school in the morning. That was how it worked in rural Vekllei, a million miles from the automatic trains on endless timetables. Out here, you paced life around the station.
There was not much to say about this, between the two of them. Tzipora looked at Cobian and pulled a froggy smile that tried to express that it was nobody’s fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiery Peaks</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-07-fiery-peaks/</guid>
      <description>After three days in Ada, Tzipora set off towards Mt Miya. She made good time, and after three hours had happened upon the shoulders of the bright Volouisnesnkull Glacier. It was about here that she heard a morbid industrial siren, echoing up the valleys from far away.
At first she thought it might have come from Ada, since Boya Chemical had a large plant there, but as she lay out her things for lunch she heard the distinct whine of a turbojet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chemical Feast</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 02:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/posts/2020-05-06-chemical-feast/</guid>
      <description>East of Montre, West of Tjornes, waits a rare sight among Vekllei’s hard igneous slopes — a crown of gentle sedimentary cliffs packed with ruddy sandstone, which melt glacially into the sea chasing blue-sky bergs.
Tzipora was, at the time, making her way on foot from Montre-Lola to Ada, which was a coastal town in the North-East known for its luxurious health spas. Tzipora was not much interested in health, but she was interested in walking, and she made a pilgrimage along the coast every few years to make sense of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
