<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>Government</title>
	<link>/factbook/society/state/government/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Government </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<webfeeds:icon>//favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="/factbook/society/state/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Cabinet</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the government series of articles The Commonwealth Cabinet is a petty executive of Vekllei, and exists to advise the Directory with opinion and technical expertise.
It consists of members of parliament, either in a National Assemblies or the Senate, as well as experts and notable professionals in industry, science and economics. They are appointed rather than elected, and have a term of four years. Each Sorda appoints two members as privy advisors, and the rest are elected as Directors by employees of a relevant commonwealth parliament or ministry.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/government/">government</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>The Commonwealth Cabinet</strong> is a petty executive of <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and exists to advise the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/directory/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Directory</a> with opinion and technical expertise.</p>
<p>It consists of members of parliament, either in a <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-purple); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-purple) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/assembly/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei-purple fis"></span> National Assemblies</a> or the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-purple); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-purple) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/senate/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei-purple fis"></span> Senate</a>, as well as experts and notable professionals in industry, science and economics. They are appointed rather than elected, and have a term of four years. Each <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/sorda/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Sorda</a> appoints two members as privy advisors, and the rest are elected as Directors by employees of a relevant <a href="/parliaments/">commonwealth parliament</a> or <a href="/ministries/">ministry</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Civil Servants</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/civil-servants/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/civil-servants/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles Vekllei has a large government that is responsible for broad aspects of life and living in Vekllei. Members of government that are elected are known as public servants. Members of government administration, ministries, bureaus and departments that are employed are known as civil servants.
Titles of Civil Servant Managers in Vekllei
1. Minister
A minister leaders a ministry and reports to a public servant.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Vekllei has a large <a href="/government/">government</a> that is responsible for broad aspects of life and living in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>. Members of government that are elected are known as <em>public servants</em>. Members of government administration, ministries, bureaus and departments that are employed are known as <em>civil servants</em>.</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><p><strong>Titles of Civil Servant Managers in Vekllei</strong></p>
<p><strong>1. Minister</strong></p>
<p>A minister leaders a <a href="/ministries/">ministry</a> and reports to a public servant. While it is often a political position, ministers are appointed by the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a> or <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/directory/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Directory</a>, and are not elected. They employ a large staff that coordinate with subordinate bureaux and commissions.</p>
<p><strong>2. Director</strong></p>
<p>A director or executive leads a government bureau (not to be confused with industrial <a href="/bureaus">bureaus</a>) or organisation. They are usually appointed from industry or promoted from within, and are expected to be experts in their field. A single bureau is responsible for an entire aspect of administration in the country, and is a highly demanding position.</p>
<p><strong>3. Secretary</strong></p>
<p>A secretary or commissioner leads a government department or commission. They may employ a personal staff, who are known as undersecretaries.</p>
<p><strong>4. Officer</strong></p>
<p>An officer or chief leads an office, a specialised division of a government department. These are specific roles requiring specific expertise.</p>
</span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Council</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/council/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/council/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the government series of articles The Commonwealth Council is the supreme executive of the Commonwealth, comprising leadership from both the Directory and Cabinet. It has 16 members that are elected from the Directory and Cabinet as required. Sorda are elected every four years, and cabinet members are elected every two years, but cabinet MPs will lose their positions on the council if they lose their seat.
Commonwealth Council]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/government/">government</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <strong>Commonwealth Council</strong> is the supreme executive of the Commonwealth, comprising leadership from both the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/directory/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Directory</a> and <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>. It has 16 members that are elected from the Directory and Cabinet as required. <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/sorda/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Sorda</a> are elected every four years, and cabinet members are elected every two years, but cabinet MPs will lose their positions on the council if they lose their seat.</p>
<blockquote class="note ">
  <span class="text"><p><strong>Commonwealth Council</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>8 combined offices (Sorda) from the Directory</li>
<li>8 members of parliament, either from the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-purple); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-purple) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/senate/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei-purple fis"></span> Senate</a> or national assemblies, elected from the Cabinet by internal vote</li>
</ul></span>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Directory</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/directory/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/directory/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the government series of articles The Commonwealth Directorate or simply the Directory is a federal council of elected peers, each representing a constituent commonwealth. Although chaired by a rotating office, the Directory represents a single head of state as a petty executive.1
The Directory consists of each Sorda representing a constituent, with observers present from territories. In total, there are about 16 members of the Directory, elected every four years.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/government/">government</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Directorate</strong> or simply <strong>the Directory</strong> is a federal council of elected peers, each representing a <a href="/constituents/">constituent commonwealth</a>. Although chaired by a rotating office, the Directory represents a single head of state as a petty executive.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>The Directory consists of each <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/sorda/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Sorda</a> representing a constituent, with observers present from <a href="/territories/">territories</a>. In total, there are about 16 members of the Directory, elected every four years.</p>
<p>The Directory makes decisions based on advice and opinion of the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>. Together with the Cabinet, the Directory forms the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a> as the supreme executive body of the Commonwealth.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>There are two petty executives in Vekllei, which together form the Supreme Executive known as the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a>. The other petty executive is the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/cabinet/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Cabinet</a>.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Government Bureaus</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/bureaus/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/bureaus/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles A bureau is a statutory department of a ministry or ministerial parliament. They are professional, autonomous organisations run by a Director and staffed by civil servants.
They are typically large organisations with various degrees of devolution, and often control constituent commissions, boards or corporations.
Bureaus are organised into departments, which may comprise a number of offices. They are lead by an Executive Council, which typically includes a selection of staff from the Bureau as well as representatives from the ministry, industry or specific organisations from elsewhere in the Government.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>A bureau is a statutory department of a <a href="/ministries/">ministry</a> or <a href="/parliaments/">ministerial parliament</a>. They are professional, autonomous organisations run by a Director and staffed by civil servants.</p>
<p>They are typically large organisations with various degrees of devolution, and often control constituent commissions, boards or corporations.</p>
<p>Bureaus are organised into departments, which may comprise a number of offices. They are lead by an Executive Council, which typically includes a selection of staff from the Bureau as well as representatives from the ministry, industry or specific organisations from elsewhere in the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Government</a>.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Municipalities</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/municipalities/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/municipalities/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles ✿ Read more: The Good, The Municipal Municipalities are the bedrock of sundress municipalism, and a physical feature of everyday Vekllei life. A municipality refers to both a local council and its services, including libraries, schools, and policemen. Municipalities in Vekllei are the predominant form of local government, and vary dramatically in scale, power and resources. They usually refer to council municipalities, which are bodies of elected industrial and political leaders of a community.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/municipal/">The Good, The Municipal</a></em></span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><strong>Municipalities</strong> are the bedrock of sundress municipalism, and a physical feature of everyday Vekllei life. A municipality refers to both a local council and its services, including libraries, schools, and policemen.</span>
</blockquote>

<p>Municipalities in Vekllei are the predominant form of local government, and vary dramatically in scale, power and resources. They usually refer to council municipalities, which are bodies of elected industrial and political leaders of a community. This open-ended definition means that municipalities scale in Vekllei from tiny villages to major metropolitan areas.</p>
<p>Municipalities are the basis of Vekllei localism, a belief in local concern and decentralised decision-making. In general, Vekllei municipalism describes the places where society in abstract meets the individual, and so also has cultural and aesthetic qualities. The sum of a municipality is expressed in the <em>Atlantic Municipalist</em> tradition, which consists of the following principles:</p>
<blockquote class="note panel">
  <span class="text"><p><strong>Principles of Atlantic Municipalism</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Local employment, or “commutelessness.”</li>
<li>Slumlessness, beautification, and a will to architecture.</li>
<li>Property stewardship.</li>
<li>Open air and clean water.</li>
<li>Land usefulness (&ldquo;friendliness&rdquo;).</li>
<li>Private ownership of private needs.</li>
<li>Public ownership of public needs.</li>
</ol></span>
</blockquote>

<p>There are 14,000 municipalities across the Commonwealth. The usage of &lsquo;municipal&rsquo; can refer to a political council or the spirit of Atlantic Municipalism.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>National Assemblies</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/assembly/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/assembly/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles The National Assemblies are lower houses of elected representatives in Vekllei. Each constituent republic has an assembly, which elects members of parliament and a Sorda to represent their interests in the Directory.
There is an assembly for each republic, numbering 68 in total. Combined, there are 1520 members of parliament. The number of MPs is related to population size. Republic with large populations may have over 100 sitting MPs, and smaller republics]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-vekllei-purple fis"></span> <strong>National Assemblies</strong> are lower houses of elected representatives in Vekllei. Each <a href="/republics/">constituent republic</a> has an assembly, which elects members of parliament and a <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/sorda/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Sorda</a> to represent their interests in the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/directory/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Directory</a>.</p>
<p>There is an assembly for each republic, numbering 68 in total. Combined, there are 1520 members of parliament. The number of MPs is related to population size. Republic with large populations may have over 100 sitting MPs, and smaller republics</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Senate</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/senate/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/senate/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles The Commonwealth Senate is the upper house of the Vekllei government and has special legislative powers to approve, defer or reject proposed laws. The Senate cannot introduce most types of legislation, and so acts as a check on a National Assemblies, which collectively form a federated Lower House across 8 constituent commonwealths.
Membership in the senate is proportional to the number of constituent commonwealths, which submit five members each.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<p>The <span class="fi fi-min-vekllei-purple fis"></span> <strong>Commonwealth Senate</strong> is the upper house of the <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> <a href="/government/">government</a> and has special legislative powers to approve, defer or reject proposed laws. The Senate cannot introduce most types of legislation, and so acts as a check on a <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-purple); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-purple) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/assembly/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei-purple fis"></span> National Assemblies</a>, which collectively form a federated Lower House across 8 <a href="/constituents/">constituent commonwealths</a>.</p>
<p>Membership in the senate is proportional to the number of <a href="/constiuents/">constituent commonwealths</a>, which submit five members each.</p>
<p>The Senate is able to form Commonwealth Committees and Commissions, which engage in special inquiry of concern to the country. Although the results of these bodies are not legally binding, they have significant influence on government and the public and help draw attention to issues that have not recieved government or public notice.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sorda</title>
	  <link>/factbook/society/state/government/sorda/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>/factbook/society/state/government/sorda/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Part of the state series of articles ✿ Read more: The Prime Minister(s) of Vekllei Sorda (lit. Union) is the Vekllei name for the combined office of two Prime Ministers.
Constituent commonwealths in Vekllei elect two prime ministers, consisting of one man and one woman. Together, they form a single office in the federal Directory, and are expected to make combined decisions in the interests of their constituent. This combined decision-making office is called Sorda, and in the Council represents a single seat.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net"/> <blockquote class="note series">
  <span class="text">Part of the <em><a href="/state/">state</a></em> series of articles</span>
</blockquote>

<blockquote class="note link">
  <span class="text">✿ Read more: <em><a href="/stories/ministers/">The Prime Minister(s) of Vekllei</a></em></span>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Sorda</strong> (lit. <em>Union</em>) is the Vekllei name for the combined office of two Prime Ministers.</p>
<p><a href="/constituents/">Constituent commonwealths</a> in <a class="slink"  style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/world/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> elect two prime ministers, consisting of one man and one woman. Together, they form a single office in the federal <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-millmint); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-millmint) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/directory/"><span class="fi fi-min-vekllei fis"></span> Directory</a>, and are expected to make combined decisions in the interests of their <a href="/constituents/">constituent</a>. This combined decision-making office is called <em>Sorda</em>, and in the <a class="slink" style="color: var(--color-vekllei); background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--color-vekllei) 10%, transparent);" href="/factbook/society/state/government/council/"><span class="fi fi-min-council fis"></span> Council</a> represents a single seat.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
