<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>2023 on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2023/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2023 on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Caught</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/caught/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/caught/</guid>
	  <description> They both just agree to pretend they didn&amp;rsquo;t catch each other smoking on the roof. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sand</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sand/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sand/</guid>
	  <description> Self portrait &amp;ndash; thinking about how much I hate posting. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>America, 2059</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hispanic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hispanic/</guid>
	  <description>By November 2059, America was in an uneasy peace. The lease of nuclear sites &amp;ldquo;essential for continental strategic security&amp;rdquo; had been secured by Washington the previous month, and the June ceasefire was still in place despite a border skirmish that killed half a dozen GIs not far from where Tzipora was, in Southwest Utah.
The Dallas Administration, which was at this point calling itself the American War Government, was using the ceasefire to lick its wounds and negotiate with state militias to form a central command.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Government Jet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/state-jet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/state-jet/</guid>
	  <description>The Prime Ministers of Vekllei take a vow of humility upon taking office. This means they have to live on the Parliament Grounds in protected rural acreage, in modest homes known as lodges that are built in a traditional Vekllei style. This spirit of servitude exists in many aspects of a Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s term, from their humble remuneration to their suits and carriage.
The humility of person, however, does not mean the humility of state.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Ruins</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ruins/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ruins/</guid>
	  <description>From Copetpek to Reykjavic, the hills of Lola are pockmarked by collapsed brick chimneys and fenceless gates. Here is where they died, in their hundreds of thousands. These monuments watched over the postwar period, where the craters had been filled in and decontaminated.
You were not supposed to play in the ruins because of residual radiation. That&amp;rsquo;s what they were told as kids. The truth is that the stones were next to harmless after seventy years.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sketch for a Friend</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/neko/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/neko/</guid>
	  <description> A drawing for my friend Nubik, featuring his character, Neko. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Constable Zelda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/constable/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/constable/</guid>
	  <description> Disclaimer: Tzipora has never worked for/cooperated with the police. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All That Glitters</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/gold/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/gold/</guid>
	  <description> Vekllei has a cultural tradition of medallions and pins, which make up a lot of the jewellery in a moneyless society. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Veranda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/veranda/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/veranda/</guid>
	  <description> Sitting out on the veranda in the sun. </description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Department Commerce</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/department/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/department/</guid>
	  <description>Despite having many consumer products, Vekllei is not a consumer society and is not equipped to succeed as one. Benevolent state monopolies produce staple goods &amp;ndash; food, clothing, and shelter &amp;ndash; and everything else is left up to the anarchic participatory industriousness of its people, which is situated somewhere between a productive free market and chaos.
These planned production mechanisms facilitate the reliable overproduction of essential goods that meet the needs of Vekllei population.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Prime Minister(s)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ministers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ministers/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei is a nonpartisan democracy with two, equal heads of state &amp;ndash; one man and one woman. Known as Crown Ministers in Vekllei, they generally acknowledge the title of Prime Minister overseas, as the head of Vekllei government and secretary-general of the Vekllei Cabinet. The position is a quirk of the postwar period, when radical alternatives to existing systems of government were being explored in the anarcho-feminist whirlwind of independence.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Look</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/the-look/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/the-look/</guid>
	  <description> The Look. </description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>