<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>2023 on MillMint</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2023/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2023 on MillMint</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>Department Commerce</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/department/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/department/</guid>
	  <description>Despite having many consumer products, Vekllei is not a consumer society and is not equipped to succeed as one. Benevolent state monopolies produce staple goods &amp;ndash; food, clothing, and shelter &amp;ndash; and everything else is left up to the anarchic participatory industriousness of its people, which is situated somewhere between a productive free market and chaos.
The state monopolies are more than just state-owned industries &amp;ndash; indeed, illustrating the borders of state control is a thankless task, since Vekllei does not really function in a private/public binary &amp;ndash; instead, state monopolies imply a means of social control; the implementation of a Vekllei worldview.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Prime Minister(s) of Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ministers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ministers/</guid>
	  <description>Vekllei is a nonpartisan democracy with two, equal heads of state &amp;ndash; one man and one woman. Known as Crown Ministers in Vekllei, they generally acknowledge the title of Prime Minister overseas, as the head of Vekllei government and secretary-general of the Vekllei Cabinet. The position is a quirk of the postwar period, when radical alternatives to existing systems of government were being explored in the anarcho-feminist whirlwind of independence.</description>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>