<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>2023</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2023/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2023 </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>On the Stair</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/stair/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/stair/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora and Cobian on the staircase of Tzipora&rsquo;s apartment after school. Tzipora doesn&rsquo;t sleep that well, so her energy plummets in the early afternoon. After school, she loads up on soft drinks to keep her going until dinner. There is a marked change in her spirits after she&rsquo;s got some sugar in her system.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/stair.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora and Cobian on the staircase of Tzipora&rsquo;s apartment after school.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora doesn&rsquo;t sleep that well, so her energy plummets in the early afternoon. After school, she loads up on soft drinks to keep her going until dinner. There is a marked change in her spirits after she&rsquo;s got some sugar in her system.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sketch of Coretti Adoula</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/coretti/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/coretti/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Coretti Adoula, with her boyfriend Moise behind her. Pictured here is Coretti Adoula, Moise&rsquo;s sweet-natured girlfriend. Originally from the USSR, she moves to Vekllei and enters Tzipora&rsquo;s orbit of friends via Moise after they start dating.
She&rsquo;s eating Vekllei chips, which are seasoned above smoking meats and are usually eaten without sauce. Most supermarkets and many cafes offer them as snacks, as a tasty byproduct of meat preparation.
Here is her original sketch:]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/corettibg.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Coretti Adoula, with her boyfriend Moise behind her.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Pictured here is Coretti Adoula, Moise&rsquo;s sweet-natured girlfriend. Originally from the USSR, she moves to Vekllei and enters Tzipora&rsquo;s orbit of friends via Moise after they start dating.</p>
<p>She&rsquo;s eating Vekllei chips, which are seasoned above smoking meats and are usually eaten without sauce. Most supermarkets and many cafes offer them as snacks, as a tasty byproduct of meat preparation.</p>
<p>Here is her original sketch:</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/sketches/coretti.jpg" alt="sketch of coretti"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Jeep</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/jeep/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/jeep/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The M2 &ldquo;Stallion&rdquo; General-Purpose Utility Vehicle. The M2 &ldquo;Stallion&rdquo; is the backbone of the army. It carries everything from troops to stretchers to fission reactors across streets, sand and snow. It is customisable at the factory and in the field, and can serve nearly any role for Vekllei&rsquo;s fast-moving, hard-hitting army regiments.
It is a medium-wheelbase1 utility vehicle with a naturally aspirated 6-cylinder, 4.6 litre diesel engine made by Atlantic Auto.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/jeep.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The M2 &ldquo;Stallion&rdquo; General-Purpose Utility Vehicle.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The M2 &ldquo;Stallion&rdquo; is the backbone of the army. It carries everything from troops to stretchers to fission reactors across streets, sand and snow. It is customisable at the factory and in the field, and can serve nearly any role for Vekllei&rsquo;s fast-moving, hard-hitting army regiments.</p>
<p>It is a medium-wheelbase<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> utility vehicle with a naturally aspirated 6-cylinder, 4.6 litre diesel engine made by Atlantic Auto. No one company can lay claim to the success of the vehicle &ndash; the M2 is the result of industrial collaboration on a national scale, involving hundreds of contractors to meet a visionary committee brief. It has a 5-speed manual transmission with front and rear locking hubs that allow it to leap up boulders, with enough torque to tow armoured vehicles out of the line of fire.</p>
<p>Almost all aspects of the vehicle can be repaired and replaced in the field. The electrical system, engine block and panelling are accessible and modular. Its reliability is famous, and it will run happily for hundreds of thousands of kilometres in fire and ice.</p>
<p>The M2 can be configured as an ambulance, troop carrier, power supply, fuel truck, gun platform, or for many dozens of other uses as required. To this end, it forms the basis of Vekllei&rsquo;s flexible military logistics systems, and should be regarded as essential to the Vekllei Army as their rifles.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The M2 also comes in six-wheel configurations for heavier payloads.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Zelda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/tzipora/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/tzipora/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Tzipora lo Ula de Helette Azela ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/tzipora.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora lo Ula de Helette Azela</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Health Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/health/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/health/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Nurse of the Commonwealth Health Service. Healthcare in Vekllei is universal, and run as a government service for the wellbeing of the public. The system is financed and governed by the Commonwealth Health Secretariat, and is provided regionally by national health authorities.
There is no cost to any treatment in the Vekllei healthcare system, and it covers all kinds of care necessary for a comfortable and dignified life. Healthcare professionals, including doctors and nurses, are highly regarded in the Commonwealth and enjoy considerable benefits provided by their health authority.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/nurse.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Nurse of the Commonwealth Health Service.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Healthcare in Vekllei is universal, and run as a government service for the wellbeing of the public. The system is financed and governed by the Commonwealth Health Secretariat, and is provided regionally by national health authorities.</p>
<p>There is no cost to any treatment in the Vekllei healthcare system, and it covers all kinds of care necessary for a comfortable and dignified life. Healthcare professionals, including doctors and nurses, are highly regarded in the Commonwealth and enjoy considerable benefits provided by their health authority. All Vekllei households have an elected doctor, called a General Practitioner, who is their first point of contact with the health system.</p>
<p>Elective cosmetic surgery is uncommon in Vekllei and hard to receive, so medical tourism is a popular way to receive cosmetic dental treatment and other elective procedures, which occur most commonly in the US or Europe.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Dapper Soldier</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/soldier/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/soldier/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Officer in the Army of the Atlantic Crown. Some officers in the Army of the Atlantic Crown wear a tie with their jumpsuit. This is a choice that dates back to WW2, but also a symptom of the visible humanitarian role that the army plays in Vekllei and Africa.
General infantrymen still wear conventional fatigues.
Yes, the Commonwealth Army is formally known as the Army of the Atlantic Crown. This convention gets applied to recent branches too, like the Rocket Navy of the Atlantic Crown.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/soldier.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Officer in the Army of the Atlantic Crown.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Some officers in the Army of the Atlantic Crown wear a tie with their jumpsuit. This is a choice that dates back to WW2, but also a symptom of the visible humanitarian role that the army plays in Vekllei and Africa.</p>
<p>General infantrymen still wear conventional fatigues.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yes, the Commonwealth Army is formally known as the Army of the Atlantic Crown. This convention gets applied to recent branches too, like the Rocket Navy of the Atlantic Crown.</p>
</blockquote>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Revised Mail Uniform</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/mail-revised/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/mail-revised/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Revised postal uniform. I wanted something a bit more striking and graphic. Vekllei isn&rsquo;t simply a recreation of midcentury fashions, but a projection of what those design instincts might look like in 100 years. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/post.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Revised postal uniform. I wanted something a bit more striking and graphic. Vekllei isn&rsquo;t simply a recreation of midcentury fashions, but a projection of what those design instincts might look like in 100 years.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Caught</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/caught/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/caught/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ They both just agree to pretend they didn&rsquo;t catch each other smoking on the roof. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/caught.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">They both just agree to pretend they didn&rsquo;t catch each other smoking on the roof.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sand</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sand/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sand/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Self portrait &ndash; thinking about how much I hate posting. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/sand.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Self portrait &ndash; thinking about how much I hate posting.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>America, 2059</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hispanic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hispanic/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[By November 2059, America was in an uneasy peace. The lease of nuclear sites &ldquo;essential for continental strategic security&rdquo; had been secured by Washington the previous month, and the June ceasefire was still in place despite a border skirmish that killed half a dozen GIs not far from where Tzipora was, in Southwest Utah.
The Dallas Administration, which was at this point calling itself the American War Government, was using the ceasefire to lick its wounds and negotiate with state militias to form a central command.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/hispanic.jpg"/> <p>By November 2059, America was in an uneasy peace. The lease of nuclear sites &ldquo;essential for continental strategic security&rdquo; had been secured by Washington the previous month, and the June ceasefire was still in place despite a border skirmish that killed half a dozen GIs not far from where Tzipora was, in Southwest Utah.</p>
<p>The Dallas Administration, which was at this point calling itself the American War Government, was using the ceasefire to lick its wounds and negotiate with state militias to form a central command. The romance of a grassroots revolt, risen in a frenzy of rage and opportunity, had worn off. Now, the secessionist regions were digging in for serious fighting.</p>
<p>The quality of life varied between states. In Texas, things were better, but the borders had been closed. In Utah, things were collapsing. There was not much money around and the government in Salt Lake had lost control over their army. In towns like Cherry, police and soldiers worked together to maintain order or murder and rob; whichever took their fancy that day.</p>
<p>Tzipora knew she was at risk, but her options were limited. She lived and worked at Hotel Cairo (formerly Hotel Zion), which was a ways out of town. Most of the other girls had gone home or fled the state months ago, so there was plenty of work. No one else would employ aliens. She did not yet have enough money to make it to the East Coast, which would require bribing pretty much everyone she met along the way. The journey was dangerous, too &ndash; the busses had stopped and the trains weren&rsquo;t running, so you had to walk. There were a lot of violent drifters just moving through these days.</p>
<p>Come November 2059, it was obvious her time was running out. Posters had gone up announcing all &lsquo;Hispanics&rsquo; &ndash; a term here meaning people that looked like they came from Mexico or further south, not just spanish-speakers &ndash; were to be evacuated from the border. Neighbouring Nevada was a Washington-controlled state, and there would certainly be fighting in Utah. Ostensibly they were worried Latinos had more allegiance to the United States than to Dallas. More likely they just wanted them gone.</p>
<p>The posters said they would be evacuated to Colorado City, but Tzipora figured that was a crock of shit. That was a free city; they wouldn&rsquo;t take foreigners, and especially not people like her. She didn&rsquo;t know where they would send her but she didn&rsquo;t like it. It was not just rumours; Tzipora knew foreigners were being picked off the streets. Dallas was talking about saving the &ldquo;free states&rdquo; from &ldquo;Despotism &amp; Outsider Agitants,&rdquo; and Tzipora looked like an Outsider Agitant.</p>
<p>Hotel Cairo was outside of the evacuation zone, but she would have to carry her work-residence papers everywhere she went now. She just needed to save her cash; the US Dollar was a magical thing. In times like these, it bought comfort, security and opportunity. Staying was a gamble, but what choice did someone like her have? The Dollar was the great equaliser; it was life itself.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Government Jet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/state-jet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/state-jet/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Prime Ministers of Vekllei take a vow of humility upon taking office. This means they have to live on the Parliament Grounds in protected rural acreage, in modest homes known as lodges that are built in a traditional Vekllei style. This spirit of servitude exists in many aspects of a Prime Minister&rsquo;s term, from their humble remuneration to their suits and carriage.
The humility of person, however, does not mean the humility of state.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/statejet.jpg"/> <p>The Prime Ministers of Vekllei take a vow of humility upon taking office. This means they have to live on the Parliament Grounds in protected rural acreage, in modest homes known as lodges that are built in a traditional Vekllei style. This spirit of servitude exists in many aspects of a Prime Minister&rsquo;s term, from their humble remuneration to their suits and carriage.</p>
<p>The humility of person, however, does not mean the humility of state. The 4th Commonwealth takes great pride in its industrial and social achievements, and so diplomats and ministers travel in Vekllei aircraft built for diplomacy, as indicators of wealth and taste &ndash; social vectors for good business. To this end, the Air Force maintains a fleet of bare-metal jets for official business inside and outside the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>This Comen Firewick &lsquo;60 jet has been extensively modified for the security and comfort of the Vekllei public servant. It is a medium-sized government aircraft mostly used for flights within the Commonwealth, stretching the width and depth of the Atlantic. It is easily identifiable as a government jet by its bare-metal livery, which is consistent among the government fleet and is intended to draw attention to the craftsmanship of Vekllei machines. Like most Vekllei jet aircraft, it is primarily a nuclear-electric vessel that uses auxiliary combustion engines for take-off and redundancy. This is a feature of the air-cooled reactor systems in Vekllei aircraft, which require reaching cruising speed to &ldquo;switch over&rdquo; to nuclear-electric propulsion.</p>
<p>The Firewick 60 is well-liked for its distinctive skylights, which allow views of the sky or stars from the cabin. Its interior is well-lighted, though narrower than the wide-body and mono-wing sister aircraft in the government fleet.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Ruins</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ruins/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ruins/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[From Copetpek to Reykjavic, the hills of Lola are pockmarked by collapsed brick chimneys and fenceless gates. Here is where they died, in their hundreds of thousands. These monuments watched over the postwar period, where the craters had been filled in and decontaminated.
You were not supposed to play in the ruins because of residual radiation. That&rsquo;s what they were told as kids. The truth is that the stones were next to harmless after seventy years.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/ruins.jpg"/> <p>From Copetpek to Reykjavic, the hills of Lola are pockmarked by collapsed brick chimneys and fenceless gates. Here is where they died, in their hundreds of thousands. These monuments watched over the postwar period, where the craters had been filled in and decontaminated.</p>
<p>You were not supposed to play in the ruins because of residual radiation. That&rsquo;s what they were told as kids. The truth is that the stones were next to harmless after seventy years. They did not want the kids playing there because there was no telling how many unmarked graves remained or what might rise to the surface in the rains.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sketch for a Friend</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/neko/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/neko/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ A drawing for my friend Nubik, featuring his character, Neko. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/neko.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">A drawing for my friend Nubik, featuring his character, Neko.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Constable Zelda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/constable/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/constable/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Disclaimer: Tzipora has never worked for/cooperated with the police. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/constable.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Disclaimer: Tzipora has never worked for/cooperated with the police.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All That Glitters</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/gold/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/gold/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Vekllei has a cultural tradition of medallions and pins, which make up a lot of the jewellery in a moneyless society. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/gold.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Vekllei has a cultural tradition of medallions and pins, which make up a lot of the jewellery in a moneyless society.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Veranda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/veranda/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/veranda/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Sitting out on the veranda in the sun. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/3.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Sitting out on the veranda in the sun.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Department Commerce</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/department/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/department/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Despite having many consumer products, Vekllei is not a consumer society and is not equipped to succeed as one. Benevolent state monopolies produce staple goods &ndash; food, clothing, and shelter &ndash; and everything else is left up to the anarchic participatory industriousness of its people, which is situated somewhere between a productive free market and chaos.
These planned production mechanisms facilitate the reliable overproduction of essential goods that meet the needs of Vekllei population.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/department.jpg"/> <p>Despite having many consumer products, Vekllei is not a consumer society and is not equipped to succeed as one. Benevolent state monopolies produce staple goods &ndash; food, clothing, and shelter &ndash; and everything else is left up to the anarchic participatory industriousness of its people, which is situated somewhere between a productive free market and chaos.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>These planned production mechanisms facilitate the reliable overproduction of essential goods that meet the needs of Vekllei population. The inflexibility of this system is supplanted by the private market of participatory labour, which produces the majority of consumer goods and products in Vekllei, if unreliably. Luxury goods are generally hyperlocalised or imported, and are scarce for most Veklei people.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&ndash; <a href="/assets/">State Assets of Vekllei</a></p>
<p>Since the staples of Vekllei life are produced in an inflexible planned system based on overproduction, the most common place of &lsquo;commerce&rsquo; for ordinary Vekllei people is the department store. They are a feature of the country, capable of furnishing a complete life out of simple and quality goods. Furniture, clothing, some appliances, and all types of food are available. Clothing is of high quality, and has some variety of essential fashions in contemporary society.</p>
<p>These department stores resemble the icons of consumer societies overseas, but without an efficient means of exchange to build real markets built on capital, the mechanisms to develop a consumer culture are absent. Instead, Vekllei is full of &lsquo;ghost consumers;&rsquo; people participating in consumer rituals that look like their counterparts overseas, but missing the critical aspects of consumer desire and money-value.</p>
<p>Indeed, Tzipora was surprised when Cobian took her to the Montvisiosn Department Store one day to &lsquo;shop&rsquo; for new clothes. Cobian tried things on and frowned at herself in the mirror like the Yanquis and Londoners and Parisians do, but she was really acting out what she saw in films. It was a fantasy; a child&rsquo;s idea of shopping and consumption and commerce. It was very exotic to Vekllei people, but Tzipora had lived overseas and knew the difference money-value made. There was no real desire to consume; it was a social ritual without a financial basis. They might as well have been doing each other&rsquo;s hair in the park, or trying on her mother&rsquo;s shoes.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Prime Minister(s)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ministers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ministers/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Vekllei is a nonpartisan democracy with two, equal heads of state &ndash; one man and one woman. Known as Crown Ministers in Vekllei, they generally acknowledge the title of Prime Minister overseas, as the head of Vekllei government and secretary-general of the Vekllei Cabinet. The position is a quirk of the postwar period, when radical alternatives to existing systems of government were being explored in the anarcho-feminist whirlwind of independence.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/ministers.jpg"/> <p>Vekllei is a nonpartisan democracy with two, equal heads of state &ndash; one man and one woman. Known as <em>Crown Ministers</em> in Vekllei, they generally acknowledge the title of <em>Prime Minister</em> overseas, as the head of Vekllei government and secretary-general of the Vekllei Cabinet. The position is a quirk of the postwar period, when radical alternatives to existing systems of government were being explored in the <a href="/stories/women/">anarcho-feminist whirlwind of independence</a>.</p>
<p>Although the title includes two seperate people, they represent a single office and so are expected to make agreeable decisions, if nothing else. This is a role of compromise and moderation, since each Prime Minister has the power to censure the other. Stalemates and infighting usually results in the sacking of the government by the Cabinet Secretary, since Vekllei people have little tolerance for partisan bickering in their public servants. The nonpartisan nature of Vekllei politics means the formation of government often sees unconventional members of parliament enter the cabinet, often from industry, the arts, or sciences. In this context, the ideal Prime Minister is well-groomed and patient by nature, and all great Vekllei PMs have been masters of compromise.</p>
<p>When Tzipora arrives in Vekllei in the early 2060s, the country is lead by Prime Ministers Raif Housk and Dalia Hospotet, pictured here. Traditionally, PMs divide responsibilities along their strengths as politicians. Dalia Hospotet, for example, is a master of statecraft and so meets regularly with foreign leaders to express the Vekllei position. Raif is an economist at the <a href="/cosmosol/">Ministry of Commerce</a>, and his talents lie in exploiting his deep connections to Vekllei business. That is not to suggest the Prime Ministers operate independently &ndash; quite the opposite in fact. Decisions have to be made as in agreement, as a single office, and so the relationship of the PMs resembles a married couple, with definitive answers postponed until consort can be had. The election of Prime Ministers is a marriage of two people, in a civic sense.</p>
<p>Their most important function, as two people in a single role, is to represent their people and indicate, both to foreigners and themselves, the values of their society. Prime Ministership is an intimate and symbolic position, and their appearance internally and abroad is in some ways more like the king and queen of a monarchy than the public servants of a modern democracy. But that too represents Vekllei well, as a hybrid society of contradictory yet fascinating instincts, breaking down the historicism of society by insisting that the past is the future and the revolutionary is ordinary.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Look</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/the-look/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/the-look/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ The Look. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/1.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The Look.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
