<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">
  <channel>
	<title>2023</title>
	<link>https://millmint.net/tags/2023/</link>
	<description>Recent content in 2023 </description>
	<generator>Hugo</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 08:00:00 EST</lastBuildDate>
	<webfeeds:icon>https://millmint.net/favicon.png</webfeeds:icon>
	<webfeeds:accentColor>DBEAFE</webfeeds:accentColor>
	<webfeeds:related layout="card" target="browser"/><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/tags/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<item>
	  <title>A Social Economy</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/a-social-economy/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/a-social-economy/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora has baked a baguette in class. Their school was designed the revivalist mayan-prairie style. This illustration accompanies an essay, called A Social Economy. It was written as an introduction to Vekllei&rsquo;s essential premise &ndash; its moneyless economy. It is about as brief as I can make it, but it is also a work in progress that can hopefully be updated in future, as I refine not just the ideas involved but how I communicate them.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/prairie.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora has baked a baguette in class. Their school was designed the revivalist mayan-prairie style.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>This illustration accompanies an essay, called <a href="/social-economy/"><em>A Social Economy</em></a>. It was written as an introduction to Vekllei&rsquo;s essential premise &ndash; its moneyless economy. It is about as brief as I can make it, but it is also a work in progress that can hopefully be updated in future, as I refine not just the ideas involved but how I communicate them.</p>
<p>Moneylessness is maybe the most fantastical aspect of Vekllei, and so it is particularly interesting to me. I&rsquo;m well aware it&rsquo;s a bit crazy, but taking it seriously and engaging with it is the joy of this project. My drawings help depict what a society based on these ideas might look like. All these things contribute to Vekllei&rsquo;s immersive and unique qualities.</p>
<blockquote class="hint ">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">❀ Read here: <em><a href="/social-economy/">A Social Economy</a></em></div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tolerance Comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/tolerance/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/tolerance/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/tolerance.jpg"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/fullres/tolerance.jpg" alt="comic page 1"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Seinfeld</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/seinfeld/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/seinfeld/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Drawn to celebrate 500 followers on Twitter. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/seinfeld.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Drawn to celebrate 500 followers on <a href="https://x.com/vekllei">Twitter</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Grocer Girls</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/grocer-girls/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/grocer-girls/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Miranese islanders Isuri and Catia return. As they approached adulthood, compulsory service loomed large in their futures like a great wall. The thing about compulsory service (or &lsquo;corsosva,&rsquo; as it was called) was that it could be dice toss, which was a hell of a thing for something that took four years of your life. You applied for jobs you might like to do, but if they were full or you didn&rsquo;t make the cut, you could find yourself on the other side of the country doing clerical work or working construction in the Arctic.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/united-grocers.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The Miranese islanders <a href="/stories/isuri/">Isuri and Catia</a> return.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>As they approached adulthood, <a href="/corsosva/">compulsory service</a> loomed large in their futures like a great wall. The thing about compulsory service (or &lsquo;corsosva,&rsquo; as it was called) was that it could be dice toss, which was a hell of a thing for something that took four years of your life. You applied for jobs you might like to do, but if they were full or you didn&rsquo;t make the cut, you could find yourself on the other side of the country doing clerical work or working construction in the Arctic.</p>
<p>No, thank you. There was a scheme that allowed teenagers too young to start corsosva to accumulate credit towards it, which would deduct from the total length of service. You still had to work, but at least you had security in choosing where you were.</p>
<p>For Isuri and Catia, they picked up casual work after school at their local <a href="/united-grocers/">United Grocers</a>. Vekllei might be a society of miracles, but their groceries look the same as anywhere, and the work was easy and boring. Their neighbourhood was small and they knew everyone who came through.</p>
<p>Their jobs were unadventurous, but the store was owned by a neighbour of Isuri and they goofed off a lot or sat outside in the sun when it was quiet. The stock robot did most of the work, so they were really just around to keep an eye on things, and often read magazines or played chess to pass the time.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora &amp; Cobian</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/tzipora-and-cobian/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/tzipora-and-cobian/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ The train is coming and her hair is soft. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/soft.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The train is coming and her hair is soft.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Drip</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/drip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/drip/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Tzipora wearing the chiton from yesterday. I added a hat. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/drip.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora wearing the <a href="/stories/national-dress/">chiton</a> from yesterday. I added a hat.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Veletian Chiton</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/national-dress/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/national-dress/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Diagram of the components of Veletian dress. As a union of Atlantic communities, Vekllei has no single culture and consequently no single national dress. It does, however, have a national personification: Veletia, a historic illustration of pan-Atlanticism who today makes up one of &ldquo;six sisters&rdquo; which represent the Commonwealth in total. The &ldquo;sisters&rdquo; are not in fact six seperate characters but are different forms of the same figure; homoousion manifestations of a single national spirit.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/chiton.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Diagram of the components of Veletian dress.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>As a union of Atlantic communities, <a href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> has no single culture and consequently no single national dress. It does, however, have a national personification: <a href="/veletia/">Veletia</a>, a historic illustration of pan-Atlanticism who today makes up one of &ldquo;six sisters&rdquo; which represent the Commonwealth in total. The &ldquo;sisters&rdquo; are not in fact six seperate characters but are different forms of the same figure; homoousion manifestations of a single national spirit.</p>
<p>Because of this, Veletia is closely associated with Vekllei society and the <a href="/civic-commons/">civic commons</a>, and unity and transcultural commonhoods are strongly emphasised by the Commonwealth. As such, Veletia&rsquo;s common appearance inspires a <em>de facto</em> national dress, which varies between <a href="/constituents/">constituents</a> but has the same basic elements.</p>
<p>The example above demonstrates Oslolan culture, hence the Gi and Petty Cape. In Vekllei&rsquo;s Caribbean and mid-Atlantic republics, the outfit is modified for climate, shortening the stockings, using lighter materials and dispensing with the cape. The main dress most closely resembles a <em>chiton</em>, a kind of historic garment common in Doric and Ionian Greek history. You&rsquo;ll see Greek-inspired names, styles and features throughout Vekllei, which might imply a grandiose national self-identity, but is more likely a means of avoiding emphasis of any one culture within the diverse country.</p>
<p>Like most Vekllei forms of dress, it is heavily accessorised and flexible to cultural tastes. Dress in Vekllei is concerned with commonhoods rather than differences, and so it is very common to change aspects or add items to reflect different cultures, most commonly regional patterns, colours and jewellery. The Veletian dress is most often seen where Vekllei republics meet, as an extension of the Commonwealth identity &ndash; particularly holidays, celebrations and meetings. It is worn as a kind of formal dress for certain school and business occasions.</p>
<p>It is also, of course, a symbol of Vekllei&rsquo;s unique inwardness, living politics and level of social control. Like Commonwealth culture, Veletian national dress is at its roots artificial, informed by historic political rather than cultural traditions. But as with other aspects of the Commonwealth idea, once it is lived, worn, spoken and repeated by ordinary people, it becomes real and takes on a life of its own. It is an identity by consent, and part of the shared Vekllei project &ndash; a democracy not just in politics but in culture, traditions and aspirations.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Trick of Disaster</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/trick-of-disaster/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/trick-of-disaster/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[🎥 Click here to watch the video with sound In a while, will the smile on my face turn to plaster?
Stick around while the clown who is sick does the trick of disaster
For the race of my head and my face is moving much faster
Is it strange I should change? I don&rsquo;t know, why don&rsquo;t you ask her?
The Special Activities Directorate is a branch of the Home Office at National Intelligence (HO/NI).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/video/trick.mp4"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><span class="smallicon">🎥</span> <a href="/video/trick.mp4">Click here to watch the video with sound</a></div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>In a while, will the smile on my face turn to plaster?<br>
Stick around while the clown who is sick does the trick of disaster<br>
For the race of my head and my face is moving much faster<br>
Is it strange I should change? I don&rsquo;t know, why don&rsquo;t you ask her?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Special Activities Directorate is a branch of the Home Office at National Intelligence (HO/NI). It consists of men who have seen combat but are not otherwise career soldiers &ndash; men who suit many environments well and are ideologically motivated.</p>
<p>The Directorate is dormant for most of the year. Its members have roles in other <a href="/espionage/">Noshem</a> offices or work &ldquo;on the outside.&rdquo; But when the time comes &ndash; and it always does &ndash; they&rsquo;ll be called in for jobs on the other side of the world. They are not just spooks, after all &ndash; they serve a higher purpose, as the sword of Commonwealth ideology. In this context, they have no formal allegiances or masters, just essential values which they serve in espionage and violence.</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/fullres/clown.jpg" alt="image of a man in plain clothes firing a rifle"  title="Full image of an agent of the Special Activities Directorate during *Operation Sea of Reeds*." loading="lazy" />
  <figcaption>Full image of an agent of the Special Activities Directorate during <em>Operation Sea of Reeds</em>.</figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Ham Comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ham-comic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ham-comic/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/comics/ham.jpg"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/ham.jpg" alt="comic page 1"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Airships for Tomorrow</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/atlantic-airship/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/atlantic-airship/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora practices capturing a photo through her binoculars. Airships have seen some resurgence in the mid-21st Century as an alternate means of air travel, occupying a travel niche somewhere between the ocean-liner and a passenger jet. Although relatively uncommon compared to fixed-wing aircraft, airships do fly busy routes in certain parts of the world where their capacity and leisurely speeds are preferred.
In Vekllei, all passenger airships are operated by Commonwealth Airways.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/airship.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora practices capturing a photo through her binoculars.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Airships have seen some resurgence in the mid-21st Century as an alternate means of air travel, occupying a travel niche somewhere between the ocean-liner and a passenger jet. Although relatively uncommon compared to fixed-wing aircraft, airships do fly busy routes in certain parts of the world where their capacity and leisurely speeds are preferred.</p>
<p>In <a href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, all passenger airships are operated by <a href="/air/">Commonwealth Airways</a>. Airships can dock without a runway, making them ideal for Vekllei&rsquo;s many archipelagos and Caribbean island belts, where they are most commonly seen. There are daily airship routes between Kalina&rsquo;s republics, the Bahamas, and between the Verde, Mira and Azores Commonwealths. Other routes link Vekllei&rsquo;s remote islands weekly, or commute passengers between Oslola and Kala. International routes are also common, especially to the US and UK. Since airships can only fly in certain weather, their routes are often seasonal.</p>
<p>The smallest Vekllei airship, CNV <em>Astrid</em> has a capacity of just twenty-six. The largest, pictured here, is the CNV <em>Comet</em> with capacity for nearly 500 people. With helidocks, internal elevators and a sky-lounge with panoramic windows, Vekllei&rsquo;s larger airships are a far cry from the gondola-balloons of yesteryear. In total, there are 16 airships in service with Commonwealth Airways. They are machines of enormous prestige, and they carry the Commonwealth flag wherever they go.</p>
<p>The largest airship in Vekllei service, however, belongs to the Vekllei Air Force. Originally a command centre that could spend the summer months over the Arctic circle, it is undergoing conversion to become a flying aircraft carrier.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Police Livery</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/police-livery/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/police-livery/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[A selection of patrol cruisers showing the different liveries of different police forces. Vekllei is of course a federalised Commonwealth, and so it has different kinds of policing for different kinds of laws. The array of cars on the left have jurisdiction related to the Commonwealth (smuggling, financial crime, mint security, intelligence liaisons, protection, etc.) and the cars on the right are administered by its republics (local law enforcement and regional policing).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/livery.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">A selection of patrol cruisers showing the different liveries of different police forces.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> is of course a federalised Commonwealth, and so it has different kinds of policing for different kinds of laws. The array of cars on the left have jurisdiction related to the Commonwealth (smuggling, financial crime, mint security, intelligence liaisons, protection, etc.) and the cars on the right are administered by its republics (local law enforcement and regional policing).</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Heatwave</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/heatwave/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/heatwave/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Oslolans when the temperature hits 25°C. Oslola is part of Vekllei, and is known as Iceland in our own world. In this setting, the North Atlantic is a bit more temperate thanks to the Oslolan Low Pole and strong ocean currents. Still, they&rsquo;re acclimatised to cool air, and 25°C (77°F) is hot weather for them.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/heatwave.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Oslolans when the temperature hits 25°C.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Oslola is part of <a href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a>, and is known as Iceland in our own world. In this setting, the North Atlantic is a bit more temperate thanks to the Oslolan Low Pole and strong ocean currents. Still, they&rsquo;re acclimatised to cool air, and 25°C (77°F) is hot weather for them.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Commonwealth Police</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/commonwealth-police/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/commonwealth-police/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Municipal vs Commonwealth policewomen. Vekllei has many different kinds of police across its islands, but these two are the most well-known. The Commonwealth cops (called Police of the Parliament) are famous for their sabre, which they are trained to use as a deterrent.
Left: Police of the Public, which are municipal police. They spend a lot of time walking around their neighbourhoods and sometimes carry a pistol, usually a revolver.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/commonwealth-police.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Municipal vs Commonwealth policewomen.</div>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> has many different kinds of police across its islands, but these two are the most well-known. The Commonwealth cops (called Police of the Parliament) are famous for their sabre, which they are trained to use as a deterrent.</p>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p><strong>Left:</strong> Police of the Public, which are municipal police. They spend a lot of time walking around their neighbourhoods and sometimes carry a pistol, usually a revolver.</p>
<p><strong>Right:</strong> Police of the Parliament, which are the paramilitary Commonwealth police. They represent federal interests. They are almost always armed, often with compact machine guns.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>

<p>There are actually many other kinds of police in Vekllei, including the Federal Police and different types of special policing, but the most common are the Public and Parliament.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Slip</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/slip/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/slip/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Lame sketch I did in place of finishing a drawing. Very purple. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/slip.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Lame sketch I did in place of finishing a drawing. Very purple.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Mira Uniform</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/isuri/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/isuri/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[From left: Catia, Isuri. This drawing depicts girls wearing school uniforms on the Vekllei republic of Mira (real-life Madeira), a former Portuguese territory that now has a large population of immigrants from Ceylon.
Isuri (right) was born on Mira to Sinhalese parents and Catia (left) is also Miranese. Catia is part of a community of Portuguese muslims who originally settled on the island in the 1960s after persecution in Lisbon.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/isuri.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">From left: Catia, Isuri.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>This drawing depicts girls wearing school uniforms on the <a href="/vekllei/"><span class="fi fi-com"></span> Vekllei</a> republic of  <a href="/mira/"><span class="fi fi-mira"></span> Mira</a> (real-life Madeira), a former Portuguese territory that now has a large population of immigrants from <a href="/ceylon/"><span class="fi fi-lk"></span> Ceylon</a>.</p>
<p>Isuri (right) was born on Mira to Sinhalese parents and Catia (left) is also Miranese. Catia is part of a community of <a href="/portugal/"><span class="fi fi-pt"></span> Portuguese</a> muslims who originally settled on the island in the 1960s after persecution in Lisbon. Since 2030, all Miranese people are now citizens of the united island republics called Vekllei.</p>
<p>The uniform is in the <a href="/education/">Commonwealth tradition</a>, consisting of simple universal elements accentuated by cultural accessories. In this case, features of Miranese traditional dress like red striped wool skirts and throws or capes are included. A hat is also part of uniform, called the Miranese Carapuça.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sabae-chan</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sabae/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sabae/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Going out for drinks after work. This character belongs to a Japanese artist and train enthusiast I follow on Twitter. Something about her appearance and oversized glasses were really funny to me, so I decided to draw her. This must have been out of left field for him, since I&rsquo;d never interacted with him before, but he really liked it!
Her name is Sabae-chan, and was created by @unagiPost. &ldquo;Sabae&rdquo; is a city in Japan famous for manufacturing, well, glasses.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/sabae-1.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Going out for drinks after work.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>This character belongs to a Japanese artist and train enthusiast I follow on Twitter. Something about her appearance and oversized glasses were really funny to me, so I decided to draw her. This must have been out of left field for him, since I&rsquo;d never interacted with him before, but he really liked it!</p>
<p>Her name is Sabae-chan, and was created by <a href="https://twitter.com/unagiPost">@unagiPost</a>. &ldquo;Sabae&rdquo; is a city in Japan famous for manufacturing, well, glasses.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/unagiPost">@unagiPost</a> liked my drawing:</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/media/sabae-3.png" alt="image of Sabae-chan and Cobian"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>




 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/media/sabae-4.png" alt="image of Sabae-chan and Cobian"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<p>So I said she was planning to go on vacation:</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/fullres/sabae-2.jpg" alt="image of Sabae-chan and Cobian"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<p>His followers reacted with amusement that someone from Australia was drawing his characters:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Now you&rsquo;re an international cultured person!&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This character is more popular with overseas followers than in Japan, so I would like to consider adding English without joking.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;I have to study English! &lsquo;Lady Sabae.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/media/sabae-5.png" alt="image of Sabae-chan and Cobian"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s funny how the internet connects train enthusiasts.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Drinks</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/work-drinks/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/work-drinks/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Going out for drinks after work. A bit of a time-skip from the usual chronology. Here, they&rsquo;re all 22 years old.
Lin Zhi is a junior photovolume engineer, and recovers holographic crystal memory used in Vekllei photo-electric computers.
Tzipora is a librarian at Seispri Municipal Library and is waiting for someone to compliment her new cardigan.
Cobian is a ward nurse at Seispri Hospital in the nuclear medicine wing.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/drinks.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Going out for drinks after work.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>A bit of a time-skip from the usual chronology. Here, they&rsquo;re all 22 years old.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi is a junior photovolume engineer, and recovers holographic crystal memory used in Vekllei photo-electric computers.</p>
<p>Tzipora is a librarian at Seispri Municipal Library and is waiting for someone to compliment her new cardigan.</p>
<p>Cobian is a ward nurse at Seispri Hospital in the nuclear medicine wing.</p>
<p>They&rsquo;re going to the pub. Coretti is in a war in the Congo. Moise is in Indonesia working for a company whose name nobody can remember.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Scrap</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/scrap/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/scrap/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ She always comes out on top. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/scrap.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">She always comes out on top.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Picture of Integration</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/integration/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/integration/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Sitting on the concrete sea wall in Lola. Tzipora was a picture of integration, because she wanted badly for people to respect her. She also felt she owed something to the country which had lifted her up and given her a quality of life. She had no prospects before coming to Oslola, so she practiced gratitude in everything she did &ndash; sometimes out loud.
Lin Zhi was not a picture of integration; Lin Zhi was a black box.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/zhi.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Sitting on the concrete sea wall in <a href="/lola/">Lola</a>.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora was a picture of integration, because she wanted badly for people to respect her. She also felt she owed something to the country which had lifted her up and given her a quality of life. She had no prospects before coming to Oslola, so she practiced gratitude in everything she did &ndash; sometimes out loud.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi was not a picture of integration; Lin Zhi was a black box. She barely spoke English &ndash; the common language of Vekllei&rsquo;s immigrant society and international schools. A lot of the English she did speak came in short, sharp barks. Her severe disposition was well known at <a href="/moshel/">Moshel St School</a>. They were paired together in gardening class, and Tzipora learned soon enough that Lin Zhi was not so much rude as she was quiet and isolated, and did not trust or like her peers.</p>
<p>Tzipora was terrible at making friends, but not because she was out of tune with people&rsquo;s feelings. She knew Zhi was a private person instinctively, and so she did not ask her questions or force conversation except to plant crops and water ferns. Zhi in turn became used to her and they developed silent routines in class.</p>
<p>When Tzipora broke her arm a few months later, Zhi asked how she broke it, without looking up from the soil.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I was playing tennis and fell on it.&rdquo;</p>
<p>And Lin Zhi laughed once.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Streets of Seispri</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/seispri/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/seispri/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Central Seispri is full of switchbacks, alleys and tunnels. Seispri is one of the older neighbourhoods in Lola. It is situated on the hills above the historic capital of Reykjavic, and retains its medieval character and chaotic, vernacular architecture. It feels lived-in and worn from a thousand years of commerce.
It used to be an upmarket neighbourhood, prior to the Atomic War in 1995. Today it is tired and cramped, after its slipshod reconstruction in the early postwar years.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/seispri.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Central Seispri is full of switchbacks, alleys and tunnels.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Seispri is one of the older neighbourhoods in <a href="/lola/">Lola</a>. It is situated on the hills above the historic capital of Reykjavic, and retains its medieval character and chaotic, vernacular architecture. It feels lived-in and worn from a thousand years of commerce.</p>
<p>It used to be an upmarket neighbourhood, prior to the Atomic War in 1995. Today it is tired and cramped, after its slipshod reconstruction in the early postwar years. Seispri has a large community of immigrant Jews from Southern Europe, and has large populations of Greeks and Albanians too. They give this old place new life and character.</p>
<p>To Tzipora, Seispri was her home. Vekllei did not spend much time thinking about the past these days. This moment lived for the future.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Good Morning</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/good-morning/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/good-morning/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Waking up to bed hair. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/gm.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Waking up to bed hair.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Station Girls</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/station-girls/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/station-girls/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora and Coretti await a train to assist with boarding. Tzipora the Platform Attendant # Tzipora was a train enthusiast &ndash; of course she was, you somehow knew that looking at her. She was a member of the Vekllei Rail Association, and worked a couple days a month as a platform attendant. It was part hobby and part job. She had training in first aid and disability services, and so she helped Commonwealth National Rail &ndash; she rode the trains around giving timetable advice and assisting disabled passengers board and alight trains.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/station.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora and Coretti await a train to assist with boarding.</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="tzipora-the-platform-attendant">
  Tzipora the Platform Attendant
  <a class="anchor" href="#tzipora-the-platform-attendant">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Tzipora was a train enthusiast &ndash; of course she was, you somehow knew that looking at her. She was a member of the <em>Vekllei Rail Association</em>, and worked a couple days a month as a platform attendant. It was part hobby and part job. She had training in first aid and disability services, and so she helped Commonwealth National Rail &ndash; she rode the trains around giving timetable advice and assisting disabled passengers board and alight trains.</p>
<p>She had been shilling the Rail Association to her friends, but none of them shared her enthusiasm for train travel. The exception was Coretti, who joined because she was dating Tzipora&rsquo;s friend, Moise, and was trying to know her better. They were employed by CNR in an unusual legal framework as &ldquo;associate employees,&rdquo; or volunteers. These jobs are common in Vekllei, where work is play and volunteerism is beat into them.</p>
<h2 id="uniform-notes">
  Uniform Notes
  <a class="anchor" href="#uniform-notes">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Commonwealth National Rail employs nearly 40,000 people and has many uniforms. Both Tzipora and Coretti wear white gloves, which is a recent addition. You are supposed to wear them if you are going to touch people, since there are now many immigrants in Vekllei and not all of them are as comfortable as Oslolans being touched or pushed by service staff.</p>
<p>Both Coretti and Tzipora are wearing their ordinary shoes and school skirts. The practical colours of their school uniform allow a single navy skirt, white shirt or pair of leather shoes to be useful in many different roles in society, reducing waste.</p>
<h2 id="civic-associations-in-vekllei">
  Civic Associations in Vekllei
  <a class="anchor" href="#civic-associations-in-vekllei">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Three types of civic association exist in Vekllei.</p>
<ol>
<li>Labour Syndicates: organised labour in enterprises that are not democratised. Most commonly, these apply to small and medium-sized businesses.</li>
<li>Policy Advocates: special-interest policy groups that are expressly political.</li>
<li>Councils: organised associations of people with something in common.</li>
</ol>
<p>What all have them in common is that they are <em>organised</em>; they have a leadership structure, and keep records. Similar organisations exist in many other countries, but Commonwealth <em>councils</em> are unique in their ubiquity and power in society. Their interests range from Polish cultural groups to academic associations and, indeed, railroad employees and enthusiasts.</p>
<p>It is important to remember that work is primarily social in Vekllei and consequently it does not occupy the same role in people&rsquo;s lives. Few Vekllei jobs simply &ldquo;clock in, clock out.&rdquo; Instead, there is a vast sea of semi-professionalised labour that exists somewhere between employment and hobbyism. It is in this context that councils proliferate, and force a reconsideration of how we think about work.</p>
<p>Large companies have large associate councils. These are not integrated directly &ndash; they exist voluntarily, as congregations of enthusiasts. Commonwealth Airways has several associate councils with which it engages and does business, including the Student Pilots Association No. 1184, Commonwealth Air Enthusiasts No. 622, Atlantic Model Aeroplane Association No. 646, Air Doctors Social Club No. 801, Women in Flight No. 340, and many others.</p>
<p>Councils are a means to engage with customers, provide employees with social and recreational opportunities, and solicit ideas and labour from enthusiasts. Consequently, there are millions of Vekllei people who have semi-professional gigs on the side. These councils, in turn, provide avenues for employment and a means to socialise with like-minded people. They also contribute representatives to the civic ecclesia<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> of a local area, and thus advise local government. They are often fickle, schismatic, and poorly organised &ndash; but they&rsquo;re social organisations, and are afforded those shortcomings.</p>
<p>Other types of council might represent Islamic interests in a city, or Lithuanian culture. Others organise amateur bakers. Their diversity allows for a kind of organising not represented by labour unions or political associations, and validate a variety of interests in the function of democratic government.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>A civic ecclesia is an advisory body of citizens in a <a href="/polis/">local administration</a>. It consists of notable citizens in good standing, cultural groups and representatives from Councils.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Jump Comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/jump/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/jump/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/comics/jump/feature.png"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/jump/1.jpg" alt="comic page 1"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>




 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/jump/2.jpg" alt="comic page 2"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>




 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/jump/3.jpg" alt="comic page 3"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>




 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/jump/4.jpg" alt="comic page 4"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Miss Colombia</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/miss-colombia/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/miss-colombia/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora&rsquo;s only party dress. Tzipora was a foreigner. It was hard to pick out a distinct cultural background amidst her school uniform and wardrobe of modest, secular dailywear, which is typical of Vekllei. But she was a foreigner, and on a few days a year, when she wore her only party dress, you remembered that fact.
It is easy to lose track of who comes from where in Vekllei. About half of people were born overseas, and the other half have history in one of a dozen scattered republics that make up the country.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/dress.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora&rsquo;s only party dress.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora was a foreigner. It was hard to pick out a distinct cultural background amidst her school uniform and wardrobe of modest, secular dailywear, which is typical of Vekllei. But she was a foreigner, and on a few days a year, when she wore her only party dress, you remembered that fact.</p>
<p>It is easy to lose track of who comes from where in Vekllei. About half of people were born overseas, and the other half have history in one of a dozen scattered republics that make up the country. It is a deeply multicultural society, a fact which is treasured and protected by the Commonwealth government.</p>
<p>At school, they wore the same uniforms every day, which made seeing your classmates at the end-of-term formal a shock. People you thought had lived here all their lives showed up in gowns of styles you&rsquo;d never seen. And here was Tzipora, previously known as an Italian, a Gypsy, an Indian or whatever else they guessed of her, now revealed to be Colombian &ndash; as she always had been.</p>
<!--In general, the centralisation of textiles and clothing manufacturers in Vekllei has had the effect of obscuring ethnicity. The Commonwealth has no common race, language or culture. Instead, it is a country by values and circumstance. This is a market that offers everyone basically the same department stores with the same styles of clothes, whether your family has been here for two weeks or a thousand years. The wardrobes of Vekllei people are filled with modest dailywear and something nice for church or occasions, which has the effect of reifying the appearance of society.

To clarify, when we talk about dressing people 'basically the same,' we do not imply literal uniforms as found in their schools or something comparable to the 'Mao-suit' -- department stores offer a million items in many styles. But they are all *commonwealth* styles, in a vision of the *democratic* man and woman, and so they do not contribute to the diverse cultural clothing background of Vekllei's disparate republics. That is not to say that traditional or cultural clothing does not exist (it is common) or that it is suppressed (it isn't) -- just that this state of affairs is convenient for a new country eager to celebrate a shared, civic identity in which any man filled with the democratic spirit can gain citizenship.-->
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Cola Comic</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/cola/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/cola/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/comics/cola/feature.png"/> <p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/cola/1.png" alt="comic page 1"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>




 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/cola/2.png" alt="comic page 2"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>




 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/cola/3.png" alt="comic page 3"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>




 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/comics/cola/4.png" alt="comic page 4"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Portrait for Nico</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/nico/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/nico/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ A portrait for my friend Nico. Happy birthday, dear friend! 🌺 ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/nico.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">A portrait for my friend Nico. Happy birthday, dear friend! 🌺</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Portrait</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/portrait/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/portrait/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Portrait of Tzipora &amp; Cobian finished in a painterly style. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/portrait.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Portrait of Tzipora &amp; Cobian finished in a painterly style.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Dunes</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/dune/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/dune/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora flying down a sand dune at 45km/h. Oslola has a number of highland dunes made of fine black sand, formed by its active volcanoes and shaped by glacial runoff.
A popular game when visiting is to race someone to the bottom. Because these dunes are very steep and very tall (up to 40 meters) it&rsquo;s easy to end up flying down face-first.
The dunes also have a very important role in Oslolan mythology, as the birthplace of subterranean mole creatures called Somoron.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/dune.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora flying down a sand dune at 45km/h.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Oslola has a number of highland dunes made of fine black sand, formed by its active volcanoes and shaped by glacial runoff.</p>
<p>A popular game when visiting is to race someone to the bottom. Because these dunes are very steep and very tall (up to 40 meters) it&rsquo;s easy to end up flying down face-first.</p>
<p>The dunes also have a very important role in Oslolan mythology, as the birthplace of subterranean mole creatures called Somoron.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Weirdo</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/weirdo/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/weirdo/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Zelda&rsquo;s a weirdo, but she&rsquo;s a friend. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/weirdo.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Zelda&rsquo;s a weirdo, but she&rsquo;s a friend.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Friends</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/friends-draft/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/friends-draft/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Paint-sketch of the girls together I never ended up finishing. Clockwise:
Cobian is an Algic girl, which means she&rsquo;s indigenous to Iceland in my world, which is called Oslola. She comes from a mixed indigenous Arctic background. Her mother is kind of crazy and Cobian is a bit insecure, but she&rsquo;s very close with Tzipora. They drift between friends and girlfriends, it&rsquo;s complicated.
Coretti is Afro-Russian. Even though she was born in Congo (sometimes called Zaire in my world) she grew up in the USSR and immigrated to Oslola later on.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/draft.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Paint-sketch of the girls together I never ended up finishing.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Clockwise:</p>
<p>Cobian is an Algic girl, which means she&rsquo;s indigenous to Iceland in my world, which is called Oslola. She comes from a mixed indigenous Arctic background. Her mother is kind of crazy and Cobian is a bit insecure, but she&rsquo;s very close with Tzipora. They drift between friends and girlfriends, it&rsquo;s complicated.</p>
<p>Coretti is Afro-Russian. Even though she was born in Congo (sometimes called Zaire in my world) she grew up in the USSR and immigrated to Oslola later on. She&rsquo;s very patient and graceful, and is dating Tzipora&rsquo;s best friend Moise.</p>
<p>Lin Zhi is Chinese and always goes by her full name. She doesn&rsquo;t speak much of their language and she&rsquo;s kind of a hothead so she&rsquo;s a bit of a mystery to them. But Tzipora attracts eccentric characters and Lin Zhi doesn&rsquo;t have any other friends so she hangs out with them.</p>
<p>Finally, Tzipora (being held) is the main character of the story. Her mother was Spanish Roma and her father was Yiddish. She&rsquo;s very friendly but intense and she&rsquo;s sort of the focus point which the friendship group is centred around. She&rsquo;s got more going on with her (she doesn&rsquo;t live with her parents and how she came to Vekllei is ambiguous) but she&rsquo;s just trying her best.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The News</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/news/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/news/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ &ldquo;Tzipora, I&rsquo;m not going to read it if it&rsquo;s another article about airlines.&rdquo; ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/news.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">&ldquo;Tzipora, I&rsquo;m not going to read it if it&rsquo;s another article about airlines.&rdquo;</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora&#39;s New Look</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sack/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sack/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora&rsquo;s new fit: a sack worn over a school shirt. This was part of an experiment simplifying her style. This scene takes place in the borough of Sojiya, next to her home in Lola.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/sack.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora&rsquo;s new fit: a sack worn over a school shirt.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>This was part of an experiment simplifying her style. This scene takes place in the borough of Sojiya, next to her home in Lola.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Saba Island Sneakers</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sneakers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sneakers/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Caribbean uniforms. Characters don&rsquo;t have names yet, if you have suggestions let me know. The girl on the left is kind of angry all the time. Tzipora and her friends are from Oslola (Iceland), these girls are from Saba (Saba Island). I&rsquo;ll do a proper post on Saba soon, this was just character concept stuff.
The shoes are knockoff Vekllei anarchocommunist Stan Smiths.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/sneakers.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Caribbean uniforms. Characters don&rsquo;t have names yet, if you have suggestions let me know. The girl on the left is kind of angry all the time.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora and her friends are from <a href="/factbook/society/state/constituents/#oslola-commonwealth-iceland">Oslola</a> (Iceland), these girls are from <a href="/factbook/society/state/constituents/#kalina-commonwealth">Saba</a> (Saba Island). I&rsquo;ll do a proper post on Saba soon, this was just character concept stuff.</p>
<p>The shoes are knockoff Vekllei anarchocommunist Stan Smiths.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sulking</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sulk/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sulk/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Tzipora is sulking because Cobian called her hair &ldquo;short and oily.&rdquo; ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/sulk.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora is sulking because Cobian called her hair &ldquo;short and oily.&rdquo;</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Anarchist Trams</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/trams/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/trams/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Life is not that different, but is improved in ordinary and meaningful ways. People still go to school and work, as depicted here. The progress is in democracy and quality of life, not in essential patterns of human behaviour. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/tram.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Life is not that different, but is improved in ordinary and meaningful ways. People still go to school and work, as depicted here. The progress is in democracy and quality of life, not in essential patterns of human behaviour.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Analyst</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/analyst/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/analyst/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Ayn is an Intelligence Analyst at HO/NI&rsquo;s Section 3. Intelligence officers in the Commonwealth have ranks, called Grades, and receive awards that can be displayed above their ID tag in formal settings. In civilian clothes, two awards (usually the highest but at the discretion of the officer) are worn in a ribbon bar. In full dress the medals are worn.
From top to bottom, Ayn&rsquo;s accessories are listed:
Ribbon bar featuring the Order of Veletia and the National Service Medal.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/analyst.jpg"/> <p>Ayn is an Intelligence Analyst at HO/NI&rsquo;s Section 3. Intelligence officers in the Commonwealth have ranks, called Grades, and receive awards that can be displayed above their ID tag in formal settings. In civilian clothes, two awards (usually the highest but at the discretion of the officer) are worn in a ribbon bar. In full dress the medals are worn.</p>
<p>From top to bottom, Ayn&rsquo;s accessories are listed:</p>
<ol>
<li>Ribbon bar featuring the Order of Veletia and the National Service Medal.</li>
<li>ID tag featuring name, photograph, ID number, expiry and department.</li>
<li>The HO/NI Intelligence Pin worn by all officers.</li>
<li>The Order of Veletia, awarded for saving many lives or preventing extraordinary harm as part of service, or for acts of extraordinary courage. Ayn received this for her part in Operation Sea of Reeds.</li>
<li>The National Service Medal, awarded for consistently distinguished and competent service to the directorate. Ayn received this shortly after ten years service for her exemplary work in analysis.</li>
</ol>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hardware</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hardware/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hardware/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ &ldquo;Throw out the hardware. Let&rsquo;s do it right.&rdquo; ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/fullres/hardware.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">&ldquo;Throw out the hardware. Let&rsquo;s do it right.&rdquo;</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Downpour</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/downpour/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/downpour/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Where warm oceanic currents meet arctic air, a downpour catches Cobian on her way home. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/downpour.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Where warm oceanic currents meet arctic air, a downpour catches Cobian on her way home.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Natural Corners</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/corner/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/corner/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ If you can find a natural corner, they make a good place to read away from all the noise. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/corner.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">If you can find a natural corner, they make a good place to read away from all the noise.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Tzipora, the Wanderer</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/field-portrait/</link>
	  <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/field-portrait/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Portait of Tzipora wearing school clothes in the Vekllei Highlands. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/field-portrait.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Portait of Tzipora wearing school clothes in the Vekllei Highlands.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Atomic Main Battle Tank</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/tank/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/tank/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The &ldquo;Sekhmet&rdquo; No. 4 MBT, with commander in Day Fatigues The experience of Commonwealth Expeditionary forces in West Africa exposed many weakness in existing equipment and strategy. Vehicles designed primarily to defend urban environments after a nuclear war found their weak points ruthlessly targeted in close-quarters asymmetric fighting. If the Commonwealth was truly going to become a great democratic power, with a hand in the affairs of its allies, that meant assembling a force trained for all climates in all theatres of the world.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/tank.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The &ldquo;Sekhmet&rdquo; No. 4 MBT, with commander in <a href="/stories/infantry/">Day Fatigues</a></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The experience of Commonwealth Expeditionary forces in West Africa exposed many weakness in existing equipment and strategy. Vehicles designed primarily to defend urban environments after a nuclear war found their weak points ruthlessly targeted in close-quarters asymmetric fighting. If the Commonwealth was truly going to become a great democratic power, with a hand in the affairs of its allies, that meant assembling a force trained for all climates in all theatres of the world.</p>
<p>These lessons became more important as we approached the middle of the 21st Century, after the Africa Wars intensified and the scope of Commonwealth peacekeeping expanded. The Army of the Atlantic Crown, as it is still called, needed to professionalise. The decision was made to separate the existing fighting servicemen &ndash; the traditional Army, made up of hundreds of thousands of Atlantic conscripts and dedicated militias and reservists, would remain as a defensive force across the Commonwealth. The new Expeditionary Corps would be an elite, professional Army trained for specialised and extended war-fighting overseas, to meet the moral and political commitments the Commonwealth had made to the 21st Century. Counted in regiments rather than divisions, the Expeditionary Corps is the tip of the spear of Commonwealth warfare, fighting short and surgical wars that leverage the country&rsquo;s technological and equipment advantage.</p>
<p>Expeditionary Corps units are made up of tactical brigades that are assembled out of strategic regiments for special purposes. The 23rd, 24th and 25th Armoured Regiments are the elite armoured shock units of the Commonwealth&rsquo;s armed forces, and use its latest tank platform, the No. 4 &ldquo;Sekhmet.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Military equipment is numbered consecutively in Vekllei, so the No. 4 MBT is the 4th domestic MBT in service. It is a distinctive tank, with a pronounced bustle that overhangs the domed molten salt fission microreactor and steam turbine engine. The bustle houses the armoured munitions magazine, which feeds 100mm shells into the stabilised cannon. Another distinctive feature is its &ldquo;panoramic&rdquo; vision blocks and periscopes, which give the driver and gunner much improved visibility while turned in. This was an evolution from the No. 3 MBT, which in exercises demonstrated the superior accuracy of fighting with hatches open.</p>
<p>The reactor is highly armoured, and additional anti-rocket slat armour is often mounted to further protect the turbine and transmission from shoulder-launched missiles and rockets. There are currently 480 No. 4s in service, which have replaced No. 3s in the Expeditionary Corps. A previous-generation export version is also in service in Yugoslavia and the DR Congo.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>General Infantry</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/infantry/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/infantry/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Uniforms from left: Day Fatigues, Battle Fatigues, Barracks Dress, Social Dress It had not even occurred to Coretti that she would see combat. She had never intended to enlist with with the infrantry at all &ndash; her life plan, so it was in 2066, was fairly conventional. She would do her four years in Compulsory Service, studying while working as an administrator or circuit technician, and leave with some experience and civil awards (and with luck, a honeymoon).]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/infantry.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Uniforms from left: Day Fatigues, Battle Fatigues, Barracks Dress, Social Dress</div>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
<p>It had not even occurred to Coretti that she would see combat. She had never intended to enlist with with the infrantry at all &ndash; her life plan, so it was in 2066, was fairly conventional. She would do her four years in <a href="/corsosva/">Compulsory Service</a>, studying while working as an administrator or circuit technician, and leave with some experience and civil awards (and with luck, a honeymoon). But the call went out that year: the government had pledged to save democracy in the Congo, and the infantry needed soldiers with a good grasp of French to fight a nasty little bush war to prevent a Soviet or American regime.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Coretti had grown up in Russia, and couldn&rsquo;t remember Zaire. But nonetheless, she was Congolese, wasn&rsquo;t she? She could be Vekllei, Russian, and Congolese simultaneously, such was the enlightened age of the 21st Century. And if she was Congolese, as she felt she was, wasn&rsquo;t it a terrible thing to turn your back on your country? Everyone gave four years &ndash; there was no getting around it. If she chose to stay out of the army, she had a feeling she&rsquo;d regret it for the rest of her life.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="women-in-the-army">
  Women in the Army
  <a class="anchor" href="#women-in-the-army">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Vekllei accepts women into its armed forces and has done so since independence in 2015.</p>
<p>All Vekllei people have to give four years to their country as part of <a href="/corsosva/">Compulsory Service</a>, including women. The majority of people enter civilian service in construction, medicine, administration or in overseas postings. About 20% enter the armed forces, and about 15% of those enter combat units.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>Of the Commonwealth women that enter the Atlantic Armed Forces, only 15% enlist with the army. This minority is visible in striking contrast with the Navy, in which nearly half of sailors are women, and the Air Force, which is majority women. The Air Force has historically been an opportune place for female conscripts to demonstrate their bravery and fighting skill, because they make excellent pilots and the male physical and cultural advantages are not apparent there. More Vekllei women serve in combat roles in the Vekllei Air Force than American women do in the entire US military.</p>
<p>Women were poorly represented in the Army for most of its existence, which was a result of the preference and paternalism of army command. Women face unique threats of violence in combat that their male comrades do not, and this risk was generally not acceptable to the military chiefs. Even now, there is a general hesitation among the Army to rotate female-majority units into frontline service, and are often preferred as home guards and training staff instead. This attitude is changing slowly, but it is changing, spurred by the success of female soldiers on the ground, which has demonstrated irrefutably that female soldiers are not weaker, more prone to injury, or less cohesive than men.</p>
<p>The Army has made efforts to support self-selecting women interested in frontline combat roles by making available leadership positions in special brigades, and altering previously unpopular rules. For example, until 2044, female volunteers were expected to shave their heads like their male comrades. With new recognition and effective policy, there are more women in the Army now than at any point in its history.</p>
<h2 id="uniform">
  Uniform
  <a class="anchor" href="#uniform">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p>Enlisted infantry receive summer and winter versions of each uniform. At home, infantry wear &ldquo;coffee colours;&rdquo; the colour of the Army. Depending on their station overseas, these colours are covered or replaced with local camouflage. There are four basic uniforms for infantry of all kinds.</p>
<ol>
<li>Day fatigues are worn around the barracks and for most types of service outside of combat. The trousers are bloused in regulation coffee brown, but the cotton-sateen shirt is a dusty brown as part of civilian hybridisation common in Vekllei armed forces. It is always tucked. Day fatigues can be worn with or without a helmet or slouch hat, depending on duty. Soldiers also train in day fatigues.</li>
<li>Battle dress sees a field jacket worn over or replacing the day fatigues shirt, which can be tucked or left out. The equipment of a soldier varies from mission to mission, but No. 3 harnesses and No. 6 packs are most common. Coretti here is carrying a No. 16 small battle rifle, called a &ldquo;midge.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Soldiers are issued with two sets of seasonal full dress uniform in Vekllei, which is worn in parades and outside of base overseas. It sacrifices some of the attractive tailoring of foreign parade dress for comfort and breathability, since it is generally worn more often than strict parade uniform overseas. This version depicted here, called a No. 4, also demonstrates many indigenous Vekllei features. These include:
<ol>
<li>The Army slouch hat, basically unchanged in appearance since independence.</li>
<li>A white “Sam Browne” belt with a silver buckle plate embossed with the Army’s crown, which supports a No. 6 service revolver with a personalised synthetic pearl handle.</li>
<li>A ceremonial sword gifted to the soldier upon completing basic training, worn at the side. Soldiers also receive training for use of a sword, and some even wear it on patrol.</li>
<li>Slacks or a skirt, paired with brown oxfords. A <a href="/stories/crown/">Gi</a> is worn with the skirt.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Social dress is analogous to “mess dress” overseas, and is worn at social or semi-formal functions after 6pm. Before 6pm, parade dress is worn in its place. It also features Vekllei cultural items, like the cape and <a href="/stories/crown/">Gi</a>.</li>
</ol>
</div>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="equipment-guide">
  Equipment Guide
  <a class="anchor" href="#equipment-guide">#</a>
</h2>
<blockquote class="hint panel">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text"><p>This index is not comprehensive &ndash; many standard patrol items are not depicted here.</p>
<ol>
<li>Unit Patch</li>
<li>Camouflage paint tube</li>
<li>No. 2 Emergency radio</li>
<li>Canteen and cooking implements</li>
<li>Nylon rope</li>
<li>Division Epaulette</li>
<li>A lensatic compass</li>
<li>Can of serum albumin blood-volume expander</li>
<li>No. 12 WP Smoke</li>
<li>No. 6 Tear Smoke</li>
<li>Machete</li>
<li>Diamond and ruby deployment pin</li>
<li>Name plate</li>
<li>No. 6 Service Revolver</li>
<li>Award for overseas deployment</li>
<li>Award for gallantry under fire</li>
</ol>
</div>
</blockquote>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>All Vekllei people undergo combat training as per its ungovernable doctrine, but only a small minority of people enter the armed forces as soldiers.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Short</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/short/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/short/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[From left: Tzipora and Fitri. Fitri is the shortest girl in Moshel St School&rsquo;s 10th Grade. Tzipora is the second-shortest. It is for this reason that Tzipora likes Fitri.
Tzipora doesn&rsquo;t mix with her crowd much, and doesn&rsquo;t really know much about her. They&rsquo;d talked a couple times when they were paired up in science class, but Fitri was shy and closed off. There was something about her timidness and appearance that made her seem obscure and impossible to learn from.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/short.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">From left: Tzipora and Fitri.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Fitri is the shortest girl in <a href="/moshel/">Moshel St School&rsquo;s</a> 10th Grade. Tzipora is the second-shortest. It is for this reason that Tzipora likes Fitri.</p>
<p>Tzipora doesn&rsquo;t mix with her crowd much, and doesn&rsquo;t really know much about her. They&rsquo;d talked a couple times when they were paired up in science class, but Fitri was shy and closed off. There was something about her timidness and appearance that made her seem obscure and impossible to learn from. That wasn&rsquo;t Fitri&rsquo;s fault, Tzipora supposed, but it did nothing to change her opinion. Sometimes people just don&rsquo;t connect.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Grey on the Mind</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/grey/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/grey/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora in all-grey. Tzipora has conservative tastes in fashion that fuse with her eccentric instincts. The result is something between timidness and postmodern rebellion.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/grey.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora in all-grey.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora has conservative tastes in fashion that fuse with her eccentric instincts. The result is something between timidness and postmodern rebellion.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Hats</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hats/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hats/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ A) the beret B) the sunhat and C) the crown ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/hats.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">A) the beret B) the sunhat and C) the <a href="/stories/crown">crown</a></div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>On the Stair</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/stair/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/stair/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Tzipora and Cobian on the staircase of Tzipora&rsquo;s apartment after school. Tzipora doesn&rsquo;t sleep that well, so her energy plummets in the early afternoon. After school, she loads up on soft drinks to keep her going until dinner. There is a marked change in her spirits after she&rsquo;s got some sugar in her system.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/stair.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora and Cobian on the staircase of Tzipora&rsquo;s apartment after school.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Tzipora doesn&rsquo;t sleep that well, so her energy plummets in the early afternoon. After school, she loads up on soft drinks to keep her going until dinner. There is a marked change in her spirits after she&rsquo;s got some sugar in her system.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sketch of Coretti Adoula</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/coretti/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/coretti/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Coretti Adoula, with her boyfriend Moise behind her. Pictured here is Coretti Adoula, Moise&rsquo;s sweet-natured girlfriend. Originally from the USSR, she moves to Vekllei and enters Tzipora&rsquo;s orbit of friends via Moise after they start dating.
She&rsquo;s eating Vekllei chips, which are seasoned above smoking meats and are usually eaten without sauce. Most supermarkets and many cafes offer them as snacks, as a tasty byproduct of meat preparation.
Here is her original sketch:]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/corettibg.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Coretti Adoula, with her boyfriend Moise behind her.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Pictured here is Coretti Adoula, Moise&rsquo;s sweet-natured girlfriend. Originally from the USSR, she moves to Vekllei and enters Tzipora&rsquo;s orbit of friends via Moise after they start dating.</p>
<p>She&rsquo;s eating Vekllei chips, which are seasoned above smoking meats and are usually eaten without sauce. Most supermarkets and many cafes offer them as snacks, as a tasty byproduct of meat preparation.</p>
<p>Here is her original sketch:</p>
<p>


 
<figure>
  <img src="/images/sketches/coretti.jpg" alt="sketch of coretti"  loading="lazy" />
  
</figure>
</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Vekllei Jeep</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/jeep/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/jeep/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The M2 &ldquo;Stallion&rdquo; General-Purpose Utility Vehicle. The M2 &ldquo;Stallion&rdquo; is the backbone of the army. It carries everything from troops to stretchers to fission reactors across streets, sand and snow. It is customisable at the factory and in the field, and can serve nearly any role for Vekllei&rsquo;s fast-moving, hard-hitting army regiments.
It is a medium-wheelbase1 utility vehicle with a naturally aspirated 6-cylinder, 4.6 litre diesel engine made by Atlantic Auto.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/jeep.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The M2 &ldquo;Stallion&rdquo; General-Purpose Utility Vehicle.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>The M2 &ldquo;Stallion&rdquo; is the backbone of the army. It carries everything from troops to stretchers to fission reactors across streets, sand and snow. It is customisable at the factory and in the field, and can serve nearly any role for Vekllei&rsquo;s fast-moving, hard-hitting army regiments.</p>
<p>It is a medium-wheelbase<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> utility vehicle with a naturally aspirated 6-cylinder, 4.6 litre diesel engine made by Atlantic Auto. No one company can lay claim to the success of the vehicle &ndash; the M2 is the result of industrial collaboration on a national scale, involving hundreds of contractors to meet a visionary committee brief. It has a 5-speed manual transmission with front and rear locking hubs that allow it to leap up boulders, with enough torque to tow armoured vehicles out of the line of fire.</p>
<p>Almost all aspects of the vehicle can be repaired and replaced in the field. The electrical system, engine block and panelling are accessible and modular. Its reliability is famous, and it will run happily for hundreds of thousands of kilometres in fire and ice.</p>
<p>The M2 can be configured as an ambulance, troop carrier, power supply, fuel truck, gun platform, or for many dozens of other uses as required. To this end, it forms the basis of Vekllei&rsquo;s flexible military logistics systems, and should be regarded as essential to the Vekllei Army as their rifles.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>The M2 also comes in six-wheel configurations for heavier payloads.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Zelda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/tzipora/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/tzipora/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Tzipora lo Ula de Helette Azela ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/tzipora.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Tzipora lo Ula de Helette Azela</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Health Vekllei</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/health/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/health/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Nurse of the Commonwealth Health Service. Healthcare in Vekllei is universal, and run as a government service for the wellbeing of the public. The system is financed and governed by the Commonwealth Health Secretariat, and is provided regionally by national health authorities.
There is no cost to any treatment in the Vekllei healthcare system, and it covers all kinds of care necessary for a comfortable and dignified life. Healthcare professionals, including doctors and nurses, are highly regarded in the Commonwealth and enjoy considerable benefits provided by their health authority.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/nurse.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Nurse of the Commonwealth Health Service.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Healthcare in Vekllei is universal, and run as a government service for the wellbeing of the public. The system is financed and governed by the Commonwealth Health Secretariat, and is provided regionally by national health authorities.</p>
<p>There is no cost to any treatment in the Vekllei healthcare system, and it covers all kinds of care necessary for a comfortable and dignified life. Healthcare professionals, including doctors and nurses, are highly regarded in the Commonwealth and enjoy considerable benefits provided by their health authority. All Vekllei households have an elected doctor, called a General Practitioner, who is their first point of contact with the health system.</p>
<p>Elective cosmetic surgery is uncommon in Vekllei and hard to receive, so medical tourism is a popular way to receive cosmetic dental treatment and other elective procedures, which occur most commonly in the US or Europe.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Dapper Soldier</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/soldier/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/soldier/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Officer in the Army of the Atlantic Crown. Some officers in the Army of the Atlantic Crown wear a tie with their jumpsuit. This is a choice that dates back to WW2, but also a symptom of the visible humanitarian role that the army plays in Vekllei and Africa.
General infantrymen still wear conventional fatigues.
Yes, the Commonwealth Army is formally known as the Army of the Atlantic Crown. This convention gets applied to recent branches too, like the Rocket Navy of the Atlantic Crown.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/soldier.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Officer in the Army of the Atlantic Crown.</div>
</blockquote>

<p>Some officers in the Army of the Atlantic Crown wear a tie with their jumpsuit. This is a choice that dates back to WW2, but also a symptom of the visible humanitarian role that the army plays in Vekllei and Africa.</p>
<p>General infantrymen still wear conventional fatigues.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yes, the Commonwealth Army is formally known as the Army of the Atlantic Crown. This convention gets applied to recent branches too, like the Rocket Navy of the Atlantic Crown.</p>
</blockquote>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Revised Mail Uniform</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/mail-revised/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/mail-revised/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Revised postal uniform. I wanted something a bit more striking and graphic. Vekllei isn&rsquo;t simply a recreation of midcentury fashions, but a projection of what those design instincts might look like in 100 years. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/post.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Revised postal uniform. I wanted something a bit more striking and graphic. Vekllei isn&rsquo;t simply a recreation of midcentury fashions, but a projection of what those design instincts might look like in 100 years.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Caught</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/caught/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/caught/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ They both just agree to pretend they didn&rsquo;t catch each other smoking on the roof. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/caught.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">They both just agree to pretend they didn&rsquo;t catch each other smoking on the roof.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sand</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/sand/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/sand/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Self portrait &ndash; thinking about how much I hate posting. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/sand.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Self portrait &ndash; thinking about how much I hate posting.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>America, 2059</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/hispanic/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/hispanic/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[By November 2059, America was in an uneasy peace. The lease of nuclear sites &ldquo;essential for continental strategic security&rdquo; had been secured by Washington the previous month, and the June ceasefire was still in place despite a border skirmish that killed half a dozen GIs not far from where Tzipora was, in Southwest Utah.
The Dallas Administration, which was at this point calling itself the American War Government, was using the ceasefire to lick its wounds and negotiate with state militias to form a central command.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/hispanic.jpg"/> <p>By November 2059, America was in an uneasy peace. The lease of nuclear sites &ldquo;essential for continental strategic security&rdquo; had been secured by Washington the previous month, and the June ceasefire was still in place despite a border skirmish that killed half a dozen GIs not far from where Tzipora was, in Southwest Utah.</p>
<p>The Dallas Administration, which was at this point calling itself the American War Government, was using the ceasefire to lick its wounds and negotiate with state militias to form a central command. The romance of a grassroots revolt, risen in a frenzy of rage and opportunity, had worn off. Now, the secessionist regions were digging in for serious fighting.</p>
<p>The quality of life varied between states. In Texas, things were better, but the borders had been closed. In Utah, things were collapsing. There was not much money around and the government in Salt Lake had lost control over their army. In towns like Cherry, police and soldiers worked together to maintain order or murder and rob; whichever took their fancy that day.</p>
<p>Tzipora knew she was at risk, but her options were limited. She lived and worked at Hotel Cairo (formerly Hotel Zion), which was a ways out of town. Most of the other girls had gone home or fled the state months ago, so there was plenty of work. No one else would employ aliens. She did not yet have enough money to make it to the East Coast, which would require bribing pretty much everyone she met along the way. The journey was dangerous, too &ndash; the busses had stopped and the trains weren&rsquo;t running, so you had to walk. There were a lot of violent drifters just moving through these days.</p>
<p>Come November 2059, it was obvious her time was running out. Posters had gone up announcing all &lsquo;Hispanics&rsquo; &ndash; a term here meaning people that looked like they came from Mexico or further south, not just spanish-speakers &ndash; were to be evacuated from the border. Neighbouring Nevada was a Washington-controlled state, and there would certainly be fighting in Utah. Ostensibly they were worried Latinos had more allegiance to the United States than to Dallas. More likely they just wanted them gone.</p>
<p>The posters said they would be evacuated to Colorado City, but Tzipora figured that was a crock of shit. That was a free city; they wouldn&rsquo;t take foreigners, and especially not people like her. She didn&rsquo;t know where they would send her but she didn&rsquo;t like it. It was not just rumours; Tzipora knew foreigners were being picked off the streets. Dallas was talking about saving the &ldquo;free states&rdquo; from &ldquo;Despotism &amp; Outsider Agitants,&rdquo; and Tzipora looked like an Outsider Agitant.</p>
<p>Hotel Cairo was outside of the evacuation zone, but she would have to carry her work-residence papers everywhere she went now. She just needed to save her cash; the US Dollar was a magical thing. In times like these, it bought comfort, security and opportunity. Staying was a gamble, but what choice did someone like her have? The Dollar was the great equaliser; it was life itself.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>A Government Jet</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/state-jet/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/state-jet/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[The Prime Ministers of Vekllei take a vow of humility upon taking office. This means they have to live on the Parliament Grounds in protected rural acreage, in modest homes known as lodges that are built in a traditional Vekllei style. This spirit of servitude exists in many aspects of a Prime Minister&rsquo;s term, from their humble remuneration to their suits and carriage.
The humility of person, however, does not mean the humility of state.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/statejet.jpg"/> <p>The Prime Ministers of Vekllei take a vow of humility upon taking office. This means they have to live on the Parliament Grounds in protected rural acreage, in modest homes known as lodges that are built in a traditional Vekllei style. This spirit of servitude exists in many aspects of a Prime Minister&rsquo;s term, from their humble remuneration to their suits and carriage.</p>
<p>The humility of person, however, does not mean the humility of state. The 4th Commonwealth takes great pride in its industrial and social achievements, and so diplomats and ministers travel in Vekllei aircraft built for diplomacy, as indicators of wealth and taste &ndash; social vectors for good business. To this end, the Air Force maintains a fleet of bare-metal jets for official business inside and outside the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>This Comen Firewick &lsquo;60 jet has been extensively modified for the security and comfort of the Vekllei public servant. It is a medium-sized government aircraft mostly used for flights within the Commonwealth, stretching the width and depth of the Atlantic. It is easily identifiable as a government jet by its bare-metal livery, which is consistent among the government fleet and is intended to draw attention to the craftsmanship of Vekllei machines. Like most Vekllei jet aircraft, it is primarily a nuclear-electric vessel that uses auxiliary combustion engines for take-off and redundancy. This is a feature of the air-cooled reactor systems in Vekllei aircraft, which require reaching cruising speed to &ldquo;switch over&rdquo; to nuclear-electric propulsion.</p>
<p>The Firewick 60 is well-liked for its distinctive skylights, which allow views of the sky or stars from the cabin. Its interior is well-lighted, though narrower than the wide-body and mono-wing sister aircraft in the government fleet.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>New Ruins</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ruins/</link>
	  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ruins/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[From Copetpek to Reykjavic, the hills of Lola are pockmarked by collapsed brick chimneys and fenceless gates. Here is where they died, in their hundreds of thousands. These monuments watched over the postwar period, where the craters had been filled in and decontaminated.
You were not supposed to play in the ruins because of residual radiation. That&rsquo;s what they were told as kids. The truth is that the stones were next to harmless after seventy years.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/ruins.jpg"/> <p>From Copetpek to Reykjavic, the hills of Lola are pockmarked by collapsed brick chimneys and fenceless gates. Here is where they died, in their hundreds of thousands. These monuments watched over the postwar period, where the craters had been filled in and decontaminated.</p>
<p>You were not supposed to play in the ruins because of residual radiation. That&rsquo;s what they were told as kids. The truth is that the stones were next to harmless after seventy years. They did not want the kids playing there because there was no telling how many unmarked graves remained or what might rise to the surface in the rains.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Sketch for a Friend</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/neko/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/neko/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ A drawing for my friend Nubik, featuring his character, Neko. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/neko.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">A drawing for my friend Nubik, featuring his character, Neko.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Constable Zelda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/constable/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/constable/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Disclaimer: Tzipora has never worked for/cooperated with the police. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/constable.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Disclaimer: Tzipora has never worked for/cooperated with the police.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>All That Glitters</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/gold/</link>
	  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/gold/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Vekllei has a cultural tradition of medallions and pins, which make up a lot of the jewellery in a moneyless society. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/gold.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Vekllei has a cultural tradition of medallions and pins, which make up a lot of the jewellery in a moneyless society.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Veranda</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/veranda/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/veranda/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ Sitting out on the veranda in the sun. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/3.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">Sitting out on the veranda in the sun.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>Department Commerce</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/department/</link>
	  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/department/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Despite having many consumer products, Vekllei is not a consumer society and is not equipped to succeed as one. Benevolent state monopolies produce staple goods &ndash; food, clothing, and shelter &ndash; and everything else is left up to the anarchic participatory industriousness of its people, which is situated somewhere between a productive free market and chaos.
These planned production mechanisms facilitate the reliable overproduction of essential goods that meet the needs of Vekllei population.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/department.jpg"/> <p>Despite having many consumer products, Vekllei is not a consumer society and is not equipped to succeed as one. Benevolent state monopolies produce staple goods &ndash; food, clothing, and shelter &ndash; and everything else is left up to the anarchic participatory industriousness of its people, which is situated somewhere between a productive free market and chaos.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>These planned production mechanisms facilitate the reliable overproduction of essential goods that meet the needs of Vekllei population. The inflexibility of this system is supplanted by the private market of participatory labour, which produces the majority of consumer goods and products in Vekllei, if unreliably. Luxury goods are generally hyperlocalised or imported, and are scarce for most Veklei people.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&ndash; <a href="/assets/">State Assets of Vekllei</a></p>
<p>Since the staples of Vekllei life are produced in an inflexible planned system based on overproduction, the most common place of &lsquo;commerce&rsquo; for ordinary Vekllei people is the department store. They are a feature of the country, capable of furnishing a complete life out of simple and quality goods. Furniture, clothing, some appliances, and all types of food are available. Clothing is of high quality, and has some variety of essential fashions in contemporary society.</p>
<p>These department stores resemble the icons of consumer societies overseas, but without an efficient means of exchange to build real markets built on capital, the mechanisms to develop a consumer culture are absent. Instead, Vekllei is full of &lsquo;ghost consumers;&rsquo; people participating in consumer rituals that look like their counterparts overseas, but missing the critical aspects of consumer desire and money-value.</p>
<p>Indeed, Tzipora was surprised when Cobian took her to the Montvisiosn Department Store one day to &lsquo;shop&rsquo; for new clothes. Cobian tried things on and frowned at herself in the mirror like the Yanquis and Londoners and Parisians do, but she was really acting out what she saw in films. It was a fantasy; a child&rsquo;s idea of shopping and consumption and commerce. It was very exotic to Vekllei people, but Tzipora had lived overseas and knew the difference money-value made. There was no real desire to consume; it was a social ritual without a financial basis. They might as well have been doing each other&rsquo;s hair in the park, or trying on her mother&rsquo;s shoes.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Prime Minister(s)</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/ministers/</link>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/ministers/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[Vekllei is a nonpartisan democracy with two, equal heads of state &ndash; one man and one woman. Known as Crown Ministers in Vekllei, they generally acknowledge the title of Prime Minister overseas, as the head of Vekllei government and secretary-general of the Vekllei Cabinet. The position is a quirk of the postwar period, when radical alternatives to existing systems of government were being explored in the anarcho-feminist whirlwind of independence.]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/ministers.jpg"/> <p>Vekllei is a nonpartisan democracy with two, equal heads of state &ndash; one man and one woman. Known as <em>Crown Ministers</em> in Vekllei, they generally acknowledge the title of <em>Prime Minister</em> overseas, as the head of Vekllei government and secretary-general of the Vekllei Cabinet. The position is a quirk of the postwar period, when radical alternatives to existing systems of government were being explored in the <a href="/stories/women/">anarcho-feminist whirlwind of independence</a>.</p>
<p>Although the title includes two seperate people, they represent a single office and so are expected to make agreeable decisions, if nothing else. This is a role of compromise and moderation, since each Prime Minister has the power to censure the other. Stalemates and infighting usually results in the sacking of the government by the Cabinet Secretary, since Vekllei people have little tolerance for partisan bickering in their public servants. The nonpartisan nature of Vekllei politics means the formation of government often sees unconventional members of parliament enter the cabinet, often from industry, the arts, or sciences. In this context, the ideal Prime Minister is well-groomed and patient by nature, and all great Vekllei PMs have been masters of compromise.</p>
<p>When Tzipora arrives in Vekllei in the early 2060s, the country is lead by Prime Ministers Raif Housk and Dalia Hospotet, pictured here. Traditionally, PMs divide responsibilities along their strengths as politicians. Dalia Hospotet, for example, is a master of statecraft and so meets regularly with foreign leaders to express the Vekllei position. Raif is an economist at the <a href="/cosmosol/">Ministry of Commerce</a>, and his talents lie in exploiting his deep connections to Vekllei business. That is not to suggest the Prime Ministers operate independently &ndash; quite the opposite in fact. Decisions have to be made as in agreement, as a single office, and so the relationship of the PMs resembles a married couple, with definitive answers postponed until consort can be had. The election of Prime Ministers is a marriage of two people, in a civic sense.</p>
<p>Their most important function, as two people in a single role, is to represent their people and indicate, both to foreigners and themselves, the values of their society. Prime Ministership is an intimate and symbolic position, and their appearance internally and abroad is in some ways more like the king and queen of a monarchy than the public servants of a modern democracy. But that too represents Vekllei well, as a hybrid society of contradictory yet fascinating instincts, breaking down the historicism of society by insisting that the past is the future and the revolutionary is ordinary.</p>
]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
	<item>
	  <title>The Look</title>
	  <link>https://millmint.net/stories/the-look/</link>
	  <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	  
	  <guid>https://millmint.net/stories/the-look/</guid>
	  <author>
		  <name>MillMint</name>
		  <uri>https://millmint.net/</uri>
	  </author>
	  <description>
	  <![CDATA[ The Look. ]]>
	  </description>
	 <content:encoded>
	 	<![CDATA[<img src="https://millmint.net/images/sketches/1.jpg"/> <blockquote class="hint caption">
  <div class="icon">
</div> 
  <div class="text">The Look.</div>
</blockquote>

]]>
  	</content:encoded>
	</item>
	
  </channel>
</rss>
