<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Characters on MillMint</title>
    <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Characters on MillMint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Characters</title>
      <link>https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://millmint.net/utopia/characters/draft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint &#34;&gt;
  ߷ This article is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/intro/#three-utopias&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hobart&amp;rsquo;s characters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who live in &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/vekllei&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vekllei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fc&#34;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;lthough almost all characters&lt;/strong&gt; in this project were born in Vekllei, they are of vastly different heritages and backgrounds. A study of modern Vekllei is a study of immigration. Most characters here have swirling ethnic, religious and cultural histories aiding and obscuring their destinies. This is useful, because if you&amp;rsquo;re following along with this project, you&amp;rsquo;re in some small way an immigrant yourself. It&amp;rsquo;s through the eyes of these people that you see Vekllei, and their lives contribute to the utopian dimensions of this project as utopias-of-living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; &gt;Tzipora (Zelda)&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;M&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&#34;smallimg&#34; style=&#34;background-color: transparent;&#34; src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/mastheads/characters/zelda.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tzipora lo Ula de Helette Desmoisnes&lt;/strong&gt; is the main character and &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/utopia/intro/#three-utopias&#34;&gt;character utopia&lt;/a&gt; of this project. Often called Zelda by her friends, she is the protagonist of this project and a significant person within Vekllei. Although born in Vekllei, Tzipora was raised overseas in Colombia and later educated in the United States. It was not until her return to Vekllei in her teen-age years that she was formally diagnosed with &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/posts/2021-05-28-forever/&#34;&gt;Gregori Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;, a genetic disorder that affects her ageing and extends her natural life. Since her arrival in Vekllei, she has formed sincere and long-lasting relationships in her homeland, stabilising the neurotic parts of her personality and making her happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/tzipora&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  See all stories featuring Tzipora
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;details &gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Get to know Tzipora&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;Appearance&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is blue-eyed and black-haired of mixed Inuit-Scandinavian and Eastern-European heritage. She has a round head and a big smile, and is skinny and naturally athletic. She parts her short hair in the centre and ornaments it with fountain hairpieces, traditional hair loops and floral assemblies depending on the occasion. She is most remembered for her youthful appearance, since she does not age beyond late prepubescence as a consequence of her genetic condition. Despite this, she retains a serious, cultivated manner and alternates disarmingly between intense hyperactivity and careful, deliberate physicality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She dresses in conservative fashions and has maintained a consistent taste throughout her life. She has a preference for loose-fitting clothing, particularly buttoned shirts, slacks and skirts of various styles. She is most commonly seen in a pleated white shirt, modest skirt, folded socks and penny loafers or sandals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora is nonconformist by way of ignorance or obstinance depending on the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is paranoid and conservative, good-natured and austere, with a moral outlook bound by her deepest anxieties and obsessions. She is deeply spiritual and material, fascinated with objects and their history. She has many collections of many things she’s found. She’ll likely die a Catholic, but has a confrontational relationship with God and no longer attends mass. She has Jewish ancestry and struggles to reconcile the fractured parts of her family history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzipora may be intense and inward-facing, but she can also be disarmingly charming and self-deprecating. She has a good sense of humour. There are not many girls that can so easily reconcile the contradictions between the peculiar and the healthy, the eccentric and the friendly, and the violent and the domestic. That’s part of her character — an essence of being that radiates decency, good taste and a respect for the spirit of all things.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; &gt;Cobian&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;F&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&#34;smallimg&#34; style=&#34;background-color: transparent;&#34; src=&#34;https://millmint.net/images/mastheads/characters/cobian.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cobian lo Ro de Viviya de Queismesnah&lt;/strong&gt; is Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s longtime friend and occasional girlfriend. Conservative in manner and appearance, Cobian is easily remembered by her circular spectacles and stern fringe, styles maintained since childhood. Tzipora and Cobian met during secondary schooling in Vekllei, and remained close throughout the rest of their lives. She is very close with Tzipora, but has tepid relationships with Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s (mostly male) friendship group out of jealousy and a general distaste for boys. She is rigorously polite in the middle-class sense of the word; formal among strangers, gossipy among friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/cobian&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  See all stories featuring Cobian
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;details &gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Get to know Cobian&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;Appearance&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobian is green-eyed and black-haired, descended mostly from Inuit-Scandinavian ethnic groups common in Vekllei. She is more Asiatic in appearance than her friend Zelda, and is tall for her age. She styles her long hair in many different ways, most commonly in a bun or braids. She is healthy but inactive, and tans easily without freckling. Cobian is naturally graceful and well-mannered, traits Tzipora is deeply envious of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She dresses in prim, well-maintained clothing courtesy of her despotically hygienic mother, and has a penchant for ironed shirts, pleatless skirts, synthetic hosiery and jewellery she considers befitting a maturing young woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Tzipora meets her, Cobian is a figure of sympathy and irritation. She was deeply insecure after old friendships fell apart in the tumultuous transition between middle and secondary schooling. Once she became comfortable around her new friend and matured out of some old insecurities, Cobian revealed herself to be easy-going and friendly, a person of small pretensions and genuine friendship. In her own skin, she makes an excellent conversationalist, charmingly attentive and ready to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people think she&amp;rsquo;s pretentious; she&amp;rsquo;s not pretentious. She likes good food and is highly fashionable in her interests and styles, but Cobian is also deeply empathetic and finds interest in new things via her friends she&amp;rsquo;d never previously thought about. She makes up most of Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s social life, which leaves plenty of space for Zelda&amp;rsquo;s big personality and obsessions. Zelda has a deeply stablising effect on Cobian, rounding out some of her mother&amp;rsquo;s strict legacy through Zelda&amp;rsquo;s androgynous habits and far-fetched fascinations. But Zelda&amp;rsquo;s big personality does not include much talking or grace, and in these deficiencies Cobian&amp;rsquo;s social talent shines. Together they make a great pair, their neighbouring personalities aiding their best selves.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; &gt;Moise&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;j&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moise ra Hasapis&lt;/strong&gt; is Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s neighbour and best friend. Like Tzipora, he was born overseas and has only started schooling in Vekllei in late childhood. Imposing in both attitude and posture, Moise is feared and respected among his peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/moise&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  See all stories featuring Moise
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;details &gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Get to know Moise&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;Appearance&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moise is brown-eyed and dark-haired, with powerful Greek features inherited from his mother and father. Hard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; &gt;Coretti&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;o&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coretti lo Rus de Gloria Adoula&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;a href=&#34;https://millmint.net/characters/moise&#34;&gt;Moise&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; girlfriend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/coretti&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  See all stories featuring Coretti
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;details &gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Get to know Coretti&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;Appearance&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; &gt;Zhi&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;h&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lin Zhi&lt;/strong&gt;, who prefers being addressed by her full name, is Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s friend and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/zhi&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  See all stories featuring Lin Zhi
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;details &gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Get to know Lin Zhi&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;Appearance&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; &gt;Baron&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;7&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baron Desmoisnes&lt;/strong&gt;, colloquially &lt;strong&gt;The Baron&lt;/strong&gt; behind his back, is Tzipora&amp;rsquo;s adoptive father and guardian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/baron&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  See all stories featuring Baron
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;details &gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Get to know Baron&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;Appearance&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;headerbox&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h1 class=&#34;title&#34; &gt;Ayn&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;emoji&#34; id=&#34;whirlybat&#34;&gt;4&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;section &#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ayn Rumouisen&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a  href=&#34;https://millmint.net/tags/ayn&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;  class=&#34;book-btn&#34;&gt;
  See all stories featuring Ayn
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
a.book-btn:hover {
  filter: brightness(85%);
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;details &gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Get to know Ayn&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;markdown-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;h5 id=&#34;appearance&#34;&gt;Appearance&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
.gt-container {
  display: none;
}
a.book-btn {
  margin-top: 0;
  border: 1px solid var(--color-pink);
  //background-color: rgba(255, 43, 78, 0.25);
  //color: var(--body-font-color);
  color: var(--color-pink);;
  }
article h5 {
  margin-top: 1rem;
}

.headerbox {
  margin-top: 2rem;
}

.title {
  line-height: 3; 
  font-size: 1.5rem; 
  font-weight: 700;
  margin-top: auto!important; 
  margin-bottom: auto; 
  filter: brightness(35%);
}

.emoji {
  line-height: 50%;
  font-size: 35pt;
}

.section {
    opacity: 1!important;
  }

.section p {
  opacity: 0.85;
}
&lt;/style&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>